[ Crowd Sounds ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Thank you.
Good morning and welcome.
My name is Ali Ozer.
And with my colleague Daphne,
we'll be talking to you about
what's new in Cocoa this year.
For -- on our menu today for
appetizer, we have API
refinements followed by two main
courses AppKit and Foundation.
So let's get started.
So on the API refinements front,
in previous years we've talked
to you about the large efforts
to improve API exposure of our
frameworks: Properties,
nullability, generics, the Swift
3 naming guidelines last year,
and most recently string
enumerations and nested types.
This time, I'll talk a bit about
the last two.
And I'll do that by giving an
example that covers both.
So in this scenario we focused
on a lot during the last year
and you'll see it in a lot of
our APIs.
So here is NSSharingService as
it comes across is Swift 3.
We have a number of global
symbols, as you can see here,
coming across S strings.
And then we have methods like
let method in a sharing service
that takes an argument of type
string.
Now in Swift 4, we've introduced
a new type called name.
This type is nested inside
NSSharingService.
An init method now takes an
argument of type
NSSharingService.Name.
And, of course, the values now,
the various values you saw
earlier are now declared this
NSSharingService.Name.
And their names are a lot
shorter since they're no longer
in the global context.
So with that, the code becomes a
lot simpler.
Instead of this in Swift 3, you
now can type this in Swift 4.
And, of course, you get a much
[inaudible] set of completions
when typing.
Here you are.
And you type your dot and you
get exactly the values that make
sense for that init method
rather than older strings in the
frameworks.
So you might be wondering about
the source compatibility
implications of this change.
In Objective-C, there's no
nesting.
That's only a Swift thing so
that has no impact.
And the string enums are
achieved with a typedef as you
can see here.
And this is totally source
compatible.
So no sourcing compatibility for
Objective-C.
In Swift, the Swift 3 name
remains exactly the same.
So your code is source
compatible.
The Swift 4 has a brand-new
name.
And the old name no longer even
exists.
So Swift 4 is not compatible.
However, we do have a migrator
for moving to Swift 4 so you get
to choose when you want to move
and move your sources over.
So that's it.
That's it as far as API
refinements.
You will see these changes apply
to a number of our APIs.
So next, I'm going to just dive
into AppKit.
And I'll start off by talking
about the big feature we
introduced last fall, which is
Touch Bar, of course.
Touch Bar so --
[ Applause ]
As many of you are aware, Touch
Bar is an input device that
replaces the top row of keys on
your keyboard.
It provides controls for both
the system and the default, the
active application by default.
Now being a multi-touch input
device, and a beautiful retina
display, Touch Bar provides rich
interactions and also dynamic
content.
So here is some of the Touch
Bars that are part of the system
and a part of our system
applications, as you can see, a
wide variety of rich content and
interaction models in these
controls.
Now, one important thing to note
about the Touch Bar is that
although it is a beautiful
display, the Touch Bar is an
input device.
That's its primary purpose in
life.
So it's not appropriate for
display purposes such as stock
ticker notifications and so on.
So in your applications, treat
it as an extension of the
keyboard.
Now I'm going to highlight some
qualities that makes the Touch
Bar such a compelling feature to
support in your applications.
First, Touch Bar is context
sensitive meaning it easily
adapts to whatever the user is
doing.
Let me just give you a quick
example.
Here you are typing in TextEdit.
And as you're typing, the Touch
Bar shows you, by default, quick
type completions for whatever
the user is typing.
Now when you make a selection,
the Touch Bar switches to show
you text formatting controls as
you can see here, colors, bold,
italic and so on.
Now, here we are typing in the
To field of a mail message.
And you can see that the Touch
Bar completions are now giving
you e-mail addresses.
In fact, Mail is using
predictive addressing to predict
what addresses you might want to
type.
And here, when you're typing in
the subject line of Mail, you
again get quick type.
However, you also get the Send
button on the left end of the
Touch Bar because, after all,
you are in Mail.
So these are some of the ways
that the Touch Bar is context
sensitive.
And there are many examples of
this.
Touch Bar, second, is
customizable.
And that enables the user to
arrange things in a way that
makes sense for them.
So the user can customize the
default control strip as you can
see here.
They can choose to expand the
control strip, which they can
also customize in a variety of
ways.
And they can also choose to run
with default function keys on
for specific apps that they
choose.
In addition, the user can
customize the app bars for apps
that provide customization.
For instance, here we are in
calculator.
You can go ahead to the View
menu and choose Customize Tool
Bar.
That puts you in customization
mode.
And you can see that the items
in the Touch Bar are jiggling in
anticipation of being
customized.
Let me zoom this in a bit.
And you have a whole palette of
items that you can drag down to
the Touch Bar.
Now, note that customization is
an opt-in feature.
It's much like an NSToolbar.
Now it's a feature users expect
from your apps, so we encourage
you to implement it if it makes
sense at all.
For instance, if you have many
more commands than you can
display in the Touch Bar or you
just want the users to have the
ability to arrange default items
in there.
The last quality of Touch Bar, I
want to highlight, is its
ability to provide unobstructed
access to content.
You can take advantage of the
presence of Touch Bar to hide
controls on-screen to reduce
clutter.
For instance, here is Keynote.
In fact, the app we're using for
these presentations.
Here is Keynote in presentation
mode.
You can see that in presentation
mode, there are no controls on
the display, but the Touch Bar
still reflects controls that
allow me to advance through the
slides and go to any specific
slide if I want.
Another example here is
QuickTime in full-screen mode
where the media controls fade
away from the main screen, but
you can still present them in
the Touch Bar.
Now we do have some important
updates to Touch Bar
functionality and NSTouchBar
APIs in macOS High Sierra.
And I just want to highlight
some of those.
So let's get started with the
color pickers.
You might be aware that the
color pickers in Touch Bar in
macOS Sierra, we have two modes
for color pickers: The simple
mode and the HSB mode.
We've now added a mode selector,
as you can see here, with four
additional modes, the grayscale
mode, RGB mode, CMYK mode, and
the Swatch mode.
Now the colors shown in that
last Swatch mode are the same as
the colors shown in the color
picker in the bottom area of the
color picker.
These are the favorites that are
chosen by the user so the color
is over there.
You'll also note that we have a
button here on the right end of
color pickers, most of them,
that allow you to add currently
selected color as a favorite
swatch directly from the touch
bar.
Now with these additions, the
Touch Bar color picker has
gotten fairly sophisticated and
can replace the main color
picker, the main color panel on
the screen for most use cases.
And this, of course, goes back
to that point I made about
enabling unobstructed access to
content.
So the user cannot actually run
without having the color panel
up in most cases.
Okay. We have an API update in
this color picker Touch Bar
item.
This new method, this new
property allowed color spaces,
enables specifying the color
space to be used, let's say the
color space of the current
document.
So the color picker can show
colors as they will appear when
used in the document.
Let me just show you an example.
Here is the simple color picker.
Now if you set the
allowedColorSpaces to
genericCMYK, you'll see colors
that are somewhat more muted
because this is the way they
would appear in the CMYK
document.
And here's a more extreme case.
If you're working on a
monochrome document, this is the
colors you would get.
We have some API updates on
NSGroupTouchBarItem as well.
First is the constructor for the
alert style.
Now you may be aware that when
AppKit shows an NSAlert, the
buttons are automatically
reflected in the Touch Bar as
you can see here.
Now if you, yourself, are
showing custom UIs with buttons
and you want to do the same kind
of thing AppKit does with
regards to placement and sizing
of the buttons, we have an API
for you.
And this is init
AlertStyleGroupItem
WithIdentifier method which
allows you to create a
GroupTouchBarItem and add your
buttons and get the same sort of
sizing and placement behaviors.
Another API on GroupTouchBarItem
provides the ability to specify
compression options.
So this determines how content
is managed if space grows tight
on the bar.
For instance, here is a bar.
In the middle we have four
buttons all with icons and
titles.
In a language like German, which
has bigger titles, by default
one of the buttons would drop
off.
But you'd rather have the
buttons compress than to lose
one of the buttons.
And you might want to choose
between whether you want the
icons to drop off or the titles
to drop off so something like
this or like this.
And also note that when one of
the icons drop off, you probably
want all of them to drop off for
consistency.
So this new API will let you do
that.
You specify to prioritize
compression options to apply.
And these include things like
hide images, hide text, or break
[inaudible].
The last API provides support
for right-to-left interfaces in
the GroupTouchBarItem class.
So the previous APIs provided
right-to-left support in
specific cases such as segmented
control.
But now we have an API on
GroupTouchBarItem that allows
more flexibility.
Here is a FaceTime Touch Bar.
And in a right-to-left language,
you want it to appear like this
where those groups are flipped
inside each other but the whole
bar is not flipped and those
groups are not flipped across
the app section of the bar.
And this new API lets you
specify the user interface
layout direction on a per
GroupTouchBarItem basis.
Last thing for Touch Bar that I
want to highlight is Playground
support.
As you know, Playgrounds are
really fun.
Let's see this in action.
So you go ahead and enter your
Touch Bar code in the, sorry the
font is small but you don't need
to read this.
There's no quiz.
And then when you see this in
action, you can see your Touch
Bar items.
And, in fact, the whole Touch
Bar just come alive in
Playground.
[ Applause ]
And you can do fairly
sophisticated things: Check for
the placement and sizing and
also do things like replace the
Escape key, which is a fairly
advanced operation that you can
do right there in Playground.
So we have two sessions for
Touch Bar: The Fundamentals
talk, which is right after this,
will give you a great overview
of how to incorporate NSTouchBar
APIs into your application and
advanced talk this afternoon at
5:10, which will take you
further with some powerful
real-world use cases.
And both talks are entertaining
and educational so I encourage
you to attend them.
We also have a lab tomorrow
morning for Touch Bar from 9:00
to 11:00.
Okay. So next let's talk about
document sharing.
In macOS Sierra, we introduce
this sharing service, cloud
sharing, which enabled
persistent cloud-based sharing
sessions with other users.
In this release, we enable
iCloud drive-base document
sharing.
And let me show you what this
means.
Here we are in TextEdit.
You can go into the Share menu.
You can choose Add People.
This brings up the Add People
dialogue.
You can choose how you want to
send your invitation.
Let's choose Messages.
Let's invite our friend John
Appleseed, of course, and send
it off.
And you can see the document is
now shared.
And you can see that in the
title bar.
It indicates it's shared.
And John Appleseed can go ahead
and make his valuable
contributions to the document or
not so valuable.
And so the question for you is
how many lines of code in
TextEdit did it take to do this?
Of course, since I'm asking you
it's probably not, you know, 800
lines or thousands but the
answer may shock you because
it's really zero.
And TextEdit is already a
NSDocument based app and already
adopted auto-saving.
And thanks to that, TextEdit
gets all this functionality I
showed you for free.
And this is true for any
NSDocument based app you might
have.
In fact, this whole Share menu
here is new in macOS High
Sierra.
And it includes other classic --
I'll call them classic, you
know, they're from a few years
ago, sharing services such as
Mail, AirDrop, Notes, et cetera.
So this whole menu is free in
your NSDocument based
applications in macOS High
Sierra.
NSDocument, you can on a per
instance basis, indicate whether
a document should be shared or
not, so you can disable the
default sharing.
This method share initiates a
share.
And the prepare method allows
you to make any final changes to
the picker before the menu is
presented.
And NSDocument controller, you
have a property that lets you
pretty much disable this whole
sharing service.
So you can control it yourself
if you want.
And then the StandardShare menu
item will return the menu that
you can place yourself, rather
than let the app get placed in
its default location.
Tabbed Windows.
We added Tabbed Windows in macOS
Sierra in the last release.
And we did it in a way that
pretty much worked automatic for
all applications.
So here you can see it in action
in pages, for instance, where I
can go to the Window menu, Merge
All Windows, and bam.
Now I get -- all my documents
are tabs and you can just choose
between them.
It's really nice feature
reducing clutter.
In macOS High Sierra, we added
the Tab Overview feature.
This is new.
And you go to the View menu and
select Show All Tabs and then
this now shows you the tabs much
like Safari has been able to do.
And then you go ahead and
visually select which tab you
want.
So it's all automatic.
Again, your apps will get this
for free.
We do have some APIs that let
you have more control over tabs.
One is the NSWindowTab class.
It represents instances of this,
represent information about a
single tab.
And just using this Safari tab
bar as an example, the title
[inaudible] title properties
allow you to customize the
default title that's shown.
And by the default title is, of
course, the title of the window.
The toolTip property lets you
customize the default toolTip
that's displayed.
And accessoryView property lets
you insert an accessoryView in
the tab bar.
And you can see here, in Safari,
the little speaker icon which
Safari uses to indicate webpages
that are playing audio.
So you can do this now on your
own tabs as well.
The NSWindowTabGroup class
represents information about the
whole tab group in that window.
You can ask for its properties
like whether it's visible or the
overview is visible.
You can integrate the windows.
You can change which window is
front.
And you can also add and remove
windows from the tab group as
well.
Now a new delegate method in
this application for opening
URLs.
As you're likely aware,
NSApplicationDelegate provides
several callouts to open files
but none for handling URLs.
So this new method application
open URLs will be called with
URLs instead of files
[inaudible], but it will also be
called for any custom URL
schemes your application may
have registered for.
So previously this was something
you would have to register an
Apple event handler for and you
don't need to.
And this is now much easier.
And if implemented, this gets
called for all open requests
except those automatically
handled by NSDocument, which are
taken out of this list.
So fairly straightforward.
Thank you.
NSCollectionView will now -- in
macOS High Sierra does
responsive scrolling.
And let me show you what this
means.
Here we have a CollectionView
with six visible items but, of
course, there are many more
items above and below the
collection view, the visible
area.
CollectionView does prefetching
meaning it will go ahead and
prefetch some items that are not
yet visible with the
anticipation of the user
scrolling to that area.
So this is automatic for
applications of linked on 10.13
and you don't need to do
anything.
However, if you do want to
affect the way this works,
there's a new prefetch data
source with two methods you can
implement.
So this prefetchDataSource is
the same delegate API as iOS
has, the same delegate, sorry,
the same data source method.
And two methods here are -- one
lets you hear about prefetch
items being prefetched.
And the other lets you hear
about prefetch being canceled
say because the user stops
scrolling.
See you can actually use these
to customize the prefetching
behaviors above and beyond
traditional data source
behaviors you're already
implementing but, again, these
are options.
You don't have to implement this
data source at all and things
will still work.
Next, we have a few updates
about colors.
First, new properties NSColor to
implement system colors.
So these are properties such as
systemBlue, systemBrown,
systemGray, et cetera.
You can see the list here.
So these are colors that are
meant to be used when you want
colors that match the system
colors or colors used by system
applications.
So these colors may change
between releases and between
different appearances.
For instance, the same color,
same system color used in the
Touch Bar will appear different
than when used in the window.
So this allows your app to
remain fashionable no matter
when or where.
Of course, this also means you
should not make any assumptions
about these exact colors here
since they might change out from
under you.
Now, these are available back to
macOS 10.10, that's Yosemite.
And they're also available in
the Developer list of the color
pickers.
So you can actually directly
pick them and use them in your
application, say in Xcode.
Another update in colors
involves the older standard
colors.
And what do I mean by older
standard colors?
It's these guys, NSColor.red,
.green, .yellow, et cetera that
we've had for many years.
These have traditionally been
defined as saturated business
graphics colors.
For instance, red is 100, green
is 010, et cetera.
These used to be in the generic
RGB or calibrated RGB color
spaces.
Now the values remain the same,
but we've modernized them
kicking and screaming into the
sRGB color spaces.
So what this means, of course,
is that the color values are
somewhat different.
And because of that reason, this
change only occurs for
applications linked against the
10.13 SDK or later.
And you can see this is the way
the colors come through in
generic RGB.
And here's the way they come
across in sRGB.
And there are some visual
differences.
We didn't want to introduce
visual inconsistencies in your
applications.
The one last color feature I
want to mention is colors in
Asset Catalogs.
Xcode now has the ability to let
you add colors to Asset
Catalogs.
And you can see a simple case
here.
Now you can also -- you cannot
add or provide just one color
for a given named color.
You can also provide multiple
colors, one per gamut.
For instance, here we have the
radioactive color with an sRGB
gamut and a Display P3 gamut
color.
And this is not something you
have to do very often.
This is pretty rare.
But you might need to do it if
you have a number of P3 colors
that are saturated and that when
reduced to sRGB come across as
the same.
So you want to distinguish them
in sRGB.
You might want to provide this
RGB variance.
But, again, it should be fairly
rare to need to do that.
So how do you get at these
colors?
We have API for this, both and
NSColor and also in UIColor.
You basically create an NSColor
by supplying a name.
You can also supply a bundle if
the Asset Catalog is not in your
main bundle.
We have a number of enhancements
for accessibility as well.
And I'm going to talk about
NSAccessibilityCustomRotor.
You might be aware,
AccessibilityRotors, enable
easier searching of content via
assistive technologies.
For instance, a voiceover user
can browse links in a webpage.
This new API enables you to
invent custom rotors, for
instance headings in a pages
document.
And here's an example of that.
And this is similar -- yeah,
it's a good API.
It's similar to the
UIAccessibilityCustomRotor API
on iOS, which we introduced last
release.
And fairly straightforward, you
implement the
accessibilityCustomRotors method
on the accessibility protocol
and return an array of the
custom rotors you'd like to
vend.
A little property clean-up note.
So we had a number of object
properties in AppKit still
[inaudible].
Now these come cross especially
sad in Swift as unknown and then
to add insult to injury, also
unsafe.
And so we changed a bunch here.
Delegates, [inaudible] outlets,
and naturally weak relationships
such as parent pointers or first
responder as you can see here.
These have become weak.
And the contentView here on
NSBox, that's an example of a
property that has become strong.
And you can see the way they
come across now in 10.13.
Now, these changes are
compatible for the most part,
but you should be aware that a
weak property will become
automatically [inaudible] out
when the object being referenced
goes away.
So that could represent some
compatibility, some change in
behavior, risk incompatibility.
So it's something to keep an eye
out for.
And, by the way, one more thing
here.
We can't show you his or her
name or face but in doing this
we fulfilled this developer's
WWDC wish.
So I don't know if you're out
there, but happy WWDC to you.
[ Applause ]
So we listen.
So a few updates on Text.
My first, we have improved
orphan handling in NSTextField.
What this means is we'll reduce
occurrences where you might have
a single Chinese or Japanese
character occurring on a line by
itself, especially in two line
cases.
And this affects, for instance,
the lookup alerts and so on.
We have CGGlyph-based APIs in
NSFont and NSBezierPath.
This provides improved impedance
match with lower-level graphics
APIs and, of course, provides
better performance.
We have a new class called
NSFontAssetRequest for
downloading system fonts.
These are fonts that are part of
the system but that do not ship
with the system.
So with this API now, instead of
getting the default synchronous
UI, you can actually incorporate
an asynchronous UI directly into
your applications.
And last but not least for Text,
we have support for Nastaliq
script.
Nastaliq is a style of writing
in the Arabic script used for
languages like Urdu.
It's a striking script.
It requires some typesetting in
order to render properly.
And we finally have support for
it in the Cocoa Text system.
And we can just show you an
example.
Here's the word Nastaliq
rendered in traditional script.
And here's the same word
rendered in Nastaliq script.
And you can see why this is a
challenge because of the flowing
diagonal nature.
Now, some honorable AppKit
features mentions.
NSSegmentedControl has alignment
and distribution properties that
provide you with more control
over layout.
NSLevelIndicator has a
beautifully refined new look and
some API refinements as well.
NSMenuItem now allows you to
have a KeyEquivalentWhenHidden
so you can actually have
additional key equivalents in
your menus.
NSTableView allows you to use
auto layout to compute row
heights automatically.
We have asynchronous restorable
state encoding meaning objects
that actually implement states
preservation and restoration can
now do so asynchronously, if
there was a performance,
potential performance hit in the
way they were doing it.
We have improved handling of
large items during dragging.
So as you're dragging a large
image around a screen, it will
now be automatically scaled down
so you can actually see what
you're dragging over.
And finally, NSDrawers have been
deprecated.
Now, if you're wondering
NSDrawers, what are they?
Well, don't bother because
they're deprecated.
Okay. And so two more things
before I hand the stage off to
Daphne.
First, Container Views.
So we have a number of Container
Views in Cocoa: NSBrowser,
TableView, OutlineView,
CollectionView, StackView, and
GridView.
And if you ever wondered how to
choose among these, we have a
talk for you.
Choosing the Right Cocoa
Container View this afternoon at
3:10.
So come here once and for all,
which one of these is the best
container view?
Or are there may be more than
one winner, of course.
Next, I have a question for you.
Have you ever tried to call
print when debugging your
application and instead of
displaying that object, that
darn object you're trying to
print, you get a panel like
this?
Some of you probably have.
So in the subclass of NSView,
print is ambiguous.
And it will hopefully try to get
you to print your app using, you
know, a piece of paper.
Now I'm not saying this was
terrible.
Walking away from the computer,
a few pieces of paper may be the
best way to debug a problem
sometimes, but it's often not
what you really wanted.
So we have an API change for
you.
NSWindow and NSView and
NSWindows print methods have
been renamed to printView and
printWindow.
So now this in Swift 4, so a tip
for you, migrate and profit.
Now speaking of tips, be sure to
head to this presentation Cocoa
Development Tips Friday morning
at 9:00 where you can hear many
more tips.
And really, frankly, I really
don't know how many because
we've lost count of how many
tips we have.
You can count on your own.
Now -- and we also want to give
you the opportunity to share
your own tips with everyone.
So if you know of any handy
Cocoa development tips to share
with developers, please tweet
them using the #WWDC17 and
cocoatips.
And who knows, your tip may make
it into this presentation on
Friday.
So with that, I invite my
colleague Daphne on stage.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. My name is Daphne Larose.
I'm an engineer on the
foundation team.
We'll start off by talking about
two of the new big things in
Foundation.
We have better support now for
Key Paths.
And we also have support for
encoding and decoding in Swift.
We'll start with Key Paths.
So we now have a new literal
syntax that's both type-safe and
performant.
Some of you are probably already
familiar with how it looks in
Swift 3.
Now, it's even simpler in Swift
4.
It has a backslash base type dot
and then the property name.
The simplicity of this has
enabled us to enhance some of
our pre-existing APIs, for
example KVO.
So, in this example here, we're
trying to observe a particular
property dog on the class
DogOwner.
And so before it was a lot more
set up involved, a lot more code
that you had to write.
Now, you can actually get a
block-based, closure-based
observation back that is much
cleaner, much simpler, only two
lines of code in this example.
And the simplicity of the syntax
makes the Key Paths a lot
simpler to use.
For encoding and decoding in
Swift, we now have support for
converting between your
type-safe Swift [inaudible] and
loser formats like JSON, P
lists, etcetera.
Deeply customizable so it's very
easy to make changes for your
own custom structs.
And it's incredibly easy to use.
So easy, actually, that all it
involves is just declaring your
struct as codable.
And so with doing this, you
don't have to write any
boilerplate code.
You don't have to do anything
extra.
You automatically gain
implementations for encoding and
decoding for free right
out-of-the-box.
So as some of you are probably
well aware, we already have a
What's New in Foundation talk in
about two hours, which is pretty
great for us because it frees us
up to talk about what else is
new in Foundation.
So I'll go into it with a little
bit more detail.
So we have a lot of new API, a
lot of enhanced API that's
available on both macOS and iOS.
We'll start with
NSXPCConnection, which is
available on iOS, by the way.
It allows authors to publish
progress in a way that it didn't
before.
And so we have an example
protocol here that would be
shared by client and server.
Before it would just return
void.
Now it actually can return
NSProgress.
And what's nice about this is
that it allows the server to
return a progress to the client
even before it returns its
reply.
And so the client is actually
able to see these updates live
as they're happening.
[ Applause ]
URLSession now has a new Boolean
property that allows URLSession
to actually monitor connectivity
on your behalf.
And so it'll wait to start your
URLSessionTasks until
connectivity is satisfactory.
So no more manual retries if
there's insufficient network.
You don't have to worry about
all of that.
Setting this property handles
that for you.
Now, if you choose not to set
it, that's fine.
That's your choice but it goes
back to the old behavior.
Multipath TCP is now available
on iOS.
And URLSessionTask, like
NSXPCConnection now supports
Progress Reporting.
We're going to be talking more
about that in part two of the
advances in networking talk.
That's later on today.
Part one is going to be pretty
awesome too so you might as well
check that out.
NSFileProviderService now has
support for more direct
communication between apps and
file providers.
File providers for those who
don't know are app extension
pairs that own and manage
documents.
They also sync those documents
up to private cloud services.
And they can make those
documents available for other
apps.
In this API, apps are now able
to more easily discover file
providers for any URL.
And they can use the specialized
services that these file
providers provide.
There's going to be a talk on
Friday for this.
So if you'd like more
information, you should check it
out.
So the nice thing is that the
changes we made for
NSXPCConnection and the changes
we made for URLSession are
actually all linked to the
changes we made in
NSFileProviderService.
And so to tie it all together,
we'll bring back this protocol
that we talked about earlier.
We have an app, our client, and
we have a file provider, our
server.
The app calls over to the file
provider, gets an NSProgress
object back.
File provider starts downloading
the file that was requested
using URLSession, [inaudible],
then updates the progress.
So now what's cool about this is
that the app is actually seeing
these updates as it's happening.
The download eventually
finishes, final update is sent,
and now the file provider is
able to reply with the requested
file.
So let's switch gears a little
bit.
We now have API for being able
to check the available storage
space more accurately and with a
sense of intent.
And so we see here important,
opportunistic, it's a little
unclear yet as to what that
specifically means.
So we'll talk in a little bit
more detail about it.
So let's say we have a volume
that has an arbitrary amount of
free disk space.
Opportunistic represents this
free space as well as any files
that the user doesn't
necessarily expect to be there.
So an example of that would be
an old episode of a podcast that
the user has already listened
to.
Important represents free and
opportunistic as well as any
files that the user does expect
to be there but is ultimately
replaceable and purgeable.
So an example of this would be
an audio file that the user
requested to download.
They expect it to be there.
However, if it needs to be
removed to make space, they can
also request to download it
again.
So what's nice about this is
y'all, as developers, are now
able to do preflight checks.
And so in this example, we
actually check how much
opportunistic space is
available.
And if it's above 50 Megs then
we go ahead and download an
additional file.
So what's nice about these
checks is that you can do them
beforehand before you actually
write a lot of data to disk.
And so what it's implying here
is it's checking hey, do we have
enough room to make room for the
file that we're actually about
to download?
So NSLinguisticTagger now has
support for tagging a unit.
So you can tag by word, by
sentence, by paragraph, and also
by lemma.
The API has been completely
redone and revamped.
And it now has some convenience
methods that include
dominantLanguage.
So now you can actually detect
the dominantLanguage of a given
string.
JSONSerialization supports
sorted keys.
So now let's say we have a
dictionary that has an arbitrary
set of keys and values.
When you serialize this
dictionary and then print it,
the keys are printed in
arbitrary order.
But now you can add this
sortedKeys option and have them
print in order.
And so a huge use case for this
is being able to dif JSON files.
It makes for much better
readability and it's just much
nicer.
And this was a highly requested
feature, so we're really happy
to be able to provide it to you
guys.
[ Applause ]
NSItemProvider now makes its
operations more explicit.
It also supports progress
reporting like NSXPCConnection
and URLSession.
You're probably seeing a trend
here.
It also allows you to enhance
your custom classes to work with
multiple representations, for
example data.
So a lot of the efforts put into
this API, this release, were
actually motivated by the new
support we have for
drag-and-drop on iOS.
And so if you want to learn
about that, you can check out
the talk on Thursday.
NSUserActivity already had a
property for webpageURL but now
you can actually specify the
link that referred to that
webpageURL, which is really
convenient.
We now have added new available
APIs to several of our classes
which allows for better error
handling as well as convenience
methods that take URLs rather
than strings.
And so as an example on the
[inaudible], NSTasks, you see it
takes a URL as well as returns
an NSError.
And so 4, in process, it throws
rather than raises an exception.
For NSDictionary and NSArray,
there were already methods that
handled errors, but now we have
these convenience methods that
are just much easier to use and
much cleaner and help you do the
right thing from jump, which is
nice.
We have a new key in NSError
that enables you to display the
error in a way that's more
relevant to the user.
So you're able to customize the
"what failed" while still
keeping the "why it failed".
And so to kind of give an
example of this, this error
message, super decent message.
However, it has some information
that may not necessarily be
particularly relevant to the
user.
For example, ImgDatabaseV2, to
them that really could mean
anything, right?
And so now with this new key,
you can actually give them an
error that still conveys the
same message, the same error,
but it's in a way more palatable
and more understandable to the
user.
We now are able to convert
between NSRanges and Swift
ranges much more easily.
And so in this example, yeah,
all right.
In this example, we're using
NSRegularExpression, which only
takes an NSRange.
And so now we have an
initializer on NSRange that
takes a Swift range and a Swift
string.
And, on the flip side, we have
an initializer and range that
takes an NSRange and the same
Swift string.
So, as you can see here, much
cleaner, much easier.
And for those who have had to
suffer through writing around
this, I hope this is making you
smile because it's pretty great.
We have a lot of performance
improvements this release in
Foundation, which is pretty
exciting.
So we now have support for
Copy-on-write and several of our
collections.
What this means is that the copy
has been moved from the initial
creation of the collection to
the first time the collection
actually gets mutated.
It makes for a much faster
creation and you can just kind
of create them and throw them
away as you need.
Data is now inlined in your apps
making it much faster.
And it's been generally sped up
and it's now also its own
subsequence type.
Calendrical calculations with
NSCalendar is now much faster
and much more accurate and also
overall take significantly less
memory.
We also support a faster
bridging of NSNumber to and from
Swift.
And so we have a talk on Friday
at 1:15 that's going to do a
deep dive of these.
I highly recommend that you
check it out.
So I'm sure a lot of you are
aware NSArchiver and
NSUnarchiver were replaced in
10.4.
They've now been formally
deprecated.
However, old formats are still
supported.
So you can still unarchive using
NSUnarchiver.
However, on behalf of the Cocoa
frameworks department, we are
requesting that you now use
NSKeyedArchiver from now on.
Thanks. Core Data now has some
new indexing features as well as
support for persistent history.
Course Spotlight is now
available on macOS.
And Thermal Notifications are
available on iOS.
And so they'll be covering a lot
more detail on these in the
talks that are happening later
this week.
Actually, Core Data's talk is
right after this one.
So you'll have to use your
[inaudible] against you can be
at the Touch Bar talk and that
one.
And just to wrap up, Ali served
you the appetizer of API
refinements and the first main
course of AppKit.
I served you the second,
Foundation.
And for dessert, I'm going to
tell you about the release notes
and recommend that you check
them out to get a lot more
sample code and detailed
explanations of a lot of the
changes and enhancements that we
made this release.
And so for more information, you
can check out this link.
And just another quick reminder
to tweet your tips.
There's a possibility that yours
might end up showing up in the
talk on Friday, which is pretty
exciting.
And here's some related
sessions, a lot of which we
already covered in this talk.
Thank you for your time.
[ Applause ]