&gt;&gt; Hey there!
Hi, everyone.
Good afternoon and welcome to
this year's edition of what the
heck have those HLS folks been
up to lately.
It wouldn't fit on the slide
though so you kind of get what
you get.
My name is Roger Pantos.
I'm going to be your host here
tonight and we have a bunch of
stuff to talk about.
We have some new CODECS that are
interesting, we have some new
streaming features, and we have
some enhancements to our APIs.
But first, we have our own
announcement to make.
I am happy to announce that the
IETF has approved the
publication of the HLS spec as
an Internet draft.
[ Applause ]
So what this means is that the
current draft that's published
on the site now, which is -23,
will move through the IETF
publication process and once it
does then it will be assigned an
RFC number.
Now we've been sort of
refreshing the draft for like 8
or 9 years now and there's a bit
of question, okay, well why now?
Why publish an RFC?
One of the reasons is that we
have heard feedback from some
people that it's a little scary
to be writing to a spec that's
sort of continuously in draft
mode.
And we get that.
We understand it.
And so publishing the spec as an
RFC will allow it to serve as a
stable reference going forward,
which means that you'll be able
to build on it with confidence,
you'll be able to cite it in
other specifications, and we
hope it will help improve things
a little bit in some areas of
the industry.
Now, are we going to stop
improving HLS?
No, of course not.
We're going to continue to
evolve it.
And we're going to make it
better and better for the user's
streaming experience, starting
with the things we're going to
be talking about today.
And so the way we're going to do
that is we're going to introduce
a new internet draft that will
build upon the coming RFC as a
baseline and so keep an eye out
for that.
Okay. Now, let's move to the
other big news of the conference
which is HEVC.
As you heard at the keynotes and
elsewhere, Apple has chosen HEVC
as our next generation video
CODEC.
Now, why did we do it?
In one word, efficiency.
And primarily, encoding
efficiency.
HEVC is around abouts 40% more
efficient than AVC.
I mean, it depends on your
content and it depends how good
your encoder is, but 40% is a
nice ballpark figure.
And for those of us who spend
our time schlepping media over
network that's exciting because
first of all it means that your
user is going to see startup at
a decent quality 40% faster, and
when the player adapts its way
all the way up they'll see
content that looks 40% better.
And so that's an important thing
for us.
So HEVC is good.
Where can you get it?
Well as we've said, we are
making HEVC widely available.
And in fact, on our newest
devices, our newest iOS devices
with A9 and later and our latest
generation of Macintoshes, we
have support for HEVC built into
the hardware and so that
includes support for FairPlay
Streaming.
Even on devices, on older
devices that don't have that
hardware support, we are still
going to deploy a software HEVC
CODEC.
And so that will be on all the
iOS devices receiving, iOS 11.
That will include the Apple TV
with tvOS 11 and Macintoshes
that are upgraded to High
Sierra.
So, HEVC is going to be a lot of
different places.
We'd like you to use it.
And to use it with HLS there are
a few things you need to keep in
mind.
The first is that HEVC
represents an entirely brand new
encode of your content for a lot
of people, and that means on the
bright side there's no
compatibility version -- burden,
rather.
And so we decided that it was a
good time to refocus our
attention on a single container
format and we looked at the
alternatives and we decided that
fragmented MPEG-4 had the most
legs going forward.
So that means if you're going to
deploy your HEVC content to HLS,
it has to be packaged as MP4
fragments.
[ Applause ]
Now, another nice thing there is
that it makes the encoding story
or rather the encryption story a
little bit simpler because our
old buddy common encryption in
cbcs mode works the same way
with HEVC as it does with H.264.
And so there are no new rules
there, you just have to do the
same sort of thing you do to
your HEVC bit streams.
As with any new CODEC, you're
going to be deploying it to an
ecosystem where some devices
can't speak HEVC and so it is
critically important that you
mark your bit streams as HEVC so
the devices that don't
understand it can steer around
it.
And the way to do that, of
course in HLS, is with the
CODECS attribute in your master
playlist.
I've got an example here of a
CODECS attribute for HEVC.
It's a little bit more
complicated than H.264 but it's
not -- it's got a few more
things in it but it's not too
bad.
And the entire format is
documented in the HEVC spec. So
speaking of older clients in
H.264, there is naturally kind
of a compatibility question
around here of, first of all,
can you deploy a single asset to
both older and new clients?
And the answer is yes.
Here we go.
You can mix HEVC and H.264
variants in the same master
playlist, and that goes for both
the regular video variance and
also the I-frame variance.
You can have HEVC and H.264
versions of those as well.
As I said, you do need to
package your HEVC in MPEG-4
fragments, but for backward
compatibility H.264 can either
be in transforce frames or in
fragmented MPEG-4, your choice.
Again, it becomes even more
critically important that you
label your media playlist so
that we know what is what.
And finally, we have actually
updated -- we have -- if
you-guys don't know, we have a
document called the HLS
Authoring guidelines, Best
practices for Apple TV and
stuff.
I think we changed the name.
But anyway, it doesn't matter
because there's actually a video
on demand talk that's available
today called the HLS Authoring
Update, and we've updated that
for HEVC.
And so the Authoring guide now
has some additional
considerations for HEVC as well
as sort of a initial set of
recommended bit-rate tiers to
get you-guys going on that.
So check out that talk.
I hear the guy giving it is
awesome.
Next, we've got a new subtitle
format, and this is called IMSC.
Now many of you will not have
heard of IMSC.
In the consumer space it's not
quite as big as VTT is yet, but
it is sort of a grandchild of a
more well-known format called
the Timed Text Markup Language
or TTML.
TTML is kind of a extremely
expressive, not particularly
lightweight authoring language,
primarily, for subtitles and
captions and it's used for
mezzanines and interchange and
that kind of thing.
And so what the Timed Text
working group did was they took
TTML and they kind of slimed it
down, streamlined it a little
bit for delivery of regular
captions to consumers over the
Internet.
And so that is called IMSC.
Now, we already do VTT and so it
brings the obvious question of
well why is IMSC different?
And the primary difference is
that IMSC has much better
support, much more extensive
styling controls than VTT does.
VTT kind of has a few basic
styling controls and then for
the rest of it leans on CSS.
IMSC has a much more
self-contained set of styling
features that are focused on the
kind of stylings you need to do
for subtitles and captions.
And so it's gotten a certain
amount of traction, particularly
in the broadcasting industry,
and so much so that it was
chosen last year as the baseline
format for MPEG's common media
application format that we told
you about last year.
And so what we're doing in iOS
11 and the other various
releases is we are rolling out a
first generation ground-up
implementation of IMSC and so
that's in your seat today, and
we expect to refine it going
forward.
So just as with HEVC, there are
a few things you need to know
about IMSC in order to use it
with HLS.
The first thing is how it's
packaged.
Unlike VTT, which the segments
-- where the segments are just
little text files, the carriage
of IMSC is defined by MPEG-4,
part 30 and it basically what it
comes down to is XML text inside
of MPEG-4 fragments, and so it
takes advantage of all the
MPEG-4 timing facilities.
And I say text because IMSC
actually defines 2 profiles, an
image profile and a text
profile.
Our client only supports the
text profile of IMSC, and so
when you label your playlist,
which you should do because you
face the same issue with old
clients not understanding IMSC,
you'll want to add the CODECS
tag for IMSC, and I've included
a sample here which is
stpp.TTML.im1t, and that
essentially says I have
subtitles in my playlist that
conform to the text profile of
IMSC1.
Now, I've been talking about
IMSC and HEVC sort of in the
same breath.
I just want to sort of emphasize
that they're not linked.
You can use them independently.
You can use HEVC with VTT.
You can use IMSC with H.264.
You can use them all together,
and you can actually even have a
single playlist that has VTT and
IMSC so that newer clients can
get the benefits of IMSC styling
and older clients can continue
to use VTT.
And so let's take a look at a
playlist and show you what that
looks like.
I've got a fragment of a master
playlist here and that first set
of lines up there should be
pretty familiar to you.
That's what your master playlist
would look like if you had a
video variant called bipbop
gear1 and it had VTT based
subtitles in it.
That next set of tags has the
same video tier but in its
CODECS attribute you see it's
labeled as IMSC.
And so the first one will pull
down the VTT.m3u8 playlist, the
second will pull down the IMSC
if the client can understand
that.
If we sort of dive into those
two media playlists they're
actually pretty similar.
You can see that the VTT is, you
know, as you'd expect, just a
list of .VTT segments and the
IMSC is also sort of, in this
case MP4 segments because there
are MPEG-4 fragments and it does
have them tagged because that's
what fragmented MPEG-4 requires
is we need to be able to point
at the movie box.
So, but other than that they're
very similar.
So IMSC, VTT they're very
similar.
They do the same thing.
Why would I switch my HLS
streams for IMSC?
Well, you might switch your
streams if, first of all, if you
want more stylist to control and
you don't have an entire CSS
parser to lean on in your
playback devices then IMSC can
be attractive.
A second good reason is that you
may be authoring your captions
already in TTML, or perhaps
you're getting them from a
service provider in one of those
formats.
And you may find that
translating TTML's IMSC is both
simpler and perhaps higher
fidelity than doing the same
translation to VTT because
they're much more similar
formats.
So another good reason.
And a final reason is that you
may find yourself producing
IMSC1 streams anyway.
We mentioned that CMAF is
requiring IMSC for captions in
CMAF presentations, and if you
find yourself wanting to take
advantage of the pool of
compatible devices that we hope
CMAF will produce then you're
going to end up with IMSC1
streams and you may be able to
just drop the VTT streams and
that would simplify your tool
chain and your production
workflow.
So now having said all of that,
maybe none of that applies to
you in which case sticking with
VTT is a fine choice.
It's going to continue being
around.
In fact, maybe you're mainly
focused on North American market
in which case 608 is fine too.
It's not going anywhere.
So, we've just got different
choices.
Now, I've been talking a lot
about IMSC1.
There might be a question
lingering as to well is there an
IMSC2?
And the answer is kind of.
It hasn't been finalized yet, in
fact it's still working through
its process but the Time Text
working group is planning on
defining an IMSC2, and one of
the features in it that we're
keeping an eye on is some more
silent controls that are
particularly aimed at some
advanced Japanese topography
features such as shatti and
ticochiyoko [phonetically
spelled].
And so the short story is that
IMSC2, we expect the story to
evolve over the next couple of
years and so keep an eye out for
it.
Okay. So that's our CODECS
story, now let's talk about some
streaming features.
And first I'd like to talk about
something that we have that we
hope will make the lives of
those longsuffering produces of
live streams a little bit easier
in terms of helping them
maintain a robust experience
because HLS players are usually
pretty good when everything
going on in the back end is kind
of running tickety-boo, but when
things start to fall over on the
back end the clients could
actually do a little bit better
to help things move along.
Let me show you what I mean.
So here we have -- I guess here
we have a -- your typical live
HLS playlist.
Got a ten-second target
duration, segments are you now
10 seconds or thereabouts, after
10 seconds you might want to
reload it.
File sequence 12 is at the
bottom there, but oh now file
sequence 13 appears.
10 seconds later you reload
again, file sequence 14 appears.
Those things aren't appearing by
magic, of course.
You've got some encoder worker
somewhere that's chewing on a
media source, and every 10
seconds it's writing on a new
segment file into the CEN.
What would happen if for
whatever reason the encoder
suddenly rebooted?
Or maybe you knock your
microwave dish with your elbow
or something, you lose your
media feed.
Well, prior to this HLS clients
had no way of knowing that that
had happened and so they had no
way to help out.
But now we defined a new tag
which is called the GAP tag, and
so now what you can do instead
on your back end is when you
lose your encoder or you lose
your media source your packager
can continue writing segments
but instead of writing the media
data it can simply write a dummy
URL and affix that with a GAP
tag.
And it can continue doing this
as long as the encoding for that
stream is disabled.
And so 10 seconds later you
might get another segment that
is indicated as a gap.
So this tells the player that
the stream is still alive, it's
still chugging along, it's still
updating but things aren't so
good in actually media data
land.
Once things are restored, once
your encoder comes back or your
-- you've straightened out your
microwave dish or what have you,
then the packager can continue
producing segments as it did
before.
So, what does the GAP tag mean
to you as a client?
Primarily it means that there's
no media data here and so of
course as a first approximation
the player shouldn't attempt to
download it because it's not
there, but more interestingly as
soon as the player sees a GAP
tag appear in a media playlist
it can go off and attempt to
find another variant that
doesn't have the same gaps
because you may have multiple
redundant encoders producing
different variants or redundant
variants, and so maybe we're
playing the 2-megabit stream and
we might find that when we find
the 1-megabit stream that oh,
actually he doesn't have a gap
and so we can just cleanly
switch down to it, we can play
through the 1-megabit stream.
Once we're done with the gap we
can switch back up to the
3-megabit stream, the 2-megabit
stream, and it's all good.
The user won't even notice.
So, we have a fallback case
which is that you might just
have one encoder, or like I said
you might have knocked out your
media source, you may have no
media for the entire gap, and
the behavior of our player in
that case is we'll just in a
live stream scenario continue to
play through silence until media
comes back and we can resume the
presentation.
Now, the new GAP tag amongst
other things is described in a
version of the HLS beta spec
that I was up last night
writing, and so I think we're
posting it today, which is
awesome.
I can't wait to see it.
Yeah. Okay.
Feedback of course is welcome.
So that's the GAP tag.
Let's talk about another new
feature, and this is also kind
of aimed at your back-end folks.
And what we're doing is we are
supporting simple variable
substitution in m3u8 playlists,
and do to that we kind of
barrowed a little bit of syntax
from PHP.
And so what that means is if you
see something like that
highlighted bit in a playlist
what it is saying is take that
thing that's surrounded by the
braces and replace it with the
value of the variable whose name
is file name.
And so if the variable value
happens to be foo then you would
end up with a string that is
foo.ts.
Now, to define these things we
defined a new tag and it's
pretty simple, I'll show it to
you in a second, and it either
defines a variable inline the
playlist or it can import it.
Now, this is what makes things
interesting because remember I
said makes life a little bit
better for people producing
streams?
Well how does it do that?
I mean, yeah, you could -- if
you've got big honking URL's you
could use variables to make your
playlist shorter but, I mean,
gsip [phonetic] already does a
better job of that so that's not
-- that's kind of -- but what's
interesting is when you have the
ability to define a variable in
a master playlist and make use
of it in a media playlist that
allows you to construct your
media playlists ahead of time
with little placeholders that
are filled in sort of in a late
binding way when your master
playlist is defined.
So for instance, you could have
a bunch of variables references
in your media playlist on your
CDN and you could produce your
master playlist dynamically from
your application and at that
point you can say I want my
variable to be this, and
suddenly all your media
playlists on the CDN will take
advantage of it.
So let's see what that looks
like.
Here's a master playlist.
It's pretty simple example.
So I've got a define tag here.
It has two attributes, the name
attribute says the variable name
is auth and it has a value which
is this definition of an auth
token.
And you can use this various
places in the master playlist.
For instance, in my gear1 thing
here I've decided to tack on the
auth token to the URL for the
first variant, but now let's
imagine that we load that media
playlist.
Again, media playlists can have
variables just like master
playlists do.
In this case, I've got a path
that has this big long path.
I don't want to type a whole
bunch of different times.
But the second define is a
little more interesting.
In this case, we're importing
that auth variable that we
defined in the master playlist
and we're applying it to
different places such as this
URL in the media playlist, and
so this allows you to sort of
have a loose coupling effect
between your master playlist and
your media playlist.
I think that people are going to
find a lot of interesting uses
for it.
Next, okay.
So we talked about some back-end
features.
Let's talk about something that
you can actually use to provide
a compelling user experience.
Now what do I mean?
Well for instance, what if you
wanted your users to be able to,
when they're watching a match,
to be watching one camera of
someone sort of crossing the
ball but at the same time
watching the goal keeper cameras
so they could see his point of
view as well.
Or what if you're watching a
race and you want to see the car
camera in Hamilton's car but you
also want to keep an eye on
Vettel behind him.
And so in that case what unites
these kind of features is the
ability to play multiple live
streams that are synchronized
with each other so that one
doesn't get ahead of another.
[laughs] This is your future.
So in order to do that, all we
require is that you have two or
more live streams that are
synchronized by the use of a
date-time tag.
That basically means you put
dates in your playlist and the
dates are both derived or are
derived in all the playlists
from a common clock.
And once you've done that then
you can create multiple
independent AVPlayers and you
can start the first one playing
and then start the second one
playing in sync by using the
AVPlayer setRatetime atHostTime
method.
Now, I should be up front here
and say that using this method
in AVPlayer gets you some
serious AVFoundation street cred
because it's not the simplest
API in the world.
But to help you out with that,
we've actually got some sample
code for you this year.
It's an Apple TV app.
It's called SyncStartTV and I
thought rather than just talk
about it maybe I should show it.
You-guys want to see it?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; All right.
Let's do it.
So I'm going to switch us over
to the Apple TV here, if I
remember which device it is.
I think it's this one.
We've got -- I have my little --
in order to demonstrate a live
synchronized stream, I first had
to produce a live streaming
setup and so I'll just talk a
little about what's going on up
here.
I wrote a little app that takes
the feed from the back camera
and chops it up and actually
serves it from the phone as an
HLS stream.
And I've got two of these guys
here, two phones, both sort of
focused on the same thing.
I've got my left and my right
and they're actually connected
over the network and they're
using a clock that is a pretty
precise clock that's being
shared between them, and so they
are off there doing their thing.
So let me start my -- I don't
have a -- I couldn't get the
rights to anything really
exciting so we're going to do
this instead.
So let's see.
I'll start up my -- something
going on here.
And let's start one of the
cameras.
In fact, let's get them both
going here.
So you've got you.
Right is online.
And left is online.
Okay. So here we go.
Get my remote oriented
correctly.
Okay. So SyncStartTV.
When you launch SyncStartTV it
gives you the opportunity to
select either left or right
videos.
So let's select this guy.
Pops up a Bonjour picker and you
can see that both of my streams
show up here in Bonjour.
So let's start with stage right
and see what's going on over
there.
Nothing much going on over
Let's start this guy going in
sort of -- all right.
Now select left video.
And look at that.
They're in sync!
[ Applause ]
Oh my goodness.
Hold on a second.
All right.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
How do I get my slides back?
All right.
Here we go.
Well, this is fun for all ages.
Okay. So I guess I skipped right
past my slide.
Oh well. One of the things I
wanted to mention about this
kind of presentation where
you're showing multiple streams
at once is that you do have to
be careful to make sure one of
your streams doesn't sort of
suck down all your network
bandwidth and leave the other
ones starved.
So normally you would do this by
throttling each stream.
We're giving you another tool
for that this year and that is a
resolution cap.
And so essentially it's as the
name applies, it allows you to
programmatically say you know
what, I'm displaying this in a
little 480p window, there's no
point in switching up the way to
1080p.
And so when you have an app
that's got video thumbnails or
multi-stream or stuff like this
and you don't want to have to
dive into the gory details of
your playlist and set a
bandwidth cap, this is kind of a
handy thing to have.
There is a case where you may
set a max resolution is actually
smaller than anything -- any of
the tiers that are available.
In that case we'll just pick the
lowest one and we'll play that.
It's really easy to use.
If you've got a player item you
just set its preferred maximum
resolution to the CG size and in
a few seconds it should take
effect.
Both sort of up and down.
Okay. So let's talk about a few
other things.
Last year we introduced HLS
offline support which is the
ability to download your HLS
streams and play them somewhere
like an airplane where you don't
have a network.
And when we talked about that we
mentioned that we would be at
some point in the future taking
a more active role in managing
that disk space.
Well, the future is now and so
I'd like to introduce you to a
new part of our settings app in
iOS 11.
This has a section where a user
can go and see all the apps that
have offline assets and how much
disk space their using, and the
user can choose to delete them
if they want to free up disk
space.
So what this means for you folks
is primarily that the OS is now
sort of capable of going off and
deleting your assets while your
app is not running.
And there can be a couple
different ways that could
happen.
The user could decide to do it
themselves or we may ask the
user if it's okay to delete some
of their content if we need
space for like an OS update or
something like that.
And so in iOS 11 we're
introducing a new API that
allows you to influence the
choice of what assets get
deleted when, and it's called
the
AVAssetDownloadStorageManager.
And the way it works is you
create a policy on each offline
asset that you have on your disk
and you set it with manger.
Right now the download storage
management policy has two
properties, expiration date and
priority.
And today we define just two
priorities that are important to
default.
So for most people what you're
going to do is mark assets the
user hasn't watched yet as
important, and once I've watched
them switch them back down to
default.
The expiration date property is
there in case your asset at some
point becomes no longer eligible
to be played.
For instance, you may find that
you may be in a situation where
a particular show may be leaving
your catalog, you no longer have
rights to stream it.
If that's the case you can set
the expiration date and it will
be sort of bumped up in the
deletion queue.
So, using it is fairly straight
forward.
The DownloadStorageManger is the
singleton so you go grab that.
You create a new mutable policy,
you set the attributes, and then
you tell the storage manager to
use that policy for an AVAsset
at a particular file URL.
You can also go back and look up
the current policy later on.
So that's coming your way.
The other thing about offline is
that we got some feedback from
some of the folks who have
adopted it that downloading more
than one rendition, like if you
want your English audio but also
your Spanish audio, is maybe a
little bit harder than it could
be primarily if your application
is subject to going to the
background and being quit half
way through, and so I'm pleased
to say that in iOS 11 we're
introducing a new way to batch
up your offline downloads.
It's called an
AggregateAssetDownloadTask and
it allows you to, for a given
asset, indicate an array of
media selections like this and
then when you kick off the
download task we'll go off,
we'll download each one, we'll
give you progress as we do, and
then we'll let you know when the
whole thing is done so hopefully
it will make things a little bit
easier.
[ Applause ]
Okay. The next set of things
we're going to talk about here
today all revolve around
managing content keys on your
device, and it's a fairly
complicated topic and so what
I'm going to do is hand you-guys
over to our very own HLS key
master, Anil Katti, and he's
going to walk you through it.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
Thank you, Roger.
Good evening everyone.
Welcome to WWDC.
So two years ago we introduced
FairPlay Streaming, a content
protection technology that helps
protect your HLS assets.
Since this introduction we have
seen phenomenal growth.
FairPlay Streaming is used
protect premium content that is
delivered on our platforms, and
today we are excited to announce
a few enhancements to the
FairPlay Streaming key delivery
process that will allow you to
simplify your workflow, scale
your FairPlay Streaming
adoption, and support new
content production features.
But before we talk about the
enhancements I would like to
start with a quick overview of
FairPlay Streaming.
FairPlay Streaming specifies how
to deliver -- how to securely
deliver content decryption keys.
There are three main elements in
the FairPlay Streaming system,
your media-centric application,
the one that holds the playback
session is at the center.
You have your key server on one
side that provides the
decryption keys, and
AVFoundation is on the other
side that gives you support for
decryption and playback of the
content.
There are five steps involved in
delivering content decryption
keys and it all starts when the
user is browsing through your
app trying to pick something to
play, and when it does that your
app creates an asset and as
AVFoundation decide to playback.
When AVFoundation receives the
playback request it starts
passing the playlist and when it
sees that the content is
encrypted and uses FairPlay
Streaming for key delivery asks
your app for the key by sending
you a key request through the
delegate call back.
At that point, you could use the
key request object to create
what we call server playback
context or SPC in short, which
is an encrypted data blob that
contains the information your
key server requires to create
content decryption keys.
Your app then sends the content
decryption key to your key
server and obtains content key
context in return, or CKC, which
is another encrypted data blob
that contains the actual
decryption keys.
As a last step, your application
provides the CKC as a response
to the key request object that
it initially received.
So assuming AVFoundation has
already loaded playlist and
media data by now it now has the
FairPlay Streaming keys that it
requires to decrypt the content
and start the playback.
Well in a sense, FairPlay
Streaming keys are similar to
these other resources, and in
fact if you recall, if you're
using FairPlay Streaming for key
delivery today FairPlay
Streaming keys are delivered
with AVAsset accessory APIs,
similar to other custom
resources, but that's pretty
much where the similarity ends,
right?
FairPlay Streaming keys are
specialized resources that have
very specific operations defined
on them.
I'll give you a couple of
examples now.
So AVFoundation allows you to
free FairPlay Streaming keys so
that you could save them in your
app storage and use them later
on like when the user is trying
to play content offline.
And you could also define
FairPlay Streaming keys to
expire after a certain duration
and the keys have to be renewed
before they expired in order to
continue decryption.
As content production features
continue to evolve, FairPlay
Streaming keys will continue to
get more specialized and so does
the key delivery process.
Further, FairPlay Streaming keys
do not have to be associated
with assets at the time of
loading.
So we think by decoupling the
key loading from media loading
or even the playback, we'll be
able to provide you more
flexibility that can be
exploited to address some of the
existence pain points and also
provide better user experience.
So with all these things in mind
we are so glad to introduce a
new API that will allow you to
better manage and deliver
content decryption keys.
Introducing AVContentKeySession.
AVContentKeySession is an
AVFoundation class that was
designed around content
decryption keys.
It allows you to decouple key
loading from media loading or
even playback, for that matter.
And it also gives you a better
control over the lifecycle of
content decryption keys.
So if you recall, your
application loads keys only when
it receives a key request from
AVFoundation and but that -- you
can change that with
AVContentKeySession.
With AVContentKeySession you get
to decide when you would like to
load keys.
However, if you choose not to
load keys before requesting
playback, AVFoundation still
sends you a key request on
demand like it does today.
So now we provide you two ways
to trigger the key loading
process.
You could use -- your
application could use
AVContentKeySession to
explicitly initiate the key
loading process, or AVFoundation
initiates the key loading
process on demand when it sees
the content is encrypted.
So let's see how using
AVContentKeySession to initiate
the key loading process could be
helpful.
And the first, use keys that I
have for you today is around
playback startup.
Key loading time could be a
significant portion of your
playback startup time because
applications normally load keys
when they receive an on-demand
key request.
You could improve the playback
startup experience your user
receives if you could load keys
even before the user has picked
something to play.
Well, AVContentKeySession allows
you to do that.
So you could use
AVContentKeySession to initiate
a key loading process and then
use the key request that you get
to load the keys independent of
the playback session.
Now we call this key preloading
and after loading the keys you
could request a playback so
during playback you don't have
to load any keys, and the
playback -- the decryption could
start immediately.
The second use case I have for
you today is gaining a lot of
prominence day by day and it is
around live playback.
We have seen an explosion in the
amount of live content that
delivered on our platforms,
thanks to a more immersive and
integrated experience users
receive on our devices.
With more users looking to
consume sports and other live
events on our devices,
developers are using more
advanced content production
features like key rotation and
key renewal to add an extra
layer of protection while
delivering premium live content.
Due to the nature of live
streaming, your keys servers get
bombarded with millions of key
requests all at once when the
keys are being rotated or
renewed.
Well, you could use
AVContentKeySession to alleviate
the situation by load balancing
key requests at the point of
origin.
Let me explain how you could do
this with a simple illustration
here.
Consider the scenario in which
millions of users are watching a
popular live stream like Apple's
Keynote.
It's possible that they all
started at different points in
time but when it's time to renew
or update the key they all send
requests to your key server at
the exact same time.
That presents a huge load on the
key server for a short duration
of time and then things get back
to normal, until it's time to
renew or update the key again,
right?
So this pattern continues
leading to input load on your
key serer.
You could use
AVContentKeySession to spread
out key requests by picking like
a random point within a small
time window before the key
actually expires and initiating
the key loading yourself.
So what this allows you to do is
scale your live offering without
having to throw mode or
[inaudible] of your key server.
So now that we have seen some
use cases where initiating key
loading process with
AVContentKeySession was helpful,
let's see how to do it in terms
of code.
You could initiate a key loading
process which is three lines of
code, it's that simple, and here
it is.
So the first thing you do is
create an instance of
AVContentKeySession for FairPlay
Streaming.
You then set up your app as a
contentKeySession Delegate.
You should expect to receive all
delegate callbacks on the
delegate queue that you specify
here.
The third step is to invoke
processContentKeyRequest method
and that will initiate the key
loading process.
So have to note a couple of
things here.
There are no changes required in
your keys or your key server
module implementation in order
to use this feature.
This is -- all implementation
here is on the client side which
is great.
Second, the identifier that you
specify here should match with
the identifier that you specify
in your EXT-X-KEY tag in your
media playlist.
What that allows us to do is
match the keys that you loaded
here with the keys that you
would request during playback.
And third, you should have an
out-of-band process to obtain
the keys for a particular asset
from your key server so that you
could load all these keys at
this point.
When you invoke
processContentKeyRequest method
on AVContentKeySession, we send
you an AVContentKey request
object through a delegate call
back, and this is exact same
delegate method that gets called
even when AVFoundation initiates
the key loading process.
So now you could use the key
request object to do all the
FairPlay Streamings plus
[inaudible] operations like you
could request an SPC, this is
very similar to the way you do
your request SPC with AVAsset
key sorting request.
You then send SPC to your key
server, obtain the CKC and as
the last step you would create a
response object with the CKC and
set that as a response the
ContentKeyRequest object.
So you have to keep a couple of
things in mind while responding
to a key request.
As soon as you set the CKC as a
response to the key request, you
would consume a secure decrypt
slot on the device and there are
a limited number of those.
So it's okay to initiate key
loading process for any number
of keys and you can obtain the
CKC's as well for all those
different key requests, but be
careful with the last step.
You should set CKCs on only
those keys that you predict
might be used during playback,
and do it just before you
request a playback.
So with that background, let's
shift gears and see how we could
use AVContentKeySession in the
context of offline HLS playback.
We introduced persistent keys
last year when we modified
FairPlay Streaming to protect
your offline HLS assets.
AVContentKeySession could be
used to create persistent keys
as well.
Before requesting the download
of HLS assets, you could use
AVContentKeySession to initiate
key loading process and use the
key request object to create
persistent keys.
Then you could store the
persistent keys in your app
storage for future use.
With that, this will make your
workflow a little bit simpler
because now you don't have to
define the EXT-X Session keys in
your master playlist and so on,
you could just use
AVContentKeySession.
Further, while creating and
using persistent keys, you
should work with the sub class
of AVContentKeyRequest, which is
an
AVPersistableContentKeyRequest.
I'll explain in terms of code
how to request and
AVPersistableContentKeyRequest
and also to work -- also how to
work with an
AVPersistableContentKeyRequest.
So if you recall, this is the
delegate method that gets called
when you initiate a key loading
process.
At this point, if you're trying
to create a persistent key you
should just respond to the key
request and request for
PersistableContentKeyRequest,
and we would send you an
AVPersistableContentKeyRequest
object through a new delegate
callback.
You could use
AVPersistableContentKeyRequest
to do all your FairPlay
Streaming specific operations,
like create SPC, send SPC to
your key server, get a CKC and
use the CKC to now create a
persistent key which you can
store in your app storage so
that you could use it later when
the user is offline.
When it's time to use the
persistent key, all you have to
do is create a response object
with the persistent key data
blob and set that as a response
on the ContentKeyRequest object.
That's it.
So if you're using FairPlay
Streaming for key delivery today
you would have observed that
AVContentKeySession is designed
to work similarly to what you're
already used today,
AVAssetRsourceLoader API.
In place of
AVAssetResourceLoading request,
we have AVContentKeyRequest.
AVAsset is just where the
delegates call apart, it's
called AVContentKeySession
delegate.
However, that is a key
difference.
Unlike AVAssetResourceLoader,
AVContentKeySession is not tied
to an asset at the time of
creation, so you could create an
AVContentKeySession at any point
and use that to load all the
keys, and just before you
request playback you should add
your AVasset as a content key
recipient.
That will allow your AVAsset to
access all the keys that you
preloaded with the
ContentKeySession object.
So now we have 2 API's,
AVContentKeySession and
AVAssetResourceLoader, and you
might be wondering which API to
use for loading different types
of resources, and here's what we
recommend.
Use AVContentKeySession for
loading content decryption keys,
and use AVAssetResourceLoader
for loading everything else.
I have to point out that we are
not duplicating key handling
aspects of AVAssetResourceLoader
at this point so you could
continue using
AVAssetResourceLoader like you
do today for loading FairPlay
Streaming keys, but we highly
recommend that you switch over
to AVContentKeySession for that
purpose.
So, who is responsible for
loading decryption keys if an
asset has both
AVAssetResourceLoader delegate
and AVContentKeySession delegate
associated with it?
Well, to be consistent we
enforce that all content
decryption keys are loaded
exclusively with
AVContentKeySession delegate.
So your AVAssetResourceLoader
delegate receives all resource
loading requests including those
four content decryption keys.
The app is expected to just
defer all the content decryption
key loading by calling finish
loading on the loading request
so AVFoundation could re allow
the request to the
AVContentKeySession delegate.
Let me show you how to do that
in code.
It's really simple.
So here's a delegate method that
gets called when AVFoundation is
trying to load a resource, and
when you see that the resource
is for a content decryption key
you should just set the content
pipe to say that it's a content
key and call finish loading.
So at that point we will send a
new content key loading request
to AVContentKeySession delegate.
If it's any other resource you
could just continue loading the
resource here.
So I hope this whirlwind tour of
the new API provided you some
context around what you can
accomplish with
AVContentKeySession.
Before I wrap up the talk I have
one more exciting feature to
share with you, and this is
available through
AVContentKeySession.
We are providing double expiry
windows support for FairPlay
Streaming persistent keys.
Now, what does this double
expiry window thing?
If you've ever rented a movie on
iTunes you would see that you
have -- once you rent a movie
you have 30 days to watch it.
And once you start watching the
moving you have 24 hours to
finish it.
We call this dual expiry window
model for rentals.
So what this feature allows you
to do is define and customize
two expiry windows for FairPlay
Streaming persistent keys.
That will allow you to support
items like rental feature
without much engineering effort
on the silver side and the best
thing is it works on both
offline and online playback.
So in order to use this feature,
you have to first opt in by
sending suitable descriptor in
CKC and that will allow you to
specify two expiry windows.
The first one is called a
storage expiry window which
starts as soon as the persistent
key is created, and then we have
a playback expiry window which
starts when the persistent key
is used to start the playback.
To explain this feature better
let me just give you -- let me
just take you over a timeline of
events and the context of
offline playback.
When the user rents a movie to
play offline you would create a
persistent key with a CKC that
opts in to use this feature.
This persistent key is said to
expire at the end of storage
expiry window which was 30 days
from our example.
You would typically store this
persistent key in your apps
storage and use it to answer a
key request later on.
Now when the user comes back
within these 30 days and asks
you to start play -- ask you to
play the content, you will get a
key request and you would use
this persistent key to answer
the key request.
At that point, we will send you
an updated persistent key which
is set to expire at the end of
playback experiment which was 24
hours from our example.
Along with that we'll also
explicitly expire the original
persistent key that you've
created, so you're expected to
save the updated persistent key
in your app storage and use that
to answer future key loading
requests.
That is when the user stops and
resumes playback within the next
24 hours.
In terms of code this is very
similar to the persistent key
workflow that we just saw a few
slides ago, however, we'll send
you this new updated persistent
key through a new
AVContentKeySession delegate
callback.
So those were all the
enhancements that we had for
FairPlay Streaming key delivery
process this year.
In conclusion, we introduced two
new CODECS.
We introduced a [inaudible] this
year, HEVC and IMSC1.
We added the EXT-X-GAP tag that
allows you to indicate gaps in
your livestreams.
And now you can define and use
PHP style variables in your HLS
streams.
You can now synchronize two or
more HLS streams, and we
provided new APIs that will
allow you to have better control
over offline HLS assets.
Now there is a new API
AVContentKeySession that allows
you to get better manage and
deliver content decryption keys.
And finally, we added dual
expiry window support for all
FairPlay Streaming persistent
keys so that will allow you to
support rental model with your
offline HLS assets.
It was really exciting for all
of us to work on these new
features and we look forward to
the adoption.
Thanks a lot for attending this
session.
You can get more information by
visiting our session page on the
developer site.
You can also download all the
sample code for different things
that we covered during this
talk.
We have a bunch of related
sessions for you.
I strongly recommend watching
Error Handling Best Practices,
and Authoring Update for HLS.
These are available as on-demand
videos and your WWDC app, and if
you miss any of the other live
sessions you could always go to
your WWDC app to watch them
offline or watch them on demand.
Thank you so much.
Have a great rest of the week.
Good night.