[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, and welcome
everybody to our session, Best
Practices and What's New in User
Notifications.
I'm Kritharth Jain and a junior
on the iOS notifications team
and I'll be joined by my
colleague, Teja, for this
session today.
So, today we're going to start
by doing an overview of
notifications and all the
different APIs that you as app
developers can use for doing
notifications for your
applications.
Then, we're going to jump into
four different use cases for
notifications.
We're going to start out by
introducing a new concept for
iOS notifications about hidden
notification content which we
think you're going to be really
excited about.
Then we're going to jump into
our second use case about
modifying push notification
content before delivery to the
user.
Then we'll talk about
customizing rich notifications
and how you can completely own
the UI and feel of these
notifications.
And lastly we'll talk about user
input customization associated
with these rich notifications.
So, let's start with the
notifications overview.
Now, I'm sure you all know that
there are two types of
notifications.
There are local notifications.
These are the ones that are
scheduled by your application on
the device itself and then these
get presented to the user.
And when the user handles these
notifications, your app has the
opportunity to handle its
response.
The other kind of notifications
are remote notifications that
are associated with your remote
server which then sends a
notification payload to the
Apple push notification service.
Now, if your payload has
content, then this notification
gets delivered to the user's
device and presented to the
user.
And again, if the user handles
this notification, you can
handle this response in your
application.
The other kind of remote
notifications are silent
notifications.
Now, these don't get presented
to your application users but
these allow your application to
be launched in the background
and do any extra work that your
app wants to do associated with
your remote site application.
Now, it's important for remote
notifications to use the latest
HTTPS2, authentication method,
wherever you're doing remote
notifications.
Now, notification content
exists, consists of different
properties that you can set on
the notification.
These include the title, the
subtitle, the body as well as
media attachments that you can
set on your notifications.
Notification triggers determine
when your notification gets
delivered to your app users.
Now, all remote notifications
are associated with the push
trigger and for your local
notifications, you have the
option of using time interval,
calendar or location-based
triggers.
Now, these notifications get
presented to your user in
different ways.
In iOS 11, we've combined the
notification list into a single
list.
So, if the user wakes their
device or pulls down from the
top, they get to go to the same
notification list.
And when the user is in that
state, the notification gets
added to the list right there
and then.
And if you want to see your
older notifications, then you
can just slide up on this list
to see your notification
history.
If the user's device is unlocked
if they're in the home screen or
in any other app, then the
notification rolls down as a
banner from the top.
And if your application is in
the foreground, you do have the
option of presenting the
notification banner right there
and then.
And along with these different
presentation models, you'll also
have the option of having a
sound alert as well as badging
your application icon.
Now, notification actions are
what make your notifications
really interactable.
And your user gets to them by 3D
touching on the notification
where they see the list of all
these actions as well as the
dismiss action.
And then when the user takes any
of these actions, then again you
get the response in your
application to handle this
action as you see fit.
Now, there are different
mechanisms that you can use with
these notifications.
Notification update allows you
to modify notifications that you
might have already scheduled or
published to the user.
In this example, you can see
that we're aggregating the
number of likes that your social
media posts might have gotten.
And after a certain time, say
this count changes, then you can
just go ahead and update this
notification in place.
So, your notification list for
the user is not cluttered with
redundant information.
In the same vein, you also have
the option of removing
notifications.
In this example, there's a
message about the video that was
sent to you.
And once you've seen that video,
you can just go ahead and remove
this notification locally by
your applications.
Now, with iOS 10, we introduced
extensions to your notifications
and there are two types of
extensions.
Namely, the first one is service
Now, what a service extension
allows your application to do is
to intercept a notification
before it gets delivered to the
user.
So, you can modify the
notification content or do other
background stuff that might be
associated with this
notification right in the
service extension.
We will take a look at service
extensions in depth in one of
our use cases today.
The other extension points are
content extensions which allow
you to customize which
notifications.
And again, is one of our use
cases of the talk today.
Some examples of content
extensions from first-party
applications include the
messages app which gives you the
full thread right there in the
notifications so you can reply
and get responses right from the
notification without having to
go to the application.
The calendar app shows the full
schedule as well as gives you
the option of accepting or
declining a request.
And the photos application sends
you the photo within the
notification itself and the
ability to write or comment on
it.
And again, we'll look at how you
can use all these different
tools for creating these
notification styles for all your
applications in this session.
Now, watchOS notifications work
in sync with iOS notifications.
All notifications that are sent
to the user's phone also get
delivered to the user's watch if
the phone is locked at that
time.
Now, if the user's watch is not
in range of the phone, then you
also have the ability of
scheduling notifications right
to your watchOS apps as well.
So, how do access all these
different features for
notifications?
For this we introduced two new
frameworks last year, namely
User Notifications and User
Notifications UI.
We went in depth covering all
those different APIs at last
year's WWDC and we highly
encourage you to go check out
these two sessions from last
year which contains much more
information about everything
we've covered in the overview.
All right, let's move on and
jump into our use cases,
starting with the first one,
about hidden notification
content.
And to tell you all about this,
let me invite Teja up here.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
My name is Teja Kondapalli and
I'm also an engineer on the
notifications team.
You just heard a great recap of
the API that we announced last
year and now I'm here to talk to
you about the API we want to
announce this year.
This year we decided to focus on
a feature that we call hidden
notification content which is a
way for your users to hide the
private information in their
notifications when it doesn't
need to be seen.
Why do we care about this?
It's because your users care
about their privacy.
We all know notifications are
very visible and the content in
them is richer than ever, which
means we have to be careful
about protecting the sensitive
information that may be in them.
And actually, you all had a
taste of this in iOS 10.
A message notification on the
lock screen could look like
this.
If you had gone into your
settings under notifications,
set for messages that you only
want previews to be shown when
unlocked.
So, now you can see that the
message, the content of the
message is obscured, and that's
because the user is not
authenticated.
Once they've authenticated, the
content of the message is
revealed.
And I'm really excited to
announce to you that this year
we've extended the support of
this to all apps, including
third-party apps.
[ Applause ]
We've also given your users a
global setting.
They can simply go into settings
notifications and right at the
top they can select whether they
want their previews to be shown
always when unlocked or never.
And this should apply to all
their notifications for all
their apps.
We've also given them a way to
customize these settings per
app.
So again, under settings they
can simply go to a specific
application and choose the
privacy setting for the previews
for that application.
And they might want to fine tune
these because some applications
may show more sensitive
information in their
notifications than others.
And now, because it's up to your
users to determine whether a
notification's content is hidden
or shown at a certain point, we
have given you as app developers
an API to customize what a
hidden notification might look
like.
So, let's take a look at this
application I've written that
sends me some notifications.
And you can see here, this
notification has some rich
information in it.
If my user has previews turned
off, this is what my
notification would look like.
And as you can see, all of the
content is hidden, the title,
the subtitle and the body.
And the body is replaced with a
placeholder.
Our default placeholder says
notification.
But if I had a bunch of
notifications associated with
this app, then you can see here
clearly that I have two
different threads going on.
One about work and the other
about a Thai vacation.
If my user has previews turned
off, this is what my
notification list could look
like.
But in order to prevent that, we
went one step further and we
have automatically coalesced
these for you by thread
identifier.
So, if you're already using
thread identifiers in your
notifications, this will work
automatically for you.
Let's take a look at one of my
threads.
You can see here it says two
notifications of the default
placeholder.
And this thread is actually
about my Thai vacation.
And these are comments.
So, I want to customize this
further and we can do that.
When I'm setting up my
notification category that I'm
going to associate with these
notifications, I can pass it a
new, a value for a new property.
So, here I'm setting up a
comment category and I am also
setting the hidden previews body
placeholder.
I'm just passing in a regular
string here and it says comment.
And now my notification looks
like this.
Which is still not quite right
because I know that there's two
notifications that have been
coalesced and this just says
comment.
So, instead I decide to pass in
a format string.
Which is great.
Now my notification looks as
intended.
It says 2 comments.
But this is not going to work
for the singular case.
It would've said 1 comments if I
had just one notification.
Luckily there's already a way to
account for the singular-plural
problem that's already supported
by foundation, and that's a
strings dictionary.
A strings dictionary is a p-list
file that sits in your project.
And you can, and it looks
somewhat like this.
You can see here that the first
thing I have is a line that says
comment key.
And this indicates to a system
where to find this pluralization
rule.
And below that you can see that
I have a key value mapping for
the singular and plural rules.
It says 1 with a format string
that says comment and other,
with a format string that says
comments.
And it's important to use a
strings dictionary because not
all languages have a distinction
just between singular and
plural.
For example, a strings
dictionary in Arabic looks like
this.
And you can see there are a lot
more options than just singular
and plural.
So, to account for pluralization
as well as localization, it's
important to use strings
dictionaries.
So, now that I've set up my
strings dictionary, when I'm
setting up my comment category,
instead of passing in just a
format string, I'm passing in an
NS localized string.
And the first parameter that I
pass to it is comment key which
is what I associated my
pluralization rule with, the key
that I associated with.
And the second parameter that
I'm passing is just a note about
what this string is about.
If you want to know more about
localization, we had a chat
earlier during WWDC, so you can
catch that on video.
And we also have great resources
in our docs.
And now, my notification
correctly says 2 comments and I
have confidence that it's going
to say 1 comment if there had
only been 1 comment in here.
But if we look further, actually
Jane sent me an image.
She didn't send me a comment,
and I want to indicate that.
So, I can do that as well.
When I'm setting up my
categories, after I set up my
comment category, I also set up
an image category the same way
and I associate Jane's
notification with the image
category and John's notification
with a comment category.
Now I have two notifications
with two different categories
but they're being sent to the
same thread.
So, the coalescing will
automatically work for me and it
correctly says 1 image and 1
comment.
But if you recall further, this
is all one thread and maybe I
want to distinguish this thread
from another thread that is also
for the notifications in this
application.
And I can do that.
So if you see here, the title
says Thai vacation and that's
indicative of what thread this
is.
So, maybe I want to show that.
And again, when I'm setting up
my categories, I can pass in one
or both of two new options that
we have.
Hidden previews show title and
hidden previews shows subtitle.
So, here I'm just trying to pass
in, I'm just passing in the
title.
Because showing the subtitle is
revealing too much information.
I just want to show the title.
And now my notification
correctly says Thai vacation,
which indicates the thread, 1
image and 1 comment.
Now that we know how to
customize hidden notification
content, it's important to
remember that this is a
user-defined setting.
It's up to your users at any
point to determine whether a
notification content is going to
be hidden or shown.
We've given you a way to find
the user's setting and you can
retrieve it by using the show
preview setting property in view
and notification settings.
It's also important to use
thread identifiers to take
advantage of the automatic
coalescing that we already have
supported for you.
And it's important to use
strings dictionaries to account
for pluralization as well as
localization.
So, we've looked at our first
use case of hidden notification
content.
And the second use case is
something I know a lot of you
will be doing, which is sending
push notifications to your
applications.
And we can do some interesting
things with push notifications
if only we're able to modify
them, such as attachments or
encryption.
And what I mean by that is
imagine I want to send some
media with my remote
notification.
But that media doesn't fit in
the push payload.
Well, I can instead send some
metadata about this media such
as the URL that it can be found
at and then on the device I can
download that media and then
present the notification.
Another great example is if your
server side wants to encrypt a
content in the notification, you
would want to decrypt it on the
device before displaying it to
the user.
And another great application is
a pending context-specific
information to your notification
such as location or time or
health data.
This information may only be
present on the user's device.
So, before it's presented to the
user, you can append these to
your notification.
And to do all this, we would a
service extension, which is
something we introduced last
year.
So, let's deep dive and look at
an example.
I want to send a video with my
remote notification.
So, my remote server would send
a push payload to APNS.
And in the payload, I packaged
some metadata about my video.
The notification will then get
delivered to my device and the
service extension has the
opportunity to intercept this
notification.
At that point, I can talk to the
remote server and download a
video preview before attaching
it to my notification and
displaying it to the user.
Let's see how we do this in
code.
The remote payload would look
something like this.
It's important to set the
mutable content flag.
This is what indicates to the
device that it needs to launch
the service extension before
presenting the notification.
And I also have some additional
metadata such as the type of
this media, the video URL, the
location that it was shot at and
also the user that uploaded
this.
Now, when setting up the service
extension, I simply go into
Xcode, create a new target and
select the notification service
extension template.
And I would get a template that
looks something like this.
So, in the service extension,
when a notification gets
delivered, you'll receive a call
to the did receive request with
content handler function.
And the first thing I do in
there is store both the content
handler and the remote content
that was sent.
Just in case I'm not able to
complete my operation, this is
my backup.
So, I've stored those.
And then I can handle my request
the way that I want.
So, the first thing I do here is
I grab the video URL from the
remote payload.
And because this was some custom
metadata, I use the user info
dictionary to access this value.
The next thing I do is download
from that URL using whatever
mechanism I want and I pass a
completion handler to my
download method that I want to
execute after the download is
complete.
After the download completes, I
take that file and I create an
attachment out of it.
I attach it to my notification
content and I send my
notification on its way.
And now my notification looks
great.
It has an attachment, a video
attachment attached to it.
But what if I'm not able to
complete the downloading of the
video in the set time?
There is a limit on the amount
of time that I have to use in my
service extension.
So, if I'm not able to do that,
there is a fallback, and this a
function that we call also in
the service extension called
service extension time will
expire.
In here, I can make use of both
the content handler and the
content that I had stored
earlier.
And the first thing I do is I
grab the type of media this is
that I had also packaged with my
metadata and I just set the
title to say incoming media, or
incoming video.
And I send my notification on
its way.
Now that we know how to use
service extension, let's
remember few things.
Which is that there is a short
execution time.
There's a limit on execution
time and there's also a memory
limit.
But make use of the fallback in
order to do the best possible
thing for that notification if
you're unable to complete your
operation.
It's also important to note the
notification that can be handled
by the service extension are UI
notification and they will be
presented.
And these are different from
silent notifications.
What I mean by that is when APNS
delivers the notification to
your device, the service
extension has the opportunity to
intercept it, as we just saw.
Any and all work done in the
service extension should pertain
to this incoming notification.
There should be no additional
background work for your
application that should be done
here.
All work should be either about
modifying or enhancing this
notification.
The service extension also
doesn't have the power to drop
this notification or prevent it
from being displayed.
This notification will get
delivered to the device.
If instead you want to launch
your application in the
background and run some
additional processing, you
should send a silent
notification.
You can also send a silent
notification and launch your app
in the background and your app
can determine whether or not to
schedule a local notification if
you want to present a
conditional notification.
So, now I have my great
notification with an attachment
and let's say I 3D touch to go
into the rich notification.
Without doing anything, this is
my default look.
Which looks good, but I might
want to customize it.
And in order to show you guys
how to customize these views,
I'm going to invite Kritharth
back up on stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Teja.
So, so far we've looked at our
first two use cases.
The first about hidden
notification content and how we
can customize them.
And secondly about modifying
push notification content.
Let's move to our third use case
about customizing rich
notifications.
Now, as we just saw, this is the
default look for a media
attachment rich notification.
We overlay the video with the
play button so that the user can
play the media right there and
then as well as default content
shown right below it.
And if there was no media
attached to it, then all that
the rich notification would show
would be the default content.
But what if you want to
customize this rich notification
and give it a custom look and
feel that's specific to your
application?
What if you want to completely
custom9ize the display of this
notification content as you want
to do.
And in the process you make
these notifications very
interactive and dynamic for your
users so that they can complete
these operations right in the
notification without having the
need to go to the application.
Well, we can achieve all of this
and for that we use our second
extension point of content
extensions.
So, let's take a look how we can
set content extensions up.
So, so far we've seen that the
service extension was where we
downloaded the media and then
the notification was presented
on the user's device.
Now, if you have a content
extension set up having the same
category identifier as the
notification, then the system
will launch this content
extension.
And set up all the different
views and view controllers
associated with this content
extension before opening the
rich notification.
And then uses these view
controllers to present that
custom rich notification user
interface.
What are the different things
that you can customize as part
of these rich notifications?
You can change the title that's
right above the content.
You can completely customize the
content and the way it's shown.
And you also have the option of
just removing the default
content if you've already
included that information in
your custom section.
So, to set up a content
extension, Xcode gives you a
default template to get you
started.
In this customization process,
the first place where we look is
the info.plist.
Now, of course the first thing
we do is set the correct
category for all the
notifications that we want to
associate with this content
extension.
Now, some of the easy ones we
can get here are by setting the
default content hidden flag to
Yes.
And this, we'll just go ahead
and remove the default content
before, below your custom UI.
And also by overriding the
default title, you can do that
by simply setting this flag here
as well.
Now, when we look at our code,
you can see here that our class
notification view controller
implements the UN notification
content extension protocol.
Now, the entry method into your
content extension is the did
receive notification method.
The UN notification object here
contains all the information
that's pertinent to this
notification.
So, the first thing that we do
is go ahead and extract the
content from this notification.
And then we can just go ahead
and get the attachment that we
had downloaded in our service
extension here.
And then we go and set it up in
our custom media player that we
set up in our custom UI.
There are more things we can do
in this customization.
One of the things is setting the
title that we had overridden at
the top of the content
extension.
Now, the user info object is a
key value pairing that you can
associate with your notification
payload which allows you to send
a lot more information.
So that you're not restricted to
just the title, the subtitle as
well as the body of the
notification.
So, in our example here, we
package different information
associated with this
notification such as the user
who posted this video.
The location [inaudible] was
taken as well as a description
that might be associated with
it.
And we can just extract that
simply from the user info
object.
And we use this to set up our
custom labels which, again,
we've tied to the storyboard
associated with our content
extension.
So, now that we've set this up
in Code, let's take a look at
how our custom UI looks.
So, the user goes ahead and 3D
touches in this notification.
And then you can see that we
have a completely different UI
here which might be something
similar to what our application
looks like.
So, we've gone from something
that looked like this to
something that's completely
customized.
You have your own custom title
at the top.
You have your complete custom UI
where the video is surrounded by
all the relevant information
that you want to show as part of
this notification.
And we've hidden the default
content because we've already
included that information in our
custom content.
All right, so let's take a look
at the transition again and pay
attention to the initial sizing
of this content extension as
it's being loaded here.
Now, you might have noticed that
it starts at a larger size and
then grows smaller to the exact
size of the content extension.
Now, this might not be a good
experience for your user if
they're going into your content
extension after 3D touching.
Well, we do have the option of
fixing that as well.
And for that, we go back to our
info.plist.
And there we have a property
that you can set which is the
content size ratio.
Now, this ratio is a best guess
that you want to tell the system
for the ratio between the width
and the height of your content
extension.
So, the system knows what's the
starting size it wants to load
that content extension at.
So, in our example here we just
set the value of 0.8 and once
we've done this, now when we do
the transition, it loads right
perfectly to the size of your
content.
So, it's a much better
experience for your users.
So, before we move on, let's
take a look at some of the best
practices for customizing these
rich notifications.
Now, as I've emphasized, you can
have custom UI elements and you
can display all the relevant
information using these elements
as you see fit.
You can also simply reuse your
app view controllers in these
notification content extensions.
So, you don't have to duplicate
any work.
These are simply view
controllers.
It's also important to have the
correct sizing and that the
starting loading size is also
what makes sense for your
content, for your custom
content.
And lastly, it's important to
have fast loading and layout for
your content.
Because we do want the
transition from the notification
into the rich notification to be
super smooth for your users.
All right, so this is where we
ended up with our custom UI.
Now, we did attach a video here.
However, there's no way to play
the media.
Also, this post looks like it's
coming from a social media
stream but there's no way to
interact with it.
Well, we can add all these
different mechanisms to this
notification and that leads us
to our last use case about user
input customization.
Now, some of you might be
familiar that the content
extension body does not allow
any touches.
However, fear not.
We do give you some multiple
input mechanisms that you can
use here for making these
notifications interactable.
And these are namely media
buttons, notification actions,
and custom user inputs.
And we'll take a look at all
these three different
interaction models in the
section.
Now, wouldn't it be nice that we
could just overlay our video
here with a play button on top
of it?
Well, you can do that.
Content extensions allow you to
overlay your content with media
buttons.
Let's take a look how we can set
this up in code.
So, here we are back at our, in
our class which implements the
content extension protocol.
And for getting these media
buttons, you have to implement a
few methods.
The first one is the media play
pause button frame which allows
you to tell the system exactly
where you want this media button
to be overlayed over your custom
content.
You can also customize the look
and feel of this media button by
specifying the color as well as
the type.
In this example, we just use
default.
Now, to know when the user
actually pressed the play or the
pause button, you also get
method callbacks, namely media
play and media pause.
And in our example, it's
important that call to our media
player in our custom content.
All right.
Now that we've set up our media
button, let's take a look how it
works in action.
So, the user goes into our
custom content and just by
simply pressing the play button,
the video starts playing.
It's as simple as that.
So, let's move to adding more
interaction to this
notification.
And like I said, this was a
media post and we want the user
to give us feedback to this
video post in the form of, say,
maybe a like and a comment
action.
So, let's see how we can set
these up.
Now, normally action handling
works that when the user takes
an action, you get the response
in your main application.
However, if you do have a
content extension set up, you do
have the option of intercepting
this action right in the content
extension.
So, you can act on this action
as well as update your UI the
way you want to do it.
Also, you have the option of
just forwarding this action to
the application if you want to
centralize all your action
handling.
Let's see how we can set this
all up in code.
So, here we create our two
actions, one for like which is a
simple UN notification action.
And for comment action, we
create a text input action.
And then we set up our category
with these two actions that
we've created, giving it the
same identifier that's
associated with the content
extension.
Now, when we come back to the
content extension code, the main
method that you implement for
handling these actions is the
did receive response with
completion handler method.
Now, here the UN notification
response object contains all the
information about the action
that was taken as well as the
notification request on which
this action was taken.
So, the first thing in our
example that we do here is post
this response to our server
because we just want to handle
our action in the content
extension without sending it to
our app.
Then we look at the action
identifier and determine it's
the like action.
And then just go ahead and
update our custom UI with the
like emoji.
And lastly, we call the
completion handler with the
option do not dismiss.
Because we want the user to
still interact with the content,
because the video might still be
playing after they've completed
this action.
So, once we've set this action
up, let's take a look at how
this looks.
So, the user starts playing the
video and just by simply taking
the like action, we've updated
the UI and it gives a good
feedback to the user that
they're engaging with this
content right there and then.
And the video's still playing
and the content hasn't
dismissed.
Let's continue and look at the
next action that we've added
which was the comment action.
And here again we look at the
action identifier and determine
that it is the comment action.
Now, since we know that we'd set
it up as a text input action, we
first check if the response is
associated with a text response.
And we extract the user text
that the user might have entered
as part of this action.
And then set it up on our custom
label that's again associated
with our custom UI.
And again, we call the
completion handler without
dismissing this notification.
So, once we've set this up
again, now the user starts
playing the video, presses the
comment button and just adds
their comment there.
And as soon as you post it, we
just update our content right
there and then.
So, it's, so the user gets
real-time feedback of what
they're doing and they're super
engaged with the content that's
associated with the
notification.
And they don't have to go to
your application to do all these
things.
All right, so we've set up these
two actions but sometimes a like
is not enough and a comment
might be too much.
For social media posts maybe, we
want to have the user to give
their reactions to this post.
So, one way we could do that is
add all these different
reactions as just actions
associated with this
notification.
However, this doesn't look
really nice and it's a lot of
options that we're duplicating
here.
What if you could just replace
this with a custom user input
view?
That shows up right where the
user's keyboard would've gone.
Perhaps something like this?
Well, you do have the option of
doing this.
And for that, we use an existing
UI kit API for UI responder.
And let's take a look how we can
set this up and code them.
So, now we create our new action
for reactions which is a simple
UN notification action.
And then update our category
with this action that we've
created.
Now, in the class that's
implementing the content
extension protocol, what you
need to do is override a few
methods that tell the system
that you're providing your own
custom input feed.
The first method that you have
to override is the can become
first responder and you return
the value true.
And then you override the input
view method where you're
returning your custom input
field.
Now, you have complete control
of how you're setting this input
view up.
And all the actions and the
different interactions that you
might have associated with this.
You're not going to go through
the default notification action
handling for this because this
is your custom input view.
So, once we've set this up, we
come back to the did receive
action response method and here
determining that it's the action
associated with the reaction
[inaudible], all we have to do
is call self.become first
responder.
Just simply this call will let
the system know to display your
custom input view where the
keyword would've gone.
And in our private method for
handling the bottom press for
these, we update our custom
label and also we just call
resign first responder which
then dismisses your custom input
view.
Now, I know that's a lot of
code.
Let's take a look how this
actually works.
So, you can see here that we
have our new action for
reactions.
And then when the user presses
this, our custom input view just
shows up at the button and by
pressing either of these emojis,
we can just update the UI there.
So, it's a very customized way
of how you want your users to
interact with your content.
You're not limited by just
simple action button presses.
So, we've gone from something
that looked like this.
To something that's much more
concise and a much better user
experience.
So, what are some of the best
practices for this user input
customization?
Now, let me repeat that media
buttons are the only mechanism
that you have for overlay
controls.
So, use them where it makes
sense.
You can associate them with
video as well as some playback.
Make sure your actions are
specific to the context of the
notification so that the user
knows exactly what they're doing
with these actions.
It's up to you to determine
whether it makes sense to
dismiss the content extension or
not depending upon the kind of
engagement that you're
presenting as part of your
notification.
And then the custom user input
view gives you complete control
of your input mechanisms for
these notifications.
Now, before we go today, we did
want to showcase a few apps that
we feel have really used these
notifications APIs.
Most of them that we announced
at last year's WWDC and show how
they're using these different
APIs in different ways.
The [inaudible] application
provides a very rich interface
with the media as well as the
news title and a blurb about
this content right there and
then.
And gives you the option of just
interacting with this content
with actions.
The Castro Podcast app shows you
your next upcoming podcast as
well as gives you the option of
just modifying your podcast
queue list right there and then,
again with notification actions.
And then the Shazam content
extension gives you a play
button so that you can play your
last recorded song right from
the notification as well as the
option to buy and share this
media.
All right, so let's summarize
everything that we've looked in
our session today.
We started out by doing an
overview of notifications and
all the different APIs that you
can use for doing notifications
for your applications.
Then we introduced a new concept
about hidden notification
content and how you can totally
customize how that looks to your
application users.
Then we talked about modifying
notification push content using
service extension.
And we talked about customizing
rich notification interfaces
using content extensions.
And tied to that, we talked
about customizing these user
input that's associated with
these rich notifications.
So, we're really excited to see
how you go ahead and use all
these different tools for making
the notification experience much
richer for your application
users.
For more information about this
session, do check out this
website.
That's all for the session
today.
Thank you so much for coming and
have a great WWDC.
[ Applause ]