[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
Welcome to WC 2016.
Quite a bit has happened
With the addition of tvOS, then
a lot of them with
and all our platforms
for their own unique
But they share a tremendous
and APIs, making it easy
to all four platforms
by leveraging the individual
Our expert tool chain is the
They share most of their
and the underlying
and programming languages
And today we are announcing a
that you'll be able
You'll find many more ways
and you'll be able to
in even more markets.
Our iOS 10 in particular is
In fact, if you take a
that we announced this morning,
up pretty much the entire user
covering everything from
Messages, Maps, and even Siri.
An important concept that we use
and you might remember that
years ago.
They represent an increasingly
because they allow you to
and to participate in
They allow you to
by running short-lived
that are launched on demand.
Our shipping products already
of extension points, and we're
allowing you to hook even
Perhaps the most exciting
for creating iMessage Apps.
And to tell you all about it,
I'm going to hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So I'm having a great
and I hope you all will too.
iMessage Apps are how you
Now, as Andreas mentioned,
and that means that like other
in your apps on the App Store.
But with iMessage Apps,
You can include them in
which you get at right
Looks like this.
Now, when you send interactive
you'll have the icon of
but even more importantly,
that interactive message to
they'll have this link that
If you tap on that link.
That takes you right to
so it's an amazing way to have
from one person to another.
Now, if you're building
it's really simple.
There's no coding required.
You just take all of the
for the app, the
put them into Xcode, build, and
If you want to make a
and take advantage of all
you program with Swift
like with other extensions.
And there's a new
The classes in this Messages
to everything you need
So there's an object
that you send.
There's an object representing
message is part of.
There's even an object
session, which lets you
and it's a really great way to
Now, all of this is done
that Messages is famous for.
Your app doesn't have
in the conversation outside of
and if, it doesn't even
who you're sending to, so that
Now, adaptive design
to any iOS app development,
and it's even more
That's because Messages runs in
and shapes of devices
And so it runs on iPad, it runs
over an iPad, portrait
and so your iMessage
But there's one additional
which is that they run in this
of the screen where the
between them or you
and expand it to its full size.
Sometimes the app will do it.
Sometimes the user will do it.
Adaptive design is
to that experience as well.
Everything you need to develop
and so you can really start now.
The SDK has all the things
from the Messages
And the simulator even
of Messages just for developers
of a conversation and try
to see how they're
And now Adele Peterson
of this comes together
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Darin.
As you saw this morning,
our friends at Disney have
so I'm going to show
by putting together a
Now, this only takes a minute,
so even though I'm
I'm actually almost done.
I'm going to start by
application template.
I'll give it a good name
and I'll select the
Now, I want my stickers to have
in the Messages app
by dragging in my icons.
And now I can select my sticker
Okay, let's give that a try.
Now that Messages is in the
for you to try out your
Okay, so let's launch
I just love this 8-bit droid.
So I can test out sending one
and dragging a sticker
Looks great.
And that's how easy it
[ Applause ]
Now onto iMessage Apps.
So I've got this ice cream app
into these kinds of
and create things, so I'm
to build ice cream
So here in the Compact View,
you have the completed
and when I tap the
and shows the ice
So I'm going to select a
So I'm going to select
So now the simulator shows both
of the conversation,
to use two iOS devices to
In this view, I'm
and I'm sending the
Let's look at it from the
So here Kate's received
You can tap on the message,
and send it back to John.
And then on the other side
of the conversation,
You tap the message,
and send it back to Kate.
Now, as delicious
I don't really want my entire
with these partially
There's actually a much
of collaborative iMessage App.
If I use the same MS session
then the earlier steps
of building ice cream
by concise descriptions, and
the latest ice cream message.
So I'm going to make
and show you how it looks.
So let me switch over to
Let's see.
Okay, so here's the
that creates the
I'm going to drag in -- oops --
This code looks to see
if there's a selected
That's what you get when
and it launches the
So if there is a
we'll use the session
and if there isn't, we'll
So let's give that a try.
Okay, so now we'll
We'll tap the Plus button,
add some toppings, send it back
and send it back to Kate.
So now you can see those
earlier steps of the process,
and you no longer have those
sitting on top of
And that is a little taste
of what you can do
Next up, Robby Walker
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Adele.
Five years ago, we
the intelligent assistant
Since then, Siri has spoken
to people hundreds
As of today, Siri is now
of devices and in a
Siri also has many new features
One cool example, on
you can start talking to Siri
button with literally zero
to an amazing collaboration
between our hardware
But of course, until today,
something really important has
so we're so excited to
of SiriKit on iOS.
[ Applause ]
We believe the best
to use the apps they love,
and with SiriKit, people
with those applications in
I'm going to talk about how
with SiriKit to provide a great,
The first thing Siri does is
taking audio and
Then, Siri understands what the
and turning it into
Based off that, on that
and provides responses,
Your application will
The first is vocabulary to
The second is your app logic,
and of course, a
Now, we designed SiriKit so that
and your application
And what's great about that is
to adopt SiriKit and your
high-quality experience
feels like a conversation
Let's dig in a bit.
The first role of
to provide vocabulary,
The first is app vocabulary.
These are terms that
to any user of your application.
Things like UberX or Pinboard.
The other is user vocabulary.
These are terms that are
to an individual user
Things like their contact
The main role of
to provide your app
in an extension at
The first is to help Siri
of the user's intent.
The second is to help Siri show
and when they confirm
And the third is to actually
to accomplish what the
And during the conversation,
to the user, and you can
extension to customize
with your application
like using your application
So let's take a look
at a messaging app
Hologram is the number one
in a galaxy far, far away.
So imagine someone says
to Obi-Wan saying,
Now, it's Siri's job to
into text, but Siri needs
Siri doesn't know on its own
that Obi-Wan is an important
in your user's life, and
of vocabulary to
that Siri understands
Next, Siri works to understand
In this case, send a
And Siri will also work
like the recipient
Siri packages all
into a structured object
Your application
about the countless ways someone
to Siri, whether it be
multi-step interactions.
All of that's handled
about is this really
SiriKit will then hand this
with parameter resolution.
For example, maybe
that the user said "Obi-Wan,"
to this person as
and you can instruct
Then comes the big event.
It's time to actually
and SiriKit will
to your extension
In this case, you're going to
to get in an escape pod,
roll over some sand dunes,
You're going to get the
And along the way, Siri will
for this interaction.
And if you want, you can
experience into Siri so
to your users.
And that's it.
Those are the three things
because SiriKit handles
And handling the conversation
Siri's behavior is
on how someone starts a
So if you're holding your
looking at your screen,
Siri will provide
and say less things out loud.
But if you say, "Hey,
in the car using
to show a lot more
say a lot more and
SiriKit is powered by
the same technologies that
of OS integrations, and you'll
This year, SiriKit will connect
and in each of these
than one intent to
conversational experience.
For example, in Messaging,
or search them, and in Payments,
you can request payment
And SiriKit will be available
and this is a big deal
that Siri handles
what I actually mean is Siri
in all 36 locales so that
to worry about that.
[ Applause ]
We're so excited to
and so is someone else we know.
Siri, say hello to apps.
&gt;&gt; I'm swiftly becoming
&gt;&gt; And on that note,
to talk about Swift.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks, Robby.
Let's dive in to
Now, it's easy to forget
and released it less
and in that short time,
to the App Store
including well-known
Now, Swift has also
with the enterprise as well.
Just as a simple example,
and deployed hundreds of
Now--
[ Applause ]
Now, there's lots of reasons
one of which is that
than six months ago.
[ Applause ]
And in that time, it's become
language project on GitHub,
and the number one
and it's stayed on top.
I think to me, even better than
of new people get
We now have hundreds of new
through open source, and
of poll requests.
The response has
Now, one of the reasons
that Swift being open is really
to see it go everywhere.
For example, we think that
and so we ported it to Linux.
And the community agrees.
In a very short period of time,
to other popular
Android, and even Windows.
[ Applause ]
Now, to help Swift get to
we started the Swift
The Package Manager's a
and reuse cross-platform
It can generate an
and even compile
on platforms like Linux.
Another great thing about Swift
involved with the design
Swift-evolution has been
with intense interest in
of emails on mailing lists.
It's ridiculous.
Now, we published an open
for each release,
and discuss different
to push the language
We then debate these
and we turn them into
So far, we've had over 100
This is only in six months, and
of how fast Swift moves.
But it also shows another
Despite its wide use, Swift
programming language.
Now, as you've seen
to quickly identify issues in
because we don't want to be
We are building Swift as the
and so we want it to be great
And now the problem with this
the programming language
out from underneath you can be
to new platforms and new kinds
this becomes an even
So with that as context,
let's dive into what's
Swift 3. We announced
of the open source
and we've been developing
The number one feature and the
to get these early growing
into a stable and mature base
with future versions
No?
[ Applause ]
So because of that, we're
of the language and
and the development
And there are a ton
that you can see this in Swift.
To give you a simple
about Swift 2 is that
in Cocoa didn't feel
Swift loves clarity and it aims
On Swift 3, Cocoa APIs
You could say they're
Now, we did this with a number
First, we sat down
about what really makes a great
down in a document that's
We then took that and took
into the Swift recompiler, so
to Objective-C APIs as it
But Swift goes far
Naming's a pretty
but it goes beyond just naming.
And if you look at
you'll find entirely new
Date is an example of this, and
you'll find that it provides
it's about twice as
and it's about 40 times
to reduced MalCon
[ Applause ]
Now, there are examples
and as Calendar becomes
Global Constants become
NSDate Components becomes
and everything is
If you move beyond foundation,
that we work with
but it provides this
With Swift 3, Dispatch has
has a beautiful object-oriented
[ Applause ]
And it follows all the best
from a great Swift API.
Core graphics is
Here's some typical core
it's elegant, beautiful, and
[ Applause ]
Now, Swift 3 has a
that you can learn
Swift 3 is available in Xcode 8,
and Xcode provides a
to help move your code from
Even better, Xcode 8
which means that you can
when the time is right for you.
[ Applause ]
So that's all I have
Thank you, and I'll hand
about the next big
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Chris.
So another aspect of Swift
so simple and so approachable
for implementing apps
It's also great as a first
In fact, we think this
and when we designed Swift,
that's also an explicit
And right from the
we introduced Xcode Playgrounds,
where you can quickly
And while it's great
for experienced developers
and I want to dramatically
and include kits for just
So today we are announcing
a new app for the iPad.
You've already seen a demo
It is paired with Xcode
from the ground up for learning
and teaching how
It's both playful and engaging
and it's a fun way of
for experienced developers.
It is designed to work with the
We created a new Smart Keyboard
that brings you quick type
similar to code completion
You often can write entire
to bring up a full keyboard.
When you edit inline values
we pop up these quick editing
to easily select a value,
to bring up a full keyboard.
You can quickly change the
by dragging the structural
on the screen with your finger.
And as you would
of prebuilt code snippets you
with a tap or again by
And for the times where you
to write some code,
with a dedicated
which makes it super easy
to access the many special
that you need for
Just with a swipe of a finger.
No need to switch
The app also ships the
We're building an
that will introduce you to
and we're planning to
over the course of the
in to provide learners
that they're going
So they keep coming back
with the learning process for
But you're not limited
to following this
You also have the power and the
on your own with a set
We created one that makes it
with just text input and output
to explore and visualize
on shapes.
And beyond that, since you
at your fingertips, you're free
to create pretty much
and use the app to
You can even control robots
and other accessories
so it ends up being
And to just show you
about how you can leverage the
to give us another demo.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Right. Thanks, Andreas.
Swift Playgrounds makes it easy
so let's take a look
that I created earlier and
Now, I started here with
and you can see the
over there on the right.
So just some squares
and colors rotated
Now, everything over on
of my code on the left.
At the heart of my code
That's where I create
And then up at the very
that defines how many
Well, right now, that's set to
that entire right-hand side
so to do that, let me just
and then I'll tap Run.
Nice. And I think maybe instead
That looks good.
And I really like the pattern
where the squares,
down into the center
That looks really cool.
I bet I could make
if I change the size of those
over time.
So back down in the for loop
I'm going to tap on the plus
between these two
Rather than just
why don't I try multiplication?
Run that. That looks good.
So you can start to get an
to explore and experiment
So next, I'd like to
of life to my picture.
I'll use some animation
Now, to do that, I'm going
in to the Shapes template,
and I think what I want is I
in from the center
So I'm going to tap right here
and then down in the shortcuts
and I'm going to tap on
So I'll have an animation
and I'll have it wait for just
and then everything that I put
It's going to be automatically
to pull in the rotation
And then I also want the size
so I think I'll start it out
and then back in
I'll set it to what
So I'll say square.size
and then I already calculated
that same variable,
Very cool.
So it's starting
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
And there's one more thing
I'd like to add a little
And to do that, I'm going to
into the Shapes template.
And down here at the bottom,
I've actually already added
The block's waiting
and I've also written
that will rotate each square
So I just need to call that
So back in the shortcuts bar,
I'm going to say
and then I'll tap Run.
And now I'm going to
in the top right, and
and just like that, I've
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
By the way, you may have
I haven't actually needed the
and I think that's pretty cool.
There's one more thing that I'd
So I'm a UI guy.
I love building custom
and I've been tinkering
around with this custom
I'd love to show you that.
So when you tap on the color
out from underneath your
and pick the color you want.
Now, all the code to build
So let me make the code bigger
Now, the first thing you'll
I'm importing UIKit, so I
in this Playground and in
And then all the way
this is where I tell Swift
and show it over on
There's one last thing
to my Playground here, and
that I can set the color of so
that I can try out
So I think to do that, I'll
so let me bring up the coding
"Let image view equal
And I'm going to use the
and then I'm going to
in the shortcut bar,
That's an image literal.
So when I tap on it in my
from resources that have been
[ Applause ]
So I added the Swift
so I'm going to choose that.
And then last thing I need to
the UI Image View into
so I'll just say
toss in the image view.
We'll run that, then I'm going
And know we can see
I've got our color picker,
in one little other
I want it to be a little
of the bird, figured hey,
[ Applause ]
And that's Swift Playgrounds.
Thank you.
Andreas?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ken.
So as you saw, no matter what
you always do so by
including the APIs that give you
And by writing real Swift code,
this is perhaps the
to other learning apps that
that users quickly outgrow.
In Swift Playgrounds,
to write real Swift code.
And by the way, as a side note,
the entire Playgrounds app
[ Applause ]
So Swift Playgrounds offers
and to teach and to learn how to
about letting as many users
take advantage of
And in fact, we hope that you
platform for learning by
And to get you started, we're
on our Playground's file format
And later this year,
to publish our lesson materials,
including the rich 3D
that will let you copy
Incorporate your own ideas,
and help us reach many
So once a user has
there's numerous ways
Playgrounds are simply
in all the usual ways
And we didn't stop there.
We made it easier
of your program's output and
so that you can record
and publish your
And for--
[ Applause ]
And for more advanced learners,
on the iPad and Xcode on the Mac
You can move Playgrounds
between the two environments
into developing full
And so that brings us
[ Applause ]
To tell you more about
over to Matthew Firlik
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Andreas.
Xcode 8 is a big release
so let's just jump right
about our Source Editor.
For this release, we focused
on adding the most
from all of you.
We started by adding in
and you can edit this color.
It'd work beautifully
[ Applause ]
It gets better [laughter].
We also did a support
so you can now view and define
[ Applause ]
Let's go for three.
We added in Swift image literals
in your source and as
And to help you write better
now has a command
for documenting your APIs.
[ Applause ]
So these features and a number
of usability improvements really
awesome, but we didn't
so we've added one more
out to be your number
App extensions.
[ Applause ]
With Xcode 8, we are
We're starting with
This extension works
to enable transformations,
and navigation within the file.
And this opens up worlds of
such as reformatting,
localizations, even to-do items.
Now, you can implement many
and each action is listed
Users can set key buttons for
as part of their workforce.
Now, as developers
[ Applause ]
As developers of
through the App Store or
and these extensions
on both Sierra and El Capitan.
[ Applause ]
Now, as a standard extension,
These extensions are run
and have their signatures
And to further reinforce
by system integrity protection.
Which means only
and extensions can interact
So the new source editing
towards making Xcode an
We'd love to hear
and other extensions
Now, we've also been
to that way you learn
we have a brand new API
We've merged together
for our four platforms into
Now, this reference
working through frameworks
Now, searching the unified
result for each API and we've
matching we use for code
When browsing the reference,
the platform availabilities are
And in previous releases,
as a separate download
With this release, we've
to almost one-tenth to
so now we've included
so you'll always have
[ Applause ]
Now, we also have some
to Interface Builder, and I'd
like to show them
So here we have a project.
We're calling this Trailblazer.
It's a social application
for sharing your
Now, in addition to the way
you'll now notice that Interface
it's going to render
Interface Builder now shows you
blurs, and shadows
making a seamless experience for
You'll also notice that we're
in the dimensions of a device,
and there's a new configuration
with common device sizes.
Here we're looking at
I can select one of the other
of the iPads, and I can see
displayed there.
[ Applause ]
Here you see we've designed
columns on iPad.
To view it in other ways, I can
to view it in landscape.
I can also view it in
For example, let's look at it
for slide over as
This is great because
to ensure I've implemented
for all the ways users
Now, we've also improved
for creating adaptive
Let me give you an example.
The designers of this app wanted
of the image to show the hiking
But because of the size
to do it on wider displays.
That's really easy.
In the configuration bar, I'll
and I'm presented with the
Width and height.
iPhones and iPads differ
so I'll check that option.
The configuration bar
that I'm making customizations
But you'll also note the
to show me those devices
of that customization.
Here I can see various iPads and
The last item, though, is the
That device and orientation
of the regular width size class,
because now I can ensure
for the devices I intend.
I think our interface will look
and make those changes.
I'll go into the library
and drag it into the interface.
If your hands weren't so sweaty,
you could grab the
Come on.
Nobody look for a second.
This is not going to
[ Applause ]
There we go.
That should not be
Okay [laughter].
So let's continue on.
I'm going to delete the title
and set an image for it.
We'll make it this nice
and we'll just place
Now, I will connect up this
but let's make sure we got
I'll click Done in
and we'll switch back to the
Our button appears.
When I switch back to
and that's exactly the
So Interface Builder
to design adaptive layouts.
The configuration bar is going
to show devices for
It also shows some
I'll bring up the tvOS
and you'll see the configuration
for the light interface
And I can even make
For example, let's
of the compass icon for
out a little bit better.
Now, there's one more feature
for Interface Builder
You'll see that the tvOS
out so it fits on the
Interface Builder now
at any zoom level.
[ Applause ]
So whether you want to
get pixel perfect alignments,
and work at an overview,
[ Applause ]
And that's what we have
Thank you.
Designing in Interface Builder
on a device, and editing
at any zoom level means you're
or small those devices
For this release, we've also
of our tools, and in particular,
we've made Interface Builder
We've also completely rewritten
making Xcode much
with desktop automation.
[ Applause ]
Now, with each release, we add
diagnosing, and fixing issues.
And with Xcode 8, we are taking
Over the last year, we've
which provide great
and as you edit your
We've added three new static
malleability, and deallocation.
All common patterns that can
And we've continued to
improving stability,
and adding some new options.
Xcode will now capture and
that occur during your testing.
[ Applause ]
This is a great option
collect those logs, and
you can view them right in the
We've also enhanced
to run prebuilt tests.
[ Applause ]
Woo hoo, indeed.
It means this is perfect for
with your own continuous
So now more than ever, Xcode
as you build, analyze,
But oftentimes some of
if not let's say
when you run your code.
For that, we're introducing
Runtime Issues.
[ Applause ]
Runtime Issues are
You're alerted to them
and you'll see details about
We've added a toggle at
Now, there are three
UI, threads, and memory.
Let's start with UI.
The View Debugger is already
and diagnosing problems
In addition to improved
the View Debugger will now
With each capture, the View
with ambiguous layouts, and
and misconfigured constraints.
[ Applause ]
These issues are surfaced
and the Inspector provides
Now, threading issues
and can be difficult to debug,
and there are many
Things like unlocking from the
To help you track down
we're integrating Thread
When enabled for
the Thread Sanitizer is able to
and will surface them
You can have Xcode break on
or you can collect them
at the end of your session.
And the integrated report
of these issues,
about any race conditions
and giving you stack
Like -- yes.
[ Applause ]
Now, like threading,
memory issues are often
And to debug them effectively,
of your objects and see how
so that's what we
New in Xcode 8 is a
in the Debug bar here, which
and navigate the object graph
[ Applause ]
Will you like it
that it automatically
[ Applause ]
That's good because this
for debugging memory issues,
and I'd like to show
Okay, so here we have the
I'm going to launch
Now, I was debugging
and I noticed some memory
I'll bring up the memory
and I'll click on the trail.
You'll see that memory spikes.
That one's okay.
I investigated that
from loading all the
What I noticed, though, was
our memory spikes, and we
even if we go back all the way
to the beginning
This is generally indicative
and something we can use the
so I'll click the Memory
and as we pause your
we capture a graph
The debug navigator now shows
in my application,
and the ones the
I can filter this down
from my project.
I can also type in a
to look for specific objects.
Here I've typed in "controller"
of the Comment View
That's surprising to me.
When I select any one of
for this object on the right.
Now, what you're seeing here
to this object that are
One of these objects I see here
This is somewhere in code
that my View Controller has been
That's a good place
I'll bring up the Inspector
and one of the details we show
that capture happened.
And of course, I can just click
of code that caused it.
[ Applause ]
And I can see the
I've set up an observer for
when the rating changes.
This API returns an
that I see I've properly
when the view goes away,
but I never retained
That's a common and
It's also one the Memory
to find and fix.
Now, I mentioned before the
leaks, and it's alerting
up here in the Activity view.
I'll click on that and be
where I see three types
An array, user review,
I'll click on one of the
and now we see the
A user has an array of
of those user reviews has a
If all these references
this will leak all
Now, it looks like I'm
If I wanted more details though
I can use the context menu
to the console or just bring
up a quick look to
Now, in this case, the reviewing
want to investigate, and we'll
I'll just command click on it
of code where that
And sure enough, I forgot
So just like that, the
to show me the leaks I
[ Applause ]
So that's the new Memory
Now, there is one other kind
about today, and that's
[ Applause ]
There is nothing more
on your projects than having
Well, actually, that turns
because in some cases, the
than the problem itself.
[ Laughter &amp; Applause ]
So we addressed this in Xcode 8
and we've completely rebuilt
[ Applause ]
We started by creating new
more robust, and built with
We generated a new
to clearly show you
and certificate you're using
We refined our messages
to ensure they always
and we also were ensuring to
and the results to
about what's occurring.
Based on these, we had a
to provide two new
Xcode 8 has an option for
With this code signing
of the details using
and this profile is
that you create or manage.
We'll take care of all
for adding entitlements
For cases where you
of your signing setup, you
and use Customized Code Signing.
[ Applause ]
With Customized Code Signing,
you can specify the exact
like to use and you can specify
which is a great option when you
[ Applause ]
Customized Code Signing
of our new foundations to
and assistance for any issues.
And there's one other area of
to focus on, which was
To make development easier when
Xcode now supports multiple
[ Applause ]
This means when you
you just add your
You no longer need to revoke
of your other development.
[ Applause ]
So the new provisioning system,
and multiple development
Always that Xcode 8
and gives you the
And in this release, we
and we have some great
Compared to the release we
you'll find Xcode launches
up to being 50 times faster
[ Applause ]
These improvements all add
that is fast and fun to use.
So these have been some
and enhancements
Please come by the
and let us know what you think.
Next, I'd like to invite
who's going to give you some
new platform technologies.
Sebastien [applause]?
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Matthew.
Thank you.
Let me now give an
foundational technologies,
to start with compression.
Now, if you recall, last
as our new mainstream
At three times the
than half the energy
it's a really compelling
and one that's seen
Now, today we're announcing
that we're open-sourcing
There you go.
And we believe that this will
especially for multiplatform
and backhand offline
Next, I'd like to
Now, we know that
of some applications
on having a great
but today's networks don't
to prioritize the traffic
For example, people
at work can interfere
video conference.
And so in working with Cisco,
to the network, and what
to do is identify
Identify those applications
to your business, and then
to end throughout the network.
Which gives you much
for those applications that
That is networking.
Next--
[ Applause ]
Next, let's talk about logging.
Now, logging is a
of you use during
and for field diagnostics.
Traditionally, logging
A number of you roll
The solutions that are available
and so this year, we've
and we've come up
that we think is
It's unified.
It's extremely fast.
It's very compact on how
It also gives you enough
across applications,
It has this concept
where you can capture very
that only get persisted to disc
when your application
And finally, we've
so you can capture very rich
and have those be
when you ship your application
Now, along with this
We have rewritten the console
in capability.
It gives you, for example,
through development devices,
and grade system
so that is the new logging.
Next up--
[ Applause ]
Next up, let's talk
All right.
Now, of course, HFS Plus is the
and it was first
Today it's deployed
over a billion devices.
And of course, HFS Plus was
and I think it's really a
of its original design that
system today.
But of course, when it was
on Macs, and so we thought
to launch a new file system.
And so today we're announcing
[ Applause ]
There you go.
I thought you guys
or the crowd might be excited.
Now, the Apple File
from our smallest device, the
with very large storage
It's also modern.
We designed it first
and tomorrow's storage
It's resilient and we've
to unify encryption
which gives us great
Now, the Apple File System has a
and I want to highlight
The first is called cloning.
Now, why cloning?
It turns out that if you look
for a while, you'll find many
It's kind of human nature
That's of course inefficient.
It uses up storage space.
But with clones, you're able
for that initial storage when
It's very fast and you can
and directory hierarchies.
The second feature that I want
to highlight is called
Now, what are Snapshots?
They're really an
of the file system
Why would you want this?
Well, let's say you're
Using Snapshots, you can go
of the file system
Another great example of
in the classroom.
You may set up a device for
configuration files,
and so on that you're going
As the students use a device,
they may inadvertently modify
and what you can do is you
of the class to revert
to its original state
for the next class of students.
Now, these are features of
with a developer
of the Mac OS Sierra release
We'd encourage you all to
give us feedback, and the Apple
to all Apple devices soon.
[ Applause ]
All right.
Finally, let's talk
You heard about a new, powerful
privacy in this morning's
to explain that to you.
I will start with the formal
and remind, just note that
I can guarantee you the
And I'm going to actually
to you using a couple
So the first example
to use differential privacy
and for all one of
and important questions
of modern computer science
This is of course an
We're going to poll our audience
It's also something that is
to remain private
some of your coworkers may be
So how do we do this using
Well, first, each of you
but before we send that over to
of the survey, through
we add noise to each answer.
And after we've added noise,
to know what you
We send this to Apple,
of differential privacy is that
over a large population,
to recover the answer
Now, I'm not going
on this, the actual answer.
It looks like of course
in our opinions on this,
that after you've run your
this doesn't actually really
[ Applause ]
Now, how are we actually
in iOS 10?
Let me give an example of this.
In Spotlight, we provide
and we'd of course like to
and popular suggestions
And so the way that we do
of our deep links a unique
on their device, whenever
we take that hash, add noise
of it, and send it to Apple.
Now, any one of these fragments
on their own is completely
but when we aggregate this
we're able to recover the
and then use that to
and improve our user's
That is the science behind
There's one more aspect of it
You might think, well, if we're
and this works by capturing
what happens if Apple captures
Could you not then
And this is where the
The privacy budget limits
that we can capture from any
that in the end, we can
information from any
So that is differential privacy.
It's a powerful technique
from our users, improve
and still maintain your privacy.
So with this, I'm going to hand
who will be talking about
Toby?
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Sebastien.
[ Applause ]
Good afternoon.
There we go.
So, you know, it's really thanks
such a rich ecosystem on iOS,
for new ways to help
get into the apps
and to integrate
across the rest of the OS.
You saw earlier how your
through messages, and
to tell people about your
from the home screen.
We've added a new Share button
This brings up the Share Sheet,
and so now you can Tweet your
and this is available for
Now, we have a lot of ways
into the right app at
I'm going to move through them
Handoff lets you carry on a
Spotlight can link directly
A Universal Link will take you
for a platform, and
from one application to another.
Siri will suggest apps here in
We can suggest an app
in the App Switcher
We can connect apps based
like this and this and this.
Well, I think you get the idea.
There's only one thing I really
of this, which is that
to a whole ton of functionality.
It's how your application tells
in your app, and that allows us
to create intelligent
between your applications.
And in iOS 10, we're adding two
Now, many apps use addresses
and we can use that
between your applications.
Let me illustrate
This is the Yelp page for one
of my favorite restaurants
Now, suppose it were to
with this address on it.
That would allow me to do things
like asking Siri to
My phone knows that I use
and it can make it
to order a ride directly
Or when I'm typing in a text
data, QuickType can suggest an
at and Maps can include that in
with a quick way of getting
Now, we also interact with
and the OS can learn which
with any given person.
To do this, your app needs
to give us three
Enough context so that
in the address book for this
that you're providing, that's a
and the specific
that you'll use for this person.
Now, this is the new
which we're making available a
the OS, and you'll notice that
in here information that we
Now, when I tap on one of these
at the top of the card, we
in the list of options.
When I make my choice,
that the next time
we can take you straight
I should point out that all
to the user and accessible
Now, we deeply believe
across the OS makes for a
Extensions, of course,
and you've heard earlier
Maps extensions, and SiriKit.
Well, I'd like to
about two extension points that
A service extension runs in
to modify the push payload
to the user.
It lets you do things like
or an audio file
and embedding it directly
Or you could encrypt your
and use a service extension to
providing for full
[ Applause ]
Now, I should point
to use something
than the ROT13 algorithm
We're going to double
for extra security [laughter].
Now, if you want an even
a content extension can provide
for the expanded look
This lets you provide a dynamic
and interactive experience
to your application.
This morning, you got a quick
with its vibrant,
Now, a widget can still
within reasonable limits,
compact, fixed size to optimize
And the thing that
about is making these
from the home screen.
I'm going to tell you
to get this functionality
The first thing you want to do
and support the new compact size
so that your widget
You need to build with the
Nothing else has changed about
You just get this new
and so we're really excited.
We think this is going to
into your application.
Okay, let's switch gears
So Mac OS Sierra is adding full
in right-to-left languages,
in places where that
The Mac now joins
which quietly introduced support
And with so many potential
it's really more important
that your app be properly
And you can learn
Now, you know, when Sebastien
versus spaces, we were
where he was going.
You saw this morning how
of their windows into
AppKit will take care of pretty
and it's smart enough not to
with your document windows,
And in fact, if you're
there really is nothing
to do in your application.
If you're not using
of API you need to adopt to
but I'd really encourage
at whether NSDocument isn't
You see, we also showed you this
for people to move their
into the cloud, and
that this is the
So it's super important that
in terms of file
And here too if you're using
of pretty much all the
along with UIDocument
Now, I have an important
As you know, the iCloud
of our platforms,
use of these APIs has
to those apps distributed
Well, in Mac OS Sierra, we're
[ Applause ]
Now, your app still
with a valid developer ID, which
of those pesky, untrusted
But once you've done
of these API no matter how
to your customers.
Next, CloudKit.
We introduced CloudKit two years
that we use for building all
Now, it has a fairly
Either your data could
in the world or it's restricted
Well, the new CloudKit
and gives your app
over who can access your data.
[ Applause ]
The new CKShare class gives
who can read and write
and this API is available
On the Mac and on iOS,
for taking care of the
and managing people
We use CloudKit sharing for
that we've built into Notes,
out in the developer
With that, I'd like to hand off
to Josh Shaffer [assumed
who's going to give you
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Toby.
As you heard in the keynote,
and optimizes performance.
These improvements go
and include many enhancements
These enhancements focus
on three key qualities
The first is that
Individual interactions
so it's important to
simple information to
on what's most relevant to make
The second is that
Now, this includes
to the most common actions
For example, we've
to reduce the number of steps
It also means simplifying
that your users will
if they won't take the
And the third is ensuring that
by keeping them up to
as soon as they're needed.
Sure, thanks [laughs].
I agree. Okay, so when you think
that may come to mind is an app
Now, that's definitely part
it's important to keep in
to two other great
of complications
So these three interfaces are
into your one app,
that they present
When you update any one of
of them because if they're
information, then your users
Now, you may remember
there was a fourth
Glances provided
a summary of your
In watchOS 3, this functionality
and is instantly
with just a press
If your watchOS 2 app
that separate interface is no
but its simple design can help
for your application to
and works great when
Apps in the Dock are instantly
that the most common tasks taken
in just a couple of seconds.
Now, that's obviously a very
for it can be a great guide
in helping you design the
to make sure that they work
While each individual
some apps may be
over a longer period of time.
For example, I may refer back
to my shopping list many
In watchOS 3, each
I can instantly see the
and check off the ones
It's now really easy to design
of interaction model because
to the last app that you were
after you last used it.
Once you're done using it,
you'll be returned
[ Applause ]
When your app's not in use,
ensuring that it stays
up to date in the
when you do want to use it.
To make this really easy,
watchOS 3 includes
of Background App Refresh APIs.
Background App Refresh
of building responsive
and periodically
in the background can be a great
of app you're building.
Now, if you're building a
of apps, it's even more
up to date for the entire
so we have some additional
During a workout session, these
in the background even
ensuring that they can
and provide updates to the user
when they reach key
During the workout, they also
if you switch to another
So if I jump out to the Music
after I've dropped my wrist,
I'll very shortly be
We've also enhanced the
and accelerometer sensors
so that they now
for the entire duration
[ Applause ]
In addition to these
we've also got a whole bunch of
Crown events give you raw
from the Digital Crown.
Gesture recognizers
to add custom tap interactions
such as tap, swipe,
the gyroscope is
in addition to the
[ Applause ]
To make sure that you can do
of these hardware access APIs,
of graphics and media
SpriteKit and SceneKit give
to enhance the visuals
and also your notifications.
AV Foundation makes it
out of the watch
of simplifying navigation
you can now play
in your application
Of course, you also
and off the watch, and
as Toby mentioned, CloudKit is
Because it's built on top of
when your phone's not present
and your watch is near
Apple Watch is already a great
in stores, and in watchOS 3,
for sale within your
with just a double-tap
Building a great watch app
It's also important that
to discover and install
And to help you with that,
in iOS 10 includes an
to displaying all of your apps.
With just a few simple steps,
you can create a complication
to appear in the
It's the first thing that
after they've paired
and it displays the
from all their favorite
on their iPhone every day.
This makes it really easy for
and added right to
We've been working really hard
to give you all the tools you
actionable, and responsive
to see what you're
To give you some ideas
of how this can help
Eliza Block will now come
of Background App Refresh and
Eliza?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. So I have here an
for watchOS 2, which shows
and it tells me what his
So right now, you can
If I now suspend the app,
you can see that I have a
that he's happy, but here is
that suddenly Max
Now, this app for watchOS
which I'm going to show you now.
The first is that when I
my complication has not
that Max is now hungry.
And even worse, when I go
of the app in the Dock also
to show a unified set of data
across all the interfaces
So going now to the code,
in watchOS 3 to address
In my extension delegate, I
Handle Background Tasks,
to update all of these
Here in my Snapshot
I'm going to add just
to address both of
The first is to update
for my current friend's
I'm going to also reload
when the snapshot is taken.
Okay, so that should address
But while we're in here,
let me make this app a little
Max was kind of just a
But in watchOS 3, we can
to make some animation happen.
So I'm going to switch
and here's my application
I'm going to delete the image
Now, I wrote a tiny bit
to populate this scene
and to make an outlet, which
Drag it into my SceneKit
Now, not only can you
to your application itself,
to the notification, which
than a text-based notification.
I'm going to drag one
I need to resize
Hook it up to the outlet.
All right, and with those
and run this application again,
and we'll hopefully see
dynamic this time.
So here we have a much
of Max running around, and when
wait for him to get hungry.
We see a really sad,
of Max rubbing his tummy.
[ Applause ]
So I think this is
When I dismiss the notification,
as we hoped to reflect his
in the Dock, you can see
that the snapshot has also
that he's hungry
So that's just a few of the
with the new APIs in watchOS 3.
We're excited to see
And next up, I'd like
to the stage to talk about tvOS.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Eliza.
We've been super excited
to Apple TV just
because we believe the future
you guys have been very
to the App Store, including
health and fitness, and
So let's talk about what it
First, it's already
You use all the tools and
And tvOS includes the
that you're familiar
Plus, we've got some
to tvOS that we've built.
There's all the foundational
for building great apps.
We have a rich media stack
And of course, we've got
And we're bringing even more
With PhotoKit, you can now
that showcase users'
and we've made it super easy to
excuse me, our light/dark
So it's a rich set
and this is just a partial list.
There's a whole lot more.
Let's talk about using
and bringing them all together
to deliver a great
And I want to start with Touch.
When designing tvOS,
to bring a first-class Touch
Now, Touch needs to feel
It needs to be predictable.
It needs to be fun.
That's a particular
when the TV's 10 feet away.
So let's look at
We have updated UIKit
and views look beautiful
We've added UIFocus to allow
of your UI are focusable.
And we have updated
from the focus engine.
Now, altogether this
between what the user
and what they see
Good news here is that we've
for you.
Your UIKit apps will get
Now, if you have a
apps used to deliver content.
We've got a lot of great apps
We have a technology
a framework called TVMLKit.
TVMLKit is a new, high-level
for tvOS.
It's built on top of
that connective Touch
We provide a large
and you can even provide
and native controls.
TVMLKit has allowed teams
highly stylized, customized
Let's now talk about how you can
of Apple TV by integrating
One easy thing to do is
in the cloud using CloudKit.
Making it easier for users to
and pick it up and resume
on their iPhone or iPad.
We've also seen some great apps
that use multiple Apple
With SongPop Party
the whole family can
to answer music trivia
And to make it even easier
to each other across devices,
we're bringing Multipeer
Just a few lines of code--
[ Applause ]
Just a few lines of code,
to your apps running
Now, this morning, we announced
Now everyone in your household
that has an iPhone can have an
To your apps it looks
like the Siri Remote, but
to take advantage of the screen.
The Now Playing screen provides
as well as cover
Just like showing art and
use the Media Player Remote
Media Player Remote Command API
to add this information
The app also provides a
To your game, the new app shows
up as a micro gamepad
To take advantage of multiple
in by setting an Info.plist key.
In addition to Siri Remote
tvOS also supports
And coming this fall,
up to four simultaneous
[ Applause ]
But we didn't want
We wanted to enable
We wanted to enable games
of controllers, so
that we're updating
You can narrow your games to
[ Applause ]
tvOS will check if the
and prompt the user
That's an update on tvOS.
We're super happy to be here.
We've got a lot of
with the tvOS engineers there,
Next, I want to introduce
and talk about graphics
Geoff?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jim.
So I'm going to talk
I'm going to talk about a
We have really great
and I'll start with color.
So we're building
for our latest iPads and
of reproducing absolutely
In fact, as DisplayMate says,
"The color accuracy is visually
So how do we do this?
Well, this is all
So most displays are built
which is narrow and doesn't
would see in life accurately
or paint colors or maybe
So we're moving to the wide P3
to our ability to really
and render these
But we're not stopping there.
We're going to go
From our system APIs to
we support deep and
And if you're an
or UIView, you get it for free.
You get it automatically.
If you have to manipulate wide
we also offer APIs for that.
And of course, we have
Our latest cameras support
We have APIs to access
And we can also now capture
So that's color.
[ Applause ]
I'd like to talk
about technology now
of industry, and that's Metal.
Metal we introduced
and has been wildly successful.
And keep in mind, when
when we enhance it, we enhance
Which allows us to innovate
like Metal tessellation that
for rendering accuracy
or Metal function
Which when combined with S
of shaders that automatically
and lighting properties
And for things like
which use the architecture
to reduce the amount
in your application
Which allows your application
to specialize the way it handles
And Metal is everywhere.
Hundreds of millions
Our key graphics frameworks
and major game engines
So whether you're
or programming directly
you get all the performance
Another thing about Metal,
it's one of our foundational
of our games ecosystem.
So let's talk about games.
Over the past few years, we've
and the goal of this is to
which allow you to take
and turn them into reality.
I want to cover some
First, as mentioned this
We introduced Replay
and it's really super
It allows your users to start
edit that recording, and then
Well, this year, we're
with ReplayKit Streaming.
Now, Replay Kit can
that support the ReplayKit
This allows your users to not
with their friends
to the internet automatically
And the -- absolutely.
[ Applause ]
And even better, it's about
if you already use Replay Kit.
This is super easy and could
of your applications.
So speaking of social, let's
We're changing the way that
Now with our latest OS's,
you can invite anyone you
So your users can invite
out via message,
It's just as easy as
And the cool thing here is if
that are multiplayer APIs,
With the latest OS's,
and we're not going
We're going to add new
Game Center Sessions.
Game Center Sessions creates a
where users can come and go.
This means you can design your
in mind the way they come and go
into your application that's
in multiplayer gaming
Finally, GameplayKit.
GameplayKit is our
that allows you to instance
and make the building blocks
letting us do the
And I'd like to invite Norman
of these components and
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Geoff.
I'd like to show you how quickly
Here's a game project
It's a competitive
and enemies throwing paint
Now, I have been using the
and GameplayKit this year.
As you can see, the game
to be ready; a map, a hero,
I have already implemented the
but it is clearly
with the island bounds, so
Opening our Xcode
at the source code section,
I have already written a
GKComponent provided
like the fight component here.
And in Xcode 8, I
of my class properties
to the 2D editor then I can
gets attached to one
So to build the island map,
I've been using the
So in my game, there's
that I have specified.
There's sand, water, and grass.
Not only do I have the ability
and exterior tiles, I can
So here for the red
for this individual tile image,
to it to get rid of the small
in from the Media Library.
And now this tile
Let me go ahead and show
So switching back to the island
with the new tile map
provided by SpriteKit, so
I can simply select
Make a double click, and
that I want to work on.
Now that I think the island
and to make such modifications,
across the level and Xcode will
tiles to make it with
It's that easy.
So now I think I got the look
Let's look at some of the
To power the hero, our hero's
I have already attached
and the move component.
And to make the player
I can simply add a collision
So this way, it will
body for our hero
on the current tile sets
And to give the player
to throw the water balloons,
I can simply add the
And notice here how the
by the fight component
I can give it a custom
So for example, I can set
than using the default
And in addition, I have
these paint balloons
and I have a enemy
So to give the enemy the same
up the paint balloons
I'm going to give the
And to make this a fair game,
I'm going to give the same
than using the default
Now, I think my level
Let's run it and check it
So the drones are going
to be dropping randomly
and the paintball
So looks like all the
So in Xcode 8, it's very easy to
and connect all these
Because I'm using
my game will automatically
Thank you.
Now, back to Andreas.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Norman.
All right, so just quickly
we talked about.
There are now four Apple
with their own App Store that
And today we added a large
that allow you to hook
Perhaps most importantly,
that you consider creating
that you integrate
But these are just two
of the many new APIs we
And support for all of
by a new version
Xcode 8 is going to run on
Now, of course, it
for developing with Swift 3.
Now, all these technologies
from the WWDC Attendee
so you can get early access and
when we ship out products to
create even more powerful and
Also, go and check out the
which we're including in the
I think you're going to
and perhaps you'll consider
for your kids to start
Now, there are many
at the conference for you to
that we announced today.
There's more than 100
and even more labs.
You can meet every engineer
They are here to answer
So I hope you enjoyed the
around later this week.
[ Applause ]