[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, developers.
What a great venue.
This is really great.
Thanks for coming today.
It's been a long day, but we've
for you.
So I want to welcome you
to the 15th Apple
And we've got a ton of
And we'd like to, of course,
The Apple Design Awards are all
by people in this community.
And this is the moment when many
some of you get to take home one
of the Apple Design
which everyone wants one.
And so we'll see who
But to start things off, I
of context for the apps that
The App Store opened
In fact, next month it'll
And it was on July 10th of 2008.
And in those eight
Right? They've taken off.
And today, we heard 2
But if we just go
to those first days,
I mean, it all started off
And we all remember
They were 30-second slots.
And in those 30-second
or six apps that were featured.
And so each app had five
the customer -- with
And to make an impression
in five seconds is
But what happened in those ads
and they would stop
and they would pay attention to
And within five seconds,
they would have decided
and if they were going to go
And I think that's
And those apps -- basically, it
that created the phrase,
And that phrase was born.
And it was during
on that we saw enormous
I mean, we didn't have
iPhone was out.
We had this SDK.
We didn't have that before.
And we saw enormous creativity.
We saw great games,
and very valuable utilities,
some pretty incredible
and lots of other great stuff,
much of which was
And then, two years later,
And it was introduced
at the Yerba Buena
And I remember that day.
It was an incredible day.
But when the iPad
it brought a whole
And these were apps that
I mean these were apps that,
they caused us to
at what could be
And then we had universal
and bringing functionality
and the experience of all
And all of these apps early on
They changed the way that
They changed the way that we
that we worked, and that
things done.
These were transformational
And then more recently,
Apple Watch was introduced,
And with each of these, we
And so now, as you've
we've got four platforms
And this is amazing.
I mean, for me, being
I remember when it
and there was some
And then everything took
of that whole ecosystem.
And there's a tremendous
with these four platforms.
And we're starting to see
from developers on
and a few of those will
Now, tonight's winners
once again, that set a
And they set a benchmark
excellence in design, excellent
in technology adoption.
And if you've been part of
or ever heard me speak, you know
that that's not all
There's even more that we
We're always looking for
and leaves a great
meaning it draws you
and then gets you coming
That's a big challenge for apps.
We look for apps that are
to do things you
We're looking for
Because accessible and
that those apps are available
than they were prior to being
And so there's a lot
for in winning apps, and these
that we watch for
So let's get started.
Let's start with apps that
So you've heard today that we
year at WWDC, which
And these folks, these
As part of the scholarship
they had to submit an app that
for the scholarship
or they could just
that they had already
that was already
And we looked through
and we found some
So tonight we want to
And the first is Linum by
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks so much.
&gt;&gt; You're welcome.
[ Music ]
All right, so Joaquin
after he had applied for a
and that hadn't worked out.
And he decided after
he could just do
He didn't need to work
So he decided to write his own
And I'd like to show
And before I do, I just wanted
to say Joaquin was a 2015
at WWDC, so probably
about what you used
And he's also super active in
in many of the meetups
All right, so I'm just going to
So what you're seeing here
where the goal is
in the fewest moves possible.
And what you're trying to do is
and pivot them around to connect
And as the number
complex puzzles challenge
And the beauty of Linum
It's got a clean UI and
And with a smart
and approachable
terrific overall presentation
Linum is without doubt an
for a student.
So, congratulations.
[ Applause ]
All right.
And our second student
by Josh Deichmann, Patrick
[ Applause ]
Congratulations.
[ Music ]
So I guess just one of
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; No problem.
There's three guys.
So all three of these guys, one
at the Rochester
in Northern New York State.
And at RIT, they went to an iOS
this year.
And it was at that event
that they started
And Josh is the programmer.
Is it Josh?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, Josh is the programmer.
Patrick is the designer.
And Erik is the guy who created
but also kind of kept you
in terms of development.
So let me just show you
So Dividr is this fun and
And it makes use of 3D
to move the control
on the pressure that
So the more pressure you
The lighter on you are,
And you're basically avoiding
It's simple and compelling,
in Swift, supports Game Center.
And it was, without a
for an Apple Design
Congratulations.
[ Applause ]
This side.
All right.
So those are our 2 winning
Pretty great stuff.
And there were lots more.
But, you know, we've got
Not everybody can win.
All right, now let's move on
We have 10 winners this
which are all super compelling.
They're all incredibly
They're all super
And they're all optimized
that they were created
that customers will
And so let's begin.
The first Apple Design
for 2016 is Frame.io
from New York City.
[ Applause ]
[ Music ]
Congratulations.
Great job, guys.
Great to meet you.
[ Music ]
All right, so Frame.io is a
for teens working
And it lets these teens easily
review clips, approve media,
in that creative pro workflow.
And it turns out that it's
And Frame.io nails it
in the creator pro workflow by
And to give you a better
I'd like to ask Michael
&gt;&gt; Thank you, John.
So this is a typical
Now it's really media-centric,
in the lower half of the view.
Now -- whoops.
So basically what they've
UICollectionViewFlowLayout
and that really makes
Now at the top, you can see
Now this is a really fun
And that's really cool,
There we go.
And that's using core animation
with custom curves
That opens up to a table
to remove someone from a project
Now the media player is
And so what they've done here
and they've done this in a
The first one is a feature
So on this clip of this mountain
across this clip very lightly.
And you can see I
of the clip really quickly.
Now the other thing that they've
and implemented peak and pop.
So on this clip, I'm
That peaks in.
And now watch this.
When I pop, it goes
into a new view --
Pretty cool stuff.
Now the Comment View is
where all the project
and actually collaborate.
All these comments
So when I touch something,
where the comment was made.
You'll also notice that all
to a Play button.
So for example, here you
If I touch the Play
that they call Comment Replay
where it will start
and two seconds after.
And then where the comment
and the phone will vibrate.
One more time.
And here's the comment.
That's where it is.
So I'm going to let this video
because I know that there's
and there's a lion
You know, like, really?
So I'm going to put my
to go ahead and annotate
So this app is incredible.
It's written entirely in Swift.
It's using the latest tools.
It's using multiple storyboards,
auto layout, size classes.
Did I mention it
Did I mention that this
This is a really great app.
Congratulations to the team.
Back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so Frame.io
We love this app.
Hitting the wrong button here,
that's why we're
Apologies.
We love this app.
Congratulations, guys.
You've solved a really big
[ Applause ]
All right, our second
And it is Chameleon Run by
by Noodlecake Studios
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; It's just great to
to see people's studios.
I mean, we were amazed as we
from the winners tonight.
The places in which you
And we couldn't get
With a great soundtrack, fun
and natural controls
Chameleon Run is an
that you are not going
And to show you this game, I'd
&gt;&gt; Great. So thank you, John.
Hello, everyone.
Chameleon Run is
and very challenging auto-runner
with a twist that's
And it has a really
which we'd like to show you now.
My colleague, Mark,
He's going to play while I
So the objective of
through the level in
And Mark is jumping from
But if you notice, when he lands
to switch the character's color
to match the platform
And that becomes
as you make your way
OK, so that was a
Let's do it one more time
out a couple more
especially the rendering
That was something that we
If you take a look at the
in the background, the
of the character, and
and just the particle effect.
We thought that all of that
to this game.
But, OK, so we did
That was an easy level.
And now Mark is going to go
for something much,
Go all the way.
All right, here we go.
Level 15, The End is Near.
And let me tell you a little bit
So first of all, as I said,
and just the vibrancy of
And it was so clear that so
into the construction
and just fine-tuning
Then the second thing --
All right.
Nice.
[ Applause ]
Do it again.
Go for it.
So the second thing
Yeah, OK, that's me playing
So the replayability in this
Most of these levels have
and a low road that
You sort of can go up and down
as you're progressing
But the game really
and play the levels
Maybe the first time through
But then it unlocks
to collect all the crystals or
without switching your color,
that would be on a level
And the third thing about this
that is great on
but it is awesome
We love how this plays
That's what Mark is using now.
It also plays great
And it's just one of these
when you see it on the big
So that's Chameleon Run.
It supports Game Center.
It's localized in 8 languages,
Just pay once and play.
So, congratulations.
Back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Allan.
Thanks, Mark.
That's Chameleon Run --
that you'll be playing
All right, our next winner
by Auxy from Sweden.
[ Applause ]
[ Music ]
Auxy Music Creation is an
And the Auxy team realized
that electronic music was going
and started to develop this app
to create some of their own
And this is a super
with a clean minimalist style.
And honestly inside of this
to create something that
No matter what you tap
So I'd like to ask Michael
&gt;&gt; Great. Thank you, John.
So the first thing
about Auxy was the really subtle
Now I'm not locked
I can go anywhere I want,
and see where it leads us.
So I'll double-tap to start
and drums.
I'll start with some bass drum.
That's great.
So now it told me that
around by dragging,
because I just missed that one.
So we'll do some high hat.
And notice how quick and
It's really cool.
OK, I'm going to add some
That actually sounds more like
and that's great because the
to change my kit.
So let's see if I can find
Not that. Not that.
70's disco -- that's
OK. So now what do we
We need some disco base, right?
So let's add another loop.
Great. So the UI is really
on top of UIKit, and that
They also went ahead
and implemented Grand
That really helps
I'm going to add
[ Music ]
Now I can do a lot with this.
But what I'm going to do is
that I already have created.
And then now we can hear how
and created a really,
really powerful synth
So let's listen to the drums.
OK, the drums really -- they
There's a nice reverb
Let's add some bass.
It's a really fat bass.
Let's add some synth.
Really rich, analog-sounding
I'm going to play around
[ Music ]
That's not bad.
I'm going to take the Doodle
around with it a little bit.
I'm going to bring up my
to change the character
and make it more aggressive.
So we're going to turn down
to open up the filter.
Nice and aggressive -- that's
I'm going to use Multi-Touch
[ Music ]
Seriously, I could do
Now this is really great stuff.
All these guys.
[ Applause ]
The thing that we
about Auxy is they
and they implemented
that customers could have fun
without that technology
Really great stuff.
Love this app.
Congratulations.
Back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; That's pretty cool.
Thank you.
I was just talking for a moment
and it's three people
So here's an app --
More than 4,000 5-star
and it's exclusive to iPad.
All right, our fourth
that helps you to
Congratulations to Streaks
by Zervaas Enterprises
[ Applause ]
[ Music ]
Good job.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
[ Music ]
So, Streaks is a to-do list
that helps you form good
And Streaks has a simple
and it's got an excellent
probably the best Apple
And we'd like to show
TC?
&gt;&gt; Thanks, John.
So trying to form good
The last thing you want is
to set up, uninspiring to use,
and pretty much itself a
So here are five of
that I've set up for myself.
And you can see on the top
So I miss playing the
but I just haven't
I'm using Streaks to help get me
to practice regularly because
And I've been saying
[ Laughter ]
So to see how I've been doing,
for the calendar view here.
I can also peak and pop onto it.
And you can see June
But if I was to reveal to
So the crosses is where,
I've decided not to practice.
Coming back here
this is a summary
And you can see that
on a streak of 15 days.
Now we're back here.
To mark a task complete,
And there you go.
It's like I've just finished
Now when I was outside earlier,
I was reading the iOS 10
So I'm going to go and check
"Read the book" as
Now Streaks is also
And it has Watch complications
including one that is
It's based on a dotted
like the iPhone app so that
at how the dots are arranged
and which ones are
with your task for that day.
Streaks uses Watch connectivity
and iPhone are always in sync.
Now Streaks is also considerate,
especially in the way it
For instance, when it comes
Auzuki, Streaks knows that
when I come home from
otherwise she gets quite cranky.
And nobody wants a cranky cat.
So it knows to remind me
but 30 minutes in advance of
that streak and have
All right?
And it also looks at
out when it is I
so that it doesn't send me a
For when things are
you get encouragement as well.
And in addition to that, Streaks
goal so that you achieve
Now, conversely, if you've
it will suggest an
so you don't end up giving up.
OK, so Streaks is
It's exclusive to iOS and Watch,
and it was developed
Bad habits form automatically.
Streaks helps us come
I'm more confident than ever
that I'll be playing my
or to read many books, and
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So that's Streaks.
We picked this app as a
the great visual design, and
on Apple Watch.
They're localized into 25
to iPhone, Apple Watch, and
All right, our next
Lara Croft by Square Enix.
[ Applause ]
[ Music ]
So Lara Croft Go
of this classic franchise,
into this classy new app with an
into this great adventure game.
This is a great example of
with a small studio
to give them the task
of creating something
down to the smallest detail.
These guys have done
with this huge franchise.
These folks are based
Right? And it's great --
Now to show you this game,
I'd like to ask Allan
&gt;&gt; Great. Thank you, John.
So Lara Croft Go is a turn-based
in the ruins of an
And what we loved about this
of the elements of the
things like the archeological
and solving puzzles and avoiding
and reimagined all those things
into a puzzle game
and beautifully designed
So I'd like to show you it here.
I'm coming into a level
into a new game mechanic
with these rolling boulders.
But actually, before
just take this in for a moment.
I mean, check out the
I hope you can all hear the
It's just beautiful.
And we really love
to detail in the levels.
And it has a really
There's no virtual joypad
To move Lara to the next space,
But, OK, so let's start
Obviously there's this
that if I step on
OK. So, mental note, don't
But we can put that knowledge
Isn't it cool how she kind
All right, but I'm going
Here's another one.
I'm going to get it going,
and let it roll past me.
OK, so I'm safe.
And I come down now into
All right.
So now in this part, I'm
But I'm not going
What I'm going to do --
and I'm going to step back
Bam! OK, no more lizard.
So now let's go forward.
And this next one wakes up.
OK, now the game mechanic here
the lizard will move one space.
And it'll follow me through
So I'm going to climb
and go a particular way to get
Bam! It never gets old.
All right.
And I'm going to
Great. And that finishes
out this particular
And, really, this is just
There's over a hundred
with incredible detail.
And it's just hats off to
It's really beautiful.
The game supports
to synchronize its progress
It's localized in 11
And it's a premium title with
one to provide you solutions
and the other to
So, again, hats off to you guys.
Congratulations.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So that's Lara Croft Go.
It's tuned for iOS and has more
than 5,000 5-star
Tremendous work.
All right, our next winner is
from Ireland.
[ Applause ]
Congrats.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; Great job.
[ Music ]
This is a groundbreaking
for medical students,
and lifelong learners.
And we love this app for how
of teaching anatomy.
For example, medical
as a tool to help patients
on with an injury or
And that understanding actually
and more quickly.
And I'd like to ask
to show this to you now.
&gt;&gt; This was an app that
with its attention to detail,
and most importantly what
We love the iconography
Check out along the bottom menu.
The icons are consistent
and representative
I'm going to turn
on so you can get an
The app has over 6,200
without being overwhelming.
The content is progressively
Just a tremendous
But I'm going to turn
and move into the bone.
Notice the incredible
They're the result of
and artist interpretations.
The team has a skeleton on
and a medical team
to get things just right.
We love it when a team
to make things particularly
If at any point in the app
interesting, you can just tap
Are there any Warriors
[ Cheering ]
This is the ligament that nearly
when Steph went out with that
Now I'm going to
so we can see some movement.
I can select on a muscle group
I can adjust this
rotate, and see things in 3D.
One of the reasons
because it leveraged the
With the new CPU and GPU,
it allowed double the graphics
Again, check out the
Just incredibly realistic.
Now we could spend hours just
but 3D4Medical wanted
to create and share content.
So at any point in the
So I'm going to do that now.
So I'm now recording audio
I can use this --
I could create a
Or if I was a physician, I
to share with my patients.
For the baseball fans, what I'm
Pencil to pull back the
to show the ligaments that
John's surgery.
Imagine a physician
with a patient before
I can then save the
Or if I choose, I can share it
We love it when a developer
in a new way.
This is a team that
and what they could do with iPad
and created a world-class
Congratulations, guys.
Back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; 3D4Medical Complete Anatomy.
We picked this out for its
its high-fidelity models,
and the uncluttered UI.
It's exclusive to
but it's coming to
And it's unbelievable.
All right, our seventh
It is INKS by State of
[ Applause ]
Congratulations.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; So INKS is from the makers
And after extensive research at
to create a new generation
And if you think about it, INKS.
is sort of a cross between
with an artistic flare.
And you've got to see this.
So for the demo, I
the evangelism resident pinball
&gt;&gt; Thanks, John.
So right from the
you get to enjoy the
and highly realistic INKS.
The way they blend together the
Now as I hit the
you can see how it traces
and draws it onto the paper.
It's really pretty awesome.
All right, let's play a game.
Now INKS features
each of which has 24 different
of obstacles, challenges,
As John said, I'm kind
So I'll start with one of
but not so advanced
about your pinball skills.
Now check out each
They're each custom designed,
with a lot of thought and care.
They're their own
on their own before
And check out the gold, and
These show you how well you've
Now bronze is not good enough,
so let me show you
[ Laughter ]
There must be a problem
All right, let me redeem myself.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, man. OK, this was a
when I didn't have
All right, so I'm going to go
[ Laughter ]
And just to show you guys
of gameplay for more beginner
All right, let's try this.
Bam! That's how I do!
[ Laughter ]
All right.
So what I want to show you
that really demonstrate
that I was talking
So there's that big color
And each time you hit one, it
and angle in its own unique way.
And check out how the
into each other and
The team spent a lot of
the physics of it, the
into the paper and blends.
It's really gorgeous.
And I'll show you just
that just shows off how,
even though this is a
they still respected a lot of
of the bumpers, and habitrails,
and drop targets,
I mean, it's really,
And I'm probably not going to
I'll just let it go
But I think this really
traditional game mechanic
attention to detail and
which is completely
Brilliant job.
Thanks. Back to you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Mike.
So it's obvious that we picked
because it's really
It's rich and unique.
It's available in
and it's exclusive to iOS.
And it's also really
of the conceptualization and the
with Apple Pencil by the team.
So they used some other tools,
So that's INKS.
Our eighth winner today
is Zova Personal Trainer by
[ Applause ]
Congrats, guys.
Congratulations.
Good job. Well done.
Good job.
&gt;&gt; Thanks.
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; So Zova is a fitness
that helps people stay
and great HD videos that
And we loved it because
and in so many ways
and considered them deeply.
And it's really great
In fact, we like this app so
on the roadshow this fall --
and we used it as one
in our design sessions.
And we'd like to
So, TC?
&gt;&gt; Thanks again, John.
Zova is a fitness app
achievable, daily exercises.
Now this team here
of Apple technologies from day
of the app and HealthKit
to then Apple Watch support, and
But they don't just
They only deliver on
to each platform
as if it always meant
And today, we'd like to
So with Apple TV, they didn't
They took the Apple TV
about the whole medium of TV.
TV is a major part of our lives.
It's when we gather together to
Now workout apps don't have to
With the communal experiences
Zova had to think about the kind
This collection here called
up with your friend and
and get fit together.
But Zova didn't just stop
They also wanted to take full
As you will see me
as you would expect, very
And focusing on elements
Let's go into this workout here.
So, here, you get
of what this workout is about.
And also, if you have
these are video previews
of exactly what the
That way, you know what
But where the implementation
into its own is when you're
So let's try one of these.
Each workout starts with a
of exactly what the exercise is.
Now I've just pressed the
as you would expect because
when you're trying to exercise.
That's just the way it is.
When you resume the pause,
so that you can actually
of just jumping straight
But where it gets really
and holding onto the Pause
with a freeze frame so that
at the details on the screen --
perhaps the exact
Now this is possible and is
because Zova has implemented
Similarly, if I was
I can restart an
Or, if I was to swipe
you can see I can easily skip.
Now you may have noticed
to Apple Watch.
This is really neat.
What's happening here is
from my Watch.
And through HealthKit and
that onto the live
So that's my heartrate
Let's move along then.
At the end of each workout, you
log your feedback as
And this is a really fun
You can either give it a big
or if it's gone less well --
and in my case, I tend to
So there you go.
[ Laughter ]
We really like Zova's
for the lounge and living
of the features of
so that you have a true
and unique Apple TV
Built using Swift, Zova
Watch OS, and Apple TV.
Congratulations to
And back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, that's Zova.
The next winner this
by the Soulmen from Germany.
[ Applause ]
[ Music ]
So Ulysses is a powerful
of all kinds -- journalists,
And it's designed specifically
of the writing process.
And we picked it as a winner
because it's a tool
for writing without distraction.
The entire UI of the
and you're just working
And the execution of
It allows you to work
You can choose to start on
then move to iPhone,
And you get that
on any of those devices.
And to show this app to you, I'd
&gt;&gt; Thank you, John.
So Ulysses is a focused
and distraction-free
It has the power of
with flexible organization
Now it's a super clean writing
to help you through the task.
So the first thing, for example,
is I can highlight
That should look familiar.
We can also show
Now Ulysses is based
And what Markdown is --
it's a markup language
and special characters
So, for example, here you
of the Apple TV human
that navigation has
and that is a second-level
By the way, this tear-off menu
Now Ulysses also presents images
and vey distraction-free way.
Now Ulysses is really
For me, for example, I
I get creative after
If Dark Mode doesn't
there are customizable themes,
from the Ulysses User Community.
Now Markdown is an open
with a number of different
or you can create your own.
Both custom markdown definitions
and custom themes are all
OK. Now this is a modern,
So if you take a look all
that's my library column.
And in my library column,
that's where I manage
For example, here I have a
I also have filters.
Now a filter is sort
So here, for example, I'm
or the name "Ishmael".
And all of the occurrences
from the book "Moby Dick".
And I can also change the icon
to something a little
I can also do ad hoc searches.
So, for example, I know that
of the word "galleon"
And if I take a look
at the search base using
I can see that I just searched
most of those written
And that's thanks to their
and Grand Central Dispatch.
Okie dokie.
So let's go back here.
Let's kill this.
Let's go back to
All right.
Now Ulysses is
so it doesn't matter where
You can preview in a number
of different formats
It can even publish
But one of the things
that they've done is
to make your own CSS files
to style the preview
So, for example, here
and I happen to have
And I can apply that
And you can see how the
on an Apple website.
All right.
Now as John mentioned, Ulysses
eventually Mac OS I hope.
It implements Handoff.
It's available in 7 languages.
We love this app.
We use this app at Apple.
We're so happy and so proud
that you guys have created
So, congratulations.
Back to you, John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, as Michael said
As Michael said, Ulysses is
that takes advantage of iOS and
to deliver an optimized
on each of these platforms.
We talked about this new
and this is an app
of heading in that direction.
Congratulations.
All right, our last
that is incredibly
and incredibly accessible.
It is djay Pro by
[ Applause ]
You've been here before.
You've been here before, sir.
Good. Congratulations.
[ Music ]
All right, so djay Pro is one
of the first professional-grade
and video capabilities
And these guys already won an
but they have done
and they continue to innovate.
And they have consistently
with us every time
every time there's
and every time there's
Really impressive.
And we love this app because
for performance, for features,
for multi-device support,
And I'd like to ask Ryan
&gt;&gt; Hey. Thanks, John.
My name is Ryan Dour.
I'm an engineer on the
at Apple, but I'm also a deejay.
All of my life, I've
But during high school
I lost most of my
I've always deejayed with
because they offer a
However, with the rise
I was feeling pretty left out.
About a year ago, I got my
and this external deejay
into it, and it's been
However, djay Pro for iPad
to a whole new level, and I'd
So, over here, I have an
and this external mixer.
I'm going to go ahead and
So, here's the thing
The external deejay
as an extension of
And so I can use it
of a pretty cool performance.
Also, you're probably wondering
Not much. I pretty much can see
and some of the, you know,
from the deejay controller,
So knowing that, we're
to control this interface.
Let's go ahead and
OK, so the first thing
that I have access
to information I've
For example, the time.
How much time is
Let's find out.
That's perfect.
OK. So I'm the deejay, I'm
and now I have that
I also can use these
For example, if I touch it
So we hear it's at a
But if I slow it down
and I touch it again,
we can hear exactly how far
That's really cool.
I also can use these
For example, if I touch
but the second time.
Really cool stuff, right?
So between these effects
and all this accessible UI,
I can do a pretty
So I'd like to go ahead
to please take VoiceOver
that it's only available
Cool. Thank you very much.
And I'm going to
Here we go.
[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
So that's djay Pro
&gt;&gt; Ryan, you're the man.
&gt;&gt; I've got to tell you --
this is an incredible
They did not use UIKit
They didn't get any of their
Considering that,
of our accessibility APIs is
So I want to let everybody know,
and especially all the
out there, this app has
So I absolutely cannot
of you developers
Thank you so much, John!
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Good job.
[ Applause ]
Ryan, you're the man.
djay Pro -- a beautiful, fully
high-performance app
Congratulations, guys.
So those are our
two great student apps
and 10 other incredible apps.
10 apps that set the
Each of these apps has
They entertain in a new way.
They allow you to
They educate in a new way.
They solve real problems
And they open doors for
to do things they
And all of them are
and extremely well-executed
Now winners today get to
the Apple Design Award Trophy.
When you tap it,
like the cover of your laptop.
It's very cool.
Go check it out from one
So you get the coveted
as well as a prize
of almost everything that
[ Applause ]
And you get some
on the App Store
[ Applause ]
All right, we wanted to wrap up
It's always fun for me to do the
with this, to know
and to see your apps
of them to arrive on stage.
It's always fun to
But before we wrap up tonight,
about something else that we've
And it's a little bit apart
that we've given out so far, but
And it does tie into
and unique, and compelling.
So to talk about that, I'd like
Cofounder and CEO of Madefire, a
to join me here on stage.
Ben?
[ Applause ]
Thanks, John.
Great to be here.
So Madefire is all
and in particular, comics.
We love comics because they're
such a powerful storytelling
People learn to read
People escape into other
Most of all, comics are
for the visual world
We've been working closely with
like to share with you tonight.
As you may have seen earlier,
Apple today launched new
They're very different
that we're all used to, and
And after speaking with Apple
we collaborated to create --
[ Applause ]
Oh, yes! App Review
OK. Apple has put a lot of
and simplifying the
And this gave us a great
with different illustrators
and to develop five totally
Each section is a visual story.
And we really wanted
with the serious content
It's created a pretty
and something we hope
around these important
if you think you know
It's pretty useful.
The comic book will be
from the developer's site,
alongside the searchable
But you will get to take home
[ Applause ]
Oh, yes, hard to believe.
In a world of screens,
at Madefire is enable people
to turn their stories
As you can see, motion books
with motion, sound, and depth.
And we're thrilled to be
of the app review guidelines.
Here's a sneak peek.
[ Music ]
So, look out for the App Review
soon to an Apple
And you can get your
I hope you enjoy the read.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
Thanks, ben.
It's pretty fun.
A great way to end a
So let's wrap up here right now.
Congratulations, first of
such incredible work over
as you worked on these apps
Hats off to you.
You've put in just an enormous
and developing these apps,
for the entire community.
And thanks to you all
who are watching online.
We've got lots of people
and through the online stream
Thank you for joining us
We look forward to seeing
in this coming year, what you're
that maybe you saw this evening
to a new level with your app
and with your design, and
that you heard today through the
So we'd like to close.
Just before we close, I'd
to come back on stage.
And while they're doing that,
and have a great
[ Applause ]