[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Ladies and gentlemen,
on stage, Haben Girma.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
Thank for the introduction
My name is Haben Girma.
I work as an accessibility
teaching organizations
with accessibility in mind.
I'm deaf-blind.
Deaf-blindness encompasses
of vision and hearing loss.
I have a little bit of hearing,
I see maybe about 1% of what
By identifying as deaf-blind,
that I'm part of a community
through touch is equal in
through sight, sound,
Our world is incredibly diverse,
that celebrate that
that diversity, we all benefit.
So I identify as
to design non-visual access
to help maximize communication.
This is tricky for some people.
One of my best friends,
wasn't sure how to say hi.
She was sitting next to me,
in one of our classes
And she waved hi, but
And she voice hi, and
It was our first day of
and she wasn't thinking
She was thinking about
And after a while, during the
She did the most logical
She went onto Facebook and sent
I'm sitting right next to you.
Technology has facilitated
for a lot of people.
And when apps are designed
iMessages, mail, other
people with disabilities like
to connect and share
I saw that Facebook message my
out to her and we were
and I explained the various
Technology facilitates
when both parties are
in practicing inclusion.
I want to share a photo,
of the communication
In this photo I'm standing
from a digital Braille display.
Digital Braille, comes through
that pop up to form
And I read these letters
Braille is a tool,
I primarily use English Braille,
and I've seen Braille in
I was once on a ferry
and I remembered feeling a bit
of the signs were
So Braille is a tool and the
that produces this
Also in the photo, President
and he's typing on an
and what's being
to the digital Braille display.
I'm reading what's being typed
and this is a communication
Deaf individuals have been
for hundreds of years.
Communities around the world,
In the United States,
the dominant sign language
Which is heavily influenced
My brother is deaf-blind.
And when he communicates with
When he's signing I put
and feel what he is signing.
When he wants to listen to me,
and feel what I'm signing.
Tactile sign language is
that has developed,
by the deaf-blind community.
Another form is print on palm,
they could write in
and other forms of characters.
Humans are incredibly creative,
of us to connect and engage
Another form of communication
And dance is expressed
Some deaf individuals who are
dancers and will
by watching the other dancers.
Other individuals will watch the
by watching the fingers and
People are very creative
For me, dance is all
Salsa is like a kind
and people communicate
music, emotions,
Some of the signals
and the people I dance with
and switch those visual
Through dance we celebrate
Communities that celebrate
to be inclusive,
to make sure everyone can
So dance is one community
that practices inclusion.
When I join a community,
the first question people
you communicate?
The second question
have you heard of Helen Keller?
[Laughter]
Helen Keller was an
she lived from 1880 to 1968.
She advocated for
disability's rights,
She spent her whole life
of Helen reduce her
She succeeded despite
Disability never
disability is not something
The barriers that exist
And it's up to every single
to remove those barriers.
Helen was successful because
that chose to practice
She went to Radcliffe College,
and Radcliffe provided
And made sure she
They worked to ensure
Not every community
Harvard wouldn't admit Helen.
Back then Harvard
Helen's disability
her gender didn't hold her back,
that chose to deny
As another example, Helen's
to experience marriage.
Helen fell in love,
but her family prevented her
from marrying the
Helen's disability didn't
She wrote extensively
But her family, her community,
chose to create insurmountable
All the barriers that exist
Of members of society, we play a
and making sure that everyone
and has access to opportunities.
We've come a long way
More and more communities
and relationships.
Harvard eventually
to open its doors to women.
And now technology
for people to connect.
I often wonder, what would
what freedom would she have
to the world of apps
to people with disabilities?
One of the features
for developers, is
And VoiceOver is a
when an app is compatible
in speech or digital
I'm going to share a
that shows how VoiceOver works.
[ Applause ]
Apple has a variety of
VoiceOver is one
Another one, support
When you support Dynamic Type,
and need larger font sizes can
Another feature is Captioning.
Support for Captioning allows
of hearing, to access the
Support for Assistive
switch controls, switch
with limited mobility.
So these are some of the
for your apps to be accessible,
for people with disabilities.
But don't stop there, keep
of new ways for people to
Our goal is to have a
in the app store,
Right now if I need an app,
to shopping, I need
for an accessible app.
And sometimes, there isn't
Our goal is to have every app
and I mean every single
Several years ago, I went
and when I arrived in my hotel
in Beijing I did what I always
I explored and while
I discovered an unidentifiable
It felt a little like
but I've never seen
I was wondering,
[Laughter]
I was super curious to
but not curious enough to taste
So instead I got out my camera,
and texted it to a friend,
Is it safe to eat?
I learned that it
And I discovered I
Now imagine a lot
why would a camera app
Why would blind people
We take pictures for the
take pictures.
To capture moments, to share
Our goal is to make sure
Try not to make assumptions
with disabilities
Instead, strive for inclusion.
And after you strive for
here are a few things
It helps to plan for
It's much easier, it
If you plan for accessibility,
I'll give an example
Imagine someone builds
but realizes they forgot to put
of the building, and then
That's more time consuming
it would be much
for an elevator from the start.
Same principle applies
You save yourself resources
when you can have accessibility
And there are engineers
designers with disabilities,
to help you with the process.
There are all so many disability
and around the world, to
engage with us, from initial
Apple also has a
to help you with this process.
Their online tutorials,
accessibility guidelines
Tomorrow evening here, at WWDC,
we're going to have an
and join us.
I'll be there to
lots of accessibility
including developers who've
of making sure their
So these are resources
and will help you design
Accessibility benefits
but it also benefits you.
Accessibility has many
people with disabilities are
About 1 in 5 Americans
So when you design with
you get access to
more people can benefit
Another thing to keep in mind is
for everyone including
For example, when you
and you add alternative
more text is associated
And because of that, it's easier
through powerful
The videos from WWDC are
produce a transcript and
and find exactly where in the
This is an example
that benefits the
also benefits the
But the most important
Disability drives innovation.
When you think about new ways
new ways for people to connect,
you're going to find yourself
Throughout our history
innovation, that benefits
of the products we use today,
can be traced back
In 1808, an Italian inventor
of the first working
He wanted a solution
that didn't require vision.
That someone can do by touch.
Now Turri had a lover who was
to be able to write
So he designed the first, one
as a possible solution.
And now today, around the world,
lots of people who use
both sighted typists
More recently, one of the
Vinton Cerf, is hard of hearing,
and his wife is also hearing
for a solution that would
without using hearing.
And to communicate from afar.
Disability drives innovation,
not just by non-disabled
with disabilities as well.
Vinton ended up developing one
and electronic mail
to communicate from afar.
And now, just about
and sends text messages.
Solutions designed with
up benefiting the
And central to innovation
I'm going to share a
And a jungle gym
There are multiple ways to get
or wrong way to climb,
or wrong path to take.
When I'm climbing I
This is about, 20 feet tall,
it's a pyramid shaped
And when I climb, I reach out,
until I find the solution.
There are many, many, many
by touch, by sight, by sound.
You could have someone
voice guidance.
If you have a mobility
you can design an
Exploration values
and the more open you
in multiple perspectives,
to design, develop
One area where we rarely
And haptics is the concept
of communication
I have an Apple Watch,
and it taps my wrist twice
And that's a form
of communication based
I recently went surfing,
and that whole experience
Here's a photo of
and a tandem board
I'm standing near the front
and in the back is
Matt Allen from Maui
He was using tactile signals.
I could also feel the power
through the surf board.
The wind, the sun,
Skin is our largest organ,
yet we've barely explored
There's a lot of potential
of haptics and technology.
Keep exploring, keep
that are going to increase
And as you go through this,
engage with the disability
plan for accessibility from
that it's going to benefit you.
Thanks for listening everyone.
[ Applause ]