[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Ladies and gentlemen,
Senior Vice President,
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, well I'm
because this is not the type
I'm not a developer,
I'm head of Wildlife
at World Wildlife Fund, which is
globally to protect wild
and to reduce the human
WWF has been around
We work in more than 100
than 6 million members
I'm usually talking to audiences
or policymakers like congress
But one of the things
about today is how we're
to help save the planet and
And it may surprise you to hear
and new ways we're using
But first, I want to
at the state of the planet.
We don't hear a lot of good
we are in fact facing
of the world's most
But we're also on the cusp of
and I'm going to tell you
But first, here's the backdrop.
Our living planet
that in the last 40 years
of the world's vertebrate
That's mammals, birds,
It's affecting many of our most
and tigers and elephants.
Why is this happening?
The reason it's happening
and degradation and
Habitat loss is driven mainly
to growing human numbers,
and for commodities like
Also developing infrastructure
and generally growing
And climate change is only
by creating increased
such as more intense
which is impacting
including wildlife migrations
and seasonal breeding
Now simultaneously a
in wildlife products
of our most endangered species.
This is a trade that is valued
in wildlife and wildlife
Which makes it one of the
in the world amazingly
and human trafficking.
And it's taking its toll on some
For example, a surge
in recent years has led
as 30,000 elephants a year.
Are traded for their ivory,
in Asia, but also here
We are a major wildlife
which surprises a lot of people.
By the time I finish this talk
killed illegally
Now surge in poaching of rhinos
over the last decade from
to over 1200 killed last year.
This is driven by
but also in China where rhino
for cancer and unbelievably
And this latter use is a
in any kind of traditional
of these uses has any
And in the last century
of the world's wild
as few as 3900 in the wild.
Tigers are killed illegally for
and other body parts,
in modern-day health tonics.
So it's a pretty grim
and people often ask me well
discouraged all the
with these horrifying statistics
in the wrong direction.
And my response is well yes,
for sure, but we're making
some of these trends are
And that is because I believe
I'm going to talk to you today
the power of technology, and
Now I know these
that this conference is
but what I want to
into a wildlife conservation
So let me tell you what's
Seven years ago tiger numbers
When we look back now we realize
if tigers were going to survive.
So we came up with the idea
on tiger conservation.
That had never been done before
and we wondered if anyone
With all the pressing
who would care about tigers.
Well, we found an
in President Vladimir Putin
out has a soft spot for
Well, we convinced him
to a unique gathering
Russia to chart a path
We put forward an ambitious
of tigers in the wild
which is the next
We knew what it would
it's a pretty simple formula.
They need healthy habitat,
and they need to be
We also knew that the main
political will.
Well fortunately, the leaders
and these are the countries
in the wild agreed
to a bold new recovery
This was the first of its kind
We call this TX2, Doubling
And this year marks the
And guess what, governments
to implement the recovery plan
and tiger numbers are
For example, tigers have been
as breeding in the wild
And tigers have been recorded
in places they've
or documented before, which
and Myanmar, which is where
and her cubs was
For the first time in a century
beginning to tick
If we are successful
of doubling tigers it
of the greatest achievements
And personally, I
because I've seen this
So 20 years ago, gosh that
of you were born.
Twenty years ago
in India called Ranthambore,
It was a bad time for tigers,
poaching had hit many areas
which was once a tiger
about 10 tigers left
The park was suffering
poor enforcement,
We saw almost no
that place thinking well there's
survive with all the pressing
with how can park
Well this tiger named
about the time I
We didn't see her then,
she did manage to survive.
In fact, she went
of Ranthambore's
Well after I left Ranthambore
in the park, but
The Indian government started
more park rangers,
and things started
And amazingly, tigers
And Machali not only
on to have 11 cubs with
one of them appropriately
because he was the
And then those cubs went
And so Machali's dynasty
and many of them are
Well I had the chance to go back
to Ranthambore just a few months
and I witnessed an
The park was teeming with life
and Ranthambore's tiger
That's a number that actually
of the park, so much so that the
some tigers and relocating them
and is planning a set of new
And that's unprecedented
in recent tiger conservation
So I believe we can double the
if governments
and conservationists help
Perhaps the boldest idea
in tiger conservation today is
where they've become extinct.
And this is what Cambodia
This photo was taken in 2007
and it's the last known
None have been seen there since.
Well just three months ago the
plan to bring tigers back to
of the country, which is a
there's still a lot of
it's under pretty
but there's enough
And we are working with
in several ways to help prepare
for this possible
We're working to help bring
such as the sambar
which is a type of wild cattle.
These are important species
It happens to also be that
with local people and a lot
out because of poor enforcement.
So we're helping to
and also helping the government
in this area because tigers and
without good enforcement.
And we're also working to
for the prospect of
of the world's great predators.
Interestingly, in our
as human populations grow
with people.
It's happening all over the
in Cambodia, there's
for bringing tigers
Because tigers have
of Cambodian culture
Well if all goes well the
to get eight tigers from India
It's a long and complicated
without controversy or risk,
of the most exciting
in wildlife conservation.
Well I'm happy to say that
in parts of their range.
Whole new populations
by physically moving these
to help set up safe
where their numbers can grow.
And I want to show you a video
out in South Africa where
to physically move these
and lift them up by
on a journey that would
if not days by road.
&gt;&gt; Black rhino and
under huge pressure.
We really have to
If they don't have champions
[ Music ]
And this is the kindest
of moving a rhino from
&gt;&gt; It's a big operation, it's a
in a really short time.
&gt;&gt; There are no roads, there
You know, most of these
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; The WWF Black Rhino
to boost the growth rate
of the black rhino
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; It's become a passion, it's
and yeah, it gets
&gt;&gt; There hasn't really been
with 20 black rhino
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; It's a bit sad to let them
The field rangers
&gt;&gt; Every single one is
it's a wild animal that's
&gt;&gt; We're really glad for them
we know that it's critical
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Over 1400 kilometer journey,
it's the longest journey
&gt;&gt; The black rhino coming back
in this area it was
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; This has been a very
because we've got Eastern Cape
we've got [inaudible]
&gt;&gt; And I think it
because all the different
&gt;&gt; It's a huge thing too to see
to this particular area here.
[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; There's no doubt that
difference to rhino
[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So in the midst of a poaching
of the country whole new rhino
through this extraordinary
for the species in South Africa.
Well another country that is
is Nepal where it has
of greater one horned
from 400 animals about 10 years
to get 800 by 2020 and
Because of the dense forest
in the more traditional method
and the latest rhino
in Nepal in March of this year
from one national
And I want to show you a video
of a rhino getting
See it, has a bit a hard time
Finally out.
It gives you a sense
of how powerful these
Well there's wonderful evidence
that these recently translocated
Just three weeks ago
to this adorable little
to know his new home
Well, sometimes big ideas
of technology and we are
in our work, on the ground, in
crowdsourcing to the
and all the sensors
There's no question that
and accelerate many of our
But just for a larger context,
in India, the human
about a billion people.
India is projected to add
to its population by 2050.
In Africa, the human
by the year 2015 and double
Technology needs to
to this crowded new world.
So let me show you some of
in our work from new tracking
to detecting and deterring
and drones.
So our work tracking
We used to rely on pugmarks
which are animal droppings
and that was very laborious
So camera traps have become
of monitoring animals
Camera traps are cameras set
by a motion sensor when an
And these are especially useful
at night like lions or species
like a brown hyena where
by their markings and
In fact, the latest tiger
and thousands of
that are giving us the latest
And as cameras become lighter
and smaller they are
into what the world looks like
And videos like this help
like turtles are
which helps us understand
They are also great tools
This video has been viewed
it's gone viral and it's been a
helped connect people to
And innovative uses of GPS
to understand where wildlife
and their seasonal migrations.
One of our scientists made
by putting special
with the latest GPS
of eight zebras he discovered
of northern Namibia to
about 200 miles south.
And this turns out to be the
migration in Africa and
that as recently as just
about the longest land
and this technology
So here's an animation of the
of about six or seven months.
Each colored dot represents
They start in this
and they start moving south
You'll see the dark green
season is coming.
They move south pretty
where it turns out they eat a
wet season.
They hang out there for about
of start meandering
to the place from
It takes them a little
but they finally end up back
to their preferred
And the importance of this
to advocate for protecting
through its whole
and thus preserve the
in this particular area.
Well, one of the most
that I'm most excited
of thermal imaging cameras to
Thermal cameras are also known
as infrared cameras
from a person or an animal.
And in a pilot we're undertaking
in Africa we're pairing
that is able to distinguish
So when a person crosses
or inappropriately the software
to enforcement authorities.
Since these cameras were
they're put on poles actually
of 2 miles, up to 2
And since they were installed
intruders in this
and one suspected
And let me show you the
or suspected poacher
You see him walking
which is the border of the park.
He's looking for a way to get
Finally finds a way, jumps
And that red box around him
the alert that's sent
to enforcement authorities
So if this technology
if this pilot works we hope
where we think it could
in perimeter security
Well remember I said earlier we
footprints as a way to track
Well we're still
but these days we're
Through advances in DNA
of information can be drawn
in the snow, including
and incredibly what it
So as we're working
to refine this technology
But this has the potential
to revolutionize
in their natural habitats and
it could be useful for species
in very extreme environments,
to study and very
So this is exciting as well.
Well, we've been hearing
in so many different ways
of our work in conservation.
There's been a lot of
The challenge we have with
to develop civilian level
of the similar capabilities
but at a fraction of the cost,
otherwise they're just
by park managers and
So we're experimenting
of downscaled systems of
and for different needs.
For example, we're using
of prairie dogs here
Prairie dogs happen to
for the most endangered
which is the black-footed
So by knowing where prairie dogs
or have the potential to live
so we can thus help better
for them.
We're also using drones to
and address poaching in Africa.
Well the challenge
that they are probably
as reactionary tools or
when another sensor is set
that the drones can
where potential illegal
In fact, drones because
of the videos is not as broad
We are now working to
so that more can be
We're also trying to
like with the thermal cameras
from animals and thus, send
So we're continuing to
and they certainly have a
if we can get the
We're also continuing to think
of our challenges and I wanted
in their early stages
These are wire snares, snares
to wildlife everywhere.
Literally millions and
around the world and they
for wildlife.
They're easy, unfortunately
and relatively easy to use
to detect them better, so
In fact, in one park in
to give you a sense of
Malawi is a country in Africa,
over an eight month period
that were in this
So what we're doing is we're
of radar to try to map where
of metal we can use
Potentially positioned
so that rangers can
and go out and collect them.
And if we can do this
in a cost-effective way it could
Snares typically grab
and inflict a lot of injury.
Sometimes it'll grab them
fortunately the zebra
but often species do not.
We're also working on a gunshot
where poaching is happening.
And we got the idea from
which we actually read about
ShotSpotter is used by police
where gunshots are happening
that are placed on buildings.
We called up the Washington DC
down to see ShotSpotter
We sat in the command center
as pins dropped in real time
as shots were going
It was quite a surreal
The challenge we have on
where do you put
in a vast national park?
No buildings there,
Well the idea that we're working
on a special collar
that could help rangers
where maybe an animal
and if it's only wounded they
of saving it than
and it could prevent
Also it could be
by simply seeing this device
on the elephant poachers
This could be a great
but right now the costs
limiting factor.
Well none of this really
people on the ground,
the enforcement officers,
who are really critical
In fact, it's often the people
who are its greatest guardians.
I mentioned earlier
and its successful rhino
A lot of that success is due
of communities and conservation.
Nepal has achieved
In fact, in the last six
Nepal has had zero
This is an amazing
when rhino poaching
big rates everywhere
The reason for this
of local communities, big
but particularly communities
that share critical tips
and help track poaching
and illegal trading
And in fact, one notorious rhino
in Nepal after community
and they banded together
And he's now serving
which is a long sentence
In the country of Namibia all
across Africa have been bucked
to the involvement of
Namibia has actually seen
of its wildlife populations
and its elephant numbers have in
At a time when unfortunately
in most other countries
And this is because communities
in conservation as the
of the wildlife there.
Legislation in Namibia
and the responsibility to
under their jurisdictions.
It also allows them
from the revenues associated
with wildlife related
This gives them a direct
in conservation and that
This is truly a model program
and world development
a lot of countries
to learn how they're doing it
of these same practices.
While communities of
to address the needed
of the most important
That letter that was up
it is a letter in
It also happens to
for the word elephant in Thai.
We asked people in
to be the world's second
to help raise awareness
by trying to imagine a
By symbolically erasing
from their names.
This campaign went viral, over
They posted pictures
without the letter Chor
on Twitter, on Instagram.
And result was huge public
to crack down on the
and to reform its ivory
It was a big success.
Just two weeks ago here in
government announced a new
to ban almost all
of ivory in the United States.
Something we've been working
This regulation was
by huge public outpouring
In fact, WWF was
than a million signatures
which is the most the
from an organization
And the significance of
because the U.S. is one of
in the world, it has also
in China, the world's
In fact, one of our big
joint commitment by President
to take action against
and we're beginning to see
And I'm really happy to share
that just a week
at the U.S. China strategic
in Beijing that they
of this year a timetable
down their domestic
This is a huge deal
If China makes good
and we will do everything we
it will be a game changer
[ Applause ]
So inspiring people to
in conservation issues
of our strategy at WWF.
And new technologies
in ways we never
We first entered the app world,
with the launch of WWF Together.
On the iPad, it's now
It's an app that
from around the world through
the art of origami
that use embedded Apple
and the accelerometer.
[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
We were thrilled to be
to accept the Apple
Our work in close collaboration
with Apple actually started last
in China to protect up to
That important work led to an
of millions of people through
ever called Apps for Earth.
Hopefully many of you saw
of you participated in
in this ten-day promotion
Twenty four developers
with conservation messages
of conserving natural
and finding solutions to some
of the most pressing
People around the world could
down greedy pigs who were
Or in Star Wars Galaxy of
to help save the
Or challenge friends and
to test their knowledge of some
of our time, such
We reached millions of people
with critical conservation
And we also raised critical
In fact, I am super excited to
that Apps for Earth raised over
[ Applause ]
This is unprecedented, it's
and this critical funding
of the initiatives you've heard
in the wild and protecting
It's a huge deal.
We are so grateful to everyone
to Apple who made
If we can do this kind of thing
can do if we continue to
in support of conservation.
We're making important progress,
To save everything we need
of critical challenges that the
There's no question that
to play in our vision
We need your help to
the lack of connectivity
where conservation happens,
of the global system for
And we need your help to develop
with longer battery times so
in a protected area, both
and transmit data in real time
to conservation scientists
And as the technology
of things develops
to deploy it in conservation.
And we need your help to
to reach people everywhere
about conservation to get
Nature and all the wonderful
of it is powerful and resilient
if given half a chance.
Technology can help do that,
when we share ideas
And we at WWF look
Thank you.
[ Applause ]