[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. Good morning.
Good afternoon.
My name is Ajit, and I used
from here on the East Bay.
I was an electrical engineer in
And in 2007, I did
I moved back to India from
to be an entrepreneur.
I'm an inventor at heart,
of different fields, a
But eventually, I
on that was rather
I decided I wanted to work
I wanted to make assistive
who had difficulties with
Now the way I got into
when I went back
there was a friend of mine.
And she runs a school in the
of India, and it's
Now, Vidya Sagar is
It's a school for kids with
cerebral palsy, autism.
And when my friend found
for instant problems
that I visit the school and
if there was anything
So I went to Vidya
and I met some of the kids.
Now that visit was
You know, I saw that these
they were smart, they
they were enthusiastic,
But the reason that they weren't
in a regular school was
And that was that they had
Now, if you look at kids with
that they can't communicate is
that process muscle
so they have difficulty
of the different muscles that
But with autism, it's actually
The first kid that I met
at Vidya Sagar during
His name was Santhosh.
Now I was sitting across
and Santhosh had a lot of
that we take for granted.
For example, he found it really
He would find it really hard
out what kind of emotion I
The other thing that
of difficulty with was language.
Because language is
You know, it's very abstract.
It's not something that
but it's really one of the most
We have all of these
all of these different words,
that we assign meaning
For example, if I
the word "dog" doesn't
with the animal the way
the way that I write the word.
You would never be
out that it actually refers
It's very much abstract sound
you know, a convention
And that's why someone
of difficulty with this.
Our brains have the ability to,
of thousands of these
But kids with autism find
for their comfort.
So my friend who runs
she wanted me to look at
and she wanted me to see if I
that could give a voice
I thought that was a fascinating
from a technology perspective.
I also thought it was a huge
because there were kids all
over the world, who
My starting point to
of assistive technologies
that had actually been
and the 80s and was being
What people working with kids
that many of them have extremely
So they have a lot of
of language, but they
with the concreteness
They're able to remember
They're able to recall pictures
to do with sound
Even in India, it wasn't
with books like these.
Picture books, picture charts,
that they would wear
And if they wanted to ask for a
to request for water for
to a picture of water in their
to other people that
At that time in [inaudible]
this concept was being used
of these devices that
And this is an example
This is a fairly -- you know,
They were pretty bulky.
They ran a special
They were often custom-built,
and they were paid
So they were pretty expensive.
This device, for example,
between $5,000 to $10,000.
And that price point is
for even the most affluent
But what was happening
for example, the
And that was the beginning
Right? So it was possible
to actually buy electronic
which were being
in these touchscreen
And to assemble them together
for a fraction of the price just
for a few hundred
to create these things
So that became my strategy
I thought I would
that they could use on top of
from these smartphone
and we would then use that
to communicate.
So I took this strategy and
of creating assistive
And I quickly came up with
You know, those of you who've
for a specific class of people,
of coming up with these
pretty standard.
You go to the field, you talk to
you see what they have to say.
You ideate to come up
and you build these
to the people whose
And then you get their feedback,
of different times
that works beautifully.
You know, that process
In my particular case though,
Because the very reason that we
because these children
So it was a chicken-and-egg
You know, we were
and ask them what they thought
about the prototypes
But what would actually
that the kids would use the
two minutes, and then
And we had no idea -- you
Were they bored?
You know, did they not like it?
Did they think it was
Were we solving the
So that was a frustration
we lived with for
You know, every developer --
I'm sure every one of you here
that's very close to your
You know, in my particular case,
His name was Rohit.
Rohit was one of the
out every single one
And one day, he came
where we were trying
And I could see --
I could see the determination
He was going to communicate
He was completely -- he had
as he walked into the room.
And, you know, I gave
And I sat there, waiting
And Rohit actually took
Very painstakingly,
he tapped on various buttons.
And then the device
[ Laugther ]
[ Applause ]
It's not exactly the kind
up on your website, but
Believe me.
Because from that point onwards,
You know, we could convince him
to tell us exactly
exactly what he didn't like.
And within a few months,
that met Rohit's expectations.
And that was the device that
We called it Avaz.
Avaz is the Hindi
It also means similar things
Let me show you the device
So this was the first prototype
the first product that
It's the big, bulky,
and it's stuffed
You know, you could
You could put it on a desk.
Along with its wheelchair mount,
so it was pretty heavy.
It had about an hour
You know, there was a really
on the day that we were
We kept it on a desk, and a
down with his hand.
And it fell down on the
of the tiles on the floor.
[ Laugther ]
That was how heavy it was.
You know, as a concession to
we replaced the case
So that's the final version
This device costs about $600
And at that price, it was
of similar dedicated
in the market at that time.
And it was a breakthrough
It was the very first time that
for speech-assistive
And almost immediately
we started getting orders
You know, every special
and they wanted to know how they
and how they could use it.
But Avaz was still a
I mean, it's meant for the
that have these particular
So we had this -- you know,
in these small volumes
So even though the
even though we got
and even though this was
that we were intending
the more devices
the more money we were losing
so much money in creating these
You know, we were
out how we could make
And then in 2010, the
Steve Jobs announced the iPad.
And that was the start
But it also was a revolution
because we saw this as a
out of this hardware corner
and being able to make
making this application
to make the devices to do that.
So, in 2010, my team
and I started learning
And in 2011, we launched the
Now the core functionality
of Avaz actually remains
compared to the first version
that we launched
And let me show you a
So this is Avaz.
And you can see that
of different pictures.
So there's pictures in here,
of these different categories.
So there are literally thousands
And a parent, or a teacher,
and add words from the
from the child's life as well.
And the way that Avaz
with a disability
A child would be able to recall
And every time they
&gt;&gt; I
&gt;&gt; It will speak that out.
And they would be able to
&gt;&gt; Feel
&gt;&gt; This way, and they could go
&gt;&gt; Describe feelings.
&gt;&gt; And they could pick
&gt;&gt; Excited
&gt;&gt; To be able to
&gt;&gt; I feel excited.
&gt;&gt; And then the app
So that's Avaz -- essentially,
with a picture vocabulary that
So Avaz was literally
for kids with disabilities.
You know, when we put Avaz
it was immediately
in many different ways.
For this kid, Rohit,
to build Avaz, he
You know, he grew to be
so effectively that that same
he went on to use Avaz to write
and to go on to college.
You know, the media all over
of this kid who'd
with an assistive-technology
And not just this kid.
You know, they started
over the country about who kids
And even to this day, I think
around these disabilities
People started concentrating
on what these children could
of these children and
So that's one of the things that
My personal favorite --
[ Applause ]
My personal favorite anecdote
about Avaz users is actually
in the school where
in the school of Vidya Sagar.
You know, the children at Vidya
up this play for the parents
and for the well-wishers
And it just so happens
it was almost a convention that
the most important roles,
who could speak -- I
And the presence
of the nonverbal children was
The year we put out Avaz,
the principal made this
He said, "This year, all of the
who can't speak,
to deliver their
You know, I was sitting in
that that play was going on.
You know, I was extensively
But really, the principal
up on the stage and fix things
[ Laughter ]
But I was sitting in the
And the atmosphere
It was electric.
You know, I could see how much
delivering their dialogues and
all of their actions
And I turn back and I looked at
and they had tears
You know, this was
that these kids were
in this quintessential
of being a part of
And at that moment, I think it
about how transformational
in the lives of these kids.
[ Applause ]
Another really important
of Avaz happened a little
We got a call -- you know,
she got a call from a
You know, so this
And this call was actually --
from most of the
you know, for customer support.
This lady had bought
And, you know, she wanted
to know a bunch of
You know, she wanted to know
for whether this device
and she wanted to know how
She wanted to know how to
She wanted to know how
you know, over the months.
She essentially wanted
to implement the
Now this is actually a pretty
Because in most installations
a speech therapist would be
with the kid in order to
So the speech therapist
with the kid maybe once a week,
they would do all of
And so we asked this lady,
"Why don't you ask your speech
You know, that person is
to give you an answer to
On that day, I found
out something very
This lady's son didn't
In fact, the closest
to that lady was 300 miles away.
If she had to find a speech
she'd have to get on a
and go to a speech
In fact, I'll tell you this.
In the entire country of India,
the country of 1.3
there are 1,800 speech
You could take all of the
and you could put
and you could fill this room
of speech therapists
So this was a mind-blowing
This was really an
And what we had to do eventually
Avaz, and we had to build this
So it's almost like a
And what that sub-app did --
it was a pretty new
What that sub-app did was
to be a therapist
That was the only way that we
You know, as a startup,
we couldn't train the 5 million
But this was actually more
than even Avaz itself because
for the child, we were actually
for these children to get
and from the people that these
to -- to their parents.
So this happened, you
after we brought Avaz out.
And shortly after
from the President of India.
I had less facial
[ Laughter ]
But even more rewarding
you know, after five
this year, at long last, one of
to buy iPads, install Avaz on
to every school that they
[ Applause ]
This is the very first time
that the Indian government has
for kids with speech
the very first time that the
in this stuff.
And in fact, the Apple guy
the guy at Apple that was
of these devices, he told me
that this was the
of iPads in India.
And it's
for an assistive-technology
How cool is that?
For an assistive-technology
[ Applause ]
Today, there are
around the world whose lives
Avaz is an artificial voice
for 30,000 children
You know, at these
we could see some very
in the way that Avaz was used.
And let me talk to
about how Avaz was being
What Avaz did very
to help kids have this
So instead of having to speak
to remember how they sounded,
they could use pictures
So, for example, if a kid wanted
and they wanted something to
and find the word
If they wanted to say that they
for example, they
and find the word "toilet".
If they were eating something
and they found the food
into the app and they
and they could say that.
The problem happened when
with more than one word.
So, for example, if a kid
it was quite common that
"water" first and then they
And they would do
They would do it
But they were doing
as they were doing it right.
Or, for example, if they wanted
they would just pick
and they would pick
You know, they weren't really
You see, Avaz was very
down this symbolism of words
of pictures into that.
But this is actually a different
This is a symbolism of grammar.
And grammar is something
and there are the
And those rules of
that they're even very hard
to explain and to understand.
You know? For example, if
"I want to eat,"
of the word "to"
You know, if you asked me,
It's just a word that's there
because it's ungrammatical
[ Laughter ]
If you take these sentences,
"He broke the window,"
these two sentences are
But the object that's
Right? The window is the
Why is it that it appears on one
and on the other side of
Or if you take this sentence,
of this is obviously, "I ate."
But if you negate this sentence,
why is it wrong to
Right? So there are these
There are these things
of which word presents
There are these meta-rules
And this was actually
We went out behind the
of giving communication,
equal communication to
And we knew that our mission
underfulfilled if we were
without giving them the
and to put these words together.
The problem was that,
there was actually
very little theory behind
with autism grammar,
to put words together.
We trawled through all of
We went to all of the
But very little insights
The insight that kind of
in our head quite consistently
who lived 2,500 years ago.
He was an Indian philosopher.
I don't know if he
[ Laughter ]
The Indian government put out
He has the unfortunate
with a kind of sandwich.
It's called Panini.
[ Laughter ]
But Panini lived in -- it didn't
[ Laugther ]
Panini lived around 500 BC.
And Panini did something
which is unprecedented
He took a language, the
and he created a concise,
of rules -- 4,000 rules -- that
OK, so he had this set of 4,000
of course still relevant today.
But with these 4,000 rules, if
any sentence that you
to be grammatically-correct
And conversely, any
in Sanskrit, any sentence, any
any grammatically-correct
with these 4,000 rules.
It was almost like he had
to generate Sanskrit.
So that codification of a
that was absolutely beautiful.
It was phenomenal.
But that codification of
that maybe this is an
Maybe we can codify the
into a computer in some
that to give kids with
But even though we
the other missing component
How could we get kids to
And the answer to that really
in a school for kids with autism
with -- I happened to
where there was this little
and there were her teachers.
And this girl, you
and she was almost
But once in a while,
And that's what happened
She jumped up and she
And there was no
She just finished
so her teacher thought
to talk about her lunch.
So they tried to get
about her lunch on Avaz.
But it was very clear
that was not what she
So we were all standing
out what she meant
And then her mother started
So her mother said,
Eat lunch?
Eat breakfast?
Eat snacks?"
And then the girl took out her
and she pointed to
And then her mother
You eat? Someone else eats?"
You know? And then she
And then her mother
Eat now? Eat later?"
And it turned out that
to eat ice cream on her
Now it's not often that
when the lightbulb
But in this particular case,
like it happened yesterday.
Because what struck me was
that realization that this
to communicate what she
I mean, this girl could not put
She could not put multiple words
She could not select
She did not know what
She did not know the way in
It's almost as if her mother had
out what the meaning was
So this was the other
You know, and I took this idea
that we could really represent
if we joined words together
And I combined that with
from my study of Panini and all
and the resource in
over the last few years.
And I put that together
It took me three years to
I started in 2012.
It was in 2015 that the
And in 2016, we put
this year, just a
It's called FreeSpeech.
And let me show you a quick
to you how we solved
OK, so this is the
And you can see that it
that Avaz has pictures.
In fact, if I tap on the
on the bottom-left, it has all
But unlike Avaz, when
in FreeSpeech, you
at the beginning
In fact, you can start
So, for example, supposing
and I drop it here
Here's the interesting part.
&gt;&gt; Take
&gt;&gt; The app actually gives you
of questions around the word
so that you can add more words
It's very similar to what
For example, if I drag
and I put it into
&gt;&gt; The teacher takes.
&gt;&gt; It automatically
with that specific meaning.
It says, "The teacher takes."
I can take the word "book", and
it will say, "The
And if I take the word "school"
"to", it will say, "The teacher
Let me show you a slightly
So, supposing we pick the
that in here, it pops up
And I can take the word "parent"
If I put into "want",
it will say, "Want the parent."
But if I took that from that
into the "who", it will
And you see that every
it actually gives you
So more questions pop up.
So you can see that
which is next to "parent".
So if I tap that, it will
"Whose parent wants?"
And then I can drag the
and drop that in here.
It will say, "Her parent wants."
If I tap this little button on
I can convert that
So I can make it,
If I add the word "see",
"Her parents want to see."
And I can drag the word
"Her parents want to see you."
In fact, I can do even more
I can say that all of
And I don't have to use the
All I can do is I
at the bottom that says Past.
It will say, "Her parents
And I can negate that.
So if I press the Not button
"Her parents didn't
I can make a question out of it.
&gt;&gt; Didn't her parents
&gt;&gt; Or I can make even more
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Why didn't her
Thank you.
So that's how FreeSpeech works.
And FreeSpeech is pretty amazing
because I think it's
that someone has actually come
That's what the app
I mean, you have all of
and the app is putting
Now why is that important
The best way to kind of explain
to a different disability.
I'm sure many of you here
Some of you may have
with it when you were kids.
Kids with dyslexia have a lot
You know, English
I have difficulty
But if you give a kid
and you ask them to type,
magically their disability
Why? Because of spell check.
Because of autocorrect.
So a kid with dyslexia who
to communicate, is able to type
though they have
Avaz does exactly that for kids
who have a language
It plays to their strengths.
They're able to take
out pictures from the tablet,
in different configurations.
But every time they do that,
the algorithm is automatically
sentence and is speaking
Now, we did trials for about
FreeSpeech out on the market.
And the results with kids
with autism were dramatic
There were kids who were
or they were communicating
And suddenly, in minutes --
literally minutes after they
they were constructing these
In fact, there was this
I want to show you
This kid was in -- you know,
single words to communicate.
And you can see that he's not
fluently, but he's actually --
FreeSpeech is teaching
Let's look at the video.
&gt;&gt; Eat want.
&gt;&gt; So, the kid is
&gt;&gt; Drag.
&gt;&gt; Eat.
&gt;&gt; He eats.
More words.
Food and drink.
Meal.
&gt;&gt; Meal.
[Inaudible]
More words.
Press meal.
Press drag.
&gt;&gt; He eats lunch.
&gt;&gt; He ate lunch.
&gt;&gt; Did he eat lunch?
&gt;&gt; Good job!
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; This is pretty incredible.
You know, this kid was in --
this is a kid in
And this kid's speech
he was completely
In fact, his therapist
You know, before Lucas
he was a linguist.
And so he sent this video to us.
And to say he was blown
because the same day that I
from Lucas asking me if he could
[ Laughter ]
And that's how Lucas
in speech therapy in autism.
In fact, when we put
Lucas also had a
because Lucas had this
And this other kid had a --
but he was facing a very
This other kid that was
on Lucas' caseload,
He came from a bilingual
bilingual, English and Spanish.
So, at school, he would
All of his teachers would
But when he went back home, his
and all of his neighbors, they
Now this is a challenge that
with for many, many years.
You know, devices like Avaz,
They do exist in
But the problem of how do
who speaks two different
challenge for kids with autism
and for the therapists
So, let me give you a short demo
Let me go back into
to you what the issue is.
So, this is Avaz, right?
So we looked at the
to create a very quick sentence.
I'm going to say, "I want
And let's say, "I
Right? So I pick out these
And so let's say that a kid
"I want to go home,"
Now there is a Spanish
so let me switch into
So -- yeah.
How many Spanish
OK. I don't know Spanish at all.
I know zero Spanish.
But, you know, I'm going
to create a Spanish sentence
So, let's see.
So I have the picture
I can recognize that.
That's here.
And then I have "want".
And this looks like the
And this is "go".
And so there's places in here.
And this is "home".
Is that the right
If I went to Mexico and if I
at me because this is
You see, I've actually
of picking the right
the words "I", "want", "go".
All of these are correct.
But in Spanish, the way that the
For example, the word "querer"
you actually have to inflect
when you use it for
And similarly, you
in Spanish the same way that
You'd actually put that
"casa" to say "tu home".
So the problem here is
between two different languages,
the interface actually
And you can see that, right?
The Avaz interface
between the two languages.
But the user experience is
because kids have to learn
to be able to construct
and to be able to
So this was a problem that
but really everyone
with kids with disabilities.
Essentially, the child had to
of using the same app for them
So the idea that kind of
"Can we use FreeSpeech
FreeSpeech is essentially,
a representation of meaning.
Right? So the way that you
the way that you
they're essentially
that you're trying to say.
And the app is putting
So can we use that to be able to
you know, even if they
So I'm going to go
and there's a Spanish
And you can see that,
the interface completely
And all the words
The labels are in
And when I drag a word
all of the interface elements
The questions are in Spanish,
But here's the interesting part.
When I start putting words in,
&gt;&gt; I want.
&gt;&gt; It actually gives me an
So I can say -- so if I want to
I can take the same words
&gt;&gt; I want to go.
&gt;&gt; And I can put that in here.
And I'm following exactly
&gt;&gt; I want to go home.
&gt;&gt; But I'm creating a
You know, the --
[ Applause ]
So we put this out, you
and we're already getting
who found this quite useful, not
with a disability, but in a
for ELL -- for English
and kids who are in
who are entering the
without knowing English.
There are teachers who
if they can do this with those
So could you use FreeSpeech
Or, for that matter,
to teach anyone a new language?
Let me show you something else.
You know, I'm going to go into
to go back into the Settings
How many Chinese-speakers
Oh, OK. All right.
Well, typically when
I try to pick a language that
[ Laugther ]
Unfortunately, WWDC is a
for that trick to work for us.
I'll just keep my
You can see that the
to Chinese now the
to Spanish the last
But there's something very
to happen now.
So I'm going to take words out.
So let's pick the word
Can you see what's happening?
It's actually creating
It's actually creating a
but in English and in Chinese.
And I can do all of the things
For example, I can say,
I can say, "It didn't happen."
And that's how you can
in a completely different
FreeSpeech interface.
[ Applause ]
Could you use this
Or, vice versa, can
to learn English?
That's an experiment
I was in China in May.
And I went to China and I tried
in China to start
to learn English instead.
And I want to show
of an experience that we had.
So this is a school in Shanghai.
You can see the kids are
[ Foreign Language ]
They're having an
The kid loves the iPad.
[ Foreign Language ]
They're killing it, right?
[ Applause ]
So, that's the next big
And we're trying to create
at its heart to teach language
to learn a new language,
that are trying to
You know, it's very interesting.
There was a study that
about five or six years ago.
Of all people, it was
So there was this spy
who did this very
He took a bunch of the
to sort them, he tried to
of which language is
for an English-speaker to speak.
Which one do you
[ Laughter ]
Well, number 3 was Arabic.
Any Arabic speakers?
Number 2 was Korean.
And number 1 was Japanese.
Any Japanese speakers here?
OK, wow. All right.
So, the native Japanese
The NSA thinks yours is the most
And by the time you
you were speaking
You know, why do kids
It always frustrates me.
It always makes me very jealous.
You know, I have a little son.
He's one and a half years old.
And I know that in another
he'll be speaking
And it's always been
to me in why they do that.
What the theory says
of language acquisition says --
is that kids learn a
and much more effectively
because they're immersed in it.
You know, they hear it,
and they know what the meaning
because they understand
in which it's being said.
What if we could
and provide the same capability
That's why I'm excited about
Because with FreeSpeech,
and you know what the meaning is
because you're using
And every time you make
the app is telling you
in the language you're
That's the interesting thing,
and that's what we're
You know, language is something
which is really interesting
In this connected world
in the world is two clicks away
language is really
that we have as a species.
I mean, think about it.
Right? How many of
with whom you don't
You know, communication
that children with
But it's also the last barrier
And that's why the
so satisfying and
You know, I build apps that
kids with disadvantaged
You know, I build apps
to make the lives of
But I'm hopeful that
that I'm doing could
with a different light and
at the most beautiful,
of human inventions -- language.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]