[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello true believers!
So, let me know, do we have
[ Cheering ]
Alright! Good to hear!
So, you know the phrase,
with great power comes
Right? So, you've heard that
whether that's comic books
but really the phrase connects
Our heroes and our villains,
between our heroes and our
to respond, the choices they
have power.
So, that's the phrase;
with great power comes
And I learned that
See, like the characters
that made me make decisions.
I was lucky, when I was very
or five, my mom let
of the 1960s Spider-Man
up with panels from
And something about Spider-Man
I don't know if it was
the red and the blue.
Perhaps it was his
Maybe it was because
I don't know, but something
about Spider-Man
like no other character
In fact, I was into him so much
it was the book fair for my
and I walked in and there
against the back wall
Not actually Spider-Man,
a paperback sized reprint
Amazing Spider-Man
I never forget, and I walked up
and I grabbed it,
And I read that book over
And it opened my eyes
It introduced me to
and from that moment
That was my thing, comic books.
And I was one of those crazy
I read them through grade
and even through college.
And I had a pretty good
between my freshman and
It was -- I remember
and I saw some weird
This was an apartment I was
my parents had divorced
So, I saw these weird lights.
I go outside and I see
that we live in is on fire.
And the flames were
and our apartment
And as the flames started going
across the building I
of the apartment
that I thought we
So, these were years before we
I know horrible, so our
they were in photo albums.
So, I was running in
our apartment building,
I was grabbing some
pictures off the wall,
that I thought had
And then I remember
out in the building,
And I knew I had one
So, I run in, I can't see
through the apartment, down
I open my closet door
from the apartment,
Now you might think
Why would someone run
on fire to get comic books?
Well, I mean at that moment
in my mind how much the comics
and these characters
So, I mentioned my parents
who has been through a divorce,
you know how unsettling it is,
and it sort of rolls this
But during that, during
whatever was happening in
I had really good friends,
through these events in my life.
And luckily those friends helped
for Marvel, the company I dreamt
that little kid watching
And when I got to Marvel, that's
and that's when that mantra,
with great power comes great
See not only does it
and the decisions they must
it also applies to us,
So, we say to ourselves,
Well, our power is
with these amazing
Our other power is our
We think we're pretty good at
in film, or in print,
That's where I work now,
for the Marvel Games Division.
So, if that is our power, the
that we tell with them,
Well, our responsibilities
that in some way help people.
That connect to them,
and hopefully give them
that they can then
Now, I mentioned I had
that helped me through my
and to embrace power
And even though we grew
probably in different
and if not around the world,
I think you do.
Let's see, there's six of them
My first friend, he was a skinny
and he really wanted to
He wanted to serve the country,
that he could do that would
And so he would go -- he
and they turned him away.
They said he was too skinny.
He had flat feet.
They didn't want him.
But that did not
He kept going to different
And there was a soldier
and he went from one
to another collecting some
And he said, didn't I -- I just
And he said, to his
that's the guy we want.
And the other one said, him?
The skinny one?
And he said, yeah.
See, it's not about
it's about this muscle.
I can see this kid has heart.
He's not giving up.
That's the kind of person
So, my friend was lucky.
He succeeded.
He got in.
He became a soldier.
He not only became a soldier,
In fact some call him a
So, I guess you can guess
[ Inaudible Audience Response ]
Captain America!
So, here is the cover
See the date up there, 1941.
And what's remarkable and
Well, what is he doing on it?
Who's he punching?
Hitler! Because that's
If you were in a room with
and the powers, you'd sock
Little problem with that.
See, this comic was
Months before December,
months before America was
So, when his creators, Jack
to work they were in trouble.
There were protesters
up into the offices
and that's what Marvel was
they were called Timely,
they were yelled at
He said, Jack and Joe,
You've published a comic book
with a character named
and he's wrapped in the
in the face the leader
that we are not at war with.
What the hell are you doing?
Now, it was at that
in from the sales department;
Keep doing it [laughter].
It was an immediate
Why? Because it was
Jack and Joe were
as their art form
They were both Jewish.
They had relatives and
They knew what was going on.
They knew about the ghettos.
They knew about the work camps.
They knew what the
and they thought America should
It's also important -- what
What is he holding?
Is it a bazooka?
Is it a machine gun?
No, it's a shield.
Like I said, these
They send messages.
So, I think they chose a shield
Well, it defends him.
Look, it's blocking that bullet.
They're saying a message
and America itself should
that can't protect themselves.
So, it was a big hit.
But like I said, it
because some felt we should
And why are we -- why is
of this nation?
But they thought it was more
And that's not the last time
that we've made statements
So, here we have a cover
out just a year ago, but you
in the suit, right?
So, you see above the Captain
The Falcon, who you may
from Captain America
Captain America Civil War.
In the comic books
In fact there was a time,
where they changed the name
from being Captain America to
And I know for me as a young
and a black man, from
working together, that
So, we recently did a story
where Steve's Super Soldier
and he said to Sam, America
Will you take the shield?
Will you take over for me?
And we did -- and he said, yes.
We published this, and of
People were not happy,
People feel -- why
around with my character?
You know, you're ruining them.
Why are you changing thing?
And we even get people
why have you turned
And we had to say, well we
different -- make him
This is actually Sam
He's stood behind
and with him, for decades.
He deserves his chance
Now why did we do this?
Well, we like to try different
and stretch the brand
but we also like to say things.
So, I'm just thinking
and I don't know exactly what
but I think perhaps
that it doesn't matter what
if you have the heart.
If you have the heart you
My next friend, he
He was from Queens as well.
He was a bit of what
He was picked on by the jocks.
See he was really into
And he was an orphan
by an older aunt and uncle.
And he really felt the
And one day his uncle said
up you're going to have a lot of
So, when you do grow
up you should use your
And my friend kind
And when he grew up and he was
pretty smart and he did
and one night he was out and
chasing a thief and the
hey help me stop this thief.
And my friend said, from now on
and he took a step back.
And that thief ran by,
and as fate would have it
into my friend's uncle
And my friend said, if only
one of the only nice
If I'd listened to him
and my aunt wouldn't be
And from that moment forward,
he decided, I will use
So, who am I talking about?
My next friend -- Spider-Man!
So, now it's 1963.
I mention that because all
of our creators were
about what's going
And this was really the birth
And what do I mean by that?
Well, Spider-Man looked
than heroes that came before.
And once you start reading
out he was truly different.
And his creators, Stan Lee and
at too when they came into work.
So, they came into work and
said, what are you doing?
You've published a comic with a
and he has an insect
Everybody hates bugs.
What are you doing?
And you've covered his face.
He looks like a bank robber.
We can't see his face.
And worst of all,
Teenagers should be sidekicks.
Who wants to read
Well, the new generation did.
So, the greatest generation
It's 20 years later.
It's the rise of
They have disposable income.
They want to read about
They want to read about heroes
that are a little more
they're not square jawed
or rich billionaires, they
from Queens who gets picked on.
But the publisher
didn't know who was
And so he's yelling
what the hell are you doing?
As you can guess, at that moment
Boss, boss, look at
Keep doing it!
Another hit.
And you can see what made
I mean check out poor Peter
and the glasses, and the kids
at him, and as you can see, via
you see that he's ostracized.
He feels alone.
He is an underdog.
But look behind him.
Look at the shadow
And don't we all feel
We feel the world is against us.
We feel the world is judging us,
if given the opportunity,
So, as with Captain America,
Spider-Man was a
when he came out,
They didn't get it.
But many more did.
And that wasn't the only
that we did with him.
Let's see, in 1970 the president
believe it or not, went to Stan
Stan we have this
And we're going to lose
And President Nixon knew
that Marvel were publishing.
And he said, could
that would mention
Stan thought about it and he
And what was remarkable
of Amazing Spider-Man.
Now we had many characters
Stan could have selected one
of our less popular
He picked Spider-Man.
Now, you'll see there's
on this cover.
Now see up there on the top
That's the Comic's
was a seal of approval
that the comic was safe for
it didn't have, you
of violence, things like that.
What's not on this cover?
There's no Comic's Code.
See what happened was,
to publish it Stan
to the Comic's Code Authority
of approval and the Comic's Code
Stan said, why not?
He said because it
Stan said, but it's not
It's an antidrug story.
And they said, we don't care.
You -- the Comic's Code says
in the comic, so you
with the Comic's Code
And Stan said, good, we're
without the Comic's Code.
First time that happened,
People really responded to it.
They responded to, really kind
In the story Peter's
the son of the Green
and Spider-Man had to council
But they handled it in
at the time could appreciate.
Stan was really speaking to
that they wanted to hear.
But, as you can guess, it
but sometimes we've
Right? We have to use
But it didn't stop
No. We use Spider-Man
to speak to other things.
So, in this case it was
of comics called The Ultimate
They were set on another
of started -- we started now.
Rather than having our
we kind of started
but wanted to make it different.
We wanted to make it unexpected.
And so actually on that
in battle protecting Aunt
And in that reality there was
who happened to also be
And when that world's Peter
world still needs a Spider-Man.
So, he made his own
that world's Spider-Man.
And, as you can see, looks a
He's half African American,
And I remember the day I came
at the time for Marvel
An editor is sort
we're selecting the writers
on the series, and we're working
of the way, deciding
to what's in the word balloons.
We work on everything.
And we also have access
to an email account
and people can write in letters.
Usually they write in and say,
why can't Peter Parker
be happily married ever after?
Why can't Rogue and
Why are you so cruel to them?
Because drama, that's why.
So, that --
[ Applause ]
So, I remember I came
and that email account
And some of them weren't happy.
One was from a dad, I'll never
when my kids get home from
to the backyard and
up all their Spider-Man comics
He said, why did you make -- why
Why did you do this?
Why with your East
Why are you ruining our hero?
So, I wrote to him and I
to buy a single additional
but just so you know,
in the regular Marvel Universe
But we're offering an
that looks a bit different.
So, I said, you don't have
but please don't burn
It will not have the effect on
It will be far, far worse.
Now he didn't respond.
I don't know if he
I'd like to hope he didn't.
Who can say?
But I can say, immediately
that I read a great letter.
A young woman wrote in
She says, now my little brother
like him, and he feels great.
He feels he is represented
And that's why we do it.
[ Applause ]
Alright, my next
Oh, he really loved his dad.
His dad led this --
like an empire, you could say.
My friend really -- he
to one day take over for him.
And as fate would have
and my friend did have to step
And he found it was so much more
and he realized it was
by others outside of it.
And he had to find the
into the boots of his father,
I'm talking about
who many of you may
to in the latest Captain
So, Black Panther was
of The Fantastic Four, 1966.
And it was remarkable because
introduced by one of the
And what's also crazy cool is
He was no one's servant.
When the Fantastic Four
to his nation of Wakanda,
up that was in Africa.
They saw that he was a king,
that was the world's
advanced country.
And so again, I think the
and Jack Kirby, were
Were making a statement just in
And people loved Black
And they were very smart in
and I think they told some
like this next cover.
So, here we are in
Black Panther is
He's actually ripping himself
on fire.
What an emotional,
One of the things I love about
I love that they chose, not
at the bottom, but there's
This always -- this again
of underdogs feeling
feeling the world is against
deciding to do the
My next friend, she
I think I should stop
what's up with all the orphans?
Well, in any sort of art form
especially in fiction --
on the side of your character,
say a limited page count of a
in a movie or in a video game,
you have to make
that helps your audience
So, that's why you -- it's a
all these orphans; Luke
every Disney princess,
There goes mama [laughter]
Why do we do this?
Because again, we're
on the side of the hero.
And what's the one thing that
or if it's unfortunate enough
to sympathize with,
something everyone can fear.
So, it gets your audience
It also literally forces the
Our characters must now
and again make their choices
So, that's why you often see
So, my next friend;
and she felt like a freak.
She was like this friend,
and she had silver hair.
She was black but she had
like everyone was judging
and thinking she was some
And one day this really nice
you're not cursed,
I want you to come with me
where everyone looks really
to fly around in, and together
and we're going to show
like you are not evil.
That people like you are good.
And we can all work together
So, can you guess
Storm! Storm, a mutant.
In the Marvel universe we
by how they get their powers.
So, if you get bitten
or if it's cosmic rays,
the creators were really
at the time, and the
That's why there's all this
But if you're a mutant you
it's in your genes
and when you hit puberty, ta da!
You're body starts changing,
you grow wings, lasers
And isn't that what you felt
like when you were
I did. And so the
about is Professor X, right?
And so he comes up to
come with me and we're
We're going to show the world
and work together
And it's a great message.
And another message
I've mentioned America a
And super humans are a
We came up with them and I
and you could say right now
to the world is the super hero.
We export the super
But this issue was different.
This issue introduced
So, you have Storm
The big metal guy is
And to me, as a kid,
My mom was Ukrainian, and so I
you know anyone from
and anywhere near Russia was,
you know those were
But in the comics I saw that,
Colossus is a hero.
It meant a lot to me.
So, also you see Nightcrawler,
Wolverine, with the
True story.
International group.
Again, I think they were making
again, it doesn't
or where you come from,
We can all be heroes.
And storm was really unique
because she wasn't only
she can control the weather,
and lightning and storm.
Not only that, but she had
I mean look at this next cover.
That's her rocking
with the mohawk and the leather.
And she was saying to the
Love me or hate me,
Now, this issue was significant
because she actually challenged
of the X-Men, and she did it
by a gun and she didn't
But she was very smart
and she beat Cyclops.
So, here I am, this white kid.
At the time I was living
and I read a comic book where a
for leadership of Marvel's most
And you know what I said, and
We said, alright!
Cool! She's earned it.
So, I think stories like this,
and images like this,
And Storm isn't the only
We actually have a
In the movies you've seen Black
we announced we're finally going
to do a female solo
We have a history of
like to celebrate them.
So, this year we did an
We were going to -- it
to International
And so we said, let's do a
So, up top you see these images.
We created these covers.
We created 24 different
to go on our comic books.
And I knew we were doing
So, I called up my
because at this point I'm now --
for the Marvel Games team
and I said, hey, let's team up.
I want to do women of
And they said, well how
I said, I'm going to call all
who create all of our mobile
if they want to participate.
I'm going to say, hey do you
that you were going to
Do you want to hold
And everyone whose logo
And so we did the Women
It was covered by
and then Forbes picked it up.
And it was a way for
without even saying anything.
See, at the time,
of Gamer Gate was in the news.
And people were asking me, what
And I said, what do I think?
I -- we love our female readers.
We love our female characters.
We love our -- most of
We want to invite
And that's what the Women
And that's what it
to make a statement on it.
My last-- Yes!
[ Applause ]
Let's see, my next friend --
I lied a bit, it's
It's a group of friends,
but they're so united
These friends, like my
in some way, and
and they felt like misfits.
But they ran into each
and they said, you know what?
You're my kind of misfit.
And they formed a
and they were all very
you know despite our differences
and we can save,
we can save the entire galaxy.
My next friends, The
Now this -- Yeah!
Yes, that's a talking
that does deserve applause!
So, this cover that came out in
of the series at the time.
I was asked to edit
and I wanted to do a team book.
I had a book that was a
And I said, well now I want to
you know the freaks and geeks
I want it to be a
And then I got this name,
There was a team in
And we hadn't used that
And I'm like, I want to use
You hear it and you know
they guard the galaxy.
So, one night I have
of the Marvel Universe, they're
And they -- with
And I have them open, and
and I'm going through and I'm
that I remember from
but we haven't seen
So, I'm putting sticky
and I have them spread
And my wife comes in and she
You're making a mess!
I said, honey, I'm building
and this is going
And I show her a page and
And I said, it's a raccoon!
Back in the 80s there was
Raccoon that I thought
I mean it was a raccoon with
and a bad attitude, and
And I thought if we just
then the world will love him.
And I just continued
and I found all these
Groot, a walking tree and Drax,
but not too smart assassin, and
in the galaxy, and that's
And it didn't have a huge
that read the comic
And I remember one
Hello. It's a friend over on the
the crew here in Marvel Studios,
we really like your
especially Guardians
I'm like, that's cool.
Cool bud, I'm glad you like it.
No, no, we really like it!
So, what does that mean?
Can't tell you, bye.
Click. Well, what do
The movie poster.
And I said, that's
They made it about our team!
And it was remarked
and of course it was great,
and the director, James Gunn,
it was awesome and --
about it was the
for a Marvel Studios movie.
Usually we look back, if
and Captain America, we look
in the 60s and even
and we base the stories on that.
But they were basing
from just a few years ago.
And it was characters that
When you see the
and assume these are new created
They're decades old.
They're from the 80s and the 70s
and even the 60s
And they're crazy.
They're freaky, right?
They're -- it's like
And people are like,
I remember the headlines;
to be Marvel's first flop!
I said, no it's not!
It's going to be great!
And the reason it was a hit,
even though the characters
in space, they grounded
It was all about family
when Peter Quill is
all through the movie, when you
talk about how they feel
of their kind, or in Drax
They were all alone, but they
we will be each other's
Groot goes from I am
That was the message.
And I think everyone, in one way
As we grow up we often
We leave our family.
We go to school.
We get jobs.
What do we do?
We look around.
We find other misfits
and we form new families.
I think that's what is at
in every scene and that's why
Alright, I have one more
And he is not on this cover, but
Let's see, so there I was,
at work when I was
And it was a February
and I had walked 20 minutes from
And my phone's ringing and I
in 20 minutes and I
and I look at my emails.
And there's a wall,
And some of them were, like
mheroes@marvel.com,
And some of them were again,
saying how they loved some
And one subject line
That got my attention
And it was not a letter
and Gambit or Peter
No, it was from a
She said, I need your help.
Said, my little boy Anthony,
this morning he did not want
We call it blue ear because
He said, mama, I'm
And I said, why not?
And he said, because super
So, Anthony at that age,
So, Christina tells me
Super heroes where hearing aids.
And he said, you mean
And she said, yes of course.
And he said, well
She said, I'll tell you when
She drives Anthony to school.
Runs back.
Help! Oh, what am I
I don't know if any super
and he can't know
But I have faith, I think
I'm not a liar right?
So, there I am, and the
And I go to the meeting.
And my finger is going to the
and I said, what
Catholic guilt!
What would he do?
But that is seriously
when I was growing up.
I didn't really want
I wanted to be Peter Parker.
Because even though he wasn't
to do the right thing.
So, I said, okay, power
What can I do?
Well, I don't have
but I have information
And I have access to images.
I have that.
So, what's my responsibility?
I've got to use that
So, instead of deleting the
Marvel Editorial.
I said, what can we do?
Do we -- do you remember any
Or could we even maybe
to draw someone with
And my good friend Tom
he reminded me of Hawkeye.
He said, oh, remember Hawkeye?
I said, you're right.
Back in the 80s he was on a
by rubble and he used a sonic
and it burst his
And his good friend Tony
that he is, made
And to this day he's
And we've done stories
to wear his hearing aid or not.
We've done whole issues in
and to use him as a metaphor,
and should be a hero, no matter
So, I went through
and I grabbed this
of my favorites when
And I sent it to Christina
I want you to show this
that not only do super heroes
of the world famous
And if Anthony wears his
honorary Avenger.
And I thought, [applause] -- And
for the day, off
The next Monday I get in my
So, my friend Manny
he knew I was sharing
He draws this, on his
He draws this over the weekend.
He knew I sent the Hawkeye
And then he invents Blue Ear
because that's what they
And I send that to Christina.
And we -- I said, hey
And we said, yeah, okay, cool.
Good deed done for the day.
We're done right?
No. Next day I get
by Nelson Ribeiro,
With his mighty hearing
and he will go help!
I send this to Christina and
It's awesome!
Three weeks later she
Bill you don't know
on Anthony's life.
I've had to print out these
because he keeps
and gets them all muddy.
And now I had to put
And he brings them to school,
with hearing challenges, and
and get so excited, and
and represented, and they
And the teacher saw --
[ Applause ]
The teacher saw how
and the teachers
where all the kids
And as fate would have it,
Anthony's grandfather
Plot twist!
So, one day the Senator is at
and says, hey, do you
negative political
And he says, no, I
These people at this company
to draw these pieces of art
And it was covered
And it started getting
And then I have the New York
to ask me about this,
And from that day forward
from families saying,
Can you send me the comic book?
And I had to keep saying,
There's just these
But I kept getting these emails.
Kept getting them.
And I bugged the hell
And I kept saying, we
We got to do a comic.
There's a need for this.
Families need this information.
Kids need to see
So, I kept bugging them.
I kept bugging them.
And at the time I was working
with a division called Custom
with clients outside of
or Cirque du Soleil, or
We would create things
does anyone remember those
with our characters?
Yeah! That was good stuff!
That's the kind of
We would make comics
using our characters in an
to also promote another brand.
So, finally we partnered with
and we made a comic book!
But we decided, hey let's use
Why? We want to get
He's one of our most
But not only is he
We used him as a metaphor.
We said to the kids, hey, if
like Blue Ear or if you have
that's Saphira on the
because this is in the
we wanted to have
for young women to see.
So, we said, hey, if you
or cochlear implant,
He uses his tech to
You can use your tech to
And the comic came out, and the
from Italy and Australia
for copies of the comic book.
And that created
Yes, it did not stop.
And one day I get a call and
I'm like, alright.
So, I'm in the limo
Mom. Yes Billy?
Mom, in half hour I
I'm going to be on.
Billy, what did you do?
No, mom it's good!
It's Blue Ear.
He's going to be on the show.
And actually, Christina and
and we're going to meet up.
And they're all going
And then guess what.
Then we're going into the
[ Applause ]
So, there's Nelson, who
There's me, grinning
And there's Anthony,
in the whole Blue Ear costume,
because mom saw how
And he felt like, I'm
And so he dresses up like this
and now the town
And guess who was
of his town's Halloween parade
So, these Marvel characters;
Power and responsibility.
What can we learn from them?
We have to use our
Now, you may be thinking,
I can't leap through the sky.
I don't have rays
No, but everyone in this
and incredibly gifted
to create good things.
We have to use and realize
We need to use them to create
like Anthony, and kids around
We must use our creations to
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]