[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Hello.
[ Foreign Language Spoken ]
So hello and welcome
Looks like it's your first
If you didn't understand
of the talk, you're
So let's talk a little bit
So as you might know,
Apple ships its products
And two-thirds of Apple's
Which is why it's really
that the linguistic experience
So we have users all over
to Milan and Dubai and from
And of course these
to be using your
in their native languages.
They're also likely
in languages you didn't expect
that aren't related
For example, English, you
global language.
So today I'd like to talk
what we've been up to for
of internationalization.
Some fundamentals about getting
and internationalizing your app.
Then some quick fixes that
to make it a great app
And lastly, some things to
and mentality standpoint when
So let's get started
I'm really excited to talk
that we've added in iOS 10.
Now if you look around you,
you're probably sitting
who speaks more than
The U.S. is an extremely
and California especially so.
And with iOS 10 we embraced this
by offering you multilingual
So you can choose from a mix
Or any two of the languages here
on the same layout without
and you'll get autocorrections
for both those languages.
Another enhancement we've
of Latin American Spanish.
And this comes to iOS,
And this is the first time
that your app might
that is not for specific
And I'll talk about
at the code level in a bit.
Another great enhancement is
that is added in foundation.
And this will take care of
and region aware manner
and it already supports
like temperature, energy,
Now, I won't be going into
but there's a whole session
So please check that out.
We've also localized the
And so when you request the
you're automatically
that supports different
such as those used
And when you're in this state,
in the bottom left of the
between these different
Now in some cases,
to specify ASCII capable number
that the input that
to be restricted
Some examples of this are credit
They're edge cases, but things
One of the huge new features
in macOS Sierra is native
for languages like
And macOS has been redesigned
with right-to-left
And of course, macOS joins our
like iOS and watchOS
which already support
languages natively.
Again, this is a huge topic, and
And again, there's
What's New in International User
that you should definitely
So let's get started with
that you need to know
Let's take a look at an app that
It's been re-themed,
but probably still
So what are the various
to internationalize here
in different languages
First of all, you need
So this is basically any button
in it, you need to make
into all the different languages
Then there's another
to be localized but it
and so you should use
And this will save
And lastly, you need to
so that it will work well
And for languages that have
than the language
So if we do all this right,
and we translate it
and it looks fantastic.
Notice how in Chinese the a.m.
/p.m. marker goes before
like it does in English.
It'll also work well
for right-to-left
Notice how the layout
of the entire app is
And in this case, see how
numbers which are different
Again, if you use formatters,
So those are some fundamentals
Let's take a look
from the user side as well.
What does a user do when they
like an iPhone?
Well, every Apple
up will first ask you
And what's going on
that every language has a
and of course, every region has
So let's say a user chooses
What that becomes at the end
of the day is a language
What you may not know is
that language codes are
So for example, Spanish,
from Latin American Spanish
which then inherits
This is really important
to be localized into
So we want to know, okay,
that the user would prefer
if we don't have their most
on the system.
Also, this hierarchy is not just
like English have a hierarchy.
For example, Indian
that are more close
than to American English, and
in which it inherits
And English and Spanish are
that have such a hierarchy.
We also have other languages
and Portuguese that have
So I hope you all are taking
on these aspects because
The reason I'm mentioning this
to help you solve this
to know anything about this.
So I'm going to show
that in the next
So what's the first
We need to localize the strings.
Now there is a little
It's simple.
But there's some setup
about that in detail
there's a lot of documentation,
that goes into detail about
So let's assume that you've got
so you've got some
If you're using storyboards
with Base Internationalization,
There's nothing you need to do.
You launch your app.
The strings get loaded.
You're golden.
If you are creating or loading
to call NSLocalizedString.
NSLocalizedString will use the
with all the fallback,
and it will load the most
Now, note that it's
to your translator because
distinguished by which
and the comment helps
Let's move on to slightly
Let's say you're getting
like a server or
Well, in that case you
or the other process know,
hey this is the language
please give me strings
And in order to do that, you
on the Bundle that
and get the first
that to your remote service.
If you have an even
and for some reason you have
say, on the server that
of languages you
Let's say you have a
then you can call the class
and give it the available
And again, it will match
So I mentioned this Bundle's
times during the
So what is all this about?
And what is Bundle doing
So what Bundle does for you is
okay user prefers English
U.S. localization.
We do have an English.
So okay, in this case it
It figures out things like
but we have British but not
And again, with the Spanish
if you say I prefer Mexican
out that oh the best
in the list shown here is
And similarly, for Chinese
This is a lot of
that you do not want to be
And definitely if you have
like take the language
on hyphens or something like
that code because you
So now you've localized all your
You want to double check
that everything you have
To do that, you can use the
which will actually find
with localizability,
where you're feeding
into the UI.
And that's all there is to
Next let's talk about
This is a common kind of
with all the delivery services.
And this, however, is not a good
So it says AM9:41, which to an
look like nonsense.
But believe me, I've
And similarly, you might see
in Chinese where
/p.m. marker after the numbers,
which is completely
So how do we avoid
The problem is actually
which is formatter.dateFormat
It seems like the
It looks pretty nice in code,
but it's actually
And although it yields the
out for English, so it'll give
thing out in Chinese, and it
Why? Because it's applying
which language you're
The correct approach for this is
to just use the predefined short
And it's going to give you
for Chinese, and for any other
localized in.
And of course, there
So we have the short style
You can also get a
which has the seconds.
You can have a style
or the full time zone name.
There are variety of different
And of course, not
For dates, also, we
of styles going from
Now you might come back to me
of those styles is
They want, you know,
or just this or just that."
That's fine.
So you can use a format.
The important thing is to use it
with the setLocalizedDate
which will make sure that it
for the current language
and gives you the
for that language.
There are also two classes
They're fairly new, although not
which will let you format, say,
a duration like 4
Or a date interval like
9 to 9:40 a.m. So the
is that if you use
all the localization is going
Next let's talk about
that you can format, names.
Now, if this is how you're
or their friend's name to
they're going to get a really
So let's not do that.
Instead, you should show the
for that given language
So how do we do that?
It's actually really simple.
You create a
Fill it with some name
like any other formatter,
from the components for any
And again, we have a variety
which is the full name
which you can use for initials.
And of course, it supports
New this year, though,
So now you can go from a full
And it's as easy as creating a
and then looking
If it returns nil, it
to successfully construct
The really cool thing, though,
is that this is not a
at some set of static rules.
It's actually a statistical
in the name in the
it knows that in John Appleseed,
to be the given name and
And it's still going
And of course, it supports
So there are a lot
I talked about Date
and
in detail.
The components and interval
And there are some formatters
which are existing formatters
And there's the brand new
in this set of releases.
So be sure to use these
in your code because they
and you will also save
Which you shouldn't be
So that's all about at this
in terms of strings.
Now let's take a look at
of the layout to make sure
that the UI actually works
So the key word here
It does what it's intended --
which is it automatically
And so whether you're
if you use Auto Layout you
interface for a right-to-left
And again, Auto Layout is a big
into detail into how you
because there are sessions
and from previous years that go
What I will tell you is that
and NSStackView as much as you
to use APIs that leverage
that your views will
for right-to-left languages
when they get long
So we will have sample code
to implement a version of the
Now one thing that you
for layout is that sometimes
Now you see this
Are you sure you don't
And you have two options there,
Now in some languages you can
be longer than can fit in
So what do you do?
Well, in this case, you see
to a top-bottom orientation
of a left-right orientation.
And these kind of creative
that you should keep in mind for
you ask a translator to
where it might not even be
The next thing is
And a lot of you may not
for your apps.
So we have a lot of scripts
like Vietnamese, Thai, Arabic,
or lower or both than the basic
to write English.
And so what happens
which is that somebody
to true on the label.
And what that does is it clips
and besides being very ugly and,
in that language, you often lose
like a diacritic mark.
In this case the pronunciation
on the right is changing
So to fix this it's
Don't set clipsToBounds to
And that should be enough
More interestingly, though,
you also need to consider
So let's take a look here
and English on the right.
And here it's English
on the right, sorry about that.
But see what happens when
into the same amount of
It looks really cramped.
And any Hindi reader will tell
and it doesn't look nice.
So what you really need to do is
to give each script the
and to look good on screen
The good news is that
Any time you have a
a lot of this is done by default
when you set a custom font
that you get a preferred
Now, you might say, okay
and I can't use this.
Well, there is a solution
out the fonts and typography
into more detail about
that a custom font will
Next, for table views, we
which is that if you have a
we will actually make the table
in other languages like English.
Again, this gives the script
and it just overall looks more
The way you can take
by using the standard
And now you might say, okay,
you know, it's not
I mean, I don't just have
it's not as simple
And I'll be like, okay sure.
I agree. But what
in using UITableViewCell is
It has a bunch of
usually to get exactly
So try that first before you're
custom UITableViewCell.
So that's mostly what I have
that will make your app great
Let's talk about some things
that are more design based.
And also the mentality
for making great apps.
First of all, it's
Now you know that when you go to
for an app one of the
to notice is that icon.
And oftentimes, at
if the icon doesn't look
because that's going to
And I don't want to have an app
So icons are really important,
that the icon that
for different languages
in different layout directions
like left-to-right
So photos has a great icon here.
This is a great example of an
or numbers that would tie
It also doesn't have
like left-to-right
So it really works well,
in English, and in Arabic.
Now if you are making a
and you want to make sure
for right-to-left languages.
You should take a look at some
And if you are using artwork
that would need to change
then you would probably need to
for right-to-left languages.
Now here you see an
that you can't just
You need to create
in a right-to-left language.
But if you do have images
there is actually API for
to create separate artwork.
There's more information about
in International
But the key is asset catalogues.
Another thing that you might
about is your app's name.
Now, when looking at various
one consistent theme we've
in the least is that users
that work for them
And that applies to
Because if they can -- if they
app does by looking at the
then they're much more likely
to tap inside the
And of course, the world is --
users all over the world are
or at least they're bilingual.
So your app should
about the UI language and
that the user will type.
For example, a very common theme
in Asia like India
that people will run
but they'll have content
like Hindi in this case.
So when you have an app and you
that the user's going
especially make sure to
and Japanese keyboards
that the experience works well.
And here's an example that I
that in our opinion
at the things I just
So this is Evernote.
And first of all,
It doesn't have any words
that would associate it
So that's great.
However, they have also gone
and localized their
And this is actually if
you'll see that they have
because the Chinese word
that they've chosen also
for elephant, which is their
You'll also notice that they
And there's a lot of attention
You'll see, for example, that
in which they're
you actually have the
So the user is seeing
in the screenshots exactly the
to get when they
This is exactly what
So take advantage of the fact
that you can upload
and screenshots to
And lastly, I wanted to talk
What you can do to go above and
for people in the --
or in a specific country.
I'll give a couple of examples.
One is if you have any
such as templates and pages.
You could create
for different languages.
And so for example, in Pages
for cards for some languages.
And just one more
for more advanced feature,
you're a calendar app, and you
for the Middle East and also
like China where they
Well, you could support
in your calendar app just like
because this is going to
for those users.
Now what your app
depends on what your app does.
And so you need to take a
if there's an area where you can
That's really all I
So in summary, localize
Use standard system APIs
Make sure that the apps' layout
for languages with
longer translations, which have
English-sized scripts
When designing the
make sure that it is
and doesn't tailor to a
And finally, at the end
if appropriate, and screenshots.
Now for more information,
to get some other useful links
about internationalization
There are also some
that I mentioned
So for example, there's
in International
And there's also a
One talk that I wanted to call
out specifically is
It kind of will talk more about
at the end about how you can
for both internationalization
that need accessibility support.
And that's all.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]