[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
I'm Conor Hughes, an engineer
on the Accessibility
And welcome to What's
Today we're going to learn about
in our operating systems and
to know to make sure your
So let's get started.
So accessibility is a big word
and many are not
What does it mean?
To us, accessibility means
for everyone, with all
This means both designing
with different needs
about your basic
This being WWDC, we're going
on Apple platforms
with four major classes
vision, hearing and learning.
Motor encompasses
and Multiple Sclerosis and
to push with force on the screen
Vision accommodations
and partial vision loss.
Hearing covers hearing
And learning, which includes
Our operating systems can do a
in all of these areas.
But apps are a core part of
So for our platforms to be
we need you to make sure your
which is why we're so happy
about how to do just that.
So let's go over what we're
First we'll go over some of
in Mac OS, iOS, watchOS and tvOS
so you can see some
of how software can
for people with different needs.
Then we'll take an iOS app
for accessibility issues.
Then dig into the
to make sure your
And finally, we'll
to fix the issues we
including using some new API
So what new assistive features
Well, there are quite a few, so
at what's new in
First off, motor.
So some people may only be able
through pressing a
for instance a switch on
They can interact with the
for instance, through Switch
which moves through the
When someone wants to
under the cursor, they
Switch Control lets people with
from simple taps to
iOS and OS X have had Switch
So what's new?
Well, we're excited to announce
that we're bringing
Now, people who use
to directly interact
The familiar Switch interface
that highlights elements
Or an alternative
with an onscreen remote.
And what's more,
without repairing their switch.
Someone using Switch
or their Mac can immediately
totally autonomously
We think this is a
And we can't wait for
Next up, Dwell Control.
There are a number of
that track someone's focus when
So they may take the form
on a headband, or actually
Dwell Control is a
which integrates
by allowing them to
When the mouse dwells
Dwell Control presents
And when a timer expires,
for instance a mouse click.
This allows someone to control
to manipulate the mouse.
And of course, it's customizable
just like Switch Control.
So next, let's look at vision.
So, for many years Mac OS and
like invert colors
to help people increase
on their device, deal
or work around color issues.
This year we're expanding
across Mac OS, iOS and tvOS.
We've added color
with color blindness, which
like this, appear
And we've also added the ability
to tint the entire
which can significantly increase
who find reading black
So in watchOS, someone using
spoken aloud to them
or tapping on the watch face.
But sometimes they may want
without disturbing
So in watchOS 3 we're
Taptic Time is a VoiceOver
of distinct taps from
to help someone tell time
So iOS has a lot of
with visual disabilities
with the content
But what about their
In iOS 10 we're introducing
Magnifier is available
And it lets someone use
to magnify objects in
And I'd love to show
Okay, so I'm going to
into Settings, General,
and flipping the switch.
Now I can turn on Magnifier
by just triple clicking
So here we are.
So, if I want to read what's
for instance, I can
I have access to things
for a low light environment.
I can lock focus on a
And in case I have trouble
or I'm pointing at
I can take a freeze frame
And we captured this image
at the device's native camera
out and in, move around.
And Magnifier also supports
to help someone increase
So for instance, maybe
maybe inverted grayscale,
So that's pretty
Okay, so that's an example
Okay, so what's new in hearing?
iOS has supported hardware
TTY technology allows
to hold text conversations
Here is what an existing
As you can see, it's
and probably difficult
But it's incredibly important
especially when you factor in
from TTY to voice, allowing
to contact businesses,
who may not be using one.
We thought it would be
of this device was
without any additional hardware.
So new in iOS 10 anyone can
in a familiar interface
to use any additional hardware.
These calls work with legacy
to dial a non-TTY number through
Plus, it has built
in TTY-specific quick type
in with existing
And finally, learning.
Dyslexia is an incredibly common
the ability to read
of people around the world.
In iOS 10 we're excited
of enhancements designed to
We've implemented
and Speak Screen to help people
that's already been entered.
And we've implemented new
to help people immediately
And I'd love to show
Okay, so I've turned on typing
in Accessibility
So I'll just fire up Notes.
And what I'm going to
to type the word
to pause after typing the O.
And I've turned on
where iOS will read the last
to me after a pause
that I didn't enter a visually
&gt;&gt; E.
&gt;&gt; So, it may be difficult
but iOS just read
So that wasn't correct.
&gt;&gt; O.
&gt;&gt; Great. Now, I'm going
and iOS is going to read
because I've turned
So I can get immediate feedback
as to whether the word I've
&gt;&gt; Welcome to our session.
&gt;&gt; Okay. So that's
of enhanced typing
So, hopefully I've whetted
of accommodations
to make sure the entire
to everyone.
So if you're new
you may be wondering about
accommodations into your apps.
And if you've used the
maybe it's time for a quick
onto some new API.
So, how do we use the
to make sure our
Well, the first step is to
Traditionally, the best way
up an assistive app like
and see what happened.
You'll want to check that
are exposed.
That everything that is
so someone using
You'll want to check that
with VoiceOver can do everything
And finally, you're designing
for your app.
So you'll want to make sure
with VoiceOver, for
and smooth an experience
So this year we're also excited
that there's a brand new
lot of more powerful and
catch mistakes.
If you want to learn more about
to check out the
for Accessibility on Wednesday
For this session we're going to
because it's still the best
with accessibility
Okay, so let's do it.
Let's take a look at a live app
and find its accessibility
So, for this presentation
but the same basic flow
Okay, so the first thing I'm
to my accessibility
into Accessibility Settings.
And all the way at the bottom,
Accessibility Shortcut,
Okay, so let's fire up
a pro app for selecting
And turn on VoiceOver
by triple-clicking the Home
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver on.
DogRoutePro.
Routes.
&gt;&gt; So, there are two, excuse
to navigate your app
You can take one finger
and VoiceOver will select
and read what's underneath
Or you can swipe with one
to move forward or back
So let's see how accessible
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop.
0.8 miles.
&gt;&gt; So, immediately I
that if you activate this cell,
But nothing conveys that
Let's keep going.
&gt;&gt; [Inaudible] button.
&gt;&gt; So this button has a label
of the image I used
That's the framework's
on the only information
So we'll have to give
All right.
So let's activate this cell.
To activate an item
when the item is
to double-tap onscreen
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop.
0 -- Avenue Loop.
Routes. Back button.
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's go
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop.
Avenue Loop ratings.
Heading. Distractions.
Smells. Greenery.
Friends.
&gt;&gt; So for this ratings graph,
the graph values are
to someone using voiceover.
Let's keep going.
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop route.
Heading. Broadway and Ridgeway.
Hazard. Boys' Choir on Ridgeway.
41st and Broadway.
&gt;&gt; So, because I gave these
the frameworks were able to use
for the map annotations.
So that's good.
Let's move on to this Steps tab.
&gt;&gt; Steps. Text selected.
Step 41st.
-- Broadway and Ridgeway.
Turn right at Broadway
Boys' Choir on Ridgeway.
Boys' Choir between Gilbert
Continue along Ridgeway.
Be careful of cars and children.
&gt;&gt; So, VoiceOver was
in these table view cells.
But you'll notice that these
on the route are not
for someone using VoiceOver even
that there are hazards from the
Okay, let's jump
and discuss how we
So, what did we learn
First, those route list cells.
The Favorite button has that
from the name of the
In addition, it isn't clear
that the table cell itself can
Now, for the ratings graph,
those graph values were totally
And finally, in the route step
waypoints that were hazards
from the other steps
So how can we fix
Well, to understand how, we need
to understand how VoiceOver
from our interface and drive it.
VoiceOver interacts with our app
through the UIAccessibility
So let's take, as an
in the app we just saw.
Assistive apps like
to ask your app's user
So for instance, when Voiceover
that button, VoiceOver
what kind of thing are you?"
And the button says,
VoiceOver then asks,
What's your name?"
That button should respond
Finally VoiceOver asks,
And the button replies with
This is the information
"Favorite, Button" and draw
So these messages from
to your app take the form
The methods are all part of
By implementing the methods
of this protocol you
hierarchies accessible.
So standard UI controls
But depending on how you
to set or override
So what properties?
Let's take a look.
Now, there are a lot of methods
that you can use for
over how your interface
to accessibility.
But for most work you need
to only concern yourself
Let's go through the basic
First, there's
This property determines if
by an assistive technology
So for instance, if you have
decoration, you can
However, if it represents a
to your service, you'll
so someone using VoiceOver
focus on it and learn about it.
So now your interface element
You'll want to give it a name
That's what the accessibility
The label is a concise
For instance Send
So how does someone know that
New Alarm doesn't convey
in the same way that its
That's where the
Accessibility traits declare
to the assistive technology
and how to interact with it.
So for instance, a button
UIAccessibilityTraitButton.
An adjustable control
like a slider would
UIAccessibilityTraitAdjustable.
The traits are a bit masked,
so an element could
For instance, a selected
UIAccessibilityTraitButton and
The Button trait is what
so someone knows they can
Next there's the
This determines where
and is used both for hit testing
and for drawing a cursor
Now, for UI views you usually do
because it's computed for you
in the view hierarchy.
But you can modify it if needed.
Just remember that it is
And finally, there's
This is useful for
of conceptual value
So for instance, a slider
in percent through the
An on-off switch
And if you had some
that controlled the
of an instrument, you'd want to
through the accessibility value.
Okay, so what do you do
where each logical piece of your
to a UI view?
When you need to do that,
UIAccessibilityElement objects
regions onscreen.
And they interact with the
like your views do.
You can use them, for instance,
of a control that's built
So to do so, make the element
into an accessibility container
by setting its accessibility
of UIAccessibilityElement
that represent each
So, UIAccessibilityElement
that graph we saw earlier where
to present the graph bars.
But if you're a very astute
slight snag.
UIAccessibilityElement
so we need to set their
However, those graph bars
so their frames and
Now, to rectify this
or we could set accessibility
Or, in iOS 10 we can
in container space.
When you set this property to
UIAccessibilityElement will
container's position onscreen.
So those are the
in the UIAccessibility
with UIAccessibilityElement.
And you'll get most of the
So what are the takeaways?
First, know that the methods
in UIAccessibility protocol are
items to accessibility.
Through the methods of this
questions about what
and what they can do.
Now, for many classes
so there's nothing
But you may need to set
to get the behavior you need.
Finally, if you have
that don't map directly
use UIAccessibilityElement.
So, let's go in and use
to make our app accessible.
The first thing we're
to fix the fact that that
that it was able to be
So, the way we're going to do
all we're going to do is "Or"
in the trait
Done. All right, now
for that Favorite button.
What we're going to do here
for this cell we're going
and set its accessibility
and then the name of the route.
I'm putting the name
so it's unambiguous which
if I activate that button.
All right, let's move
So, like I said, I'm doing
So we're going to use
Now, what I want to do
to add some ivars to keep track
of the UIAccessibilityElement
So, just four ivars, one
that are
Next I'll add a short
to help me translate
into a user-friendly string.
So, rated X of 5.
And then, for each of
for these rating
to set the accessibility value
of the appropriate accessibility
that describes the rating.
So, for smells -- oops.
Put distractions first.
Smells. Greenery.
And friends.
So again, just grabbing
setting its accessibility value
to be the value string
Okay, now we need to
to be valid accessibility
So in AwakeFromNib here, for
to set it equal to a
with our self as the
Now, we're going to set the
to just be the text from the
the UI label, I should
And then finally, we'll set
of our self, because we want to
to just be those four elements.
So now we have valid
with a valid label,
and a good accessibility value.
Now we just need
So what we're going to
out the graph bars, we'll
accessibility element and
in container space.
Okay. Then the last thing we
of the cells in the
So, I'll go to the
And when we set the
that that cell represents,
to do is add some code
to manually set the
to be the waypoint's name and
And then if it's a
And then the hazard description.
Okay, so before we build
to the slides and think about
that a sighted user
that a VoiceOver user still
All right.
So again, first, that route map.
VoiceOver users can discover
the route order is lost because
elements in a spatial,
In addition, someone who's
hazards on that graph by
But someone using VoiceOver will
of the waypoints on the graph
Now, for the route step list,
in that it's easily
who can scroll through quickly
with the distinctive red
But for a VoiceOver user,
They have to go through
So how can we fix these issues?
We're going to use the rotor.
The rotor is a VoiceOver feature
across an interface by searching
So one of the built-in
is the Headings rotor,
to navigate an interface by
To use the rotor you take two
as though you're
Do that to select the rotor
up or down with one
or next with that rotor.
So this year we're
to add your own custom
We hope you'll take
to add a totally new
when people are using
On iOS, to add your
set the Accessibility Custom
that contains the elements
to search, or that super
You'll want to set
of view accessibility
which are initialized
and also an item search block
swipes up or down to
or next match to for that rotor.
All right.
Let's switch back over
and see this new API in action.
Okay. So, let's first
to the Route Step
so someone can easily navigate
that represent hazards.
So, I'm going to open up the
And I'm going to set this
So basic skeleton here.
I'm going to make a Hazards
rotor object with the name
And I'm going to set the
property to be just that rotor.
And inside of the callback here,
to get our reference
an array of waypoints,
and determine whether we're
by inspecting the
Next, we're going to find where
So, by default, if
in the table view right now,
we're going to start
or after the last item,
depending on whether we're
So we go into the list of cells.
Otherwise, if we
we're going to get it as a cell.
And then start at the
that item in our data model.
Okay. Then we're going to search
through our data model
And we're going to search
And a match is just a
So if we find a result, we're
for that result, scroll to
grab the cell that we
onscreen and return a
item result with the
Now, it also supports
in the initializer.
If we conform to UI text input,
through different
However, we're not doing that,
so we're just going
And if our While Loop terminates
we'll return nil to say we
Let's do a similar thing
Sorry, we have this
which searches our
from one annotation view
with a given predicate
to whether we should return
on what data model
So we're going to use this
We're going to override
We're going to make a
to help us make multiple rotors,
because we're basically
for the various rotors
And then we're going to use this
when setting our accessibility
We're going to have
that just returns
And a Hazards rotor that
Okay, so in this fact array,
Well, we need to create a
object with the appropriate
We're going to use our Search
Pass it the current element.
Whether we're going
And what the predicate was.
And again, if we were able to
to wrap it up in a customer
Otherwise we'll return
to find a previous or
All right.
Let's build and run this.
&gt;&gt; Avenue --
&gt;&gt; There we go.
&gt;&gt; Heading.
&gt;&gt; All right.
So let's look at
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop.
0.8 miles.
Button.
&gt;&gt; Okay. So VoiceOver
That's great.
Someone can know that they
Let's take a look at
&gt;&gt; Favorite, Avenue Loop.
Button.
&gt;&gt; Great.
&gt;&gt; Selected.
Favorite Avenue Loop.
&gt;&gt; So the selected
of for us by the frameworks.
So I'd like to activate
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop.
Avenue Loop.
Avenue Loop distractions.
Rated 3 of 5.
Smells. Rated 2 of 5.
Greenery. Rated 5 of 5.
Friends. Rated 4 of 5.
&gt;&gt; Excellent.
So our graph bars
&gt;&gt; Avenue Loop route.
Broadway and Ridgeway.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Now let's try
&gt;&gt; Headings.
Words. Characters.
Hazards. Route steps.
Hazard. Hazard.
Ridgeway and Piedmont.
Piedmont and 41st.
41st and Broadway.
&gt;&gt; Great. So our Route
&gt;&gt; Use the rotor to access --
&gt;&gt; Excuse me.
&gt;&gt; Hazards.
Hazard. Ridgeway and Piedmont.
Hazard. Boys' Choir on Ridgeway.
&gt;&gt; And the Hazards rotor
and through the list of
So, let's check out
&gt;&gt; Steps. Selected.
Steps. 41st and Broadway.
Start at --
&gt;&gt; That was me.
&gt;&gt; Hazards.
Boys' Choir on Ridgeway.
Boys' Choir between Gilbert
Continue along Ridgeway.
Hazard. Be care --
&gt;&gt; Oh, sorry.
The switch was cut off there.
So you heard, though,
So our modification to the
It's now conveyed that these
And in addition, we were
to them using the Hazards rotor.
All right.
Let's jump back to the slides.
So, a quick word on tvOS.
tvOS apps are built with UIKit,
about earlier applies
But there are a few
in mind when building your
from the fact that tvOS has
So a common pattern on
to group content onscreen
from the other content.
You can give a similar
to someone using your app
of the Accessibility
Set this property on
their super views or on
to be the headers that are
Then when someone
VoiceOver will read
in a distinctive pitch to give
of place in your content.
So I recorded a short video
And when I play it,
down into the collection view of
You're going to hear
in a distinctive pitch.
And that's because
to be the Accessibility Header
Now, you'll also
When I pause, VoiceOver will
of the non-focusable
So let's hear that now.
&gt;&gt; Available works.
Grain. Button.
Title. Grain.
Author. Vivian Li.
Description.
Close up of a strand of grain.
It glistens with morning dew.
&gt;&gt; So, the reason I showed you
that secondary Read All behavior
of the information your app
through an accessibility
even if it's not
by the tvOS focus engine.
When you do that, when you
VoiceOver will then read all
of the non-focusable
so that information
to someone using the
Okay. Let's wrap up.
So, when you're out there
with an eye to accessibility,
keep in mind what
First, accessibility
It's about making the great
available to as many
You'll want to design
in mind from the start.
Is anything difficult to use
with a motor disability?
Is anything too low contrast?
Excuse me.
UIKit helps your apps become
of the accessibility APIs.
And finally, accessible apps are
So thanks so much for being here
and learning about
So for more information you can
It's Session Number 202.
And there are some
that you should check out.
At 10:00 a.m. in this very
on Inclusive App Design.
So make sure you stick around.
And on Wednesday at 10:00 a.m.
in Nob Hill there's the
for Accessibility, which again
about that new accessibility
which I definitely
So that's all I have for today.
Thanks so much and have
[ Applause ]