[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
My name is Ali Ozer.
I and my colleagues [applause].
Thank you.
I and my colleagues Raleigh
from the Cocoa Frameworks
about what's new
Our agenda is pretty simple.
First, API updates
in AppKit and Foundation.
And in the area of API updates,
of API updates I
One, the API changes due to
and secondly, the general API
So let's get started.
Now as you heard probably
this morning, we have new API
And these guidelines still
and practices and
of what some of these are.
Using clear and consistent
striving for fluent usage, you
as an English phrase,
and non-muting method pairs
append and appending, and
These are just of the
for many years and
and we've talked about
as you see in this session here.
And now we updated
to utilize Swift features
type inference, and overloading,
and to make sure our APIs
And let me talk about some of
as a result of these changes.
For one thing, we're eliminating
which of course makes
as you might have
You saw an example yesterday in
of the union with an example.
Here's another example,
In a method call like this, both
"object" don't really
So such a name now comes across
Here's another example
NSColor.blueColor, now
Blue is already a color,
so the word color really
So in the new guidelines,
across as NSColor.blue.
But note that we're still
Here's another method from
Text is not inherently
talking about the text of
Is it the text that represents
So in a case like this, we've
and it comes across
like it used to be.
Now some of the other key
here's an example,
now this API comes across
You'll note that we've
from our method signature.
It's because the type of
and with type inference, Swift
And by dropping that word,
we actually now have three
that are all named exactly the
and it's that first argument,
URL data or FileWrapper
that distinguishes
Now another thing to note
on the first argument.
From here has now been
We do this in a number of cases.
For instance, when the
of a prepositional phrase,
we pull that phrase inside the
And you'll probably
of this throughout out APIs.
Now you'll also notice that
Here we haven't dropped
because that argument
and strings are weakly typed.
So we really need a word
and the role here is
of file we're opening.
So there, we keep the
Now many framework and standard
as a result of these
and the importer whose job
into Swift now does it
but you'll note that some
We've done that in our APIs,
which I showed earlier,
And if you yourself have
in Swift, you may need to do
like NS Swift Name, which lets
the importer is doing.
You also know that the
There's a migrator that converts
to Swift 3 and it will help
in your existing
And the Swift API
which took place just before
on video for a lot more details
on these guidelines
Now we have a number of
that some of which
and others we're
Let me quickly go through these.
Nullability is something
that we've already
It's basically declaring whether
properties can be nil or
and we've continued to
For instance, here's a method
as returning an optional value.
This is addItem on NSMenu
as returning a non-optional
that this can never really
to reflect that properly
of course, a little simpler.
We've been doing properties,
into formal properties all along
and this year we're also
to declare properties
For instance, here is a
You'll hear about this
allowsAutomaticWindowTabbing.
This is reflected as an actual
You'll also note that
to do this in Objective-C.
You can actually declare class
with this syntax
So the same feature comes
as well, which is pretty cool.
Here's a Core Data example
It had this method,
It's now declared
It's a read-only property,
so it only has a get,
And in Objective-C,
across as property
Now generics, we've
to our collections' classes
not just for collections
but they have many
I'm sure as you're aware.
Here's an example from
Here's the way it's declared
In 10.12, we just went ahead
and added a parameterized
We also touched a few other
such as this execute method
which returns an array
As a result of this, the use
like this.
You have a request which you
such as employee, and then when
your return now is
to be an array of employee.
Now this is the case
that in upcoming seeds we'll
cleaner like so, which
So from those two lines, the
that the return type is an
We've been improving
An example that we've done this
The change -- And here's a
You'll see that's
because .NSCrayonModeColorPanel
The change we've done is to take
in as a prefix, which
to come across a lot cleaner.
You know, where the
and the use case is .crayon.
Again, this is what
and this is what it looks
Now in the enumerations area,
of string enumerations.
Swift supports string-valued
and in many cases Cocoa APIs
as opened or closed sets of
And let's look at an example
In Swift 2 we had a bunch
NSStringTransformLatinToGreek
And then we have an API,
that took those strings
In Swift 3 we've actually
StringTransform and then an
values for that,
And the API that takes
where the first argument is now
So the string argument has
a little more type safe.
Now note that this is an
in that you can declare
Let me show you how you do that.
You can go ahead
to StringTransform yourself
Now the values here are the
for doing transforms.
So you can use any valid
It turns out Any to
that we don't expose
So again, go ahead and define
and pass it to the APIs just
And string enumerations are
by using of these two macros
And here's the way the string
in fact added.
In 10.11, this is what we had.
And in 10.12, we have a
which is decorated as NS
And we're also taking
to nest declarations related
An example here from NSData.
We had a option set,
and class NSData with an API
In Swift 3, this comes
with a nested WritingOptions,
And the API that uses
to WritingOptions, which is
of course much more
Now unrelated to
you'll note a few more things.
So that's the change
You'll also you might note that
of an empty set most cases
which means you actually
to pass the options
You might've also noticed that
You might've already heard
about this more later
Now my last topic
for now is noescape.
Okay. So noescape indicates
that a closure's execution will
What do I mean by that?
Here's a method
from NSCollection view
It takes two closure arguments.
You'll note that the first
This means that the execution
of this closure will
performBatchUpdates returns.
The second argument is
which means that the execution
after this function returns.
So it's a good hint to
for the compiler as well.
This facility is also
where we can decorate
to get the same effect.
So that's it for our quick
Now note in the seed you have,
we haven't done everything
so there will be some
class property changes coming
So we're going to
So with that, let's talk
to invite Raleigh Ledet
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ali.
Good morning, everyone.
As you can see, we've been very
So let's dive right on in and
So when you're dragging
as you bump up against the
and as you get along the
and even during resizing.
So it's now much easier for
and resize them just the
And we spent a lot of effort
to make sure that we only
when that is what
with your windows
The way you get snapping
to just let the system do the
If you track the mouse yourself
and manually position
to bypass window snapping and
where you ask us to put it, just
As you've seen in the keynote,
This is an example of TextEdit
And the thing about
just windows.
So this example of TextEdit with
by three different NS windows.
So what we do is every one of
of the tabs is visible,
So if you check the
it's going to return true.
But only the visible tab
to the screen.
We hide all the other windows
so they aren't rendered
up resources that way.
And we handle this
So how do you add a
You create a new window
and we will go ahead and create
and place it in the window.
If you want to remove a tab,
and we'll go ahead
This is all done automatically.
Now if the user resizes the
to resize the window
We don't want to take
to manage the other windows
when the users might
But when the user does switch
at that point AppKit goes ahead
and resizes the windows
and then changes the
at the window server level,
and so the user gets
of one window with multiple tabs
we're just dealing
So I want to cover some
in your applications
into your applications
of application you have.
If you have for example an
or a non-NSDocument
What you might want to do
if you already have an
and I'll round the section out
to customize tabs
If you're in an NSDocument
there's nothing for you to do.
This is fully automatic and,
we made exactly zero lines
It fully supports tabs and it
If you're a non-NSDocument
but what you'll probably
to New Tab button
The New Tab button is
to the right of all the tabs.
To enable that button, you need
to implement this
override in your NSWindow
up the responder chain.
For example, your
or your NSWindow controller
If you implement this override
AppKit will see it
and enable the New Tab
If you have your own
then you probably want
to disable AppKit's automatic
There's this class property
on NSWindow
This is a class property
of your application
allowsAutomaticWindowTabbing
and this will turn off
and then you can continue using
It's important that you call
of your application before you
That's all you really need to do
to adopt tabs in
It works mostly automatically.
But here's some of the API that
First off, the user can
on how they want tabbing
and they can do this in
and you can find out what
by the class property user
and they can set it to manual,
when they're in full screen.
The rest of these properties
on out I'm going to discuss
and functions on NSWindow.
So once you have an
you can set it to tabbing mode.
By default, this tabbing
which means we're just going
to follow what the user
but you can set it to
depending on your window
When we group windows together
to group windows that are
that is by looking at
So windows that have the same
grouped together into tabs.
By default, AppKit will use
up with a tabbing
We look at things such as
the properties of the
and various few other
up with the appropriate
This works really well,
but if it doesn't quite work
or if you want to have
you can set the tabbing
and AppKit will respect that.
You can find out what are the
with some instance of a
by asking for the tab windows.
Note this returns
It can return nil and
if the tab bar isn't even shown
and there are no tabs
And you can manually add
to the group.
Since these are just windows
where you add a tab window,
you add the tab window
NSWindowOrderingMode and
in relation to the other tabs.
AppKit will add a few
Namely in the windows menu,
and help the user
such as selecting the
These are just IB actions on
up to your own user
For example, you might
that toggles the tab bar.
You just wire that
toggleTabBar IBAction
and NSWindow will handle
So that's everything about
Let's move ahead and talk
We've done a lot
to enhance our already
In the screenshot you can
in Arabic.
The title bar is flipped.
The scrollers are
Even the new tab button is
And all the little attributes
and the various title bar
appropriately as a
I want to talk about
at three different levels.
What's going on at
where the user sets
in the system preference pane,
how that impacts your
on in your application depending
on the localizations
And then finally down
which is at the NSView level
where you can override
with the user interface
And then I'm going
up with a really nice
on right-to-left support
To start off with, let's
The key here is consistency.
We want to have a
to the user who's running
So regardless of what
in your application,
on a right-to-left system
over here on the right
of the menu items
for the windows title bar.
So the traffic lights
over to the other side
in the content area
over to the other side,
regardless of what localization
providing a consistent
Now we can't automatically
down into the application
to break any assumptions
that your application
So it's highly recommended that
in your application, add Hebrew
And once you have those
at an application level,
all your scroll views will
scroller and rulers
and NSBrowser will automatically
At this level, again we want
of what content views user
be, we want the scroll
on the same side
Moving down to the
by default the user interface
to match what your
This is exactly what you
but there are a few exceptions,
like media controls or spatial
where it is always laid out
for both left-to-right users
So you can modify the user
And the following controls
So auto layout will
but in the upcoming seed two
container to determine what is
And already in the
and outline view will flip
NSPageController switches its
We have a lot of support in
Let AppKit do the heavy
and provide your right-to-left
I promised you a
I've been using this
I found it incredibly useful.
In Xcode, you can modify
in the Options section, change
to right-to-left pseudolanguage.
This allows you to
in your development language,
and so you can see
but it is all using
in it.
So the window title
The scroller for the
and you can see all the little
of the title bar are flipped.
So it's a much easier
on right-to-left support
and make sure everything
in your native language.
Now I've just covered what
There's a lot more to
in International User Interfaces
at 9:00 a.m. They cover
such as WebKit, text
and they also cover
So I highly recommend that you
Let's now talk about
If you're not familiar,
when the user is dragging a
but you don't have this
But you're just going to promise
that you'll write it wherever
That's a file promise drag.
We've supported file
in OS X since the beginning.
In macOS Sierra, we're
to be more modern with the
and NSFilePromiseReciever
Now these objects allow
to support drag flocking.
If you're not familiar
it's when you're
and they can change
depending on the
and what's going on there.
So file promise drags with
drag flocking.
They're UTI based.
They're completely pasteboard
which means you can use the
to work with these objects,
and they're file
So you don't need to worry
We'll automatically wrap
or write on your behalf.
And they're backwards
They're backwards compatible
with the non-item
And what this means is you only
If you implement an
you can now provide
to anybody that's using the
or somebody that an existing
non-item-based API.
They will still be able to
and likewise with
You will be able to
from anybody using an
or using the non-item-based
So you want to provide a
so as the user starts to drag,
and you do that by
of NSFilePromiseProvider.
You want to create an instance
that you are going to
to provide an
This delegate is what's
of writing the files to disc.
At some point the destination
and you'll be asked to
for the destination.
Now you know where the
out the appropriate file name,
at this point because
up with file coordination
out some of the remaining
When the drag is completed
and we know all the
we'll call your delegate back
to URL and provide a
At this point, it's all wrapped
So just write the file
and call the completion handler
that you're finished writing.
If you want to receive
the first thing you need to
that you want to allow
And this is normally done with
and the drag types you need
to add are the
readableDrappedTypes.
It's fairly straightforward.
Now once the user is dragging
you'll start getting dragging
to get the promise objects.
So you can use the pasteboard
to read the objects forClasses
and you'll get an array of
Once you have an
you can call in the promise
by calling receivePromisedFiles
operationQueue reader.
And it will return pretty
and your reader block will
We're going to call
Once the source file has
promises, now we go ahead and
on the operation queue
Now it's important that you do
for the operation queue
to block your application while
to finish writing the files.
And this can take some
to block your application
And that's all there is to
It's much simpler API to use
and supports the item-based
So let's move on and talk
to our various container views.
We'll start off with
With collection view, previously
your contents would scroll
that you might've had.
Well, now you can tell the
with your contexts by
ScrollsWithContent to true
We also have support
for optional floating
So you can see the documents
and the content scrolls
This is real easy to do with the
Just set the
or the
true if you want
and NSCollectionView
of doing everything
You can also optionally
into a single horizontally
as you can see here, and you get
whenever you scroll
This is real easy to do with the
on NSCollectionView.
Now the sender of this message
at your section header
of your section header view
and that is how NSCollectionView
which section needs to toggle
Since you have your button in
you should have your
implement NSCollectionView
SectionHeaderView protocol
up your button to the
Then NSCollectionView will now
and automatically
depending on if there
that section to collapse.
NSTableView will now
when the column index
Negative 1 is our magic
that expands all the way across
So when you call reloadData
and columnIndexes includes
we will automatically reload
that full width cell
This only works for 10.12 and
Likewise on 10.12 linked
NSOutlineView will also
views associated with the item
Additionally, OutlineView now
you return to it
This is really useful but if
to maintain the original
that we had previously, you
to false and return to
And with that, I'd like to bring
and talk to you about
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Raleigh.
So the first thing I'd like to
This is a new container view
where we completely create
and manage the constraints
But where StackView creates
NSGridView creates these
You very commonly
like a preference pane UI.
Right, there are these
of aligned content
and pretty statically defined.
It supports alignment such as
It supports spacing of the
as its padding on an
Similar to a spreadsheet
it supports cell merging.
So a single view can
or multiple columns.
So for instance these
It also supports dynamic hiding
without changing the
So for instance, when we click
to hide the Display
And we can do that by getting
and just setting its
GridView will take
There are several other
to Auto Layout.
One is a cleanup of overall
that a view no longer needs
or layer backing in
Just by setting needsLayout
during the next display pass
One implication of this is
that layout is no longer
for layer-backed views and we
of that layout and less
which is great for performance.
But if you notice that
on your view when you expect,
make sure you're explicitly
All of this makes it easier
to do manual layout
So you can overwrite
and instead just
of your subviews,
You do want to be sure
that view's layout
This can happen if during a
frame or the frame
This will dirty that
and cause an additional
If this continues, this is
and these are pretty
So on macOS and iOS,
we've introduced new layout
so you can better understand
and why.
There's changes to the layout
properties so you
that constraint refers to.
These apply even when you're
In addition with that first
so if you are reading
be sure to handle the nil case.
In addition, Interface
for incremental adoption
So within a single
within a single view hierarchy
constants, which
NSGridView, the layout
is talked about in Friday's,
At this point I'd like
specifically wide gamut colors.
So sRGB is a pretty
Usually it's the implied color
and most of our displays
The new 5K iMac and
both contain these
that can display
Specifically, they're
and this is what we call a wide
to sRGB, it can display much
So your applications can display
to their original color and they
colors to make UI
An example of such a color
which happens to be Pantone's
It's outside of sRGB.
So previous displays
but it is fully representable
Your photos also contain
especially these
A note of irony here is that
at home are not actually going
so you'll kind of have to take
If you want to work
there's a new color
which lets you work with this.
This joins sRGB and
There's also a new constructor
on NSColor displayP3 red green
to create a color
UIColor has the same constructor
Another way of working with wide
calling extended range sRGB.
And so when working
you're typically constrained
with component values
And you can pick any color
such as this blue,
But you can't represent
of that color gamut.
So sRGB cannot represent
Well extended range sRGB
and the same white point as
to take on values less
So it can represent this
and blue value and a
It happens to also be the P3
that with extended range sRGB,
of colors necessary
This also has a color
and the existing NSColor
and UIColor constructors
that previously gave
Will now accept values less
and give you back an
which is pretty convenient.
One important thing to consider
with these wider color
So sRGB can theoretically
within its gamut, but
you can only address a finite
The black space here are simply
those 8 bits per component.
When you widen the color gamut,
of that gamut but keep
you're addressable
Your ability to specify
So this is why we
with these wider color
that you use 16 bits
It doubles the amount
but gives you exponentially
So we think that
What API do you need
to consider these deeper colors?
Well, the great news is that
So NSWindow will automatically
with these higher bit depths
even as you drag
If there's a reason you need
you can set the depth
to some value of your choice.
Views and layers within that
inherit that bit depth with the
There you should use the
CALayer on both macOS and iOS
property that allows you
to again explicitly control
So this is how you
of wide color in
We've also enhanced part of the
of these wider colors.
One example is the color panel.
So on the iMac on the left here,
the color wheel will
It will actually
from the full range of
that normal color wheels allow.
However, you can also
and explicitly choose
So even on these
that can't render P3 colors,
you can still allow
The RGB color picker
to choose the color
but it also allows you to
from 8-bit values from 0
So again you can get this
with these wider color spaces.
These color panel changes comes
to all applications
No API is needed for those.
The Working with Wide Color
and more, such as asset catalog
I'd recommend checking that out
So the next topic is
So status items are
in the upper trailing
and these are things that
of private API to achieve
First is reordering.
You can now command click and
within and beyond
You can also use keyboard
and even activate
The best part of all of this is
that this comes completely
with no API opt-in
So all items are command-click
and any items with a
in keyboard navigation.
If they have a custom
they'll just be skipped over.
The next is hiding and removal.
You can now command-click
out of the status bar, remove
and even programmatically
Unlike reordering, this
No status items will be
and you can do that by setting
to include removalAllowed.
You can programmatically
and even get KVO notified
of this change using
And if your application
meaning its only representation
there's no doc icon or other
to automatically quit on removal
by setting the
All of this gets autosaved
and the visible state so you
to preserve that using
We automatically generate
that you created in
but if you create them in
or just want to have
you can set that autosave name
to some identifier
So that's status
A lot of it comes for free, and
you can really make them
Next are control constructors.
So these are new constructors
that make it really easy to
Examples are different types
image views, sliders, and
So these are the types of
with in the Interface
and it makes it just as easily
to use these right
They come with the
the right font size,
and they support
So the label here looks
and even a vibrant dark
There's no additional
I'd love to show you an example
So this is creating
There's quite a few
and the unfortunate thing is
of those; the title,
Well with checkbox, title,
down to just that,
A bit more of a --
Just wait.
So this is creating just
just some text on the screen.
And here, we care about
Well, with labelWithString,
So, this is pretty great.
It comes out of the box --
[ Applause ]
It comes out of the box
or without auto layout.
So if you are going to be
you still need to set
IntoConstaints to false,
And so if you already have
of things, we still
over to these new system
that your controls
and feel both now
The last thing I'd like to
I only covered a number of
of our frameworks and these
but there's two more that I
to AppKit specifically.
The first is weak delegates.
So we've added new zeroing
for various delegates and data
so you no longer need to clear
delegates is deallocated.
It still supports non-weak
in which case it'll fall
or unsafe, unretained semantics.
We've also gone through
of our classes explicitly
designated initializers.
These are the same as what they
but now are just
with the one exception
So if you are subclassing
please see the release notes
for how you should
As with all newly declared
you should make sure that
with that in your subclass.
And so if you weren't
you potentially had these
that maybe were subtle bugs.
In Objective-C, you'll now
And in Swift, you're going
So you want to make sure
that you're properly handling
So that's it for
At this point, I'd like to turn
about what's new in Foundation.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Taylor.
So here are some of the things
and let me just dive right in.
Now earlier you saw
and I think we also talked
We are dropping NS prefix in
Now, as you might
of Foundation actually ships
as a part of Swift Core
in other platforms,
And we want to match the naming
with the convention established
which does not use prefixes.
As a result, a lot of our
in Foundation and
NSFormatter becomes
Now the last two here,
of a special category and I'll
Now, this is happening
It's not something
to our other frameworks,
it's only applying to some APIs.
We do not apply this
that are inherently
Examples are NSObject,
We also do not apply it to
and are, in fact, not
such as NSUserNotification,
And in one other case is classes
which are also exposed
So here we are exposing
but we're also exposing NSData,
about what I mean there.
Now first let me explain
You might already be
We've had this concept in
These are types where value is
Examples are NSString,
Now, since a number
of Foundation APIs already have
we've gone ahead and added
And here is the full set of
This is in addition of course
and set which are already
in Swift, since they're
in the standard library.
So now these types here are
and they have value
meaning they can be
if mutability makes
You can use let or var on these
at the time you declare them.
These also conform to the
as well, as you might expect.
Now existing class APIs
where we've created
and let me look at
An example is data, the
So now we have the
This is the value type for data.
This is the data
to use most often
This is the type moving forward;
which is a subclass of
which is a subclass
Now NS types remain
like NSMutableData is not
so the migrator will
Another reason we have NS types
want to subclass these types.
You know, you might
or NSMutableData to provide
and you can do that
the class types,
So these are some of the reasons
Now, let's look at
The NSData class has
This has been named count
because it's more
of the Swift Standard Library.
Methods such as write
of these other methods
They come across the same
that the NSRange and NSData
in the struct data version,
with the Swift Library.
And finally you'll note that a
is not available on this
in the case of NSData, it's
So these are some of the
between the value types
Now I'm not going to say
There is a talk this afternoon,
for Swift in the Mission room.
I encourage you to attend that
Now we have several
to represent measured amounts.
The main class here
This is an abstract type to
degrees Celsius, kilometers
And then we have
which is a subclass of unit.
This represents unit
temperature, and
So here we have the unit class.
We have the subclass dimension
such as unit length,
unit speed, and a bunch more.
There's a helper class unit
between units within
and there is a struct
of course, in Objective-C but
struct measurement which
with a unit such as miles,
so this basically is
and finally the icing
we have the measurement
which will take one of these
to the user in the
So it'll show 10 miles to a
but will show 16 kilometers, for
who's using the European system.
So it will do the
and show the user
[ Applause ]
Now out of the box, we have
Here's the whole set.
So these are subclasses of
of these unit families,
we actually have multiple units
Let me take a look at unit
You'll see that unit temperature
kelvin, Celsius, and Fahrenheit.
And these are defined
on the UnitTemperature
of the other dimensions also
that know how to convert
And even better news, you can
on top of what we
with what's already there
and you can also add your
So you can hear much more
at 4:00 o'clock,
DateInterval is a new type
It represents a date interval.
It's got three properties;
Fairly straightforward, so
fully independent
as three separate properties.
In addition to these properties,
to do things like check if a
or whether two date
Date intervals are of course
with the DateIntervalFormatter
That's something we -- That's an
We had an API string from to.
Now we have the string from API
which simply takes
so fairly straightforward.
Now at this point let me
announcement about
So handling dates can be tricky.
Now this is not relationship
Okay? I'm not a doctor.
Let's say you want to
You might go ahead and create
start date and a
This is likely correct for
whatever you're trying to
but let's say you're
You might go ahead and
24 times 60 by 60 which is the
Well this is the number of
and it's often not
The reason is because days
Months aren't always 31 days.
Years aren't always
We always keep those in
which are 23 hours or sometimes
So depending on what
with a DateInterval representing
to set an alarm exactly
Are you trying to send an alarm
You have to be careful.
Typically the correct solutions
class and you can hear
and also luckily their solutions
Solutions to Common Date
which I encourage you
ISO8601 DateFormatter is
It's a formatter for dates.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So clearly some of you have had
to use 8601 before;
It's an interchange
in an unambiguous manner.
So this is a separate
because unlike DateFormatter,
for user-localized dates, 8601
It's, you know, interchange
So it's a separate type.
We decided to keep
Using it is very simple.
So create a formatter.
Get yourself a date, again
And simply ask the formatter
and it will return
Now this DateFormatter
so you can actually -- Oh,
from that call, and
it's getting close to lunchtime.
And here is -- This formatter
also does parsing.
So you can get yourself a
from a string and it'll
So it goes both ways.
Now by default, this will do
however, there are options
of the behaviors,
Now quickly let me cover
we have.
URL has a bunch of
such as canonical path of
like whether a volume
You can read all about
There's a new class
This class helps you gather
performance information
at the network performance
PersonNameComponentsFormatter
As you know, it takes a
in a locale-appropriate manner.
Well in this release, it
So you give it a name
to you the first name,
and it does a pretty good job
since it uses a statistical
And finally -- But there are
So don't get your
And DateComponentsFormatter,
again this is API we
In addition to the full
we now have a brief style
And next release, maybe we'll
Okay, so that's it
Core data, just a quick
You already saw some
in core data with generics.
There's a bunch more
such as generational querying,
the NSFetchedResultsController
as well, I'm sorry,
You can hear all
at 10:00 a.m. What's
And one more talk I want
every year we get up here
new technologies were introduced
in a position to adopt
in the middle of something else
or maybe you wait a
Well, if you want
of recent APIs we've
to create modern
This is talk for you.
It will cover a lot of topics
to other sessions of
but also prior WWDCs as well.
It's also appropriate
all experience levels.
It's also Friday
So I hope you're here.
Okay, so and here is
to for more information.
Please read the AppKit and
which you can find in
It's there, just raw
of the stuff I talked about.
Here are the related
There are of course many more.
Thank you very much.