[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Good morning,
Welcome to Part 1 of
My name is Bhaskar
on the Messages Team at Apple.
Today we are introducing
And what that means is that
that run within the context
iMessage apps can provide
Number one, they can
Interactive messages
that your application generates
on this message, it will
For example, in the
I'm using the DoorDash app
for the party that we
On their phones they will
and if they have the application
to tap on it and tapping
At that point they will be
add stuff to it, and
iMessage apps can
Stickers are images
and we believe it
and interactive experience
And lastly, iMessage apps
of content that Messages has
videos, text, links, et cetera.
Also in iOS 10 we will
What that means is that
and create will be
in this Messages App Store.
Users will be able to get to
and they will be able to
Applications that your users
displayed within
which we call the
We also have this great
to discover your
and we call it inline
Let's try to understand what
In the screenshot shown here
from my friend but I do not
from which he sent the Sticker.
In that case, as you can
beneath the Sticker we will
from which the Sticker was sent.
And tapping on the piece of text
Store and present me
from which the Sticker was sent.
And then I can download
like any other iMessage app.
In this example shown here, I
to illustrate inline
However, it applies to
that your iMessage
Also creating an iMessage
to creating any other
that you have already created.
You will be able to use the
and framework that you
For example, some of the
You can do in-app purchase
you will have access
and your iMessage app will
And we believe these
and features will allow you
to create great apps
Now let's talk about
iMessage apps will
However, the content that your
sent to, and can be viewed
In watchOS 3.0, within
we also have a new page
The Recents Page, amongst other
that your users had recently
And you users will
to see these recent Stickers,
to send these Stickers
like they are able to
So that was about the
and the Messages platform.
Now let's get into details
This is what we're
in the rest of the
First we are going to talk
Messages framework is the
to familiarize yourself with
Then we're going to talk
about creating a
Next we are going to go into
and other constraints
And lastly we're going to talk
about creating a custom
Messages framework.
What we will not cover
to create an application that
We will cover such an
of our talk and I
to please come back for that.
That will be here on Thursday
Messages framework
that we are introducing
between your iMessages app
When your user taps on your app
it is through this framework
launch it, and provide
and other context
to lay out its UI.
Once your application has
ready to interact with it.
And at the end of that
will hopefully generate some
to share by Messages and your
to Messages by this framework.
And at that point your
that thing via Messages
with whomever they're
I would like to mention
and iMessage apps
of existing app extension
And in that sense your
and in this scenario the
as the host application
For those of you
or who have not made extensions
that you please go back and
from 2014 that introduces
So as I just mentioned, iMessage
there's one key difference
to other extension
Unlike other extension
to provide a containing
for your iMessage app.
You can only ship your
But if you already have
that you created or that
to the App Store, you can
within your containing
as I mentioned, these
So if you provide a
then your application will
of your users' phones and
within Messages.
It will also show up
and in the Messages App Store.
But if you do not provide a
as you can see, your
up in the main Home screen
It will only show up in
and the Messages App Store.
I would like to mention that if
application, you still
for your containing application.
This is the icon that will
of the system like the Settings
about your application,
the amount of storage
So now let's talk
Stickers are a fun way and
with other iMessage users.
Your users can send
like any other iMessage
Or your users, not
or your users can drag Stickers
and attach them to
And we believe this lends
and engaging messaging
But what do Stickers
Stickers are basically images
These images can be animated
And we believe Stickers
or promote any content
And we generally think
to be very, very popular
So now let's talk about
There are two ways to
First, you can create a Sticker
If you go down this
to provide any code
You only have to
for your Stickers
But if you want to
you can do so by providing code.
And your code in this case
Messages framework.
At this point let me
to create a Sticker Pack
So I have my machine here and
And here I'm going
to create a new Xcode project.
And under the Title of
to select Sticker
And then I'm going to hit Next.
And I'm going to name my project
that I'm going to use are going
to be assets depicting various
So I click Next here.
And for now just let me
I'm done. Let me quickly
Great. So, as you can see here
in a Sticker Pack application,
That is a very deliberate
and so let me reiterate this,
if you create a Sticker
you cannot provide any code.
You only provide the Sticker
So let's see how to do that.
I go into the Stickers --
that's the Catalog which
One is the Sticker Pack and the
I click on Sticker Pack.
And, as you can see it says I do
to drag and drop the
So let me do that.
So go to Finder and
And I have some assets
So I'm going to click on
to drag and drop it here.
So that's Golden Gate Bridge.
I'm going to drag
That's Chinatown.
And just to be quick
to select everything
Great. So I have all my assets.
So these assets are a PNG type.
Xcode also allows you
in your Sticker using the
Let me show you how to do that.
So I'm going to click, or
and I'm going to
And I'm going to say
So when you create a new Sticker
to provide the individual
that you're about to create.
So I'm going to go
I'm going to click here where
I'm going to drag
Third one.
And finally the fourth one.
Now let's go back to Xcode
So as you can see, I
of the Sticker here and click
in its center will actually
Looks good.
Now let me just throw
I go to the App Icon Catalog.
I go in here and I select
Looks like I may
Let me quickly do
All right.
So I provided the app icons.
At this point I'm ready.
My app is done.
So let me try and see
I'm going to go here
against the simulator.
I'm going to select iPhone 6s
as the device I want
And I'm going to go to Product
I'm just going to wait
Great. So Messages has shown up
and since I'm creating
I'm testing it against Messages.
And I'm going to run it.
And the simulator is launching.
Great. So here you can see I
in Messages in the simulator.
By simulated conversation what
of them and send a
up as an incoming message
And just to clarify, you will
out of the simulator
So going into the first one
And at this point I'm
As you can see, this
Great. Now let me see
So I go in the App
My application is ready
I click on it.
There you go.
The assets have shown
These are the same assets that I
and look how they look like.
And, as you can see the
And I can click on one
drag them out of
and attach to a message
Great. And as you can
go into the other conversation.
I see the Sticker here.
So this is how you create
However, there's one more thing
and that is how to
of this application.
So going back to asset Stickers,
to change the sizes of the cells
in which your Stickers are being
So to do that, let
And I'm going to click
And as you can see,
by the name Sticker Size.
I click on that.
There are three options,
And I'm going to click
that changes my application.
I run it again.
And Messages is launched.
Let me go back to
And there you go.
As you can see, the Stickers
and they're presented
And there's more
I'm going to go into more
of changing the Sticker cell
In that demo I showed you how
to create a Sticker Pack
and in this technique,
you do not have to
You only provide the
and for your app icons.
I also showed you how to use
to create an APNG Sticker
of the APNG.
And lastly, we also
to change the Sticker
Now let's talk about supported
We support four formats.
These are PNG, APNG,
And out of these four formats,
if you want to provide
we support APNG and GIFs.
We are also making certain
to make sending Stickers
to other iMessage attachments
on disk storage space
And to help us make these
to limit the file sizes for
So as I just mentioned, we
however, we do recommend that
if not for all of your Stickers.
Let's try to understand why
by taking a look at
So here I have two conversations
but there's a subtle
And so let me zoom in
As you can see, the conversation
on the photo and it
And the conversation to the
and the same Sticker but that
If you observe carefully
the one on the left,
does not display any
But the one on the
is displaying certain artifacts
around the edges
Now this is happening
and APNGs handle
but GIFs do not handle
And if you were to compare
of JPEGs, JPEGs in fact do not
And hence keep in mind your
out of your applications and
and therefore transparency
to consider while
We also request you to
on various colored
and even multi-colored
your Stickers can
In the demo I just showed
of the cells in which your
There are three supported
and they are small,
And for each of these sizes
dimensions of the
For small it is 100 by 100
For regular it is 136 by
For large the maximum
by 206 points at 3x the scale.
If you provide Stickers that
that are supported by the cell
then your Stickers will be
by Messages framework and in
like exactly the way you
But if your Stickers
then they will be
I would also like to clarify
to provide us Stickers at
of the resolution of the device
in which your application
Messages will take care of
if needed according
in which your Stickers are
So that is all I had to talk
and creating Sticker
At this point I would like
who is going to talk
about creating a custom
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Bhaskar.
My name is Lily and I'm an
I'm going to talk to you
about creating a custom
First, why would you want
to create a custom
The first major benefit
to customize how you display
In our previous example
in a nice grid layout.
However, if you wanted
in any other format or even
you would need to create a
A custom Sticker
to dynamically create stickers.
In our previous example
into our application
to update those assets
to push an update
If you want to pull your
or allow you users to
on device, they could do so and
through the App Store.
Messages extensions will
allowing your users to create
And finally your application
allowing your users
We can create a custom
Messages framework.
Messages framework
for creating a Sticker
In our example of Sticker
through Xcode, they use the
so you could ideally create
Messages framework.
In the screenshot we have
that's displaying Stickers.
Well, you'll notice that the
So I'm going to show
and create an application
So let's go into a demo.
So I'm going to open
to create a new project.
Bhaskar created a
but this time we're going to
So I'm going to go
And I'm going to call my
as we're going to
And we'll go ahead and
and we'll put it on our desktop.
Great. So you'll see here
Nature Stickies and
Nature Stickies does
as this is the containing
You'll provide an app icon
However, we're interested in
So we're going to go ahead and
And we'll see that
to be our principal class.
It is a subclass of the
The MSMessagesAppViewController
that handles callbacks from
We'll be talking more
and how your application
in Part 2 of our talk.
So we can go ahead and get
I'm going to select them
Great. So let's take a
If we click here we have an
The
will allow us to
It has two properties.
It has an MSStickerBrowserView
that our Stickers
And it also has an MSStickerSize
of our grid for the
We'll also see that the
conforms
to the MSStickerBrowserView
This protocol, when implemented,
of Stickers your
and the Sticker at a given index
So if we want to
we'll need to create an
And to implement the data
and subclass this.
So I'm going to go ahead
And I'm going to choose
And I'm going to call
ViewController.
Great. So I'm going to go
And then I'll go ahead
Great. So now let's
I'm going to go ahead and
ViewController class
of the
As I mentioned,
the
has two data source methods
So I'll go ahead
So now we'll need a way
to create our Stickers
I'm going to go ahead and create
and we'll see that our
And MSSticker is an
that points to an asset on disk.
It will also have a
which will be used
So let's go ahead
I'm going to go ahead and
I'm going to click Add Files
and choose these assets here.
And I've added them
In this example we're just
but you can imagine how your
these assets from your
to create them on device.
So now we'll need
So we'll write a
Great. So here we
We create a file URL
and then we initialize
with a localized description,
So now let's go ahead
that will load all
Cool. So now we can go back
and create an instance.
And we'll create a
ViewController, and we'll
Great. So now we instantiated
with a Sticker size.
This will allow your application
in the grid layouts that
So this application will
like we did through
So let's go ahead
I'm going to write a
to change the background color
So we'll write that
And we're just changing
of the MSStickerBrowserView.
And I'm going to go back
to the MessagesViewController
So now we can change
And let's go ahead and
So I'm going to choose
and I'm going to hit Run.
Oops. Oh, I forgot something.
We forgot to actually
So let's go ahead and do that.
So I'm going to return the
to return a Sticker
And now we're ready to run.
So I'll choose Messages as the
Great. And now we can
and then you'll see that
because we forgot to add that.
And we'll see that we have our
In order to change what our
to go into our project, click on
and then we could
But for now let's just see what
So you'll see we now have an
with a pink background.
So this is one small example
of how you can customize
So let's go back to the slides.
So to recap what
we introduced the
This ViewController
in your application using
This controller also conforms
to the MSStickerBrowserView
This protocol will
of Stickers your
and the given Sticker.
We also introduced the MS
This ViewController is what your
This MSMessagesAppViewController
from the Messages application.
Again, we'll talk more
and how your application
So that was a small example
of how we could customize
by just changing the
But what if we want to do more?
Your application can add Sticker
the MSStickerView
So if we wanted to
that displays Stickers
than the
does, we can do so by
On the example I have behind
This application
UICollectionViewController
And each cell
of the UICollectionView
The MSStickerView is the class
and drop functionality
into the Messages transcript.
So we also see that
which doesn't have
Tapping it will expand
allow us to choose a Sticker,
Also note that we were able
to transition how our
Your application
in a compact mode
Your users can also
on the chevron in the bottom.
So your application will have
in a compact and
So I'm going to show you how
and create an application
So let's go into another demo.
So I'm going to open up an
And it's called Sticker Picker.
And let's go ahead
Great. So we're back in
which is our principal
subclassing the
We had two views
our UICollectionView
and we also had a view
to add Stickers to
These two views are
in a StickerPickerCollection
and in an
Let's take a look
at the StickerPickerCollection
The StickerPickerCollection
subclass is a
The items that we'll have
So it can either be
or it could be a Sticker.
So let's go ahead and
The Sticker cell has
The MSStickerView will
in order to handle animations
we would have to call
when we are displaying
So let's go back
to the StickerPickerCollection
Great. So when we create this
to go ahead and create
We'll create an AddStickerItem
and then we'll load our
in our previous example.
We'll return the number of
and we'll create Sticker
for an item at a
When creating the Sticker
to assign the Sticker
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we have now put a
And, as I mentioned, our
And we'll need to be calling
to control these animations.
When we're going to display
to call startAnimating and when
we're going to want
So we can write a
if the Sticker is
by loading the image file URL,
and counting the frames.
If we have more than one frame,
we know that we have
So we'll go ahead
So we'll check to see
if our Sticker cell
And if it can, then we'll
And then when we're done
ahead and check if our Sticker
we'll call stopAnimating.
Great. So let's go back to
And we'll go ahead
and instantiate the
as that's going to be
when we first launch
So we'll do that in viewDidLoad
When the user taps the
to create the
And then we're going
into an expanded mode.
We can do so by calling
This will tell the
that your application
You'll then get a call back
from the Messages
this transition.
So
in didTransitiontopresentation
and we'll first check to see
if we have an
And if we do and our
we'll go ahead and
Or else we'll present the other
After we choose a Sticker
to go back to compact.
So we'll then again call
.compact.
So if we run our
to see all of this in play.
So I'm going to go ahead
as the application
And we're going to launch.
I'm going to go ahead and
And we're going to
and wait for it to load.
Great. So now we can go
And I'm going to choose
And we'll see it
And then we can send
So to recap what we just
we showed you how to create
UICollectionView and
of the UICollectionView
The MSStickerView allowed
into the transcript and
We also showed you how you
to an expanded presentation
And we also showed you how
from the Messages application.
Remember that your users
by tapping on the chevron icon
on designing your application.
Bhaskar talked about the Sticker
when creating a Sticker
These same file formats apply
to creating a custom
So to summarize what
we introduced iMessage apps as a
There's a new way to
and it's really fun
We also introduced
and how you could create
Messages framework.
We showed you how to create a
Xcode with no code.
And we also showed you how
to programmatically create a
In Part 2 of our talk
to create an application that
to send interactive messages.
For more information
and we'll have a related session
at 1:40 p.m. on Thursday.
Thank you so much.
We can't wait to see
and please come to our labs.
Have a great rest
[ Applause ]