[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
My name is Olivier Gutknecht
and today we're going to talk
and other system
But first, I'd like
what is not new, in Cocoa Touch.
Why, since last WWDC,
of very important products.
The iPhone 6S with 3D Touch.
The iPad Pro 12.9
The Apple Pencil, and
And, with these products
of key technologies
to make your applications
The first thing that I want
When we introduced adaptivity
that we introduced was the
The iPhone was a
The iPad is regular.
And now we have the
do we need gigantic size class?
We don't. Because now
in the framework
We have the trait system
which is how your application
and environment of
Size classes, that's one very
you have everything
to build a size based
We added new support
in Interface Builder and,
from auto layout to asset
with layout guide, and
everything is ready
We're going to have also,
two sessions this week
The first one's going to focus
And the second one,
and the techniques you can use
to make your application
And this morning there was
on design, you should watch.
The second thing that I'd like
Last year, with the iPad
we have 120 Hz touch scanning.
We are scanning faster than
And now, with Apple Pencil
on touches so you can get
force.
With iPhone 6S, you have
with 3D Touch and we shift
The APIs you need to build
And Dominique Wagner is going
to present how you can
The last thing that I'd like to
We have an API for you, so you
in your apps, I think you have
with your application
So you can have dynamic
The API for that is reasonable.
It's actually, an API
And it's important now
we can display these
when you hold the command key.
Now, let's talk about what
I'd like to cover
One, the core technologies
in your applications.
And, we're going to discuss
you can build better UIs
We're going to show how
in iOS 10 can make your
And, we're going
how your application
with all new extension points.
So let's talk about
Swift 3 is probably
Because with Swift 3, every
Because we change the rules,
from Objective-C to Swift.
And we are doing that,
so it can feel native really,
So for instance, something
we are now using
to make the intent clear.
We also try to not repeat
black color now is
One thing that I really like
and core graphics
when writing UIKit application.
And, even something like,
is now a full object API.
Let's talk about grand
There is a feature that I really
with the dispatch is the
And when queue work item to be
a new thing in iOS 10, is you
to automatically wrap every work
It's real easy to do, you
and you pass the
We have a full session on GCD,
Foundation, foundation
of Swift enhancement, we dropped
and we have a major new feature,
to the foundation API.
It's not just that.
We also have full
and measurements in foundation.
Another thing is a new date
If you know what AP 601 is,
you're probably very
[ Applause ]
And another nice feature is how
better with new NS
We have two sessions
What's New in Foundation
and Measurements and Units.
Yesterday, we announced
copy on your Mac and
So how do you use that
You just use the existing UI
There is one thing
You might have to fetch a very
if I do a copy of
it might take a second or two.
So you might see this UI.
So to avoid, problem when
you should check first, if
So you can avoid this UI.
We added four new methods
so you can easily check for
Another thing in
that you can now control what
So now you can restrict your
or set an expiration date.
[ Applause ]
Now I'd like to talk
It's not a software feature,
that we have now in the new iMac
It's a technology shift, you can
that was not physically
And, we are changing how we
The iOS devices were using
Now with this device,
in that extended
So what does that mean for you?
So first, iOS is actually
iOS and [inaudible] and in iOS
to work with a wide color range.
The first way is to
UI Image View is actually
since iOS 9.3, so
What about UI Color?
We made that very simple.
We have one existing
Second one, and new one,
The first one is how you can
in the extended sRGB space.
So now you can express a
to 1 range, if you want
The second one displayP3,
displayP3 is actually
that is quite common
So if you receive a spec with
that you're going
which is why we made that,
And that's it.
We don't have a color
You can just use these two
Now, I'd like to talk
Image rendering is something
that you're probably
with the UI graphics
add image from text APIs.
Kind of thing that you do in
render an image off screen.
So there is one problem
It's actually 32 bits sRGB only,
Also, that's not our best API,
and it's not really extensible.
So, something that you're
begin image context, API,
And I don't know how many of
of trying to get the image
I'm definitely one.
But now, we have a new class,
the new UI graphics
And what this is giving you is,
It's going to do the
If you're on a 9.7
to get a wide color context.
If you're not, you will
The other thing, it's
And, it's an object
to increase our classes
Also, and that's
that class will manage the
Which means that we can do
under the hood.
Let me give you an example.
For that the equivalent
you just create your renderer.
You try to generate an
of passing the block, and
And the thing that's
if you call again, the
to just be used the
A new feature related to
With asset catalogs, we have
right to left and left to
And of course they're
with the trait system in UIKit.
So, let's see the first one.
What color asset?
So what do we want to do here?
If you're embedding,
in your application, you
on a non-wide color device.
So what we are going to do is,
of sRGB variant automatically
And that's going to be fully
so we're going to deploy
on the right device.
The other new feature in
We added support for a
And, it's going to automatically
it's going to automatically
for a given device.
So you will a great balance
And again, that's completely
so we only deploy what is
The last feature I
for asset catalog
or image asset support.
It means that now, directly
you can specify that an
or a left to right asset.
Or something that should
directly in the asset
We also have a full session on
where you can learn more about
Now, I'd like to switch
to how you can build
and interactions in iOS 10.
And the first thing is,
that everybody can interact
We have the new accessibility
and one thing you can do with
you can connect to an
immediately know the
of a given UI element.
There is another
You can also run an audit
in the simulator or your device.
Just so you can have a
of problems you might want to
to fix, with your application.
One thing though, it's just like
that doesn't mean that
absolutely perfect.
But, that's a great first step.
We also have a new
with your applications
We added a new gesture,
[ Foreign Language ]
And not just for English.
And it's a very simple API.
The SFSpeech recognizer,
that can do continuous
And, you can connect
or a live audio stream.
So you can do real time,
You can configure it to have a
for dictation, or for
Just want to give you
You create a recognizer, you
you start a task,
to call you back with results.
Really easy to use.
We have a video in line in
Another great improvement
One thing you can do now is to
of content you have
So, with that we can provide
in quick type.
So for instance if my text
I'm going to see an
We have many predefined
you can specify first name, last
and in that case
as a full street address.
Or even things like email,
Another thing about text input
and text is how you
In iOS 7 we added support for
we are making the
for dynamic type, a trait.
So what does that mean?
Before iOS 10 the content size
on UI application.
And, you actually sent
If the user was changing,
you had to react this
Now, because it's integrated
on view controllers which mean
that you can use dynamic
And we actually also added
in existing elements
So if you build your UI with
and you want to react,
now in iOS 10 you can
for content size category
text field going to
And your application, if you're
will update automatically.
So I think that's a really
full automatic support, for
[ Applause ]
We also wanted to add new
A good example is
now you can customize the batch
in tab bar items, and you can
theme color.
So let's say that I
that is going to look like that.
If I add this code, to my
to be my new tab bar UI.
Which is probably also
[ Applause ]
Another great customization,
When we ship Peek and
we had a very simple API in
And we had built in
And now in iOS 10, you
and Pop behaviors
which means that you can
when doing a Peek.
And you can have preview
of that is, when you Pop in
to stay inside your application.
It's available as new delegate
But, the thing that I'm really
is the new UI preview
So, Peek and Pop in UIKit,
There is a look, this blur
when you want to
And there is a feel, how
how do we detect the intent
a scroll, the beginning
With UI preview interaction,
to use a UIKit provided
but have your own
And, that's just a new delegate
when you move from Peek
to give you the progress,
so you can plug your own
You can do completely
and Pop UI we think
[ Applause ]
If you want to learn everything
we have a full session
Another new thing is
in scroll views that
And it's actually full support
[ Applause ]
It's available on
and scroll view of classes.
So we already had support for
so it mean that now you
in correction views.
Let's talk about
That's a great feature in UIKit.
And last year we added support
for automatic self-sizing
What you had to do before is,
you had to compute
And sometimes it's not easy but,
at the UIKit level we know
So we have a new
so you can pass automatic
that estimation for you,
that estimation anymore.
[ Applause ]
Do you know that we
in UI correction view?
We do. And we are improving
that by adding paging
That's something that is exposed
and correction view will now
But, one feature this year,
about for collection view
It's a real simple,
So, if I have a grid,
and I'm going to
At some point, I'm going to
on screen at the same time.
And if your cells are a
it might take some time
That's not great.
So what we are doing
that we call cell prefetching.
The idea here is before we
we're going to ask you for
to ask for a cell as a block
We're going to ask for one
So we're going to, amortize
up in your application.
A great thing about
If you rebuild your
you get that behavior
[ Applause ]
But there is more.
We have a new protocol, we
Because sometimes, it's not just
about doing the layout
Sometimes you need
You need to read from the disc.
You need to fetch data from the
if we could tell you hey, we are
So you can prepare, in advance.
That's exactly what
You implement a few delegate
when we, are about
so you can have the data ready.
So that's going to improve,
of your collection
And, we made also that
[ Applause ]
We have an entire session
cell prefetching,
reordering, don't miss this one.
But I think the major new
is something that we call the
It's a new animation API.
It's a new animation
to let you build
Animation you can scrub,
We are exposing a new
And it's fully dynamic.
You can add animation
And the way, I describe
just like a timeline in a movie.
Something that you can
The model is really simple,
You just have to
You set the timing
you add your animation.
And you start the animation,
that represent that animation,
or change its progress.
It's also fully integrated
in the view controller
to explain everything
in Advances in UI Animation
But I'd like to show you,
So, this is a very simple
that you could do before,
in a navigation controller.
But with this animation API,
catch that mid flight
release it, and catch
I'm going to reverse
and let the animation finish.
And what's amazing about that,
is that it's just
So we are moving the same
to interactive gesture driven
to gesture driven to
You can fully blend
and animation.
We think that's a great
to see what you're going
[ Applause ]
Now, I'd like to talk about some
And the key thing here
that you absolutely
No, it's quite the opposite,
We have new feature
to make your application better.
Features are going to
Things that are going to measure
A good example of that
Is how we changed, openURL.
So first, we made
with a completion handler but we
So you know universal link
to a social network
if you have a native app it's
But now, with this new
if there was an application
So if there was not, you can
you can still keep
of opening [inaudible]
So that's going to really
content and deal with those
Another great feature, is the
The first one is something
The idea here is, it's quite
for your menu I and
on background queues,
And what you can do is
you can actually pin,
you can control exactly when you
to another version
So it mean that you don't have
because something changed
because you can decide exactly
to a new version of your data.
That's a really great way
to simplify your core data
The other feature is,
Now in a store we
for a multiple reader,
That's going to give you
We also have, new features on
I suggest you go
in Core Data session on Friday.
Another way to model data
in your application
So CloudKit, we already had
and private per user databases.
And what we are adding in
So you can have multiple users,
So that's going to open
of application with CloudKit.
So that's great.
But something that is
with collaboration based app,
How do you invite person to
How do you do that in a way
So we added the new UI
Which is a view controller
and it's really easy to use
that is going to control
And we're going to generate
to manage the invitation
That's really easy to build
in CloudKit.
We have an entire
What's New with CloudKit,
in Presidio on Thursday.
Now, I'd like to talk
NS user activity is
to capture the state,
And, we are using that already,
for things like Handoff
What we are doing now, in iOS
for locations in user activity.
So if I'm in an application
I can express that, the
is about this address.
So you just pass a map kit item
and now you understand how
in the text field
The system will notice
is dealing with these addresses.
So that's probably a
for a text filed
That's going to open completely
if you had options
We have many new ways you
of your application with what
which is this intelligence
features in iOS 10,
Another place, where we use
So in iOS 9, we added support
It was real easy to use,
and pass text field information
and that would just
But now what you can do is,
we have a new button
And, your user can now go
and you can continue
in your own application.
It's real easy to adopt.
Step one, you need to add,
to tell us that you support
The second step is to
delegate method.
It's real easy to implement.
We are giving you the user
and display the search,
The recent thing new also
we added support for
with Core Spotlight.
But now you can actually search
We are opening the
And that's great
a fully optimized implementation
and performance and we have
So it's real easy to use.
You just build a search
and you can search the
So you can integrate
from [inaudible] coming from a
We have a new session, this year
to cover continuation,
Core Spotlight search,
We shipped Replay
to record your screen
In iOS 10, you can use
So you can have live
of your application and because
point, it mean that third-party
that live broadcast ability.
And we are using that for
Another great framework
SceneKit is really powerful
to integrate 3D interactive
The major new feature of
rendering engine,
I could say that it now
or is internally using
But I think that's
This is your fire
That's really amazing.
[ Applause ]
And it's now available
We have a full session of
Then I'd like to
Two things about Apple Pay.
First, we are extending
to be available to your users.
Today, Apple Pay is on
and as you learned
that Apple Pay on the web.
We have support for
So for users, Apple
But what's great
we already have support
in your UIKit based application.
But now, you can use
with the new Javascript
But it could also mean
in your [inaudible]
The other place where you
is in non-UI code.
We have a new API,
And using Apple Pay in
that's a great feature for
This is the kind of flow
in messages with an extension.
I would like to point you to
The first one that
at the same time
And just after that,
in Wallet in Apple Pay.
I would like to, finish with
How you can integrate with iOS.
We have major new
messages, Siri, CallKit.
We also improved
for instance something
now you can use the same
from your keyboard extension.
We can also give you
the user is interacting with.
So you can build
in your third-party extension.
Another thing that we
is the new display
So, before, you were just,
with you preferred size.
Now we have a user
The compact mode, which is fixed
which is variable height.
It's really easy to adopt.
You don't have to do
so you can know when the
from compact to extended.
You can give us a maximum size,
You can customize the
There is one thing that,
widget though is, this is going
So, be careful about the kind
One thing to keep in mind is,
of data you're presenting
If I configure, if
to my home screen,
I expect that I'm always going
at the same level of privacy
to be surprised by thing
on my lock screen when
A completely new framework in
So user notification, that's
at the UI application level.
We have a new framework but, we
We are adding a few
First, we are unifying local
So much easier to deal with.
[ Applause ]
You have better control on
how we are going to deliver
Another great thing is,
before displaying
So in-app, you have
on the notification itself.
And, that's also a unified model
In addition to these
we also have two extensions.
The first one is the
The service extension is
on the device when we are
and before, it's
So you can process the payload
And, two great use cases, the
You can have media attachment,
But if you know what you want
you can, when receiving
fetch that and display.
And the other great feature
because now you're in
On the server and
So you can receive something,
and decrypt that
We think that's a
and great new possibility
[ Applause ]
This is the other
for the user notification
You can have embedded UI
There is one restriction though,
with the view, but you have
We have two session on user
to Notification and
in Pacific Heights on Wednesday.
Another new framework in
we are offering a new
The directory extension,
we let you configure how we
You have full control on that.
The second feature is, how
and display our label.
So when we receive a call,
in the address book and then
we can add your extension.
It's real easy to use API.
It's non-UI extension point.
It's really two methods.
But the real great new feature
in CallKit is the
With the call provider API,
we have a real first
for your voice over
Which mean that now,
like full screen
when you receive a
But it's not just that,
we are fully integrating
with a core management on iOS.
And things like,
we are automatically get, the
You can support Siri,
you will be integrated with
That's a major new
[ Applause ]
We can learn all about
Over IP apps with CallKit.
I'd like to talk about Siri.
So, you might not
But Siri is actually
depending on the context.
So if you're using Siri,
with the home button, or if
or if you're using
or as an accessibility feature.
Siri is going to tune
so you can have the best
It's a quite complex task.
Because it's involved
understanding the domain,
and that's something that we
when you build a
What we're going to give you,
is an intent representing
and that's how your extension
And, you can also help Siri
which might be specific to your
so we can again,
of the interaction with Siri.
So how did that work?
The idea behind intents
it's a non-UI extension that
between Siri and
So it's based on the
coming from Siri and responses.
And the main idea here is,
intents are a domain
So you have the messaging
the payment domain, etcetera.
And for messaging, you
that Siri can recognize
to your application for
So the main goal here, for
to make sure that, you and
when Siri understood a request.
That valid request, that we need
let's execute the request,
And when you use Siri
"tell Miko on WWDC chat
after this session," what
in the intent is the fact that,
It's the same messaging intent,
that's about your app and
We have a second
that the intents UI extension.
It's actually an
But with that you can embed
so you can have a confirmation
That's really great.
And, another great thing
it's not just about Siri.
It's a way to describe the
that in Siri to communicate
But, that's also how we
that's how we do the right
And the reason the
really great is that's how
to the system about what
For instance, in
And it's combined with and
and with that, let's say
that I am sending a message
then in the contacts UI, we're
about this contacts
And when we have,
we can show you directly your
that information
And at some point,
your application will be
in the standard contact card.
That's really amazing in term
of adding visibility
I'd like to conclude
So, messages is really
and we have two features
and the other one is
So sticker packs, no code
to package your images,
You use Xcode for that and
that on the messages store.
The other thing you can do,
with iMessage apps is use
With that you can write, a
and you can do things like,
dynamically generating
You can even use a
which is completely new.
And, you can tune your
or expanded mode and that's
that's a great feature
You can custom the
it mean that your extension,
using the messages
a concept of a conversation in
connect with what the
We have full support
in [inaudible] and iOS 10.
That's real easy to use and
to integrate in messages.
The other thing that you can
completely custom content
We have two session for iMessage
and sticker, that was this
focusing on the extension part
at 1:40 p.m. Thank you
[ Applause ]