[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to what's
[ Applause ]
I'm Hans, and I'm an
We're really thrilled
to the very first WWDC for tvOS.
[ Applause ]
So I'd like to begin
with a brief overview of tvOS.
And we'll walk you through some
And then we'll take a few of
And we even have
So let's begin.
Just nine months ago we
and with it the tvOS.
tvOS is a modern
for modern hardware,
with no 32-bit runtime.
So it would save you
that you'd spent testing
or configuring for
And unlike your iPhone,
the Apple TV is always connected
And this makes tvOS
where you can offload some tasks
user data, or even your
such as CloudKit and
CloudKit is your interface
to an almost infinite
It offers a structure
It also provides a public and
So as you've heard in
it can be accessed from
and can also be shared.
And thanks to iCloud
to ask your customers for
And this is still true even if
on other platforms that
And by using CloudKit JS and its
to roll your own solution
of the security and efficiency.
Now, traditionally customers
to be able to launch
And as app grows in size,
Because we don't wait 800
And this is not only
but also a challenge
because customers
in our apps before they
On-demand resources
of Apple TV's constant
and provides a mechanism
by which your app can
of its content is downloaded.
This means for your customers,
And while the app
the system can continue
so they're ready
minimizing further wait time.
And also, applications can
much larger than was
Let's take a look at this.
Every app has a main app bundle
of executable and
And when using ODR, your
up to 200 megabytes.
To this you can add a first
with the app bundle so they're
For example, this could be the
This first set is called
and this can be up
What if you have more contents?
Well, you can specific
to be downloaded
And this is called
And prefetch tags are
that you know you'll need
to justify blocking your
thereby preventing your
So, for example, if your user is
the system will start
five, and six.
And by the time the user is
the next levels are
and waiting for the user.
So the wait has been shifted
And the system doesn't mind
Prefetch tags can be
using the rest of the allowance.
So, for example, if
for initial install tags,
then you have 3.5
If you've spent all
of your initial install tags,
then naturally you
for your prefetch tags.
What if you had no
Well, math says it's
for your prefetch tags.
But you might want to
into initial install tags
In similar way as the
more assets packs
And the total downloadable
up to 20 gigabytes, making the
and downloadable content at
[ Applause ]
And this is not just a big
that does not feel to the
because they can get started
to use the app without
Transistor is a great game and
It has 160 megabytes of app
of initial install tags, so it
But thanks to 900
gamers are continuously
gorgeous game levels without
But ODR is not just for games.
One of my favorite
Earthlapse TV presents
from International Space Station
to the space right
It has over one gigabyte of
And yet, it downloads
and there's virtually any wait
So that's ODR.
And that, by the way, is Canada
[ Applause ]
Now, let's take a look at
We use our phone every day and
But it's unique in
and our action are
of us on the touch surface.
When you're looking
our attention is 10 feet away
and our action is on the
There's no direct
tvOS provides a unique
to make this experience
First is the Siri Remote.
Through its touch surface
focused-based interaction
for this kind of environment.
By pressing buttons and using
users can move focus from
stop on a specific one, and
To complement this
tvOS also introduces
The parallax effect gives you
and also the feeling that you
And the best way
of the parallax effect is
A layered image is an image
and it increases
when an element is in focus.
It can have up to five layers
and is actually required
And to create a new
you can use Xcode's
the Parallax Previewer
and the Parallax Exporter
And of course, all of these
at developer.apple.com.
Now, let's take a step back and
The Home screen is where
best illustrated.
Above the first row of app icons
and apps placed on the first
Your apps can present the most
as shortcuts to the
so your customers can
And this could be, for example,
album art for music,
that makes sense for your app.
Top Shelf is a great conduit
into your app, so
that you take advantage
of it beyond providing
Now let's come back to
The Home screen is a collection
And as you've heard
we believe the future
And all of this is
The App Store, just like on
discover, and download apps.
And because it exists
it supports universal purchase.
So if your customer has
they can enjoy the app on tvOS
with just one button
And thanks to Apple TV's
in tvOS 10 we're
So apps downloaded on iOS will
to the TV just like that.
So it's even easier
to get a hold of your apps.
But how are you going
tvOS offers the same
as iOS, Mac OS, and watchOS.
And many of the same frameworks
such as UIKit, Foundation,
Core Audio, and so on and so
And by the way, in tvOS 9.2
But this is still a partial list
of a whole lot more you
For example, if you're
you'd be excited to learn
that you love are all
Game Controller, GameplayKit,
Performance Traders, SpriteKit,
these are all available
And finally, tvOS introduces a
called TVMLKit.
TVMLKit makes it
to build content-centric
of the heavy lifting,
and focus management, for you.
And it does so with
and JavaScript for
It is really great for rapidly
And, of course, it's tuned
In fact, several of Apple's own
the Movies app.
And that's right, the App Store
And all of the developer tools
and optimize your apps, such
and TestFlight are also
This year tvOS continues to
As you've heard in the keynote,
so you can control
from your TV.
We're also bringing PhotoKit
so your app can leverage your
Using SpriteKit is even easier
from the focus engine.
Your movement and navigation
and fully integrated with
Speaking of movement and
of gameplay is how
You can hold the Siri
as a lightweight game controller
and clicks for jumping, for
If your title requires
you can hold it landscape as a
and two-button controls.
Well, if your game title
input, you can use the
and as you heard in the State of
You now have an option
of MFI-based game controllers,
and the app store will
if it's necessary.
We're also bringing
Using ReplayKit, players can
on device and share it
But that's not all; game
gameplays live on
In tvOS 10 we're also
UserNotification.framework
and also
for Bluetooth accessories
We're also shipping a brand
And finally, users can set
to light or dark.
And when you're actually
you have many options.
You might want to use UIKit as
of all the available frameworks.
If you're already comfortable
or if you have an
we have some great sessions
including mastering
where you can take your
And in Focus Interaction
we review the Focus system,
on tvOS 10, and of
We also recommend that
TVMLKit is an incredibly
And if your skillset already
it's really easy to use
and deploy content-centric apps.
And because TVMLKit is built on
in UIKit for further
And these sessions focus on
and we highly encourage you
And if you are a game
all the game technologies
as GameKit might
Next I'd like to switch gears
of the new features in tvOS 10.
And for that, I'd
over to my colleague,
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Marshall.
I'm a tvOS engineer.
And today we're going to dive
of the new features
We heard in the keynote
that there's a new
We'll take a look at how
to notify users when you
And finally, we're going to look
at how you can implement
in your app.
So the new Apple TV Remote app
so there's no changes
for your app to make it work.
It also includes a new
so users can use
Now, if the user is using the
against the game controller
to get a new icon in
that looks like this.
When that user taps that
with a Game Controller
by rotating the phone.
To learn more how
of Game Controller framework,
we have a session coming
Also, as you heard, the
So go download it
Next we're going to take
and how you can use
when you have new
A great way of doing
to is badging your
And we've added this
Now, like iOS you're required
from the user in order to
But on tvOS this looks
They're going to get a
So make sure that you
at an appropriate time, or this
user has with your app.
We've also added support
so you can use Apple's
to send remote notifications.
We support two notification
Those are Badge, which we just
Now, if your app is
then these content-available
up your app like you
Let's take a look
So say your user has
A great way to notify them would
with content-available
If the application's
onto this notification and
Now, the user gets
so you can send another
that updates the Badge icon.
tvOS will hold onto the
for the app to come back.
And finally, you get
and you can update
When the user is ready
and see what they have is
And then we deliver that last
to your servers and get
that's available.
In order to support
to use the new user
If you've implemented
you might be used to
Well, those have been
and they're going to
So in order to fully
and [inaudible] notifications,
to use the new user
We have a few sessions
on how you can learn to fully
And finally today, we're going
and dark appearance on tvOS.
We see that that this is a
The user will determine
between light or dark.
Now, something to consider is
that users might have their
It could be in a movie
it could be in a living room,
Or the user may change
So it's important in order
to offer them the
In order to fully support
on the UITraitCollection,
for the dark appearance.
If you don't opt-in for the dark
in the light just
So let's take a look at
to adopt the new light and
The first step is to add a
we've added one called
If you set a value of Light, it
If you set a value to Dark,
Or if you use what we recommend,
and the system setting and will
If you create new projects
this will actually
I mentioned that there is
We've added a new property
This could have a
which might the case if your
in the view hierarchy yet, or if
on what the system setting is
In order to support
we've added developer
to Interface Builder
If you use standard
these will actually
If you're used to using
with a little bit
you can then specify colors
And if you want the
you can implement
in your views or
Now in Interface Builder
in the inspector
We added a light and dark
so you can rapidly develop
We've also added a shortcut
to quick toggle between
I mentioned UIKit controls
And we use these a lot
We see that certain views like
or [inaudible] control
to look best against
If you use a table view like
it will automatically adjust
its text color, and
And if you're using the
than those adapt as well.
If you're looking to customize
to UILabel and UITextView,
so those will automatically
Text color will be set to
it will be set to white
But one caveat is if you
then you're responsible
for both those modes
We've also added two new
You can now use
or UIBlurEffectStyleProminent.
And we call these
And they'll actually adjust
based on what the
So if you use
and the system's in light,
it will use
If you use regular and
If you use prominent, it will
.extraDark will be
Now, you might customize your
So you might have code like this
that sets the title
With a little bit
we can vend a TraitCollection
And using the appearance
for each of those
Now in this case our button will
and blue in the dark appearance.
And finally, if you want the
you can respond to
You can do this using
in your views or
Let's take a look at
of this would look like.
First we override
in our view controller.
Then we check to make sure
to the new user interface
This allows us to build this
but still support users
Next we check to see that the
changed; otherwise we might be
And finally, we can check
and update our controls
Now, one more advanced use
to override TraitCollections.
And this might be the case
to support the automatic style
or view controllers in
to specify the style itself.
We use this in our system apps,
and TV shows actually
on what the elements look like.
In this case we have light
in button styles that
We also have dark pages where we
and the buttons also
In order to override
we use API that was
And this is
for ChildViewController.
In order to use this we can
Let's see what an example
First we create a new class,
and we inherit from
We can add a property that has
to set in our
And then we can another property
where we actually set the view
to set that style for.
Then we use a
for ChildViewController using
And finally, we use standard
Now, if you wanted
we could vend our
specify the style
on whatever attributes we want,
and then we can present
Next, I'd like to invite Brandon
to update your app for tvOS 10.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Marshall.
Hi, everyone.
My name's Brandon,
to show you the tvOS app
It's called Fireplaces
And fireplace enthusiasts
Let's take a look.
This app allows to you
from around the world
Let's see what a fireplace
Ahh, doesn't it feel
I think this is great.
Now, even though the simulator
our app is using the light
because we haven't
I'm excited to adopt
so let's go update our app now.
The first thing we need to do is
key to our Info.plist.
We'll set the value to
We chose automatic because
to match the user's
Okay. This is looking
So all of our standard
updated automatically.
So in this case the tab bar
and the wallpaper now
For some of you this
to do to update your apps.
However, our designers
that they want a different logo
And the background color on the
out a little bit too much.
So let's go make those changes.
So let's go to our
And the first thing
because this is an
we need to enable the trait
So to do that, we'll go to
on this Use Trait
When we do that, we're
that trait variations
with Xcode 8 or later.
And that's fine,
So now we'll click on our logo,
And there's these
to some of the properties.
So we'll click on that and add a
and we'll specify yellow.
Now, one cool feature of Xcode 8
between the light and
within Interface Builder.
To do that we'll go to the
and click on this View As:
And we have two options here.
We have light and dark.
When we click dark everything
So our logo changed color
and wallpaper have
So that looks pretty good.
So let's go update
In our AppDelegate we're
of our CollectionViewCell
Now, we want the
to change based on
So we need to use a
So first we'll start out by
So let light equals
with a UserInterfaceStyle
Then we'll replace our
with a trait-specific
So for TraitCollection,
in the TraitCollection
We'll do the same for dark
and specify a different
Now, because we can't view this
in Interface Builder,
We've added a keyboard
quickly switch between the light
and dark appearances
To do that, we'll
to switch the light appearance
to switch back to
So that's looking
But I've noticed that the
that we've changed
So let's go update that as well.
So we'll go to our to custom
and before we were
in our awakeFromNib function.
Since we want the
when our TraitCollection change,
we'll override the
function.
We'll use the same
for our light interface style,
and for our dark we'll
Now, TraitCollectionDidChange
added to a view hierarchy.
So we remove our
But for backwards
we'll just leave it in there.
Let's run our app,
Okay. That looks much better.
So let's switch to
make sure nothing has changed.
And that still looks good.
And we'll switch back
to the dark appearance,
So we've just updated our app
and we're ready to
Now I'd like to invite
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Brandon.
That was a very cool
So as you've seen,
and dark appearance
So we hope all of you can adopt
This afternoon we
of the many features in tvOS.
tvOS offers the same tools,
that you already know so it's
And focus-based interaction,
with parallax effect and Top
to create a direct and
And with Universal
your customers are ever-closer
We're also shipping a brand
And it's available as a
and test your app with it.
And with ReplayKit and
from Focus Engine, game
And finally, users can set
to their liking.
We hope you're excited
and you can learn even more
sessions this week.
And the Apple TV
from earlier this
in guiding you through
And they're available at
And of course, all this
on the session link.
Finally, we can't wait
to see the great things you
Thank you so much for coming,
and enjoy the rest
[ Applause ]