[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Hello, and welcome.
My name is Tony Parker.
I am the manager of the
and I'm here with my
about what's new in
This year the Foundation
into improving the way
and Cocoa Touch APIs in Swift.
We started by working on the
After that, we looked at how
that the Cocoa SDK uses and your
but we knew that we
So, we have introduced a
in Foundation, and
of new Swift-specific API.
So, let's go ahead and jump
Now, this year we're
from the beginning our goals for
We want you to write code that's
We've built the libraries,
and the language
And many of you have also
principals and built your
However, we all know that there
and that it the Cocoa SDK.
Your app depends on this just as
the Swift standard library.
It needs to feel like it's
Because the SDK is a
about how we develop apps on our
that the language and the
So this year we focused on
When I say expressive,
in two different ways.
First is your ability as app
that expresses your intent to
but it goes the other way too.
The libraries need to be
their design patterns and
to use the API to
And so, while working
we focused on this idea of
Every decision made about those
of the idea that the language
and the libraries
They have to work together.
So, for example,
they bring a huge
Many of the features that
of our platforms this year
in the libraries that you
to improve your experience.
These libraries have a
of our platforms, including
and Swift Open Source.
So, we have Swift
which is bringing the
to other platforms like Linux.
These libraries have a
Many of them have been
of OS X or even further back.
They also bring with them,
thanks to the Cocoa
a consistent set of conventions.
This means that when you
you can understand how it works
and what it does
And finally and importantly,
under continuous and
Not only are we adding
but we're making enhancements,
and we're going to continue
as we release new OSs.
Now, on the other hand,
brings with it things that we
For example, first class
and built in support for
of Swift's story about safety.
There's also things like
function overloading, and
all of which make
on how you design
This isn't a complete
by the way I just
There's plenty more
So, we came up with
The first was SE-0023,
Now, all these documents
to the Swift Evolution
and the rest of the
to participate in the design
Now, we see these guidelines as
and future Swift libraries.
Along with that we have SE-0006,
which applied those design
giving us a consistent and
that we can build on
which dramatically improved the
by doing things like
improving option sets
even automatically adopting
We had a whole talk about this
that you check out if you missed
Now, all these were
but we knew that we
That's because Swift goals
Mutability in particular is
and so, we turned our
Now, if you're wondering
The answer is because
and I'm not just saying
Foundation occupies a
What's interesting about it
to be used everywhere, on all
Yet, at the same time,
to establish a whole new set of
that again you see reflected
If we go back to our picture
in on the Cocoa SDK, you'll see
in your apps every day, from
to CoreData, and many
that don't fit here either.
Now, what's interesting
of these are built
So, we see Foundation
What that means is that we can
in Foundation, and that can have
Partly, that's because
of many value types.
So, we focused on this idea
We've seen everything
to the development of your apps.
We're not going to
because we have a new language.
Instead what we're doing is
and the libraries
by making incremental
The changes that we're talking
about today are a
And so with that in mind,
the Foundation team put forth
to the Swift Evolution
The first was mutability
which is about embracing
in the Foundation framework.
And also, dropping the NS
which is about establishing
and design patterns for Swift,
no matter which platform
So here is an overview of some
of the API improvements
First and foremost, value
of value types that you're
Beyond that, we did
of naming improvements,
beyond what the Objective-C
We've adopted many
on these types, which means
that your generic
on Foundation types as well.
We've added additional
of new Swift-specific features.
So, let's do a quick
Now, value types
from reference types, primarily
around copying, so value types
or passed as a parameter.
Here's a quick example.
I've got a point.
I use the equals operator
to another point, and when
you see that only
I didn't affect the
That's because CGPoint
Now, on the other hand,
reference types share
Here I'm going to create some
and its mutable data.
Then I use that same
that data to otherData.
However, this time, when
you can see that it
Now, it's important to
of these is better
You just use them
I like to think of it as a
that you can reach for when
to solve.
So, when you're trying
if your type is a value
you should think about object
Let me explain by way
So, in Foundation, we
OperationQueue has a singleton,
That operation queue,
is where you put
to happen on the main thread.
And so, there's only
It has a kind of identity.
If I were to copy the main
longer be the main
So, we believe
that OperationQueue
Another example, a pattern
that you see throughout the
So here is the delegate,
for URL session,
that the delegate protocol
called Session, and that
delegated to which URLSession
and that idea of which
again, identity.
So, we believe that types
with delegates are
On the other hand,
about their store contents.
For example, Date.
This is one of our new
Date is an absolute
We can have two Dates
the same absolute point in time,
and be talking about
We don't need to talk about the
In fact, if we look inside
as you see here, it's
and a double is something
of already intuitively
Another example is Data.
Data is another one of our
Data, normally you care about
the bytes that are there, not
So, Foundation has made
Now, copying the data
as a parameter would
So, we performed an optimization
So, here I'm going
and you see I've got a
I also have a reference.
So, another example of
when they work together.
Here I'm using both a
to get the performance
that I want along with the value
Now, if I use that equal
to another data,
that I've got another
at the same class
However, if I mutate that Data,
mutate the copy, and now we've
If I continue to
we can tell that that Data
and we don't need to
So, this is an extension, or
of the same technique that
including last year,
and value types in Swift.
So, check that out if you
on how this works.
So, we did a survey of
and we came up with
that we think would
and I think you'll be happy
that you use every
That includes Data and
but also other types that
IndexPath, CharacterSet,
And many of these types not
but gained a lot of
Now, to give you an idea
I'd like to invite
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tony.
Let's start by visiting
of Foundation's enumerations.
Now, as you know,
and option sets live in
alongside the types
For example, NSNumberFormatter
for the style, behavior, pad
And each of these are implicitly
through careful and
In Swift 2 as you
to the global namespace as well.
But that doesn't feel
Swift supports nested types,
and so in Swift 3 we made the
to be declared inside,
So NumberFormatter now has
behavior, pad position,
And their names are
and this greatly reduces
that Foundation declares
and now the relationship
our APIs more expressive
Sticking with the
many Foundation APIs also use
Examples include notification
Now of course, Swift has support
on raw representations
than integers, including string.
Wouldn't it be great if
in Objective-C?
Well, new this year we can, and
in terms of very specific
like notification name
and many, many more.
And these constants remain
and also in Swift, where we can
like their integral
in Swift 3 is both
Now another common Foundation
state with a type.
For instance, the
Now, of course, Swift support
for class properties are
and new in this year, we
to Objective-C, and
like instance properties,
except we now accept
and because we know that
we no longer need to
as we did in Swift 2.2.
It can now appear as a class
if you were defining
But we didn't stop there.
There's some redundant
we overhauled the way that
or Objective-C code
so that our final API could
We know it's our user defaults,
to be more Swift-like, we've
for both Objective-C and Swift.
Now Tony mentioned many
to be value types, and so I'm
We'll start with Date.
Now let's suppose we want
for when we should go home.
We'll start with Swift 2.2,
Let's suppose that we have
when we need to go home, and we
like a good time for our
you know, offset
Now, it's worth pointing
and remains a reference type,
potentially two dynamic
One here, and another here.
Now in Swift 3, we gain
So, let's go ahead and use it,
and consuming it
however now this var takes on
We specifically, we now
And so, we've done zero,
these two examples here are
except with the value
dynamic allocations.
Let's continue our example.
Now, of course, we can
Now, with reminders, it's
to schedule them if
and one of the great
to the table is automatic
when you satisfy certain
Date Auto has conforms
which gives us access
than operator, which we use now.
And we can go ahead
but first we need to create it.
And so we'll use another new
which is this fancy
where we initialize the
So no more selectors
and we'll schedule it
[ Applause ]
I'll also call out thread
and run loop have those
And we schedule them on our
And this is a great
of these familiar Foundation
across so beautifully
This is some of the most
possibly have in a demo.
I have a run loop, I have
I just, there's only
and this is pretty
And there isn't a
So, another new example,
in Foundation is the
And let's suppose with
we care about how
and we're lucky enough to
from where we work.
Now, measurements
and Swift supports
and not only are they
They're mathematical in
to specify operators on them.
No one will look the other
if we contemplate
and so we can compute their sum,
to a different kind of unit.
And let's suppose we were
for us to get to work.
Well, we could do that as
if we were to try to build
and it would fail at
thanks to the power of Swift 3's
we actually have designed this
in units is knowable
and so the Swift compiler
that we're trying to do
To learn more about
and the whole new
that we've introduced this year,
on Friday afternoon
about measurements and units.
I'm going to switch
I did say this was going
Suppose we want to
We'll use the new URL
and we can do this
We'll begin by describing
which we'll use as
And we iterate through
to purchase, make a copy of
that copy, specifying the
Note that we're safe
to explicitly unwrap
because we specified that it was
We can go ahead and
that we have been able to build,
like to purchase with no
All we had to do was
or not something was mutable or
of the rest of the
Now, another thing
or Swift in general brings
to the table is protocol
In many Foundation
getting useful new capabilities
For instance, CharacterSet
and IndexSet are now
So you can union, intersect, and
to your hearts' content.
Data is also now a
MutableRandomAccessCollection
but, like you always
Let's look at some of the
of Data's new conformances.
First we're going to need
to have some base64
which we'll parse using
In the explicit unwrap here
because this is a demo,
and I know that that's
You should probably use a
for yourself, but let's say,
and the nice thing to look
at when you have
That's always a good
So we're going to
We'll use as our
we'll use a native Swift array,
and we'll just use the byte
as the index and maintain
So let's, because Data
through its bytes, is natural
with a four N loop, and so
And let's take a look.
Well that definitely
and like all histograms,
and I'm seeing a lot of high
and I'd like to filter that out,
and luckily Data's a collection
to things like Map,
and all of your other
And so, let's say we wanted
that was greater than three.
It's as simple as
and we can generate
And also as a collection,
and these slices work just
or value type collections
that you're already
Mutating them invokes the
that Tony described earlier and
Now, Data also remains
of the underlying
and that's a very big sentence,
to show what I mean by that.
As an example, let's go ahead
and create a custom
that allocates no storage,
but represents a virtual
We'll call it an AllOnesData.
Very descriptive.
And I'm only going to show the
here, specifically
of this class is more
We set all the bytes to one.
So we don't need to store
and create a read-only
But we won't just
We're actually going
that wraps the reference
And using that, we just use
and it works exactly the
We have a ones value type that's
of all ones, and those
They don't actually consume
Let's go ahead and create
we've not done any mutation,
or manifest any of those
But let's get ready to mutate
we're going to actually use
year, which is the
called withUnsafe MutableBytes.
And this is much better than
on the data itself, because
to those bytes within the
which it makes it very easy to
you don't have pointers
Pointers are only going to
And so we actually perform our
on right machinery, and
the copies bytes are now
Let's move on to
I'm tired of talking about Data.
Let's talk about, URLs
Now to motivate this
about how we did
So in Swift 2.2, we would
we're going to talk about by
so special, I keep it at
And I'm curious about
I care about the creation date,
and for some reason, the
that this file's located on.
And these are just strings
this is just an array
And when I ask my URL
I just get a regular dictionary,
It's just a string to an
that result requires a lot of
you know, suggest
and suggest that
and I'm constantly consulting
that I'm getting it right, and
in terms of the dictionary.
And so you can do
and it's every failure is
So, let's see how this
In Swift 3, creating
but we no longer use a
This is moved into a
We're still talking
and instead of asking with an
to use those new strongly
that I mentioned earlier, and
and when we ask the URL
no longer are we going
but instead we're
a new Foundation value
that Foundation value type
that we're asking
As you can see, creation
its regular file is a Bool,
and volume maximum file
And it's also worth pointing
out that the URLResourceValue
It's still implemented in terms
in the Swift 2 API, so we're not
of things that are
It's still going to be,
I get potentially
And further, if you
the dictionary is still here,
to ask for a string,
for the URL resource key
Now, you might be noticing
and the reason why is, well,
The first is that you
So, if you didn't ask for the
and that again, goes back to
The second reason why
that the property itself might
of VolumeMaximumFileSize.
Let's look at two
So because we asked for regular
to explicitly unwrap
It will be there.
We asked for it.
However, the documentation
that not all volumes and not all
file system size, and so
And as a perfect example of a
in Swift, to conditionally
Now, let's talk about mutation.
Of course, the mutation
in URLResourceValues is in
and so when you try
even though this is my special
to say that it's not regular,
at compile time instead
that problem at run time.
And further, the creation date
and so something absurd
with Siri, can't work with code.
Now the last thing
about on this Foundation
about Swift's native
And we're going to talk about
because there's a
When data takes ownership
you have the option of
Data supports many
and including the option to
Now, Swift supports
and oftentimes you'll
integers where you can do case
to be able to, you know, do
with it, but here
because we actually want
that you want to provide.
Let's see this in action.
We'll start simple
Of course, you can
although you probably don't
So, you malloc, and when you
you can, you'll deallocate
and the syntax there
as using the integration
Let's look at a custom example.
Let's suppose we have a
to create glorious pointers,
that we free gloriously,
and so we can specify the custom
as providing a closure
that you do the custom
And this is really powerful, and
for framework developers,
because in other languages
to provide a second
but now in Swift 3, we can
that expresses all of
and expressively.
And so that concludes our
Hopefully we saw a great
to hand things back to Tony
to talk a little
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Michael.
All right, now you've seen just
Let's talk about how you
First, let's talk
So, keeping with this theme
we've extended the
that you're already familiar
between Objective-C and Swift,
and NSString are
that exact same concepts
and all the other value
That means that all
from Cocoa SDK is going to
and that's a key part of how we
So for example, in
you'll see this class called
presents a UI to allow your
among others, two properties
and you see here their
and also NSDate reference types.
In Swift 3, with no
just by making these
this class looks like this.
You see we've got the struct
to mark this as @NSCopying
and we handle the
Now there can be a performance
and to explain what that is, I'd
on how the bridging
We have two major strategies for
which hold a reference, and
which create a reference.
So, for example, we're
Here I've created data
that wraps a reference type.
Now, if I call some
that we hand the reference
That's because, of course,
Objective-C doesn't
It only understands NSData.
Now, in this case perhaps
that Objective-C code isn't
for any period of time.
It may access it, and
So, just holding the reference
for a short period
On the other hand, you'll see
take a data for longer period
as properties that have
In that case, in Objective-C,
this Objective-C code will
and that's because it
from any potential mutation
that it just received from
So that means that when crossing
Let's flip that around
Let's say I've got
that is calling an Objective-C
Here, the Objective-C
created the class NSData and
we create the struct Data,
and it calls copy, for exactly
in the previous slide.
The struct needs to maintain
so that it can provide the
Fortunately, almost all data
from the SDK is immutable,
which means that the copy
However, it is important
that when crossing this
For small types, like Date, you
We saw earlier the
just had a double.
So, in Swift, if we call an
which takes a date, then we
on the bridging, and
because the Objective-C
to deal with references.
Now, we do a lot of tricks in
of things like NSDates
However, it is important
that an allocation can
So, we optimize these
In your code, you should
over that bridge repeatedly.
This is because we wanted our
but it does mean that there
So, something to be aware
at adopting these
Next, let's talk
So, first, some good news.
These new types we're
for all Swift deployment
They're part of the
which means you don't need
to upgrade to the newest
As soon as Swift 3 and
you can begin using
Now, to help you, we've of
and that means that when you
you'll see a dialog box like
that you click convert.
So, let me show you a few things
that the Migrator
So here we have in
and we're calling a method on
The Migrator will fix up
into the value type
and it will change the methods
because they've changed
to our new Swift 3
both for the reference types
Here's another example.
Here, I'm creating an
and then setting some of its
because NSDateComponents is an
Now, in Swift 3,
we've introduced a
So the Migrator will change
but also it notices that you're
to a var for you as well.
Now the Migrator can
but there are some places
at what it's done, you can do
of some additional things
In this case, DateComponents
and this is something
The initializer has
in the DateComponents,
and they all have
which means that you can create
values you care about, your
And you can change
because now you don't
after you've initialized it.
And finally, our
Here in Swift 2, see that I'm
the reference type, and
In Swift 3, the Migrator
like contentsOf URL,
and it will change NSData
However, it's left the
type alone.
In some cases like this, there's
for the Migrator in order
to do what we think is the
to leave it as is and
However, if you go back and
on your own, you can
We can change the
which means that we
And we can remove
because it has a
So, we've talked
and I'd like to just
We believe that these
to Foundation are going
and your whole development
Partly that was due
but we also took the
and add a brand new
and a lot of new
We see this as the start
to continue to be this
We're going to make many
to make your Swift apps safer,
So for more information,
and these related sessions,
with Swift Open Source,
[ Applause ]
Thank you.