[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks very much.
So I'm excited to tell you all
Now, of course we've
on optimizing the
and there's been a ton
to make sure that all of your
We've also spent a bunch of
and that's really in service
because the faster we can
the faster they can
and the faster we can
to drop their wrist again,
Now in addition to all these
we've also spent a bunch of
in all of our apps as well.
Now all of those
around three key qualities for
and warn you you will
about throughout the rest of
So the first one is making
Now, being a glanceable
of different things, and it
because having a complication
on the watch face gives you
to present the most important
to the user at just a glance.
Of course, in watchOS
In watchOS 3, that functionality
which is a great place to
as well, because it's really
on the system and gives you
and summary of the best and
from your apps.
So in addition to being
of our apps to be actionable,
of different things as well.
It might mean that you take
You've seen that we've
of our built-in apps
that the most common actions
with just a couple of taps.
The Workout app, you can
and start a workout
The timer app now raises
that you'll want to set
so that once you're in it,
with just one tap you can
And so this kind of
that we definitely would
figure out the things that
in your apps, and brings
and make them really
Of course, being actionable
that you have to be able to take
It might just mean presenting
to act on, even if they're
to take an action on the watch.
Again, complications are
and the new dock as well,
presenting the most
that users can then go and act
And then the third quality,
making sure that your apps are
as soon as the users want them.
And a bunch of the
in watchOS 3 is really
of making all of the apps
By keeping them in memory,
which we'll talk a little bit
that they can resume really
that they're as responsive
And the best thing that you
that your apps remain
to do adopt the new background
which we'll talk about in
that your apps already have
to display to the user when
So thinking about apps,
to a full-screen view of an app.
That's what a lot
about when they first
but that may not be the
to interact with your
because to keep interaction
there's some other really great
to use for a lot of the most
Of course, there's
on the watch face,
And notifications,
at the most relevant time.
And notifications on Apple
to run code to populate the
and custom UI to present
And of course, with the new dock
to your apps with just the
no matter where you
Now, apps in the doc are great,
because they're immediately
As soon as you tap on
and you can interact
without having to wait at all.
The dock is great, not just for
but also for consuming
Glances in watchOS 2, that
into the dock in watchOS
through a view of
from your favorite
to get a high-level overview of
So the dock combines the best
with quick access to your apps
to provide even more
So for something like reminders,
You can get a quick overview of
and you can tap in to
and make it interactive,
For other kinds of apps, you
For example, the Workout app,
we've brought those most
to perform right to the top
tap in to bring the app full
be starting your workouts.
But the dock is also,
great for just viewing
So an app like the
for just getting a summary of
And with the Activity
up the full screen, you can
that's really glanceable
The Activity app itself has
into it to simplify the
So where in watchOS 2 it was
each of which could scroll
there's just one view,
that has the summary of
and some of the detail below.
So it's really easy
to get the information
Now, we want to keep
as short as possible, and
and the enhancements
and live right away
that the most tasks
on Apple Watch can
in just a couple of seconds.
And so as you're thinking about
for Apple Watch, for watchOS
and you're contemplating
I would definitely
of time thinking about how
Two seconds is obviously a
for that can really help
to design your apps to make
on Apple Watch as possible.
So with the rest of our time, I
The first is Background
As I mentioned, this is a
that is Background App
for building responsive
to spend a bunch of
Then I also wanted
about simplifying navigation,
to simplify navigation
but the next step is
within your apps as well.
And so we've got some ideas of
that we'll share, and
that I'm sure you can come up
in your own apps as well.
Then we'll spend
about expanding API
We've brought some
from our platforms,
We've got some brand new ones,
and we've got some
to our existing frameworks
about a bunch of the
and give you some great
that have even more detail.
And then we'll end by
and configuration, because
the first step.
You also need to get
and configure it on their watch.
So let's get started with
Background App Refresh
of building a responsive
And before you've
Background App Refresh is
You don't actually
to get some of its benefits.
So the first thing is that all
of the users favorite
They're launched in the
and kept there ready to go so
to get them, it's just a short
to wait for a full
Now, I mentioned
to the user's favorite apps,
and I do mean something
This is all of the apps that are
on the user's current watch
on the current watch
that app is one of
And all of the apps
in their dock are
These apps are the ones that
to go as soon as they're needed.
They're the ones that the user
because they're either a
or just an easy scroll
And so we want them to
and as responsive as possible.
And as I mentioned, you don't
Even your existing watchOS
behavior automatically.
But of course, there
with Background App
to make your apps even more
to the foreground and
up to date and ready to go.
And so the first
with this are obviously
and updating your app.
Keeping your app up to date
But there's another
that might be immediately
and that is that you want to
Now you might be wondering
because you haven't
And this applies specifically
Now, when the dock first
all of the apps that are in
but they're suspended and
So what's displayed as soon
as the dock comes forward is a
like in its last state.
Once the user settles on
it will be resumed
even while it's still
But in the meantime, we're
of what was there
So it's important that that
as well, so that you're
until the app gets resumed.
Even more importantly, if I
and don't land on
they're not being unsuspended
and resumed the entire
So we're just scrolling
of the last snapshots
So you definitely want to make
up to date and displaying
and the Background App Refresh
to do this.
Starting off, there's actually
that you get from the
to add any new requests
Now, the first one is
If you've actually gone
then the user has probably
or performed some action
to update the snapshot that
So when the user
the system will automatically
to happen on your behalf.
Now, it's really
because there's one new
that all of the background
So it's just a simple
on your WatchKit
and it'll get called
of these refresh
And so the first one is the
when your app is suspended.
But there's also other times
from your app, where you'll want
that we just do it
And the other one, which
is after a notification
So if the user looks at a long
they may have seen some new
of some new state in your app.
If they then go into the dock
and see something else displayed
that would probably
So when your notification
the system will automatically
task for you in that
so that you can update
update your complication, and
up to date and in sync.
Of course, there are also
to schedule updates
You know your users and you know
where you actually just want
to proactively be
and there's really
The first is going to
The question then becomes, what
So the first and most
in your snapshot is just
of your app normally is,
and it's showing exactly
when a user goes into the app.
But you might also
to provide some custom
so that it looks nicer
to glance at and digest.
For example, the Dexcom G5
the most important
about is my current
So if I look at it in the dock,
I'll see that highlighted really
But when I actually go
about more detail than
So as I bring the app full
and show more information
displaying, in this
of more information
Now, you don't necessarily have
in the dock snapshot, and a
to not do that, and just have
But you do have a lot
so if it makes sense in your app
in the dock snapshot, just
as you go into the
and not really jarring
Okay, so in addition to these
and keeping your snapshot up
to periodically be able to
in the background, and
that you would go
Now, you might just
out to the Internet to fetch
that with a NSURLSession
but there's plenty of other
to focus on is complication
Now, complications are visible
so it's even more
as up to date as possible.
So there's a kind of update
that are on the current
and that's the silent
Now, these types of updates
but they were a little
because you couldn't
of how many you would get
so it was a little difficult to
and when you would send them.
In watchOS 3, there's
for complication push
that over the course of the day,
each app on the watch face
This is great, because it gives
for how you want to use them
So for example, let's
If we just did the
and distributed our 50
that would give us about
And that's not too bad, but we
into account a little bit
that we were displaying and
For example, let's
that our user generally sleeps
If that's the case, then
to update during
and we can distribute the
through the rest of the day.
So that'll increase
to once every 20 minutes, which
with only a small
But of course, it we
about the data itself and
then we might be able to
So let's say that we knew
from the New York
In that case, we'd only need
and 4:00 p.m. when
and that would increase
to once every eight-and-a-half
So now, obviously, this
to the vast majority of
in general definitely can.
Taking into account a little
that you have about your user
that you're displaying can
to even further enhance
when using your app
Okay, but those are just
on the current watch face.
Now, if you have an
on the current watch
or an app on the
where push updates maybe
There are other ways to
In these cases, you'll
to do some periodic scheduled
over the course of the day.
So there's another
that will let you schedule
like to run, and each time
of different things that
You could start some data
or Watch Connectivity.
Or you could just load new
on the watch if you already have
But in addition to that,
to schedule the next
So it's not a fixed period that
Each time you run, you
to choose the next best
so that you can optimize
and when you know that
Now, at a minimum,
that your application can
but there are some other
to run even more
So the first would be if
by a complication.
So if a complication is
then your app will
to update more frequently
But even if you're not on
you may be able to run more
So the total number of updates
for all of the apps that
So if the dock is full, and
then each of the apps
to update once an hour.
But if the user hasn't
and there are fewer
the updates that would have been
in use can be distributed
So in that case, you
than one update per hour.
Of course, as you're designed
to plan for once an hour,
because that's the
But just keep in mind
that you could be running
depending on these
So there's one last thing
about complication pushes.
Complication pushes, when you
that may come to mind is a push
and that's definitely
You can start a complication
from the server.
But what you may not
that you can also start
from your iPhone app running
The push update API
of the Watch Connectivity
So if your app on your iPhone is
either the user is
or it's using some Background
it can initiate a complication
to update the UI on
So even if you don't
that has the knowledge
you may actually still be
to keep your watch
So just something
as you're designing
and your refresh
So that's just a quick summary
and how all this stuff works,
that it's really a critical part
So no matter what kind of app
for Apple Watch, I'd strongly
out the Keeping Your Watch Up
about Background App Refresh
to keep your apps live,
So next, let's talk about
Now, as I've mentioned, we've
of work to optimize navigation
So the system is already really
The next step is optimizing
so that it's really fast
and actions that the users want.
Now, there's one common
that I want to start with.
There's many apps that have
to their data.
For example, there's a
of information on a
In this case, I've written
of the beverages that
Now, if you want information
you can tap on it, and it'll
So here we can see that
of coffee so far today.
In watchOS 2, if you wanted to
of those other items, you
find the other item,
Now, that may not seem
but given how short we're trying
that additional time
and forth can actually
So in watchOS 3, you'll find
that have this kind of
to a new style of
where you can just use your
to quickly scroll and page
without having to do the back
So if you look at, for
or the Weather app,
to enable this ok
to make it really easy for you
to adopt this in
So the WatchKit table interface
to enable this vertical paging
into a detail view, and it's
There's just a couple of
First, obviously you can enable
But then you also
that in your storyboard
to represent the
into the detail views.
By doing that, you give WatchKit
to be able to pre-generate
and place them in a
so that it can move
So not too much adoption,
The only other thing to keep in
to match this, you also need
of your detail views
of the detail view
If the actual detail view
then that scrolling in the
over the outer paging interface.
So you definitely want to focus
on simplifying the views
You'll find, again, in the
that these views now, while
in watchOS 2 they scrolled
of information in them, are now
so that they can easily
Okay, so we've gotten our
We've optimized the background
up to date, and we've
within our app as well.
The last part of ensuring
with Apple Watch are short
out of our app as
And of course, on Apple Watch,
that means giving
that they can drop their wrists.
So there's a number of ways that
Let's just take one
Let's say that I've got an app
When I tap this Buy
and do some network activity
to perform some actions
or not I can actually
Now, that might take a while.
So my first inclination might be
to display an indeterminate
letting them know that
but I'm not sure how
Now, unfortunately, that means
with their arm up, waiting
until this task finishes.
But if I'm really confident
of the time the task
I'm not actually
by having them sit
So instead, you could decide
that you could present
that really gives
that you're taking care
to wait for it to occur.
So in this case, I've
We're working on your order."
Once they read that, they have
their wrist, and you can
in the background for up
to 30 seconds using the
on NSProcessInfo.
Generally, everything
to get their attention back.
Now, of course, sometimes
Maybe your server's
or there's some other issue.
In that case, watchOS 3 includes
framework that lets you
on the watch itself,
during this background
to get the user's
let them know something went
to fix it really easily.
So in this case, let's
my order of chicken
I can pop up a notification,
Of course, because notifications
I can have some buttons
to resolve the issue, or I
into my app so that they can fix
The User Notification framework
but of course, it's not just for
Local notifications can
for many different
And the great thing about the
in watchOS 3 is that it can work
when the watch is
because it's scheduling
on the watch itself.
But now you do have a choice
because you can either use the
on the watch to schedule
or you can continue doing what
sending a message
with Watch Connectivity and
These are actually both
and it depends a little bit
on what you're trying
The important distinction is
where the notifications
So if you send a message
with Watch Connectivity, and
the notification will appear on
and you'll be notified on
So if you were using your
If you're using your watch,
If you use the new User
on the watch itself, that
on the watch and will not
Now, that actually might
There are many cases
to schedule a notification
up on the watch at all, and
with the new User
But even better is
Thanks. But even better,
you don't necessarily
If your goal is that you want
in the right spot,
even if the user leaves their
to schedule it in both places
to send a message
and scheduling it there, or
in your cloud service,
by default, schedule it there.
And also scheduling it with the
on the watch.
If you do that, as long
as you've used the same
times that you schedule it,
watchOS will de-duplicate
so that you only have it appear
So some great new stuff with
Now, while individual
with the watch are short, there
to use multiple times
For example, here I've got
and I'm going to
up all the items
Now, in watchOS 3, each time I
to the last app that I was used
to that I can really quickly
to pick up, and check off the
I'll be brought back
to eight minutes
This is great, because
that have this kind of
where you use it for
but over a longer
This is the new user default
so it's to plan for this
and build your apps
These are just a few of the
about improving app
and there's a ton of other ways.
I'd encourage you to check out
for watchOS session, where you
of these kinds of ideas and
So that's navigation.
Now let's talk a little bit more
about the enhanced API
As I mentioned earlier,
of great frameworks from
We've got some great
For example, the User
and we've also added a
of the frameworks that are
So let's start with one
Background App Refresh.
I wanted to bring
to reinforce how important
And the three key things that
to schedule updates, perform
with that guarantee of 50
and make sure that your snapshot
and in sync with
and your complications.
Again, definitely check out
Up to Date session as well for
Now, fitness apps have a unique
because during a workout
that they be displaying
to date throughout the workout.
So the big enhancement for
in watchOS 3, they will continue
for the entire duration
This gives you the opportunity
watch-- use all of the
of where things are going,
and notify the user
or haptics, or sounds.
And of course, we've enhanced
and accelerometer so they
throughout the entire workout,
in increments that are
So it makes it really easy to
of the workout the entire
Because they're running,
which makes sure that as
they can very quickly see
of the workout without
It's a really, really big year,
and there's an entire session
of other enhancements for
out Building Great Workout
to make your workout apps
But there is one
on a little bit more here first,
and that's the background
Because there's a bit of
you absolutely want
up to date during the workout.
But you also want to make sure
that you're preserving
for users throughout the rest
to preserve their battery life.
And a big components
that you're keeping track
that you're using
And Xcode now has a great
of that, both how much
and the amount that
over a period of time.
So for the first part,
right up here near the top, that
that you're currently using,
there's a great graph that shows
about the CPU usage over time.
Now, you can clearly
where we've been
But in yellow, in
you can see that we've got a
of CPU that's being consumed
over some period of time.
Now this part is the
and it's the most important,
because while your workout app
there's a cap imposed
of average CPU usage
over this period of time.
And you want to stay below
that your app continues
and preserves the
over the whole rest of the day.
So that cap here is
by the red dotted
as your average approaches
that you stay below it.
So there's, again,
about the background
improvements.
Definitely go check out more of
that you really should keep
as you're developing these apps.
So in addition to the sensor
of apps with making heart rate
and accelerometer
we've also got a bunch of
So crown events give you raw
from the digital crown.
In watchOS 2, your apps could
within your interface or for
with the picker control.
But of course, we saw
of the picker control for
and we realize that everybody,
to digital crown events.
So that's now available, and
of other interactions
Now--
[ Applause ]
Now just gesture recognizers
to add touch interactions
There's a whole bunch
of single-finger interactions
long-press, and it's really
of your different
so that you can have
of your app screen
And of course, we've also made
in addition to the
so you've got a ton of
of the device available for all
Again, the quick-- oop.
Go for it [clapping].
Again, the quick interaction
of information on this
I do want to give you a
of the cool things that you
So first off, you can see here
to let you quickly scrub
on a graph showing you
about your account.
So in a single simple
through a lot of information,
Here we have Sweat with Kayla,
of the swipe gestures to
between these different workouts
and choose just the
Of course, you can also use
between them, and with just a
that you're interested in.
Now you'll notice
of interesting visuals here
that are adding a little
And to help make that
we've got some great
that we've bought
SpriteKit and SceneKit make
and 3D graphics and animations
to enhance different
And of course you can use them
in your long look
to make your notifications
And because we've
about simplifying navigation, we
to play back video in line
in your application
In watchOS 2, we introduced
but for it to work there,
out into a separate
where you watched a video
and then dismissed it
With inline video
to leave your application's
and you can play it
Even better, it supports
so as soon as the video
it will start playing and
If you have multiple short
the one on screen at any one
while all the others pause.
It's a really great way
to add some really
into your apps.
And because apps in the dock are
the autoplay feature can
So if you have a quick video
as you scroll through the
on your app, that video can
without even taking
So some really great
for video in watchOS 3.
SpriteKit and SceneKit can be
Here you can see a Seven
advantage of SceneKit to bring a
on their iPhone app to
So you can see exactly the
and get a lot of clarity
So in addition to adding a
to your apps, SpriteKit and
for short interaction games.
We've also bought GameKit to
which makes it really
to add turn-based gaming
Because GameKit's turn-based
of NSURLSession,
if your phone is not present,
when your watch is near
The GameKit achievement
to earn achievements on Apple
on iPhone, or iPad, or
where you've got your game.
And of course, with AV
to play sounds out
Now, gaming on Apple Watch is
and with some of these new
to see what kinds of
for short interaction
To give you just one idea
in a really interesting game,
I want to show you a quick
that WoGa is developing
that lets us go fishing at
So with just a swipe,
and I can use the digital
down to just the right
Now, I could leave it there for
to go fishing right now.
Looks like I got a bite.
Now you can use the crown
but now I actually--
That'll probably make the
although our fisherman might
So really cool how you can add
and get some great animations
Really, really looking
of things you guys do with this.
So next up, I want
We've brought CloudKit
including the new CK Share
to share data between
Again, because it's built on an
for it to work, even when
There's a whole session on
in CloudKit that I definitely
And finally, we've
Apple Watch is a great way
in stores, and of course with
you can now offer physical goods
with just a double tap
Now, there's many different
about using this, but for
to offer for purchase the most
for lunch, so that I can
at lunchtime every day,
There's a lot of ways that
for sale within your
So that's just some of the APIs
that are a part of
There's a bunch of
Definitely go check it all out.
I'd like to end by talking
and configuration,
building a great watch app
You also want to make sure
to discover it and
So the first enhancement
in the iOS 10 Apple Watch app.
There's a brand new watch face
of the watch faces that
And even better, right
it includes an entire
of your apps, and getting
and requires just
So first off, you have to
You already had an
for specifying a template
This API has been in
to not just return a string
but actually the
to get localized strings
This is important,
to build a complication bundle.
You use the-- you do
You run your app, and build
and this creates a
of your complication template
that you can then include
It's really easy to
it gets you into this gallery
We need the static
because that way we can display
in a watch face here,
yet installed on the watch.
So just a couple of steps,
You'll be right here
The gallery is the first thing
after they've paired, so
that you'll want to be.
In addition to the gallery,
to customize watch faces
It was always possible to
on the Apple Watch, and in
on iPhone now includes an entire
Obviously, they're kept in
in one will be reflected in the
on your phone to select all
like on all your watch
And with quick watch
there's now even more reason
because more users will
and your apps can
So then the last part of
and obviously, you
in the Apple Watch
It's really easy to add and
and reorder them right there.
But even more importantly, you
And there's one feature
that makes it really
that you can add
The last app that you used is
even if you hadn't
So if a user installs your
that they can add
they go to the home screen, they
The next time they go to the
in there with a big button
which, with one tab, will add it
to their permanent list
So it's really easy to discover
and also easy to add them
So again, you're going to hear
actionable, and responsive apps,
and I really do encourage
There's a great design
that you can go check out for
Experiences, where
about all these things, so
And the responsive part
that there are really two
with Architecting for
and Keeping Your
These are two that you'll
out to get all the benefits
and making sure that
and responsive for watchOS 3.
And there's a whole bunch
of other sessions throughout
of information, many focused on
that just include Apple
Thanks so much for coming
to see what you do
Enjoy the rest of the week.
[ Applause ]