[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, and welcome
to Getting the Most
I'm Matt, I'm a software
and I'll be joined on stage
In this session, we'll be
and recent additions
in iOS 10 and watchOS 3.
Just as importantly, we'll be
core concepts, and important
that you're really able to
We expect you have some
if you're here watching this
we'll list some past sessions
that you can refer to
But for now, let's get started.
As all of you here
and fitness ecosystem has become
People are getting more
because of the integration of
and CareKit with
for iPhone and Apple Watch.
We want to make sure
to keep creating
and fitness user experiences
that our users have come
So today we're going to be
to do to get these
First, we'll cover
which underpins everything
Next, we'll cover the Activity
and Health Records
both of which happen to have
to authorization.
Finally, we'll spend the
over a wide range of best
when you're interacting
So let's dive in.
First up is authorization.
If you've been using HealthKit
of this section might
but we really recommend
to the details because
for the stuff we cover
We'll sprinkle in some
so keep your ears peeled.
iOS gives users full control
and which apps can access
Before interacting
your app should request access
to the appropriate types
and then the Health Store
in turn will present the
to the user if necessary.
Be aware that the user can
at any time, so you should keep
that in mind while you're
And just as importantly,
and write authorization
That last bit can actually be
at it in a little more detail.
Here's how read and write
If the user grants you both
to a given HealthKit type, then
for that HealthKit type
If the user grants you only read
then your app can read but
for that type.
So far, so good.
Now, if the user grants
for a given type, then your
for that type but
from HealthKit for that type.
Write permissions do not
However, there's an important
If your app has write
for a HealthKit type, then
that your app has written, just
Finally, if the user denies you
for a given type, then you can
for that type.
And there's an important
of that last point as well.
If the user denies you a
permission for that app,
then that means your app
from HealthKit for that type,
even data that your
so keep that in mind.
So that was all technically
but there is one important
in general in iOS 10,
with usage descriptions.
Apps linked on or after iOS
for the user of why they're
This reinforces our principle
These usage descriptions
on your app's info.plist
for the
key if you're reading data
or the
key if you're writing data.
As a refresher, this is how
The first thing we
that HealthKit is even
For instance, maybe
of our app is running
After we've established
that we're interested
And finally, we call
on HK Health Store, pass in
and then handle the
What if you have a watchOS app?
Authorizations are shared
and its companion watchOS app,
and you can request
from your iOS code
However, the system
presented to the
so this has some important
For instance, if the user
they might already have their
and if that's the case,
they can't really easily
from your app, so this
to request initial
But there's an even
If the user's using a Watch app,
at all, and if that's the case,
the authorization sheet
So we really recommend you
when you're developing
Also remember that
for the request authorization
so definitely don't block
for a response.
So clearly it's important
to get the authorization
and on top of that, your app
or even many HealthKit
so that all raises a
When should I be
or all of these types?
Here are our recommendations
First, we recommend
to sensible groupings
to logical activities
So for instance, say
to track both food
as body measurements like BMI.
If that's the case, you might
to nutrition types the first
but then requesting access
to body measurement types
to log one of those.
One exception to that rule is
if your app has an
If this is the case, it
to request access to all
to use upfront because
where you can clearly explain to
to be doing with those types.
Regardless of which you
that you frequently
during development.
You can easily reset the
by deleting your app
of the simulator before
so that HealthKit
with the initial authorization
When you're doing this,
where authorization
or completely denied
How does your app
What capabilities are left over?
Finally, if we could
in one sentence, it's this.
Consider the user experience.
Don't present obstacles
and ensure that your
So we've spent a lot of time
Now let's move onto some
in HealthKit, starting
Apple's developed a great health
and fitness tracking
Users love how easy it is to
and improve their day, and
users can even share
with each other and compete.
Now we're giving you a great way
to incorporate this Activity
into your app with the
To do this, we start with
HKActivitySummary represents
over the course of a given day.
That includes their move
and stand hours, and
HKActivitySummary is a
It's not an HKObject, but
that you request
from its component types.
That last part's
HKActivitySummary covers some of
as the HealthKit types; active
and stand hours, but only
So for instance, if you want
like contribute to a
to the active energy type or
for activity over the course
you'd want to request access
to the constituent
Now, because an ActivitySummary
over the course of a given
or may not correspond to a
we specify the day corresponding
to an activity summary using
Let's see how that works
So suppose we want to fetch
To do that, we use an
First, we use our calendar
to create a DateComponents
to today using the
era, year, month, and day.
Next, we use those components
that restricts our query
to activity summaries whose
And then finally, we create our
and then handle the, in this
that should come
So that's how you retrieve
but the really fun part is
To do that, we use
or the analogous
on watchOS.
They look like this, and
they perform this
when you call
Some tips for using
and WKInterfaceActivityRing.
Firstly, just like in the
and watchOS, the rings look
so we recommend display
Secondly, if your
and communication features, you
of HKActivitySummary to
supply it to HKActivityRingView
and thereby display another
current user's rings
Finally, when you're using
remember to use the required
month, and day in your
Date map can be notoriously
so if you have any
or DateComponents, be sure
from a prior conference.
So we've been talking a lot
about authorization
Let's put it into
Here on the right, we
for a medical group
This app has some
but its main page is a dashboard
so for instance, your doctor's
and some healthy tips.
LoopHealth wants their patients
as well, so they saw this
to incorporate Apple's
onto their dashboard.
As you can see here,
we've already dropped
into the storyboard
but we haven't actually
that hooks it up with data yet.
Let's see how easy
So over here in Xcode, we
This is the view controller
at in the LoopHealth app.
It's pretty empty so far,
but we do have some
You can see right here we have
to the activityRingView
Up here we import HealthKitUI.
This is the new framework
that you can find
And finally down
up its app-wide HKHealthStore
so we've just set up a simple
for convenience when we need it.
Okay, so if we want to show an
the first thing we need to
to HKActivitySummary.
And since we're reading health
to include a usage description,
so let's go to our info.plist
The key we're interested
in is called NSHealthShare
which is written here in plain
Perfect. And I'll drop
in a quick usage
We're all set.
Now I can go back to
and then write the code that
Since we want to show the
and also update our rings
to the dashboard tab, the
in the viewDidAppear method.
So I'll drop that in here.
And after our requisite
notice that we call
on HKHealthStore, pass in
and then in the response, we
which we'll write to actually
Let's go implement that now.
So here's our skeleton
and what we want to
HKActivitySummaryQuery, request
and then set that
on our HKActivityRingView
First, let's create a
corresponding to today.
Since DateComponents only
of a particular calendar,
that we use back on
Oops, perfect.
Next, we can create
that components object, and
we can create our query,
and then in the response,
that should come back for today.
Now, once we have that summary,
all we have to do is dispatch
to update our UI and then
animated on our Activity
Now that we have our
to do is execute
So let's build and run and
Excellent.
So first thing you see is now
to activity summary,
to approve authorization.
Let's approve read access
and while we're down there,
of the screen, that usage
for reading health data is
It's important to note
we'd want to make sure this
so we'd include that in our
I'll approve authorization
we see the Activity Rings
[ Applause ]
So that's how easy it is
to incorporate Activity Rings
Be sure to check out the API.
Next, I'll turn it over to
to tell you about an awesome
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Matt.
Good morning, everyone.
My name is Joefrey Kibuule.
I work alongside Matt as
on the Health team.
Today I have the proud
to you a new feature of
Health Records provides
to carry the information
to you right on your smartphone.
Today the current experience
when users visit a medical
for their health records
A stack of documents
to find a particular
More recently,
health organizations have been
CDs of digitized information
But now with Health
we can help solve this problem.
Through the work that
your apps can start to
in the exchange and
In fact, in the U.S., adoption
of these APIs can help
with new regulations
to give their patients
of their own health data.
So first, an overview.
Health Records in iOS is
to represent a variety
of different patient
by health institutions.
Today we're adding
for health documents.
Standard machine-readable XML
that represents specific
These include patient
continuity of care visits,
and operative notes,
We support the international
for interoperability with a
These documents are available
through patient healthcare
and can be imported via Safari,
These documents are stored just
like all other HealthKit
and securely encrypted
Next, let's talk
Since so much information
within each health document,
we give the user
to other data types
Access is granted on a
to the health document
As shown on the right, we
to allow the user to both view
and select the document before
This UI will present it whenever
and a new one is available.
If you query for documents and
we will not show
and your query will return
If you query for documents
in the background, we will
to grant access to
HealthKit ensures that
when they're granting
to your apps the
Next, let's talk about how to
When saving a document
you can save the raw XML
into the new HKCDADocumentSample
We validate on creation
with the standard and will
We automatically extract the
and author names whenever the
in order to make querying
without needing to read
Let's take a look at
We're going to take
and transform it
The origin of this XML
from a health organization
We're then going to create a
in that data object, setting
and any additional metadata,
And then we'll save the
That's it.
Now your health document is
to be used in other
by the user in the Health App.
Now, let's talk about querying
Since HKCDADocumentSample
existing query objects you
with continue to work
However, you need to use
in order to fetch the raw XML.
Fetching the raw XML's
so when explicitly specified.
We provide predicate
for the automatically extracted
to remember that since
updated information
to previously samples are
Now, let's take a look at
for documents in HealthKit.
In this example,
for all the documents
So first, we need to
We're going to pass
into the document type
on HKObjectType.
We're then going to
You have additional
and order the documents
to you the order
And then we execute
to get the HKCDADocumentSamples
One thing I want to note in
includeDocumentData to false.
Only ever set it to true
if you need the full
Now, let's talk about some
with the health documents
First, check for validation
and HKCDADocumentSample.
The errors will tell
to transform your raw
Next, you should
that you imported
and automatically
This way, you can tell
on those automatically extracted
that you'd expect.
And lastly, request the raw
Queries that don't request,
will return the automatically
and this may be all you
to uniquely identify a
For more information on
visit the link on the screen.
Now, I'd like to switch gears
and offer some general
As you know, HealthKit serves
where your app and other
to a user's record
Your app in cloud service may
with another app
and this may require some
So there are three main topics
when talking about
First, syncing data.
Second, tracking change data.
And third, migrating data.
So first, syncing data.
You should be using
to handle processing both new
to keep up to date
Anchors act as a
of the last query operation
You could save this anchor
to create a new
You'll open one query
that you're interested in
and then pass an optional
to continuously process new and
to unnecessarily
But say for a better
in order to have fresh UI
when your application
or to keep your cloud data in
to handle processing new
when it's currently not running.
That's where HKObserverQuery
with HKAnchoredObjectQuery
Let's look at an
So there are four
to handle background
into two phases;
In the first step,
for background updates.
You need to do this
that you're interested in.
In the second step, you're
Once set up, the ObserverQuery
and deleted samples
When new samples are generated,
that's when you have
You'll get a callback
and then execute an
to fetch new and
And then in the fourth step,
you'll call the observer queries
to let HealthKit know
and delivered the
You'll then continue to cycle
in order to keep up to
Now, let's take a look at this
So in the first step, we need to
Your application needs to do
so we recommend you do it
in application
You'll then grab the step's
and then pass that to HK Health
for, passing in the steps type
and the frequency
Do note that background delivery
Your application needs to pick
it can handle in order
to preserve a user's
Also note that this
Background updates are
In the second step, we're going
to create the HKAnchored,
Here we'll have a
that we can use in order
and deleted samples when
And then we're going
That's it.
That completes the setup
to monitor new and deleted
So as I'm walking across stage
step samples, our,
into the update steps method in
in order to grab new
So first, we're going to create
passing in the steps type.
You'll also have predicate,
to filter the particular
Then we'll call the handleSteps
and deleted samples and
for the next time we need to
We then call the
to know that we've done
and then we execute the query.
Then lastly, in step four,
we're going to call the
from the observer query in order
to let HealthKit know
and processed the
And that's it.
Now your application will
and keep your cloud data in sync
Next, let's talk about
You should be using
to keep tracking of
A unique identifier is set
and persists for the
Record UUIDs in your own
on the device and
so that way you could tell a
Whenever these samples
a workout from the Health
for these changes to
those same samples are
on the device and
And ensure that future sync
deleted samples.
Now, there are two
like to discuss when
about how to avoid duplication.
The first is pre-populating
Pre-populating data is,
Pre-populating data is a
to save the user time
that may already be
Users have the ability to verify
and change it if necessary.
However, the problem is
Be sure only to save data again
Another additional potential
both from another
Remember to only pick one source
of information that's most
HealthKit has a great
that our users have
However, you know what's, what
Make sure not to save
on their behalf.
Writing only your data once
by simplifying which
to write it.
There is one particular
Sometimes duplication
For example, if data's
If a data, step data is
and his or her Apple Watch,
and HKStatisticsCollectionQuery
to automatically
of the preferred data sources
This way, our users get
of the view of their health
Now, I want to talk
Let's say that you've launched
and app that writes
Your application has been in
but your users discover
In certain locales, instead of
you actually save
That's a bit warm.
But in this case, we know
data in order to fix it.
We first need to find old
making sure to update
and then delete old samples.
Now, a few new things
between iPhone and Apple Watch.
Starting in iOS 9.3,
on a user's phone will
of their paired Apple Watches.
Apple Watch is now a reflection
of the most recent
within the HealthKit ecosystem.
In order to accomplish this,
samples are now periodically
on Apple Watch.
Make sure to save samples
after HKHealthStore's earliest
to make sure your samples
and synced back to
Lastly, sync times
You should be saving
or Apple Watch, not both.
Now, I'm going to hand it back
up the rest of our session.
Thank you, everyone,
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jeff.
Before we wrap up, I'd like to
feature that's brand new
Wheelchair support.
Accessibility is extremely
All of our and your users
and experiences as
and the great activity
to Apple Watch is no exception.
iOS 10 and watchOS 3 include
features that automatically
to wheelchair users.
And now you can work with
when you're interacting
First, there's a new
HKWheelchairUse that
a wheelchair.
The value can be yes,
Next, we have some new
to wheelchair users.
Those include wheelchair
which you can think
Finally, we have some new
to wheelchair users as well.
Those include wheelchair walk
When a wheelchair user
the watch automatically
to the new push count data type.
In addition, the stand
to the stand hours data type
Be aware that wheelchair
recorded during a wheelchair
that a user's wheelchair
This is really important
if you're querying
In this case, you want to
for both wheelchair types
so that you're not potentially
of the user's historical
To sum up, we work really
of our products and experiences
You should too.
We strongly encourage you to
of our users by supporting
to wheelchair data
So we've talked about
Let's recap.
Authorization is
for protecting users' privacy,
but getting the user experience
Keep authorization in mind when
and be sure to test it often.
Next, fit in with Apple's
by incorporating the Activity
with the Activity Rings API.
Whenever you're interacting
take care to handle all cases
deleted, or duplicated
that your users' data
and always what you'd expect.
And finally, don't forget to
new features we've
and watchOS 3, especially
something we think is
If you'd like more
of the things we
or if you have any questions,
We have lots of additional
And don't forget to check out
We also have these great
if you want to get up
Thank you for creating
that help users live
and enjoy the rest of your WWDC.
[ Applause ]