[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to Mastering
My name's Justin.
I work on UIKit.
And I am here to show you how
and really take your tvOS
So to do that, there's
to talk to you about today.
And the first is event handling.
What kind of events is
and what are the best ways for
Then I'd like to talk
This is a user interface
and we'll show you how to
Thirdly, we'll talk
Scrolling on tvOS works
than scrolling on iOS.
And we'll show you how
of scrolling.
And finally, we'll
and how you can use
to accept text from users.
So let's get started and dive
So when it comes
there are a few overall best
with you right off the bat.
And the first is, is that when
to navigate your application
to another, you don't
of your own event
The focus engine is going take
including handling different
on what kind of input device
So it'll take care of
Secondly, if you decide you do
I recommend that you start
Not only to have a
but it'll also help ensure all
in your app are going
across all the system
And finally, as you are
for your application,
that not every input device can
So for example, a user might
to navigate to your application.
And game controllers can't
So you might not want to use
to interact with
So keep that in mind as
So speaking of touches,
on tvOS using the touch
And we deliver them to you
that you might recognize
And a touch represents the
and that surface on the remote.
This is just like
It has the location and
that you are used to.
But there is one important
on tvOS and touches on iOS.
A touch on iOS is
onto the user interface.
The user is physically
That's not the case on tvOS.
The user interface
and the user is touching
And so we bucket these into
We say the ones on iOS
and the ones tvOS are
And we have this touch type
to help you tell the difference
And because of this indirection,
"What's your location onscreen?"
on a direct touch interface
We give you a location
where the user's
But on tvOS, the user
What location should we
And so what we do in this
where the user's finger
we always deliver the
as if it had begun directly in
And this is really
that any gesture recognizers
that you might have attached
to the focused view will
to participate in the gesture.
One thing that we don't expose
of the user's finger
And there is a few
but one of the really important
to discourage pointer-based
We don't want to see
or anything like that.
We'd really rather
to the focus interaction
So in addition to touches, there
that you'll get on tvOS; and
And presses are delivered
And a press represents an
that the user is
And not all of those buttons are
Some buttons, like those
are pressure sensitive.
But we can actually detect how
button, and we can deliver
You can recognize presses
including things like
and LongPressGestureRecognizer.
And we have low-level
that follow the same pattern
as a low-level touch
So we have pressesBegan,
as the user begins
We have pressesChanged,
if it's a pressure-sensitive
and the amount of
And we also have pressesEnded
And just like touchesCancelled,
yes you really do
There's one thing to
which is that press events
because they don't really have
directly to the focus view.
And they go up the
They won't go to any child
So keep that in mind when
to attach gesture
Okay, so we are talking
Let's go through some of the
to you and what buttons
on various input devices.
So I want to show you the
from previous-generation
and I want to show
And I don't have room
but keep in mind presses
from programmable
from Bluetooth keyboards.
So there is a lot of
Probably the most common
is UIPressTypeSelect.
And this is the press type that
to activate a control or select
on a CollectionView cell,
And on the Siri remote,
that's the button that's
surface on the remote.
On the Apple remote,
And on game controllers
to generate this press type.
Another really common
is UIPressTypeMenu.
And this is the press type
that indicates the
They want to dismiss a
or even dismiss your
and return to the Home screen.
And in all three of
that'll be the button
And on game controllers, we
And finally, there is
And this is obviously useful
but it can also be used
in addition to Select.
So if the users focus
pressing the Select button might
But pressing Play/Pause
into playback.
And so that's the
or the button that has
And on game controllers
to generate that press type.
Okay, so to round things
out there is just a
and these are directional
So we have up, down, left,
that can be generated.
On the Apple remote we use
On game controllers there is
So we'll use the D pad.
We'll also use the
And we'll even generate left
and right presses using
on the game controller.
Now there aren't any
for these arrows on the serial
that it's not possible
but that's actually not true.
If you do a touch tap you
down on the Select
on these four cardinal
Then UIKit will detect that
and actually generate
And this is a really
through your user interface
So just because the user
that doesn't mean that they
Okay, so I promised you that
to recognize these.
And I won't go through these
to show you a few
You know, we can use the
on the top.
We can even do a long press
into the editing mode
And there at the bottom I
of taps required.
So now I am listening for a
Okay, let's talk about
and that's the Menu button.
The Menu button has some
It kind of has to
Not only does it need
of your application,
like dismiss view
of a UINavigationController.
But it also needs to have
And eventually your
be dismissed so the user can
And your user is going
if that's not possible.
And we can think that
that this is something that App
So if your application
by pressing the Menu button,
And we don't want
So how does this work?
How do we get it so that the
by your application but
Well the technical thing
for your app to gracefully
to the Home screen is that when
the pressesEnded event
up the responder chain if you
If that doesn't happen, your
Now sometimes that's
So if you are deep into
and the user presses the
to resign your app; they
to the previous view controller.
So in that case, there might be
listening for the Menu button.
And if that recognizer
it'll send pressesCancelled
And in that case the
and then UINavigationController
that view controller.
So it's okay to not
to your application.
You just need to make sure that
at the appropriate time.
So to do this correctly,
that you start with
And when you no longer
in handling the Menu
that GestureRecognizer
And so one way to do
GestureRecognizer from the view.
You also disable the gesture.
So gesture recognizers have
And if you set that to false,
then the gesture will
And if you don't want to
there is UIGestureRecognizer
gestureRecognizerShouldBegin.
And you can implement this,
of the Menu button you
to decide right then
to handle the gesture.
If you are implementing the
methods, in your pressesEnded
or not you want to
And if you do want to handle the
But if you are not going to
that you do call super so
up the responder chain
and UIApplication has the
Finally, if you are
it's common that you only
which is the one
And so in that case
at using GCEventViewController.
Now it has this property,
controllerUser
And what this does is that
through your app using
not only are events going to
which you are probably
But they also can
like these presses
And when you are in the
you are probably not interested
in receiving the UIKit
So if you set controllerUser
to false during your game
the Menu button won't
And instead you'll
and take care of it on your own.
But when the user gets back
you are going to want
so that pressing the Menu button
So that is event handling.
Let's talk now about
Layered images are this user
unique to tvOS.
And there are these images
that you've probably
And they can have up to
a parallaxing content
And these are required
So your application
at a minimum of two layers.
So you'll have to be at least a
if you are going to be on
As the user moves their finger
the image moves in
And this is more
This helps the user to realize
that their inputs are being
to anticipate focus
And they're animated.
So they have a lot of great
especially like when
And we'll show you how you can
to really make your
Okay, so let's talk
So the video that I just showed
And if the UIImageView
then it'll automatically
that great floating appearance
if you have a layered image
But it's often the case
that a UI image is not the
becoming focused.
Images are typically a
and in that case the
to become focused.
So how do we get this
if the image isn't
Well it doesn't have
We have this property
to UIImageView called
WhenAncestorfocused.
And if you set this to be
of the image becomes focused,
then the image will
that floating appearance
and begin reacting
And these images can also
And so this is slightly
than the normal default state,
where they are sitting
They kind of have this sort
as if the user is
And you can trigger
by setting the isHighlighted
to be either true or
on or off that effect.
And you might want to do
when the user starts pressing
But there are a few cases
and you won't have to
And those are images that are
and images that are
In those cases you don't have
at all; we'll take
Okay, so we talked
So let's look at that
So one of the things
when these images become,
in their floating
or they look like
And you might have to
You might want to move
like you have a label
And you can constrain
So, you know, if I have
let's say that I have
to be the same size
Then you can constrain to
But when it becomes enlarged,
but the visible extent
And so to find out how
when it becomes focused,
we expose this layout guide
And you can attach
to that layout guide, and that
enough away from the image that
when it becomes larger.
So let's run through this.
So I have my ImageView here,
that represents the
And when it becomes focused
but the frame is still
And so now this dotted
where the focusedFrameGuide is.
And that focusedFrameGuide
even if it's not
And so you can choose
to attach your layout
Or you may choose to change
which constraints are
or not the element
And if you do that you should
that we expose on the focus
that the animation happens in
The system animation has a
of what exactly the timing is.
It depends on how quickly
or how far off-screen
at the moment it became focused.
So it's not really possible to
You are going to need to use the
that your animations will
And to show you how to do that,
I'd like to invite Randy
Randy?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Justin.
So today I am going to walk
through those two
with adding interactivity
And first we are going
And second we are going to look
at a custom collection
So to get started, I have got
with an asset catalog that
And I just have a
And we are going to
into the canvas and inspect
And we'll delete its title.
And then we'll add a
to center it horizontally
And then we'll update
to match those constraints.
You can do that with
but I usually the keyboard
And if you look closely,
of extra space around
Those are the edge
We don't want those, so
So that looks about
So we'll build and run
Now I am using the
but I have paired a
so you can get a good feel
for how the interaction
And my finger is pressing
but it's just doing this
of doing that sort
And when I move my
it doesn't react to my touch.
So let's make that better.
To do that, I am going to
for our ViewController
out an outlet for the button.
And then in viewDidLoad,
I am going to grab the
And I want to turn on that
about adjustsImage
And now if I build and
that the button responds
And it pushes in
But we still have an issue
of this button are clipped.
And that's because by default,
the button's ImageView has
So we just turn that off.
Build and run again.
We should get exactly
It's a great interactive
around with my finger
when I press on it, great.
Let's do something a
I have another project here,
and this one has a
subclass in it.
And I have gone ahead and
of the CollectionView according
to the Human Interface
for a six-column layout.
Those guidelines tell us we
And I know, based on my designs,
for the content of the cells.
And the guidelines tell us
for a six-column
between cells horizontally
between cells vertically.
And finally, to stay within
of TVs, we want to leave 60
and 90 points on the
And those numbers are
So let's take a look
I have already given it a custom
And we are going to
and add some custom subviews.
First we'll drag
And then we'll drag out a label.
Now I'll add some constraints
We want the ImageView to hug
And we happen to know that all
of our images have
So I'll also add an
And then I'll edit that
to match our images so they
And then I'll add some
I'll Control-Drag from
to add a horizontal
And then I also want
of my label will be 15 points
So I'll add a constraint
Now that we have added
we can do Command Option
where it's supposed to be.
And finally, that font
So I am going to bump it up
And we've got some outlets for
So we'll just hook
Now we'll take a quick look at
You can see I have just
in section, and cellForItemAt
So if I build and run, we should
looking for.
But we'll see what
So this is pretty much the
It's all the right things.
But right away you can't
And when I click, you can't
So let's take care
Now first, to see where the
into Interface Builder and
that adjustImagewhenfocused
And that'll be enough
to start responding to focus.
As you can see, it's big,
and when I click it pushes in.
But the labels are
They are not responding to
So to do something about
up our custom cell class
And first we are going
for that vertical constraint
and the bottom of the ImageView.
So we'll add an outlet
that the unfocusedConstraint.
And then I'll add
for the focusedConstraint.
We'll set that focusedConstraint
to be the labels.topAnchor
relative to the imageView's
plus those 15 points.
Then in updateConstraints
we'll make the focusedConstraint
And we'll make the
in the opposite case.
Finally, in didUpdateFocus,
by calling
And then we'll add a
And inside there, we'll
And that'll be enough that
we should see the label has
of the focused poster.
And when I move from one to
out of the way and back
Great!
[ Applause ]
So remember, use
and coordinatedAnimations.
And don't forget to turn
on adjustsImage
to get these effects.
With that, back to Justin.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks for that
So you can see how easy it
of this unique user
to really bring your
All right, let's change
and talk about scrolling.
So scrolling on tvOS is a bit
And it has to do with
So when the user is scrolling
they are physically
And as they move their finger,
of the ScrollView to match
But that's not really
On tvOS, you are not
but you are also not
views directly.
What you are really doing is
focused item.
Then as the focus item changes,
that and it will automatically
as needed to make sure that
be onscreen.
The focus engine will choose
for you based on
and the size of the ScrollView.
But there are some times
of what offset that it's
So for example, one common
to do is they want to that the
within the bounds
And you can do that.
And the way you can do that is
with the UIScrollViewDelegate
from iOS which is
withVelocity,
And the final parameter there,
is a pointer to a CGPoint.
And that point represents
that the focus engine
to if you don't do
That's the offset that it
But if you'd like to do your
for yourself what you
to be, you can do that.
Make your calculation about
and then store the value
to you by that pointer.
And then the focus engine
And you'll get all the great
with that, but to
But it's not to say that direct
or is never a good idea on tvOS.
There are some cases where
And so some of the situations
like you have a lot of
Maybe you have full-screen
where the photos go completely
So one example from UIKit
When you have a
it doesn't do the
And instead, you are directly
content of the
There are other cases where you
So it's another good
to do direct manipulation.
Basically, anytime where
to be the focused item,
to see what the next
and those are good situations
So if you want to do
to write your own
You can reuse the pan gesture
that already comes
The trick is that scroll views
for direct touches
And the Siri remote is
So you just need to get
and convince it to listen
We also have a directional
which is only on
And this is listening for
So that way a user who
that he can do touch input
And this gesture is
because we would rather have
focus instead of manipulating
So you'll have to enable it.
And this is the code
to do both of those things.
So we are getting
to panGestureRecognizer
And we are telling it that we'd
like to listen for
And we are getting
that directionalPressGesture
and we are telling it
And if you do this, then all
into the ScrollView will
of the ScrollView.
And it's actually possible
to combine this direct
and the focus interaction
And to show you how
I'd like to invite Kevin
Kevin [applause]?
&gt;&gt; Thanks Justin.
Hi. I'm Kevin Hiscott, and
We are going to look at
that presents terms and
TextView is a subclass
So we can take a look at how to
Let's head over to
and see what I have
I have a text view with very
pasted into it.
And if we go into our
that looks like in
When I present my
we can see along the bottom edge
that the text is
And if I try swiping
the text does not scroll.
Well let's go improve that.
Let's head over to
And in viewDidLoad we are going
to grab the outlet I have
I have called it
And on messageTextView
there is a panGestureRecognizer.
And we are going to change
to include the indirect
As Justin mentioned, those
by the Siri remote.
The second thing we are going to
This will allow the text view to
and receive these events.
Let's build and run
Now when I present
I am actually able to directly
and down with the Siri remote.
Great direct manipulation.
The other thing any good terms
and conditions ViewController
to either accept or
So to do that, let's head
in a couple of buttons.
I am going to label one Disagree
Let's build and run
What I hope to happen is for
with horizontal swipes,
to still scroll the text view.
However, when I present my
that vertical swipes does
if I swipe too far down,
down into the buttons, and I
until focus moves back
This isn't exactly the
Let's head back to
And we are going to
We don't actually
to be a focusable
Instead, I am going to
We are going to grab
and actually add it to our
This will allow the message
without being focusable itself.
Let's build and run
Now when I present
we can see that the
becomes focused.
And that's because the text
I can swipe the Siri remote
But any time I can swipe up
Great this is looking
The last thing we
on tvOS are directional
by other input methods
keyboards, or IR remotes.
And we make this really
Let's head back to my view
to grab the
Recognizer from our
This will allow scrolling
with those press types generated
The last thing we are
that GestureRecognizer onto our
Let's build and run and see
Now when I present my
I can both swipe left
but I can also tap left
with the directional press
on the Siri remote and
I can swipe up and down to
but I can also tap up and
Great! This is a
and conditions ViewController
Thanks so much for your time.
And I can't wait to
and conditions in your apps.
Back to Justin [applause].
&gt;&gt; All right, let's move
on to our final topic,
So we have this great
And there is a lot of features
if you are using
I want to go through just
One of them is dictation.
So the user can just
and their words will
We also support Bluetooth
So if you pair it with
and you just type
We have the new Apple
so that users can pair
and they can type right
to send text to the TV.
There is also a lot
of localization details the
of for you.
And it also automatically
on the input device
So there is the linear layout
that you are probably
but there is also a grid
if there is no Siri
These are a lot of great
in the system keyboard.
And if you are not using
then users won't be able to take
So we discourage you from trying
Really stick to the
so that users can enjoy
that are only available
Now there are some ways that
system keyboard.
And one way that you can
of your own views
that will appear
And you can use some API
that you might recognize
There is the inputAccessoryView
and the inputAccessory
And if you assign to these
that you are wanting
then when the keyboard
of your own views right
And I'll show you a screenshot
And finally, I want to
in behavior that's happened
UITextField has this property
and you can set to
And on tvOS 9, if you
then not only would the
when it presents itself, but the
as it's sitting there
Well now in tvOS 10 we have
And so the entire system can
And so now what we
that this keyboard appearance
keyboard, and the appearance
of the text field
by the larger tray
Okay, so here's the
So in this case I have created
and I gave it an
And I put a red border on it
And those UI labels in there
And I just put them in there
of accessory views that you'd
like that could appear
Now another great way that
at the same time as the keyboard
And you use some APIs you
and that's UISearchController.
So we have the keyboard, and the
And this also automatically
There is a grid-based layout and
on the input device
And you can even
of other view controllers.
SearchController usually wants
over the whole screen.
But you can embed it
another view controller
ViewController.
And I'll show you a code sample
You provide your own custom view
So the visual appearance
and the interaction of them
You can do whatever you want.
You might use a collection view,
that has a table view and a
Any other things you'd like --
it's totally up to you
So here's a quick sample
of how you might embed a
of something else like,
So I have got my custom
And in viewDidAppear I am going
I want to make sure I don't do
to make sure I haven't
Then I am creating
and telling it view controller
to contact as the
Then I am going to
of this UISearchContainer
And this allows me now
and I can do regular
on it.
And then I am going to add
And if you do something like
to easily use a search
much like some of the
And that is text input.
So in summary, one of the
to take away from this talk.
First one is, when you are
be careful.
Keep in mind that you
with the system gestures.
When you are working with
of the layout guides
and the coordinated
that your views can
with the system animations.
If you want to do
on ScrollViews you
of that handling code yourself.
Just reuse the pan gestures
And finally, take advantage of
that your users are getting
when it comes to text input.
So for more information
you can visit this URL,
where you'll find
We have got a bunch
that are coming up this week.
I want to call up two
that are both about
So have a great rest
Thank you.
[ Applause ]