[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, good morning, everyone.
So, my name is Tom Witkin,
and I'm an Engineer here
And this morning, we're
about building quick
into your Apple Watch apps.
And first off, we'd like to
what do we even mean
So I'm sure that many of
for iOS or for Mac OS.
And on those platforms, we're
of time a user is spending
of minutes or even hours.
But in watchOS, it's
A user wants to be able to raise
to specific information or
and then drop their
to whatever they were doing.
And so the interaction
So here are some examples
of what a quick interaction
So, for example, starting a
or marking an item
And so we think that these are
of interactions on Apple Watch,
and there are some key
that you've probably
So, first off, apps
they need to be glanceable.
Which means that,
your users should be able to get
Apps need to be actionable,
which means that your users
and well-informed decisions.
And lastly, they
You should never be
And if you're interested in
I highly recommend
out the Designing Great Apple
afternoon, or watch the video
of the What's New in
And so now we know a
by a quick interaction.
But how long is a quick
And so we think that
of interaction is
So, 2 seconds.
That's not very long at all.
And so you have to be very
and build your applications.
But we think that it's
especially with all the
that we've added in watchOS 3.
And so that's how we're
is by talking about these
And then afterward,
at some practical techniques
to build these types
And with that, I'd like to hand
to talk through the
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Tom.
Hi, everybody.
My name is Miguel.
I'll be giving you a quick
that we're introducing
to implement quick interactions.
I'll be talking about five
to make your apps glanceable,
The first has to do with
to new kinds of input.
You can now do gestures
with gesture recognizers
We are giving you access
to the rotation events
And we're also having
One is for improved
the support for the new
as well as integration with
So let's jump right in.
I'll be giving you an
and then Tom will come back
of how he combines
So if you have used
you pretty much already
for gesture recognition
If you haven't, gesture
that help you parse the
into recognizable gestures.
We're writing support
Two discretes -- the
And two continuous
the PanGesture, and
So the way you use this, like
in WatchKit, is an interface
You are dragging the
So if you look at the library,
you can now see four
These are dragged into
to have gestures
And you do the configuration
in the inspector.
The last thing you do is drag
into a function within
This is a function
when the gesture is
As you can see, one
of the parameters is the
From it, you can
where the gesture
the bounds of the object,
that the gesture is in.
So, a few words about
Gestures begin in the possible
and they can transition either
to a recognized or
When you're dealing
you really don't think too
All you need to know is that
your action method is called.
This is slightly different
They also begin in
But as their name
over multiple updates
So just assume that your action
times as your gesture is
to update your user interface.
Some tips for using
We recommend that
to the group elements
You can do that, but you
of the gestures that are
And remember that you have
in the Watch app,
to be the bigger interface
You can still set dependency
But for watchOS, this is only
and interface builder.
And be mindful that some
of the system gestures
over the gestures
For example, if you
that already has scrolling
to attach a SwipeDown gesture,
The scrolling will
The same thing for the
Now let's move onto our
the Digital Crown.
This is a unique element
that allows your users quick and
You've had access to the
through the WKInterfacePicker
To use that, you
of picker items and
And WatchKit takes care of
Here is the list style.
You have the stacks style
But for this element,
of a lot of stuff for you.
We're drawing the
of interpreting the
and we're simply calling your
So, in watchOS 3, we are
to the rotation events so
elements and drive them
This is achieved
through new classes we're
which gives you access
I'm sorry, the rotations
And the new delegate
with callbacks on
So you have two kinds of
rotations per second
What do you do with each one of
If you're interested in
you want to access the
which is now present in all
of the interface
And you query its rotations
This is probably something
when you're interested in the
in maybe a physics-based
a game, something like that.
Rotational deltas are
through the delegate protocol.
This is how you're able to
has rotated.
So you will get a callback
You will have the
as one of its arguments.
And what you want to do
to maintain an accumulator
where you add the deltas
The math you want to use
to accumulated deltas of 1.
Another example is if
in detecting half rotations, you
So you're adding the deltas
And when they cross
you know that a rotation
It's really up to you to figure
out how these rotation counts
of the content that
When we're communicating values
either positive or negative.
When your users are
of moving their content up,
we will be giving
And when they're
to moving the content down,
we're giving you
And these values are orientation
to worry about what
or clockwise means.
If your users change their Crown
to give you a positive value
and down, so you don't
Finally, there's a concept
The focus can be taken away
for example, a picker, a
So it's up to you to determine
when your interface
to be the focus of the Crown.
This is a great place to
And once you determine that
in focus again, please
And don't forget to
when your interface
Now let's put aside the input
about the vertical paging
The typical way that your users
by selecting a row
for that particular row
They need to navigate
to select another row before
In watchOS 3, we have the
So when you enable this in
into their first detail, they're
or with the Crown up and down
and see the subsequent
So this eliminates their need to
making your app seem
So how do you opt
It's actually pretty
All you need to do is enable
in your table inspector.
But you also need to make sure
that your table is
That's where you're giving
to instantiate a controller
with the given context.
You're probably already
So the API itself
There's a couple of changes.
There's a single method
into the segue mode from code.
This is useful when you're
from tapping on a complication
and you want to directly go
into a specific row
The second thing you need to be
to be smart and help you
out with the speed
So we're doing preheating
anticipating what the
of scrolling up and down.
So some of the lifecycle methods
for your controllers will be
on screen.
I won't be going too much
But we have a whole new session,
where they give a
on all the badging of
Now let's talk about
These are the ultimate
that we've introduced
of the Apple Watch product.
So from a user's point of view,
the way they interact with
by feeling the haptic
They raise their wrist and
short-look interface
If they keep their hand
into the long-look
The way they respond to
I'm going to walk through
which is the one that
So if you've done
of communicating the
through the text,
than dismiss the notification.
That is the shortest
They could also tap on the
Or, remember that notifications
associated with them.
In this case, I'm
the Accept, Maybe,
You can have up to
When you're associating
they can either be
meaning that if the
your application will become
Background actions in watchOS
to your phone.
The big change in watchOS
that there's a whole new
Please go to the Introduction
to learn all of the details
But the high-level
as WatchKit developers
You now have a set of
across platforms --
You can now schedule local
And notifications
with background actions will now
as long as they were
Let's look at the API.
The new object,
you want to become the
when your application
in the
method.
And you want to indicate
that you are adopting
delegate protocol.
There are two methods
to you in this protocol.
The first is the
This is called when your
on the watch face and the system
to tell it how you want it
So, depending on the
in the completion handler there,
the system will do
If you say that you want
we will revert back to the
for the notification and it will
If you say that you
that means that system
Since your app is
you are the ones taking care
of displaying the
in your application.
The second method is
This is when your users
So this is the callback when
because the user
And this is also the new
where you're getting a
But, remember, this is
that are scheduled
This is a good moment to make a
and delivery of notifications
Anytime a notification fires
to the Watch if the
and you have your Watch on
That's always been the behavior.
But now in watchOS 3,
to schedule your
on the Apple Watch.
So keep in mind that these are
And if your application needs
to also have a corresponding
it's up to you to
and schedule your
Now you might be wondering,
"If I schedule multiple
what happens when
Well, you have the ability to
as you use the same identifier
and on the iPhone side
So if we're in a situation
where we're forwarding the
we look at the ID first.
And if there's a similar
at that moment on the Watch,
and that's the one
so your users don't see two
Finally, let's talk about the
So SpriteKit and SceneKit are
to do the 2D and 3D
to expand significantly
of your applications.
We have two new classes
that support these frameworks --
and WKInterfaceSCNScene
Again, you do all of the
and interface builder.
You will now see the two
All you do is drag them
and they really pretty
where you're going to
And the configuration
and interface builder.
Once you're ready to
all of your SpriteKit
and SceneKit code
You continue to use the APIs.
I won't be going into the APIs
But once you have your
the integration with
in the presenting of the scene.
So if you're dealing
you call the percent function
on whether you have
And if you have a
all you do is set the scene
And that's all there is in
So I've given you
of the new ToolKit
for creating glanceable,
and responsive applications.
Now Tom will come back and
of how he combines
to make your app
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
And so now we have that
at some practical techniques
of quick interactions.
So we're going to talk
and notifications in your app.
And now these are not new, but
in some unique and new ways.
Then afterward, we're
about having a simple navigation
And then lastly,
about giving your users the
as soon as they're
your applications.
And so we'll start off with
And so we introduced
for third-party apps
And now in watchOS 3, they're
And now there are more faces
and there's some of
that have even more
So, also, now you have the
across your faces to see
So because of this, we
on Apple Watch should
And you'll now see that all the
as well, as you can see
or the Heartrate app.
So why complications?
They're extremely glanceable.
They're on their
And with just a glance,
of really important information.
They are frequently updated.
If your app has a complication
it's updated at least
And so you can always ensure
and current data always
Your app is kept in memory.
And this is really important
of your app extremely fast
within your applications
And complications
to accelerate your
to perform specific
So, for example, if we look
I tap on that and
to the Now Playing screen
because that's what's
to me if I'm playing music.
I can play and pause the
And it makes the whole
because I'm sent
Also new in watchOS 3 and
in the Apple Watch
This is great because
to add new faces to
But it also allows you
and choose among all
And third-party complications
so it's a great way
to discover your complications
and add them directly
And if you want to be part
you create a complication
And there's documentation for
So I highly recommend
So complications on Apple Watch
mechanism to get your
and really provide a lot
So if you don't have a
or you're building a new app,
Next up, we're going to move
And so we all know
on Apple Watch are
and one of the main reasons is
that they're entirely
And so you can make them
But also, it allows you
to display really valuable
in the notification.
So, for example, here in
I can see the name of the event
And ultimately, this can often
to even go and launch
because all the important
in the notification.
And now in watchOS 3, all
and SceneKit, and inline video.
And so you can provide even
of your notifications.
So, SpriteKit and SceneKit --
I'm sure a lot of you think
And they're great for gaming.
And there's a session on Friday
about game technologies
But here, we'd like to
of nongaming types
And so why are they
They allow you entire
and the layout, and the
And so it allows you to create
And so, here, we're
at an example of a Photos app.
So, here, you can see I got a
Ivy, and she has shared
But this does not include
I have no idea what
I have to read the text in order
And so we can definitely
of the customization
in our notification.
So here's an alternative
which is now using
It actually has the photos
It has the photo
And with just a glance, I can
And ultimately, I can make a
on whether I want to go launch
and grab my iPhone and
And if we look at
across the top we have the
And then below that, we
And the key thing I want
that you can mix and
and your WatchKit user
And so maybe you already
or the view animation API.
You can swap those
Or if you just have an
to add animation, you don't
in order to adopt SpriteKit.
So it provides a really powerful
to your interfaces without
and start over, which
And so if you have
make sure to take full advantage
If you just kind of have
think about what information
notification and add a custom
OK. So, next up, we're moving
on to a simple navigation
Earlier, we talked about the new
And that's great for
But here, we'd like to talk
of two other of the technologies
and those are Gestures
And so the Digital Crown
and it's a really
It allows you to quickly
and precisely interact
And it can be used in
So, for example, in the Timer
to scrub through durations
Or in the Photos application,
in and out of the photo.
So you can get really creative
with how you use the Digital
and we're really excited to
And here, though, we'd like
of a running app that puts both
to use to simplify
So, here, we have one
The goal is to show my
of the average time, and
So one version is just to kind
And maybe I can tap in on the
or I can scroll the list
And while this version
that I would need, you kind of
to find what you're looking for.
You have to tap in on rows,
and the information just isn't
And so it can definitely be
So here's an alternative
to have a graph at the top,
And so with just a glance,
I can actually see a lot
And now with the use of
and it will animate between
And then I can also use
through the graph to
So even though there's a lot
it's actually a lot
to the specific information
and it makes the overall
And so, as you can see
and match all the technologies
so Gestures, and the Digital
and they create some really
So as you're building
you should make sure to take
into account all
and see how they can help
to simplify the navigation
A lot of focus has gone into
and we really want to
through to all of
And so, last up, we're going
that allows your users to
as they're done interacting.
And so a key aspect in
on Apple Watch is that your app
And this is especially true
of networking or communicating
Because often times,
to loading indicators,
And one aspect of this is
if you're updating the
And that's a large enough topic
that there's actually
on keeping your Watch
So make sure and check that out.
But here, we'd like to talk
of responding to user action.
So, for example, you have a
to buy some food and
How does your app respond
And we want to recommend that
to your users rather than
So we'll walk through an
So, here, we have that
talking about.
I can tap on one of
and there's a big Buy button,
to be a really fast
And I tap on Buy and I
And that's because the app has
it has to process the order, it
And then once it's done that, it
And only then is it going to
and say, "Hey, your
And if we look at
it really shows the problem.
Right? We start with
We tap Buy.
And then we show the
And during this time, the
and stares at your app until
And so the user is only
at the beginning and the end,
and so most of the time
So we can definitely improve
So, alternatively, if we
and now we tap the Buy button,
The key thing here is
because we haven't
We can't actually say
because we have no idea.
But we want to provide
and ultimately give
that the app is taking
And this allows the user then
and not have to wait
And now, in the background,
the app will use a background
with the server, and then
And then, in the background,
and it can use the new local
"OK, now your order
It's on its way."
And then you have all the same
And looking at a
it really shows how much it
So we choose an item,
and so we start out
And then instead of showing
we show the feedback.
And then after we
we show the notification.
And so as far as the
the overall interaction
as it was in the first example.
But from the user's point
and far more responsive.
And so it's just a better
I do want to point out here
that processing after the
If you're doing networking,
you can use a background
And make sure to
because that will enable
up in the background
And then at that point, you
that makes sense in
Or if you have to do
you can take out a
We had a great walkthrough
in a session last year called
so make sure to check that
of processing on
So 2 seconds is a very
of how fast interactions
But we really think that
as you're building
because it can really inform
So as you're going about
or thinking about your existing
on quick interactions right
And think about what
that your users are
in your applications, and make
to the very front and are
Use complications
because they just create really
and they just provide a lot
for your applications.
Use SceneKit and SpriteKit
but also interactive
And they can add a lot of power
to your existing
And so we're really excited
to be doing with those.
Simplify the navigation.
Again, a lot of work
to simplify the navigation
But we also want that to
of our applications as well.
And, again, never
If you're showing a
try and reorganize your app
to allow the user
Provide the instant
and just give the
that your app is
And so for more information on
go and check out the
And there are tons
I highly recommend the Designing
talk this afternoon or the
With that, I want to
And enjoy the rest of the
[ Applause ]