[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and welcome.
My name is Nurinder Manj and
of TVMLKit team.
I'm here with Parry
to build great apps
Now most of you here have built
through the hard work
and optimizing user interface.
Often that means sacrificing
Some of you have built web
dynamic updates, but the user
TVMLKit, which is a brand new
bridges the gap between these
When you build your apps using
feel, and perform
Let's get started.
Today, first I'm going to talk
about what the framework
Next, we have sample app
to demonstrate a
But before that, I will cover
The latter half of the talk is
of the exciting new
to introduce for tvOS 10.
Let me walk you through some
This is an app store
a gorgeous iTunes movies app,
Another example is Apple Music.
In fact, all of these
with Apple TV are
And if you take a step back
to consider what are
they have a common goal.
They let people browse, interact
of content in a simple,
So what does the
The framework offers
interface, which is
saving you both development
That rich and complex
that you just saw is defined
and JavaScript drives
Templates are very flexible.
You can change their appearance
Now the framework
to the templates
You can enhance existing
by adding your own views
or even create brand
You can also extend
that is specific to your app.
And let me assure you
It an optimized native user
Let's build an app.
There are three main components
about that we are going to
First is Xcode to create and
Next, I will talk about
to configure the templates.
And last, I will talk
how it will drive
Now before we dig into details,
like from an architectural
A typical TVMLKit app is based
on a client server
where your client app is
on a tvOS device and your
and JavaScript files.
The framework offers an
that will download the main
up a JavaScript environment
over the control to JavaScript.
Once the control is handed
for downloading any
to present the templates
And JavaScript is
for handling any user events and
Now the first step to
Xcode provides TVML application
as a starting point
This is the partial code that
The first step here is to modify
to your main JavaScript file.
Next step is to create an
associate the javaScriptURL,
and you can optionally also
that will be passed on to the
And the last step is to create
instance with the
and that will download your main
and hand over the
You can also optionally
to monitor the state of your
if it launched successfully
Next let's talk about templates.
Now TVML is a Markup
to define Apple-TV-specific
The Markup when presented
from JavaScript translates
Now once it is presented, you
and those changes
to user interface in
Templates out of the
You don't have to do
Just fill in your content
However, you can
and behavior using styles
In terms of Markup,
that wraps the templates.
This is the XML structure
There are two child elements.
The first is head,
which encapsulates all the
The second element is the
Each template has a unique
Let's take a look at
This is the Top Movies page
This template allows
through stacks of content.
In Markup, it is called
In this particular example,
this template is
At the root of the template
which encapsulates various
shelves, grids, and
Now the top row here
which allows horizontal
with the focused
This control when in idle state
and the Markup to create
where you have a
of lockups with imagines.
There is no any additional
The row next to the
which also allows horizontal
And the Markup to represent that
but shelf allows you
and can have one
Each section further
and must have one
So what is a lockup?
A lockup is a UI control
that encapsulates image
This is a [inaudible],
And going back to our example,
that is focused has its
This is not the default
This is an example of how you
Let me show you how to do this.
Here we are defining a new class
which has a highlight style
to marquee and show
and then you set this class not
of the lockup and that
However, this is a fairly
Let me show you a
This is a stackTemplate again.
Here we have a banner which has
and banner is a sibling
There's a background color
and the template seamlessly
into the banner image
The layout for the banner title
and the button is
Another familiar example
This is also a stackTemplate.
The background image on
by the framework by
as a hero image element.
And again, the layout
and the buttons is
Now there are numerous templates
And using styles, you can
that suit your brand.
TVML Catalogue is a
and interact with templates.
Please check it out.
Now as I mentioned before,
between native and
You just saw how easy
and complex user interface
Let me show you how
the application.
The JavaScript engine that
by JavaScriptCore framework and
to debug and performance
And starting tvOS 10,
JavaScriptCore is ES6
[ Applause ]
TVMLKit adds platform-specific
to help drive the application.
Now the standard web APIs like
between client and server;
listen for user events,
session storage are all
In addition to that, TVMLKit
APIs, for instance to
access system info,
play [inaudible] slideshow
In addition to that,
the framework also
to handle media playback.
Now one important thing I
that there is a single
application controller, and you
within that single context.
Let me go into details for
The first is app object.
App object provides callbacks
and the first and
This is the starting point for
Another API I would
to handle errors,
You must provide this
to handle those unexpected
Now once the control is
the first thing you will want
to do is probably
To do so, NavigationDocument is
with here and it's equivalent
to a UINavigationController
There is a global
and you can now create
Now you're only responsible
[inaudible] them as a result
of Menu gesture is
There are three main APIs that
The first two here
and replaceDocument
Let me show you a recommended
Here is a code snippet to
Typically when you are
or launching the app, you
so that the users know
And once you have created
you would use pushDocument
Now while you are waiting for
and prepared, later
to replace your loading document
And to do that, you would
This is a very common
to show the Spinner right away
from the network.
And the last API is presentModal
or actually any other
Now the key to TV watching
and we have made
Let me show you how to do that.
With less than 10 lines of code,
you can configure a
playback experience.
Let me walk you through
First, create a MediaItem
and the URL to the video stream.
You should also specify title,
so that it can be made
of the video playback
Next, create a playlist and add
And the last step is to
associate the playlist,
And that gives you a
playback experience.
In addition to that,
like to handle interstitials,
chapter groups, time
of other APIs are also provided
from within JavaScript
Now similar to video playback,
we have also extended the
and doing so is very similar.
The only thing changed
and the URL to an audio stream.
And that gives you
and functional Audio
which is the same
Now if you're building a music
that you should do which
so that it can continue
in the suspended state and
to how you have done it
up a playback category
and add the background
and the rest is handled
And with that, I would like
to demo Building a
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Nurinder.
Hello, everyone.
My name is Jeff.
I'm here to show you a TVML
of the things that we've
You'll also get a
to build a native application
So for this demo, we'll be
of the WWDC app.
In terms of the user interface,
of content where each shelf
for a single track
So just imagine having a
app frameworks, design,
So let's get started.
So this is the Xcode project
Let's start with the
which is our app's entry point.
In the application
as you can see in just
we have bootstrapped
as a TVML application.
We also specified the
which happens to
that is running on this Mac.
So if you look at this
this is where I've configured
And as you can see, there is a
which is the JavaScript file
that drives the TVML
There is also a JSON file here
that we need for this demo.
So let's work through
So at the top of this file here,
to hold our model data.
Next in the App.onLaunch
that gets called when TVML
So the main thing that
to fetch our JSON file and then
the data.
Now before we go
we should really be showing a
This is always recommended
for better user experience
over the network.
So let me add a few
So the way to do
to create a loading
And this is done
called createLoadingDocument.
Let's jump into this
that we are basically
for a loading template and then
using the DOMParser.
Now returning to
after creating the
we will now use the
to push the document onscreen.
So this is like using
So now that we have a loading
we will now call a function that
which will use the built-in
to fetch our JSON file and
in a callback.
Next, we will convert the
into our JavaScript
Now as our UI calls
we will be creating a
So let me paste some
into our createStackDocument
Now as you can see, similar to
for the loading template
we are creating the Markup
So within the stackTemplate
we've added a top
And within the body
we are actually looking through
and creating a shelf
And this is done using the
that I have here.
So let's jump into
And again, we are creating the
And within its body, we are
for each session video.
So let's now jump into the
and you will see that we
for a single lockup that
And in this case, we are
as a custom attribute.
We are also adding an
and the height and a title.
So just a recap, we have now
that contains multiple
and within each shelf element,
we have multiple
So now let's return to
So after creating
we will now use the
to replace the loading document
with our stackDocument.
And with that, we are
Let's switch to Apple TV.
So there you go.
We now have a beautiful
[ Applause ]
where each shelf contains image
So as you can see, with
we were able to create an
and feels right at
So the next thing that we
to play a video when we
At the moment it
So let's head back into Xcode
So back into our
I will now add these
So this will register for
The select event is when
of the Siri Remote and the
when you press on
And in both cases,
my playSelectedLockup
So let's jump into this
So the first step is to
from the event.
From there, we can retrieve
custom attribute.
Next, we will create a new
of the type video and
of the video, as shown here.
We will also populate other
such as the title,
Next, we will create
and push our mediaItem
And finally, we will
set the playlist, and
to play the video
So just a recap, we have
with a playlist that
So with that, let's
So back on a UI, we will now
on the lockup and the video
in full-screen mode.
[ Music and Applause ]
Thank you.
And you can press
to exit the video as well.
So that was video
Thank you for your time.
Back to you, Nurinder.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jeff,
But just little amount of code,
you could build a
which is performance
The spacing between the lockups,
text treatments all
Before we continue, let me
Using the TVML application
create and configure
You learned how to create
and a complex stack
And you learned how to use
or replace documents
JavaScript is responsible
And in this case, we handle
and configured video to playback
Now when we introduced TVMLKit,
you could already
and a lot of you already did.
So thank you.
You have provided some
to make it even better.
We have been hard at work
and are adding some exciting new
and would help take your
To talk all about them, I would
like to invite Parry
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Parry and I'm
of the new features
in TVMLKit in tvOS 10.
Now TVMLKit provides you
with highly desirable app-level
yet flexible interface.
And the new features we've added
For example, simply by
in the search results
you can make the results
as the user is typing.
This provides an engaged
as they are trying to
Or if you have a music app,
to the top-level Menu bar, you
of Now Playing audio experience
So it comes in and goes out as
This gives your users a
to the playlist and
Now all of these features
but they're also very
And to show you that, I'm
talk about them, and at
in the demo you just saw.
So let's start with the first
light and dark appearance.
In tvOS 10, there's a new dark
systemwide and all
Your TVMLKit app is
by configuring the
It's the same thing you would
application using UIKit.
So you'll specify the appearance
You can say either
in which case it picks
But no matter which
your standard TVMLKit app
out of the box, without
All of our templates are
for both appearances,
And TVMLKit switches between
so you get it for free.
However, if you have explicit
then you will have to
for both appearances as well.
Let's take an example.
So here's a template that has
to black using an
This may not work
And for it to work,
to define the class foo specific
So in order to do
we've added a new media
that has a feature
which you can create
that is specific
So simply combine
up for both the appearances,
group them in their
put them in the document,
and TVMLKit will pick
So with little configuration
of code, your apps are
Now let's move on
that also enhances
but in a different way.
Let's talk about
It's fair to say that
of TV watching experience.
And if you have a catalogue
then you want your users
as they launch your app.
And embedding videos in your
Now just to show you what
to your app, we created
of the demo you just saw but
Have a look.
[ Music ]
It's seamless.
Not only it's not obtrusive
but it compliments it.
It makes it more immersive.
And as expected, TVMLKit does
for you and gives you this
to work with it.
So let's have a look at that.
So in a nutshell with TVMLKit,
and a playback area
Most likely it's going
TVMLKit handles the playback
to do is specify when
So you can say that
when the containing lockup
as it appears on the screen.
You have full control
over transitioning the
And if you have advanced use
for instance, then you have
in JavaScript with all of its
Now you can embed videos using
First, you configure
Second, you configure the player
with the media item
And third, you want to handle
to full screen.
Let's have a look at these
So we've made configuring the
We've added a new element
that you can use the wrap
in which you want
This gives the lockup
and look before the
And the image inside the
in which the video will play.
You can specify the
on the mediaContent as
as the lockup gets focused
Here's an example.
So here's a lockup
which wraps the image
And the width and height on
in which the video will play.
Second step, configure
Now each one of these
with its own player,
that player in JavaScript.
Simply query for
from the mediaContent's
and configure the playlist
with the media item
Here's a small code for that.
Now if you notice
of the player is
from what you saw in the demo.
You create a playlist,
and you set it on the player.
But there are two differences.
One, you don't have to
You just use the
And two, instead of doing it
when the user selects
you do it well in advance.
In fact, you do it even
which brings me to
For better user experience,
you must configure the player
Once the document is loaded,
you can change the playlist
And finally the last step,
Now it's worth noting the
transition for you.
It's one of those flexibilities
So you'll add an event
for the lockup and use
to trigger the transitioning
Here's a small example.
So here, I have added
on select event on the document.
I'm grabbing the
from the subtree
Now this would be the lockup
because all events get
And finally calling present
to trigger the transitioning.
Now you have full control
but transitioning back
to embedded mode happens
So that's it.
With these three easy steps you
inside your apps so
But what happens next?
What happens when the users
They're watching your content.
How can you make
Well that brings me to the
about today that lets
Interactive video overlays.
Now in a sense, it's a
in that it lets you
by putting a user
and you can do so much with it.
For example, you can suggest
so that they can pick from
You can let them skip
and implement a perfect
for them.
Or you could implement
of your content while the users
Even if you do it with
as interactive metadata, like
so much more engaging
And as you've seen
implementation is really simple.
You basically create a document,
and set it on the player,
that document when the
Here's the code for that.
We've added a new
in tvOS 10 called
So when you set the
we will present it for you
If the player is already
your documents will get
but if the player is not
in the embedded mode,
when the video goes full screen.
So it's really convenient
to just set it at
And with that, let's
Let's implement these features
in the presentation,
let's welcome back
Jeff.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Parry.
Hello again.
Let me show you the new stuff.
So back on the Apple TV.
So this was the demo that
Now let's go Home and hit
Let's navigate down to the
We will now toggle the
So let's go Home again.
Now because we created the
we will have the
to support automatic
So what this means is
to support dock appearance
So let's see how this looks.
Boom. There you go [applause].
Look how beautiful our UI is
And again, zero code
Now let's talk about
For our demo, we
to start playing automatically
As Parry mentioned earlier,
there are three main
Step one is to use the
Step two is to configure
And step three is to
Let's get back into Xcode.
So let's get into the
Now instead of creating a
here, I will now add the
and have it wrap our image.
That is it.
So that is step one.
Pretty easy.
Now onto step two.
Now as Parry also
each mediaContent element
in with an embedded player.
So what we will need to do is to
with a corresponding playlist
So let's head back into
Now before we present
I will now call a function
that I created called
And inside this function,
we are first retrieving
from this document.
And for each
similar to the previous demo,
we will be creating a
a new playlist object that
but instead of creating
we will use the getFeature
to retrieve the embedded player
and then we just set
So that was step two.
The final step is to
So let's head into the
which as you recall is triggered
We won't be needing
so let's replace
First we are retrieving the
then retrieving the mediaContent
and again using the getFeature
to the embedded player, and then
to take it full screen.
So let's see how this looks.
So as you can see, [Background
playing automatically inside
And when I clicked on the
to the video into
&gt;&gt; Welcome to 2015
and welcome your host
&gt;&gt; Pretty cool stuff.
You can also press the Menu
So that was embedded videos.
The next new feature we wanted
to show you is interactive
So this new feature is going
over the video while
So for our demo, let's say we
of related videos
So let's head back into Xcode.
Now in my playSelectedLockup
I will now call a
that creates my overlay called
And inside this function,
as you can see, we are basically
with a single shelf,
we have multiple
Also, we are changing the
We are adding a blurred
and we are also adding
so that our shelf
at the bottom of the player.
So let's head back into
Now after we create our overlay
to the new modal overlay
and the player object
In fact, the player will show
this property.
Now we can also show
at any time while the video
For example, we might want
to show the overlay 30 seconds
but for the purpose
we will just show
as the video goes full screen,
So let's run this.
Again, the video is going
to start playing
[Background Music].
And when I now take
you will now see the
[ Applause ]
And the overlay is also
around within the
So that was interactive
We hope the demo has
Thank you for your time.
Back to you, Parry.
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jeff.
That was an amazing demo.
Let's quickly recap what
You saw how light and dark
out of the box for TVMLKit apps.
You saw how easy it is to embed
And finally, you saw an example
of a binge-watching
through interactive
Now with that, I would like
learned today.
So there's one thing I
from this presentation
TVMLKit is an easy
that gives you native
and performs like Apple apps.
It's based off of web
and JavaScript that lets you
and reduce the time to market.
And with the new features
and how you saw how TVMLKit
for writing the user interface,
and intellectual energy on
that make your app
I highly encourage you to go to
out documentation and
There's a wealth of
I'd also like to suggest some
What's New in tvOS, and one
to happen tomorrow,
and we talk about how can
view controllers, and even
And finally, I would like to
and I wish you have a very nice
Thank you.
[ Applause ]