[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Oh, please.
My name's Woody.
I work in software
I'd like to welcome
both those of you here in
who are watching from
There's a couple things I'd
in the next 40 minutes.
We're going to take
that you can today start
Then, we'll take a
We'll take a look at
Well, it's not really new but
to start using called
And in the latter half of the
from my presentation last
So, let's get going.
Last year in the session at one
that was describing a scenario.
You were describing something
to be quite familiar
You've got your boss that's
for features and the features
to get paid, so you do that.
Then you've got your
to fix the bugs that
And you take pride in your work
Some technical debt that
Sometimes I think about building
up a pile of Jenga blocks.
In the first version,
and you start piling
and then it becomes unstable and
So, you want to take a step
of the lower-level issues.
With all these things,
And we pile on new API.
And then we give you
and it breaks source
but introduces some
And you were warned, so
And then we introduced
and new extension points and
like Siri and Messages.
And if you want to think of your
of a run loop with all these
well, you know what
There's too much stuff.
So, what you do?
What are some things
to get ready for the fall?
First of all, if you were to
of iOS 8 and 9, you would
So, there's really no
of those deployment
Let's get rid of that.
In fact, the general idea is
that you take the current
and then set your
to one version back, maybe 8.4.
But don't go to 8.3 or 8.2
and your customers don't
that we've implemented under
When we come out with iOS 10
set your deployment
Next, Issue Navigator.
Resolve those issues.
Take a look at them
When we tell you that
that there is a deprecated API,
of reasons, including to
or to better, have
or to permit more performance
in the arguments return values.
And there's really no excuse
because we tell you right there.
It tells you what to use.
So, just use that.
Switch over those.
Next, you might decide that you
and we've had that for a
But now we also have it
I know.
[ Applause ]
I think I'm the first
I really like this idea.
I think it's fantastic,
because it forces you and your
It's far too easy to
and think you'll come back to
and that's the whole
Also, do you think this would
of a new project, a new
we're going to ship
to have any art work in
We're not going to
We'll ship it and
up in the .1 release.
That would never fly.
No one's going to do that,
because this is how users
Well, actually it's how
of them interact with your app.
Many of them interact with your
features that we have built
So, why would ship your app with
or want it or use it but then
features in there?
That's not fair.
So, resolve some of
that comes to accessibility.
Add support for that.
We think that the accessibility
of your user interface
It's built into Xcode,
so you can use Interface
It's also easy to
We have a lot of
You should be using those
that you have to write.
That generally isn't
But these are.
Dimensions and measurement
If you've got recipe
and you've been converting
on your own code,
and use our code that's now
We'd like you to support
Right? You know, if you
you're probably accustomed
and see if it does anything.
No, nothing.
So, let's push hard on that
Well, that one does something.
It's hard to discover.
How awesome would
that we had already
Pop and Push and the 3-D touch?
Next. We want you to run
developer preview of Xcode 8.
If it doesn't migrate your code,
Then we have an opportunity
that when you run migrator
on the final release of
If it doesn't work,
of our own technical
The public interface is the same
but the implementation might
And it could be that the way
that we didn't expect.
So, you have an edge case.
So, tell us about that too.
This is why we do
We want you to file bug reports.
The report isn't just
And it's not just
and is not just sending
The proper way to file
BugReport.Apple.com.
Fill in the blanks.
And then once you do
and then that's the
and post back into
There's a lot of Apple engineers
We like to hear what you are
or when you report an
and you don't include the bug
for us internally to
and get traction on it.
So, do that.
Next, you're probably
of filing bug reports with us.
Because you've filed
and nothing seems to happen.
You get nothing back.
In the words of Whitney Houston,
Well, they seem to go in
because you never
Or you think maybe you get
and the engineer kind of
I want to just assure
One of the first things I did
when I joined Apple
in the bug tracking system,
to find all the issues that I
And a lot of them had traction.
I just didn't have any
So, I wanted to show you
we do look at them.
The other thing that I find
of time filing a bug.
A lot of time maybe you're
You're trying a couple
You're checking for regression.
Like, that's great stuff to do.
It takes you maybe half
and then you file
and it says it's a dupe.
And you're like, oh, I
hour my life for something
So, I just want to
Because dupes first of all
It's not like if you copy
and you file a new bug with
we're going to say oh,
we should fix that first.
It's not quite like that.
What we do do with them though,
it just means these
We need dupes too, not
but because we can have five
same root issue.
The first four don't give
to be able to find it.
But maybe it's your report,
albeit, is a dupe, but
that we need to find the issue.
In fact, an Apple engineer
for gosh, a couple decades,
Paul had said that each bug
All right.
So, in summary, things
Fix your warnings.
Replace your deprecated API.
Localize your App if
Use accessibility.
Or support accessibility rather.
Get Peek and Pop in there.
And then take a look at
and give us some
With that, let's move
It's time to move
For you. So, if you still have
like this, go ahead and get them
The approach is you add a
By the way, you don't have
You can have as many catalogs
Maybe you're working on an app
So, you have a catalog for
and a second catalog for the
We can do that.
Another example, you might have
Xcode for free from
and create the Asset
And then send it to you or
We could do that too.
When we copy files into an Asset
They are copies.
We don't reference the
So, they do participate
To migrate your project,
Choose Import From Project.
We're going to give you
that are eligible to be
into the Asset Catalog.
There you go.
You migrated your image Assets.
If you previously used
pathForResource etc.,
because once we compile the app,
the images aren't
So you won't find anything.
But if you're using image named,
in an Asset Catalog
if they're just free-floating
This API has been
This API Image Name has
and beyond just being
from an image catalog.
Asset Catalog.
For example, it internally
that you asked for
We load it up, we give
The second time you ask
we just return another
That's not how the
Contents of file loads
So, it's much more perform an,
through a table,
We support multiple
So, with image names, you'd
You'd let the framework
that you're running on.
Consider the resolution of the
retina on a Plus device.
And possibly other
for the media assets such as the
or the version of Metal that
And you get an image back.
There's two broad kinds
that you can consider.
We have scaled images.
Those are like PNG's, JPEG's.
And then we have
or just vector-based
We treat them a little
On an asset by asset basis,
to be vector-based and that
You do that by specifying
So, I'm going to talk first
and then move onto the
For scaled images, in this
to provide three different
from 1X devices,
If we don't find, because
the 2X and 3X, we'll take the 1X
that it becomes, well,
on the higher end devices or
Likewise, if you just
we'd scale it down at runtime.
These two scenarios
In this scenario, if I take
up for an iPhone 6S Plus, it's
It's going to have a visual
It's not very desirable
your customers aren't
This one, at first
I'll just provide the 3X artwork
But there's a huge problem
down a 3X image, we
And it's really big.
And then we take an
and create a scaled-down
It's an order, two orders of
So, consider this.
You're on a device
There's no need for
but you only provide 3X images.
So, we start off with the
That's fine, but then we
down convert it, get
and keep this scaled-down
which just temporarily
And if you're good, it's
But if you good, I mean
if you're lucky it's
But let's say you're
and as you're scrolling,
All of a sudden the
for your app balloons
when you use too much memory?
Anybody know, just
Yeah, right.
We terminate it.
It's terminated because you
So, provide the artwork.
In fact, you can do this
not a task but with
You give it a 3X image, let it
Scale it down, give it a name.
Great, throw those all
And if you wanted to, you could,
and this is another
Use this naming convention,
the non-retina ones is
And then add 2X and
And then when you drag
into an Asset Catalog, we
We create one asset with the
as opposed to three
For Vector Assets,
because the file contains a
to draw the image as opposed
This is the same image, not
Same image scaled
When you specify
to use single vector scaling,
you're providing one
And at build time,
into the different
It's much simpler for you.
This is the kind of thing you'd
and navigation bar images.
There you go, scale
It's also possible
You can set the scale factor
And what you do is you provide
like the limits in
Then, if you want
for the other scale factors,
as either other vector images
Then when we build it, if we see
we'll just rasterize those
in the All truck well or target.
Otherwise, we'll use the
New in Xcode 8, you can
Come on, you.
You can adjust the compression.
So, we can say for a
to use glossy compression
for a PNG we don't want
because it's going to be
We don't want to see
Another issue you can resolve
just in case the pitch
is to fix the issue or
We're referring to
The issue with rounded
So, your button might
that fits perfectly well
in a different language and
And when we change the size
to preserve the beautiful
The way you would even
in the first place is
in Interface Builder
and specify a background image.
And then we apply that
In this example, I have an
and I apply that as my
but you can see in the
when it's stretched out it's
So, one way you can
that you've been
which is using Stretchable
And you say well, I want
of pixels on both sides.
And that's fine but
of this presentation is
and rely more on the frameworks
So, instead this is built
It's called Asset Slicer.
And you can use it to
in red, don't stretch these.
Don't distort them.
The portion that's illuminated,
And by doing that, you get
and you don't have to
This is also something you could
because it's part
All right, next up, let's talk
about a design pattern
Let's first of all talk about
or trying to change
So, we have UITextField and
and the delegate is called
Fine. And in it, it
to text fields, like
Okay? We have WCSession.
And WCSession delegate.
What's inside the delegate?
Methods that relate
You can see the pattern here.
Which we break with this one.
We have the app delegate
that relate to the
But then we stick other stuff
and essentially eventually
in there including the
And we do it because it's
through the Application
cast it and retrieve it.
But it's such a strong coupling
and your app delegate and your
to be the place where that goes.
Instead of a pattern like this
where each view controller
to some common object,
in your app delegate,
Using Dependency Injection,
that one view controller
to the next view
that view controller
The idea is you give the
that it needs to do its job.
So, for mail, you'd have
A view controller
of mailboxes would have a model
of mailboxes.
You tap on one of the mailboxes.
Another view controller's
to show the messages
The middle one.
And you pass forward the one
and you keep passing it forward.
The way you would do that in
for segue and pass
The way you would do it
if you were programmatically
for the button viewed
The view controller,
The benefit of this technique
standalone now.
They don't have these strong
You can reuse them more.
Coming back, you've
You can do what we do, which
and have you implement it
to say the view controller's
and maybe update
You can pass in a closure.
You can pass object
Or, you can, if you're
it's exactly the same as
because it happens in both ways,
forward directions
Another reason why
because view controllers are
They should be able to be
of each other to
In this case, an iPhone SE's
to be different for your
on an iPad 12 inch,
If your view controllers
it's easy to do that.
All right.
Now, last year at WWDC,
on topics including playgrounds
And interoperability with
And since then, we've added
things that we couldn't
So, I want to show you
With that, we're going
So, this is the periodic
that I showed you last year.
Since then, it's been
For example, the colors
Instead of using states
now it's the kind of object
halogen, that kind of thing.
We've also added
out so it actually looks like
and that's a collection
I want to show you
One of the things that
since the last time
that the data model has
So now I have a class the
like nitrogen or oxygen.
And I have a class that
of those called, excuse
This class instantiates
the individual atomic elements,
Which I've also stored
But now that I've moved
I can show you the data
Last year when I did
to make a new playground first.
New file, playground.
Last year when I did
pasting between my
And when you do this a lot, your
with a lot of code in it.
So, instead our playgrounds
for source code and resources.
I can take my model
into the sources folder.
And then we compile
and we implicitly import
into the playground to make
Which means if I take this
and include that in
which makes it accessible
I can come over to
and instantiate an instance
Here's Californium.
Like that.
So, the ability to
and have them automatically
when they're in the
or the resources folder is a
to keep your playgrounds
and concise while also having
Now, above and beyond that,
since last year that affects
The International Union of Pure
and Applied Chemistry
of 4 additional elements.
So, now all of a sudden
that I've got embedded
like such good idea anymore.
So, I thought well,
We'll just put it online.
So I set up a little Web
at this time with
And then the idea is that
initially it'll use the
That way if there's no
there's still something
And this is also a pattern
Then we'll do a background
and in the background
if there's an update
And if so, we'll put
and we'll reference
So, I want to do the network
And for that, we have the class
and now known as URL Session.
Which is shown here.
We grabbed the Session and the
when I call it out on line 24,
is I give it a completion
Because this runs asynchronously
Go to the Network Request,
When the request either times
it gives us call back.
And in the call back on line 28,
you can see I'm printing
But you actually don't
That's a problem.
So, just think about
We have a playground
We asked it to do a
At some indeterminate
we get a call back saying
But playgrounds typically
The first line all the way
through to the end
Key word being typically.
But they don't have to.
We can get a runloop and
in our playgrounds.
To do that we import
playground support.
And then you ask the playground
And then it never stops,
So, now if I scroll
you can see I'm getting
There's cadmium.
All right.
Next I want to expand
Last I showed a drawing,
a rounded corner
This time I don't just want to
I want to do a whole table view
And we have some new features
in the playgrounds
Let me just open up
Call it View.
So, I'm going to make a subclass
This is all that it
I'm implementing the 2
or Table View Controller
Number of objects, sorry,
self-wrote index that and
And I'd like to see that live.
So, this time what we do is we
and then using that
that I've already imported, the
I grab the playground's
And then we take that
into the assistant editor who's
but rather our Live View.
See? It's a Live Table View.
It scrolls, it's active.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Is not just a static image.
It's a real interactive
If you wanted to try some
or even the existent delegate
into the playground and
No need to put this into
So, now I want to take the two
Specifically, I have this
that's happening.
And after I retrieve the data,
So, let me show you that.
First of all, comment this.
And just to prove to you that
from that site, I'm
so I have an empty
All right.
So, I have an empty
I do the network request.
When the network
and it's call back, it's a sign.
The new array of elements
And then we reload
All right.
Is that what you would expect?
It's not what I expected the
Oh, that must be a bug in Xcode.
I'll just go file a bug
But it's actually not.
It's a bug in my code,
It's a bug in my code and
We have this background
The background operation
It's not on the main thread.
UI is in the main thread.
So, in my closure, the
I can't be updating the
which is what I'm trying to do
When I tap on the cells,
and that's why they do refresh
and you can see them
This is also something
We have something new in
for Grand Central Dispatch.
So, instead of that
I can now say a dispatch
What kind of operation?
An asynchronous one.
We don't need that anymore.
And here's what I wanted
Now it bounces back to the
Dispatch cue, thank you,
Live Views in Swift and
Let's switch back to the slides.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So, just as a point of
from the previous presentation,
Some other tips.
When I dragged those files
or the resources
They are not referenced.
Also, only methods that are
properties, and datatypes,
as public are going
to you in the playground.
So, you might have to go
because the default
in Swift is internal,
I mentioned using
Now, we still have
that are constrained
And those customers try
of the operating
out there's not enough space.
So, what we do when that
under storage pressure, is we
and we delete everything
in all the applications
This way we free up space.
We need your help with this.
If you are temporarily
and you're not putting
put it in the caches folder.
Next. I thought it'd
it's doing that again.
To take the view controllers
and rearrange them in a way that
So, I'm going switch
Turn on my Bluetooth.
And take the view controllers
Well, there we go.
I have paired my
so I can use it with
It's exactly the same code
same table view, all
I can go over and I can see
And I get that neat TV effect
and its collection view.
It's the same layout code.
It's the same view controller.
It's all the same as
Well, almost.
I added this line
when I selected a
you would get that focused item.
And I used the OS
to say this is only for tvOS.
Other than that,
Which kind of brings
that if you ever think you are
and just dropping it
with no real other changes,
you're possibly doing something
out the human interface
to see how you can make
on that platform more native and
Let me give you an example.
Let's say that you made
of like cloud-based accounting.
And maybe you have an iPad
people fill out invoices.
Makes sense.
It makes no sense,
to fill out invoices
You just wouldn't do it.
Why would you do that?
This is not an app you
and launch it on tvOS.
But, the iPad version of your
visualization about how
Maybe you've got some
Those would be awesome on a TV.
You could have a version of your
of how the company's doing.
And maybe in the company's
on and it just animates
It's the same data model.
It's the same data access.
But you pivoted that
that makes it more
in which it's running.
And that's an idea I
How can we take the same data
in a way that works
In summary, modernizing your
We want you to rely on the
If you can get rid of
and instead use code that
that's code let's code
We'd like you to do that.
We want you to get started today
with the Swift converter.
We want you to architect
with fewer inter-object
for you to rearrange your app.
Finally, we want you to
to other platforms
by pivoting your data model.
There are some related
There you go.
And other than that, you
for this particular session.
And that is it for me.
Thanks, everyone.
[ Applause ]