[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
I'm Brian Weinstein.
I'm an engineer on
And today Zach, Damian and
to extend your Mac app
In macOS Sierra and
we are introducing a new
and distributing
These extensions leverage
and native code written
They're bundled with the Mac
through the App Store.
That new way is Safari
Safari app extensions have the
of webpages using
They have the power to block
or elements on a page.
They can add toolbar
And those toolbar
to display popovers using
to build the views.
And lastly, Safari app
to context menus on webpages.
Safari app extensions are
Which are bundles of
that are packaged inside
to give your users access
and content throughout macOS.
And so this means that they
and other developing tools you
and it means that Safari app
with the power of the APIs
Another major benefit
on app extensions is that they
Which means that they can be
And it means that
to download your
after installing your app.
And for those of you who require
and your extension,
of Safari app extensions is
that your extension is always
because they're packaged
So, your users will always
of your app and your extension.
One of the best parts of
that it's capable of
of extensions.
Today we're going to build
The first type is a content
which can block the loading
or hide elements on the page.
The second type will
that modifies the contents
between the JavaScript code
and the extension's native code.
And the third type of
to extend Safari's UI to add
of your app directly to Safari.
So, let's get started
To build a content
I'd like to bring Zach on stage.
Zach?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Ryan.
Hi. I'm Zach Li and I'm also
Last year in Safari we
Blocking model.
Rather than developing extension
or hide elements,
where you can declare ahead
And WebKit optimizes
to make it fast and
Best of all, this model
because the host
for the resources block.
Since then, we've seen so many
have written that really
And users love them.
Today, I'm excited to talk
out existing iOS
For those of you who haven't
before, that's no problem.
You can check out the
on developer.Apple.com.
Let's take a look at what
I really love eating.
I basically eat all the time.
Obviously I have a food
to the food I want to try.
But unfortunately, well,
I will attend my
as his best man next month.
That I need to stay fit.
At least I need to be
So, I created this
that blocks all the
that even if I'm starving
on my food blog, I wouldn't
Let me show you how the
So, this is my source code
and my app dessert
Let's go to Safari.
And the desserts are present.
Let's reload the page with
All the desserts are gone.
That's great.
Although I'll be missing them.
So, I am an iOS developer
and I really want to bring it
through the App Store.
It's actually quite simple to do
because the content blocker APIs
So, let's first go to Xcode.
Create a new Mac Application
blocker for Mac.
And let's quickly switch
because we are now
Then, create a new Mac
Use the content blocker
That's called dessert
When users get Apps from the
to run the application
to find the app extension.
But outside the App Store,
for Safari to see the extension.
So, in this case,
to continue using the
So, I'm just going
This template will set
And it comes with a simple
To make your own content
to modify this JSON file.
It's really convenient.
But in our case, we can actually
So, we can get rid
And the Swift file.
And make the ones we
to the Mac Application,
To accomplish that,
And in the target
check the Mac app
for the resources
Cool. We're pretty
But before that, I do want
to make my dessert
by displaying a better name
in Safari extensions
To accomplish that, let's go
Instead of dessert blocker
just called it dessert blocker.
And the description I want
to provide is this content
on my food blog.com.
Also, I want to provide
for my dessert blocker.
Let's remove the
And drag the ones
with predesigned ice cream
All right.
Let's view it and run
and the application is run.
So, let's go to Safari.
As you can see, it shows up
Like all other Safari
content blocker is
Let's enable this
Reload the page.
Great. All the desserts
Awesome. Now that my urges
to eat desserts are
I'm so ready to be the best man.
[ Applause ]
As you saw, without even writing
content blocker to macOS.
On top of that, we've
that it would be nice to know
is enabled.
So, we are introducing
getStateOfContent
With this API, for example, if
in the app, I can provide a
by giving instructions on how
if I detect my content
This API along with other
and Damian are going to
on Sierra and El Capitan if
Because El Capitan, the API
on the presence of Safari 10.
We are providing you with a
to check at runtime whether
Safari services APIs
Let's step through
If SFSafari service is
you can safely use the new API.
If not, fall back
These are what's new
To talk about other powerful
app extensions, I would like to
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Zach.
So, the next type of extension
that modifies the contents of
to communicate with the
by your app extension.
So, we're going to
that replaces instances
with another throughout the web.
It will get the word to
with from a app extension's
There are 2 ways for
to modify the contents
extensions can inject
and JavaScript content
Let's take a look at how
Stylesheets are injected
in the app extensions Info.plist
Stylesheets are specified using
of the Info.plist file
of dictionaries defining
And each style sheet is defined
where the value is the path
to the resources directory
And any style sheet
for a Safari extension will just
Next up is injecting scripts.
Which is almost exactly
just with two different keys.
Scripts are specified
in the SFSafari content
And the key representing
of style sheet.
And all of your extensions
in their own execution context
which means there are never
with variables in
This also allows Safari to
to your extension's
that aren't available
For example, your extension
with the native code in your app
or perform some action that can
And to facilitate this, we've
so your app extension's
and Swift code can
So, taking a look
you can see that we have Safari
with a box representing
in your extension's
of course completely sandboxed.
And the extension has injected
and that script would
that app extension what
To do that, it just calls
message and passes
Now let's see how the Swift
and responds back with the
Each Safari app extension
which is the class that
on when the user
When a message is dispatched
to the app extension,
from page userInfo is called.
And once that method is called
on our extension's
the first thing we do is check
And to act on it, our extension
to the SFSafari page
with the words to replace and
And we are structuring
where each key represents the
and the value represents what
So, when the app extension
Script(withName,userInfo,
from the extension process
that is injected into Apple.com.
Now let's see how that
for these messages
To listen for a message
we start by adding an event
So, the content script can
from the app extension.
And if you've written a
this will look very familiar.
The API to receive
of a content script is
And when our event listener
from our app extension,
the first thing we do once
as a best practice
To act on this message, we want
that was specified in the
from the Swift code
to JavaScript as event.message.
So, we get our dictionary
and we iterate over
in our content script that
So, this word replacement
that we've been discussing is
But some extensions are
on particular websites.
Safari app extensions
for specifying what sites they
in Safari 10, users
which sites your Safari
Like information about content
your extension's website
in the extension's Info.plist
under the
and it's a dictionary
The first part is the
And this extension is specifying
which means it wants access
to every webpage
And as you can see, Safari's
user about this before they're
And in this example,
the extension has an
When the access level is some,
of domains that it wants access
to in the allowed domain
And if an allowed domain starts
as a wildcard and it represents
So, now that we've discussed how
by injecting content
how those content
with your app extension's
and how you specify what
like access to.
I'd like to put this all
that word replacement extension
So, one of the interesting
about Safari extensions is that
with webpages is JavaScript
to bring code that you've
for a different browser, and
So, what I'm going to do is I'm
that does this word
to create a Safari
And I'm going to extend it so
and what to replace them
So, I already have an app
like to create a
To do that, I create
and select a macOS
and select Safari extension.
And we're going to call this
to Animalify the web
by replacing animals
And as Zach mentioned
so I'm not going to activate
So, we now have our
to jump into the Info.plist.
And open up that
And as you can see,
from the template, we have a
and the website access that
I'm going to get rid
because our extension
And change the access level
of allowed domains because
to run on every page.
The next thing I'm going to do
and I'm just going to bring in
for my Chrome extension
And as you can see, when
into the page, it just calls
and replaces bear
Now, what I would like to
like to have it replaced,
I would like to have it
and the users can choose
which animals they
I'm not going to design
but to support that, we need
from the app extension.
So, instead of doing this
we're going to send
to the app extension asking it
And so one thing that's
that Safari's extensions,
Safari app extension content
dom has loaded for more
But since a word replacer
dom, we want to wait until the
this message.
So, now let's go to
and as you can see, we
for message received with
So, we're going to get rid
with some, with the code that
Which all it does is
and sends a response back
And we're making two
because we can.
So, let's go back to the
for this message and act on it.
And once again, this is
about a few minutes ago.
We start by adding
for the message event
And when that event listener
and get our replacements
And we act on them by iterating
and calling that same
at the beginning of
So, now I would like to build
to discover this new extension.
And you can just imagine
and I've checked a few.
So, I'm just trying out
for the first time.
So, I have not signed up for
up for the Apple
yet which means I don't have
By default, Safari
allow users to enable
with the developer certificate.
But for those of you who
we've added way for
to test your unsigned
To do that, I'm going to open
and show the Develop
And from the Develop menu,
I'm going to select Allow
I'm going to type my password
and now the animal
up in our list of extensions.
I'm going to turn it on and
I was researching the
So I'm just going to reload
bear has now been placed,
and salmon has been replaced
[ Applause ]
And this is just going to
for me to browse.
So, that was how a Safari
content and how your extension
like access to.
The last type of extension that
to make is one that extends
and functionality of your
And to show us how to do that,
I'd like to invite
Damian?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
My name is Damian Kaleta and I'm
So, Brian already told
of Safari App Extensions and now
I want to tell you how you
So, let's start.
I've written this
It's a notebook app.
And as you can see
the icon got some love
Unfortunately, the
But nevertheless, it
saves it so I can view it later.
But now I want to be
of web pages directly and
And with the new Safari
I have all the tools
to build my extension
I'm going to need
So, I want to be able to
to be able to save it.
For that, I'll use
Secondly, I want to be able
and I want to be
For that, I'll use a popover.
The popover shows up when the
So, let's talk about that first.
The toolbar button
to the Smart Search field.
That way your users have
to the functionality that
As you would expect, if
of course you can move
So, how did I add my button?
I went to my extension's
and I've added
Together with four
Identifier, label,
And as with all toolbar items
that I'm using a PDF file here.
Okay, so Safari now displays my
to my extension when the user
Safari sends toolbar
to your principal object.
And as a reminder, your
that handles all of
between Safari and
And also if you want to gray
on the context, Safari provides
And you can also set batch
That usually represents
such as in red count.
So, we've got ourselves a
to display a popover when
The popover lets me insert
which is great because if you
before, you're going
that code really
So, let me show you
You have your extension
and then you'll want to define
on your principal object.
Inside that method,
to custom view controller it
to insert in that popover.
On the other side,
and Safari process is something
That remote view will
and display its contents
And as you would expect, we
of the events such
And a way to show the popover
of popover instead of command
And that's it.
At this point, Safari knows that
so you will look for that
The popover also comes with
And as you can see here, the
and the popoverWillClose.
It can help you do some
And the third one
It's the one that
view controller.
Okay, so we've added the button.
We can display a popover.
Now let's talk about
So, you typically want to use
to act on part of the page.
But in my case, I
to select the text
So, I went again to my
and then I've added
It's an array of dictionaries
that hold two different
Text and command.
And then when the user presses
or clicks your context
Safari will send
to the principal object.
Please notice that we are
This will simply represent any
want to include from
Such as in my case, I want to be
So, inside my injected script
for context menu.
And then inside that function
event userInfo on the
And notice that I'm actually
Okay. So now I'm excited to show
it into Safari.
So, let's do that.
So, before I show you any code,
this is my simple macOS
As you can see, I
I can insert my note
etc. So, let's go to Xcode.
I want to show you
First, Info.plist.
So, please notice that I'm
right over here.
Here's my text and my command.
And I'm also adding
I have my, all of my four
over here.
And as you can see,
Second thing I want to show
Let me just make it like that.
And I have overridden
on my principal object.
The first one is
This will simply return
that represents the
that displaced in the popover.
And the second one
Selected(withCommand.
And as you can see, I'm getting
and assigning my
And third thing I want to show
the code and share it between
Of course normally you
You would use a framework
So, this is my notes manager.
It will simply read and
It has some simple methods
removeLastNote, etc.
that my target membership is set
which is macOS app
Okay. So, now let me go
and as you can see, my
to the Smart Search field.
I can click it and
my most recent note will appear.
So, let's say and, let me just
Side to side.
So, let's say I'm
and let's pick this one.
And let's say that I want to
So, let's say I select
I command, CTL click it.
And then I say add
Like so. As you can see, my note
I can open my extension
And now if I want to
because let's say I don't
I can simply delete that,
It's reflected in my macOS app.
So, it's that simple to create
between your macOS
So, I showed you
I showed you how to
and add multiple
Now I want to hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Damian.
Except for leaving
So, today we showed you
that are made possible with
We showed how easy it is to
from iOS to the Mac
to get the state of
in response to your feedback.
We saw how simple it is to
that modifies webpages to Safari
with the native Swift code
And lastly, we saw how it had
of your app directly to Safari.
And remember, Safari app
on app extensions.
Which means you have the power
in your app extension
and your CSS used to
And since Safari app
with your Mac app, there's an
for your users and you can
in the Mac App Store.
For more information about the
please visit this page.
Safari app extensions are the
to make them the best
Please give us some
and any bugs you find.
On the More Information page,
that feedback and the email
our Safari and WebKit
And for related sessions,
out some of the app extension
Thank you so much.
[ Applause ]