[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
Hi. My name is Matthew
I'm a software engineer working
to talk about Focus
Last year we introduced
for building apps on Apple TV.
And whether you're building
or looking to port an existing
it's immediately obvious
that Apple TV is unlike
There's no touchscreen on a TV
of user input just
in a living room environment.
Instead, we use this, a
in order to control
The Siri Remote and Apple TV
to provide the best
But Apple TV also supports
like game controllers,
and the new remote app.
And sometimes users might feel
of these other input devices in
and tvOS helps you
through a user interaction
With Focus interaction, users
through a single focused
and they can move focus
around the screen
Users will expect that your
with Focus interaction.
And to help with that, UIKit
for all of its standard
you may also want to customize
in order to take them
and provide an even
And for that, UIKit
Now today's talk is
and we split it into two parts.
First, we're going to
in the Focus API
And then in the second part
into an extended case study
fully focusable control
This is a great demo
to get started building
in your tvOS apps.
Now a quick note
We're going to assume that you
with the Focus API
of how Focus works on tvOS.
But even if you're new to
You can still generally
of the talk today, we'll call
to help you get started with
So what's new in tvOS 10 and to
to enhance the preferred
Now as a quick review, when
we mean the process
where Focus should show
Whenever Focus updates,
for example when your app first
to know where focus
It does this by asking your app
where it prefers
Let's look at a specific
When your app first launches,
to figure out where Focus
and it's going to start by
that we're updating Focus to.
And when our app first
In this case, the Focus engine
preferred Focus view is.
The window delegates
to its root view controller,
which could also return some
as its preferred Focus view.
The Focus engine will then ask
that view what its
and it will continue
until it reaches the end, which
that it found as the new
Leveraging the Preferred
to provide a good
in complex apps, especially.
So that focus is directed to
at the appropriate times.
In tvOS 10, we're
that allows your apps to
preferences and the name of this
Preferred Focus Environments
in the UIFocusEnvironment
of objects that also conform to
And this property has
First, by returning objects that
you can specify that focus be
on screen, not just views but
The second benefit
that it returns an array of
which allows you to specify
and this enables complex,
to be expressed much
And there's a specific pattern
that Preferred Focus
in which is custom
Let's look at an
Say we have an app with a
We have a container
with two child view controllers.
In this example, we want
that focus show up in the left
but if that's not possible,
to its right child
And we can express this logic
preferredFocusEnvironments
Here, we override
to return an array of both
as the first item in the array.
This is great because
to check ourselves whether
actually contains
We don't have to know anything
about the contents
We just tell the Focus engine
and it takes care of
So if our left child
in this example happened to
the Focus engine will
to that right child
And in this example, maybe it
So the
property helps us to express
clearly and concisely,
and if the first item doesn't
we can easily fall back to the
Next up, we have
to the Preferred Focus
for more specific use case
after view controller
So before we introduce the API,
to illustrate what exactly
Say we have an app
It's a simple view controller
And our root view
that by default we want our
It did this using the
property that we just looked at.
Now suppose the user moves to
and selects that button
to present a detail
In that case we're
when this detail view
After the dismissal, focus
to our root view controller.
Now the user would
that focus gets restored
that was last focused,
which is the last
However, if we ask our
at this time what its preferred
it would still direct us to
And so instead, the Focus engine
focus item for us so that after
it automatically restores
that the user would expect.
This is behavior that
While this is almost always
and often the developer
where you might want to
of your user interface.
Suppose for example that while
our app's underlying
so that the last button
different action or data
In that case the user might not
restored back to that last item.
In that case, we
to use your view controller's
in order to determine where
And in tvOS 10, we're
that allows you to do just that.
It's called
It's a Boolean property
and the way it works
If set to true, the view
default behavior.
It'll tell the Focus engine
to use its default behavior
that was focused before
If set to false, however,
then the Focus engine will
controller's
giving your app a
where focus gets
The property is set to
that previous default behavior
and it affects view
like we just talked about,
but other common built-in view
such as navigation pops and
between your view
We recommend that when
set it always be true or always
within your view controllers
in a consistent and
We really hope that this
some of those tricky edge cases
To show you how to use
that we just talked
up my colleague Brandon
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
My name is Brandon and I'm
to take advantage of some
of the new Focus APIs
So I've been working on
and it's coming along
You can view your events for a
between weeks using the
Now when the app
on the previous button
when I think it would
if we focused on the
So let's go modify
So to direct focus, we need
to override the
property.
This returns an array
for the focus engine
We'll start by adding our
of the week to our array.
If we have no more upcoming
to default to the next button.
So we'll add that to
Now let's run this,
All right, so this time when
on the super secret party I'm
Now, I wonder what would happen
When an event is canceled,
it becomes grayed
So I would expect focus would
which is a tvOS lab
But a good developer
So let's go try this out.
So I'm going to go
and cancel my not-so-secret
All right, just as we
we're focused on the tvOS lab.
So because our first
unfocusable, the Focus
to our next preferred
We didn't have to modify
The Focus engine
Now if you want to view
you can select it to
From here, you can swipe
to the next or previous event.
I received some bug
that when they exit this view,
that was just selected.
So in this case, we've
So if I menu out, I would expect
that we would be
Instead, we're still
which is our first available
So all we need to do is update
code to return our
as our preferred
So let's go back to our
and I have the selectedEventView
of the selected event when
So if this property
as my first preferred
All right, let's run
Okay. So I'll select the
to the bash, and then menu out,
and we're still focused
And I'm remembering now
in the session that by default,
the Focus engine
preferredFocusEnvironments
from a view controller.
So to change that behavior,
we need to set the
property to false.
So let's go do that in our
and rerun the app,
All right, we'll select
move our selection to
Awesome, so now we're
which is exactly what we wanted.
So by using the
and restoresFocusAfterTransition
we're able to provide a much
Now I'd like to invite
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Brandon.
That was a really great demo.
Using these two new properties,
we hope that you can reduce the
and also provide a
Now, next up I'm really
that we're bringing focus
into SpriteKit.
Prior to tvOS 10,
to manually implement
in their SpriteKit games
of their own state and
But now in tvOS 10, we're
the same API you're
to also support your
But first, what would
Well the first and most obvious
in games is game menus.
Your users will expect
and behave similar to
The Focus Interaction model also
where users navigate around
and select items on that game
And in fact, Focus Interaction
where selection is a
And in any of this use cases,
again users will expect
to feel similar to the
Otherwise, your app might feel
And so to help with that, we've
that you're used to in UIKit to
This is a shared API,
that SKNodes are now able to
and taking advantage of all
of the Focus engine's
UIKit and SpriteKit have been
to move freely between
so you don't have to handle
So how exactly does this work?
First, let's review how
Prior to tvOS 10, UIViews were
that were capable
and they defined their
canBecomeFocused property.
UIViews also conform to the
And this allows views to get
and also control the
within their subview hierarchy.
So to support SpriteKit
to bring these same
and we've made some
We're abstracting
out into their own protocol
This protocol defines both
and conformance to the
Next, we refactored
to conform to this new protocol.
And this allows both
to share these exact same API
in your existing UIKit code.
We've also made additions to
in order to take advantage of
First, let's look at the
which provides contextual
update notifications.
In order to support focus
we're introducing two new
previouslyFocusedItem
and these tell you which items
We've made a similar
introducing a new focusedItem
to type UIFocusItem and
to query what the current focus
Now there's one more API
but it requires a little
In tvOS 9, the UIFocusItem
preferredFocusView property.
And prior to tvOS 10, this was
preferences, like we were
But you can probably
which is that it
And if we're going to support
to define focus preferences
And so this isn't going to work.
But luckily, earlier
we introduced this new
property, which does
But because it returns an array
and now SKNode conforms to the
we can now define focus
view controller, SKNodes,
to UIFocusEnvironment.
And this makes defining
in your environments
And because
care of all the use cases
but also provides
that we've talked about,
to deprecate preferredFocusView.
So if you're currently
in your applications,
to preferredFocusEnvironments
We think this will really help.
So that's Focus Interaction
Focus API now supports generic
UIFocusItem protocol.
Both UIView and SKNode
And for SpriteKit
in to supporting focus
of all the Focus
For UIKit developers that don't
there are no changes required.
The view-based API
of preferredFocusView is still
We do encourage you, however,
in your code to take advantage
of more generic and
For more details on exactly
in to focus support in
we recommend watching
in SpriteKit session happening
into more detail on exactly
So that's Focus Interaction
And that concludes our overview
And so for the next part of our
with a case study on how
to build a fully custom,
And for our example today,
we're going to use a
Now we've already done some work
of this control and I'd
We just used the normal UIButton
as the title of the button.
If you select the button,
and if you keep selecting
it'll cycle through all
Now this is okay.
It gives us the functionality
to take our app to
And this control, it's
It's not very interactive.
And so we thought long and
up with a new design and
That's a lot better.
Instead of just saying
we now visually indicate our
When you select the control,
where you can use
to change our rating
And when we're done, we
and we exit editing mode.
This is a great example of
for focus interaction and
through building this
from scratch using
And for that, I'm going to hand
[ Applause ]
All right, thanks, Matt.
So I have a project here
which contains our simple button
as nice as the one
So let's just delete that.
Let's go ahead and
to represent our new control.
We'll set up some constraints
from the top, a width
and we'll center it
Great. Now I've already
to represent this
that as a views class.
And let's go check out
We chose a subclass
because it provides a lot of
For example, it determines if
or not based on its
it doesn't have a
We have to provide
So let's go do that.
We'll start by adding a corner
and then we'll override
with coordinator to
and unfocused appearance.
So if the next focus
then we'll configure the focus
of scaling the view,
and changing the
If the previously focused
then we'll configure the
which just rests all
Now before I run this,
I also want to add motion
Motion effects makes your
and helps the user find
So to do that, I'll
to add horizontal and vertical
around the touch surface.
Now I need to go back, and when
I will add the motion effect,
I will remove the motion effect.
Now I make all these changes
within addCoordinatedAnimations
This way, our property
with our focus animations.
So let's see how this looks.
All right, so what we've done
so far is create a very basic
and unfocused appearance
So it moves when I move my
But this is supposed to be
and we don't have any stars yet.
So let's go add those.
So first we need to
to store our control state.
And then in our awakeFromNib
we'll add a horizontal stackView
I've already created the star
but if you're following along,
I configured their focus
process that we just saw.
Now when the user selects the
to edit the current rating.
So I'll add a
to our control.
And when that's triggered,
and request a focus update.
When a focus update happens,
it consults our
So we'll override that property.
And if we're editing,
as our
Otherwise, we'll just return
Let's run this, see
Okay, so this time
we have some stars
And when I select the control,
within the control; however,
to move focus to
This is because there's some
So when we try to move focus
up focusing on our control,
to our first star using
So to fix this, we want to
focusable when we're editing.
So let's override
and we'll return false if our
So let's run this, see
All right, that's much better.
So now I'll able to move
But it's difficult to tell
because we don't provide
So to do that, we need to
when our focus changes.
So let's go back to our
and at the bottom,
we'll set the current
of the currently
And let's go back up to
and we'll tie that directly
to the isSelected
And this property just sets the
So let's see how that looks.
Okay, so now when I select
that the first star is selected.
And when I move focus, all the
So it's easy to tell what
So this is pretty good
Right now I'm able to move
and I don't want
that when I'm editing
Also, when I select the control,
we always reset the current
I think it would be better
and just focused on
So let's go make those changes.
So we'll start by overriding
to restrict focus movement.
So if we're editing and the
of our star views,
to say no, focus can't move.
Also, in our
we want to return our last
and the current rating
So this way we don't reset
Let's run this one more
Okay, now I'm no longer able
to move focus outside
And when I select a control, the
and we just focus on
So that completes
By utilizing the Focus
to create a pretty complex
Now I'd like to invite
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Brandon.
I rate that demo
Okay, we chose that demo
of using many different parts
to create a rich focus
And there are just a couple
that Brandon showed us that
because they're important
for really creating a
The first tip we have is
UIControl provides a lot of
for instance, as Brandon said,
of your controls based on
So when you're building
you should also subclass
We also used the focus
to define our focus-related
when changing our focus state.
This is also really
that our focus animations
with other focus animations
of the user interface.
And we do this to make sure
around the screen when
between different controls.
So when you're defining
for your focus appearance,
please use the focus
And the last tip is
Brandon showed us how
to create a little
when you place your thumb on the
of movement but not enough
You can use the UIMotionEffect's
to implement this
This is important because
to get this direct
so that they get
as they start using
It also helps the user
so that they can sit down
wiggle the remote around,
and immediately the
Before we wrap us, just
The first is to point out that
same capabilities.
And this is definitely
to testing your custom controls.
Now the good news is that
to build your custom controls,
then your control should work
that we talked about
Bluetooth keyboards, the Siri
But not all these input devices
so that if your custom
on some custom event handling
for example, let's say
for example you're
which generates touch events
and you're using that
within your custom control,
well if a user is using
they can't generate
And so you'll have to do
that your control can behave
for all users, in
And so definitely
that use custom event handling
Try out a Bluetooth keyboard,
very important to maintaining
And finally, please,
with accessibility.
The good news here is that the
work for you.
For example, if the user wants
the Focus engine will
around the currently focused
out on the screen and
But for other accessibility
you're going to have the do
that you're used to
that your controls
And so please test your controls
to make sure that they behavior
So that's our talk today.
We introduced two
preferredFocusEnvironments and
to help manage preferred
We also announced the new
for SpriteKit and we think this
complexity of your
And finally, we took you through
to build a custom focusable
rating control.
Now before we leave today,
we'd like to mention some
to help you learn more.
Specifically, you
out the Apple TV
These cover -- these are
They cover a wide array
for people getting new to
if you've had some experience
Specifically, there's one
with UIKit that goes
of the more basic
some of the basic concepts,
of the parts of the API
It talks about some best
and debugging support, which
with building your apps.
You can find these
And for more information
you can go to this URL to
There are some other
that you should check out.
If you're building games
to the What's New in SpriteKit
about how to specifically
for focus support and then also
in Mastering UIKit
to really take your UIKit
And of course, have
Thank you for coming today.