[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Bruce Nilo.
I'm an Engineering
And today, my coworker, Mike
to talk to you about
that we're introducing
These APIs we're confident are
for you to create natural,
and responsive applications.
So we're going to begin our talk
of the existing implicit
that exist in UIKit.
We're then going to dive
that we are introducing
We're going to talk about
to view controller transitioning
so that you can take
Mike is going to come
that uses these new APIs
and a brand new sample Photos
to download in the near future.
We're then going to talk about
to touch processing and hit
and how you can use
to create even interruptible
So, implicit property animations
to -- well, they exist
to create a dynamic context
by which you can update
that can be animated over time.
It's an implicit API because
on your behalf.
It notes when the value changes
and the end value to interpolate
on the duration that you specify
that specifies the
So let's make this
Here's a very simplified
We're going to use this
We have a circle
from the left to the right.
It's the center property of
And when in this graph
or a dotted square, it
that you're actually
Whereas the solid shape is going
And we sometimes call
versus the presentation value.
So we start the animation,
In fact, you'll notice that
And the question is -
Well, today it's really easy.
Most of you are probably
with the animateWithDuration
And in this case, we're
of the center of that circle
Now the timing function that
which basically means it
Now a quick review of what a
It's basically a cubic function
with a couple of constraints.
Namely, that at the
meaning when you just started --
the progress of the value
in fact the start value.
And at the end, it's
Now timing functions that
your animation.
And it's really easy to see this
with this exaggerated
You'll notice that, halfway
the progress has barely moved.
It's really chugging
We're almost 90%
We're still only halfway there.
It's in the last 10% of
that we're going to make up
Basically, this thing
from a very slow pace to a
So that's what timing
UIKit currently really only
These are specific instances
There's the identity
There's .easeInOut.
There is .easeIn.
And finally, there's .easeOut.
And these are very subtle
to kind of affect the
Now what about springs?
We also have an implicit
where you can specify a spring.
And you wouldn't be
that's not really interpolating.
We're kind of overshooting
and kind of bouncing back."
However, in what follows,
to think about the spring as
And let's see why
Let's look at this
where we're animating a
And we're graphing effectively
as it proceeds over time.
And it kind of looks
The thing is it's not a cubic.
It overshoots its values,
as affecting the
And in the APIs that follow,
to classify spring animations.
Now there is another
to animations in iOS 8.
And I want to talk to you about
at them again a little
Basically, consider an
in the midst of the animation.
So you're going from one
And halfway through,
Now prior to iOS
there would be a discontinuity
in the animation unless you
UIViewAnimationOption
BeginFromCurrentState.
And if you did that, it would
There wouldn't be a
but it wouldn't be
The velocity changes
In iOS 8, we made a significant
for certain properties
We didn't remove the previous
And then that smoothed out
With the new
it's going to be impossible to
OK, let's get to
that we have done
Some of its features.
It's really familiar.
If you're familiar with the
suite of APIs, you'll be right
It's interruptible.
That means you can pause
You can scrub them, meaning you
like based on a programmatic
You can reverse them.
You can say, "Never mind.
Go backwards."
We're going to introduce
of timing functions, not just
with one kind of small
And finally, when the
it'll be really easy to add
So it's kind of hard to talk
to do it by going into
So let's get an overview of
At the center of it all
UIViewPropertyAnimator.
It's implemented in terms
And the reason for implementing
to two new protocols we'll
when we couple it with view
When you create a property
to create a new type of object
which is effectively
that you want that
We provide two new
We've introduced a couple of
by the methods defined
For example, the state
of an animator can be
And we're going to be talking
We also introduced a
where did the animation finish.
Did it go all the way to the
Did we reverse it and go
Or maybe we interrupted it
OK. We're going to
on the center part
We're then going to
about all these new
So let's look at kind of
which is defined by the
This is where all the fun is.
It's really simple actually.
There's a couple of properties
For example, you can set
You can tell an animation
You can pause it,
It's kind of self-explanatory.
The next protocol adds the
to this animator.
It's where you add blocks
of the properties that
There's also an interesting
which allows you to proceed
with a completely
and possibly even a
UIViewPropertyAnimator has
It also has some properties
that we're going to get into
So we're going to talk first
We're going to talk about some
so obvious that you might
and scrub an animation.
There's also some interesting
of how you can reverse
Finally, we're going
to introduce all the
So let's start a
And I've made this one a
for pedagogical reasons
And let's ask the question,
"How would you use the
And it's really, really easy.
The first thing you do is
This is just like the .easeInOut
in the existing API.
You instantiate one of these
and the timing object.
You add animations
which are updating properties
You can add an optional
In this case, that completion
to orange.
And then you can start
OK, it's kind of verbose
but now you have an
of things you can do with it.
It makes a world of difference.
So let's look at some of the
in UIViewPropertyAnimator.
There's three that
There's the state, there's
and whether it is running in the
These are observable properties
Now the first thing you do
We're going to animate the
Once you do and you've
you can start the animation.
The second you start
the state changes,
The values of the
There is target value
and there's what you
And then the animation starts.
Now what's different
that animation halfway through.
And to do that, I just
I can tell it that I
in the opposite direction.
I'm still paused when
that the states change.
And then I can start
to start going backwards.
And then I can change it again,
And when it completes,
we're going to call
that you've registered.
And in this time, we're
because we made it all the
If we hadn't reversed it
we would have called the
That way, your completion
where the animation
OK. Instead of pausing
there's something
You can stop the animation.
Now what does that mean?
Well, the first thing you'll
that circle became
We've effectively promoted what
to the actual model value that's
At that point, you can
with that circle.
But we passed in a
which means don't
to the inactive states, stay
And what that means is that,
you're going to call
to specify a position where the
In this case, we're
at the end or at the beginning.
And you're completion
with that position.
Now if you called stopAnimation
we wouldn't even call
It's just finished
Now let's look at what happens
if you call
Let's say we call
It immediately jumps to
originally targeted.
Now you might think, "Why
And it actually gives you
For example, imagine
or you're stopping this
and then you're dragging
And maybe you set up
in the end position and
And when you release it, based
it may snap into those
And once it reaches that, you
with a .end or .begin.
And so you can do some
to finalize the animations
[ Applause ]
OK, pausing and scrubbing.
Not much there, right?
Well, it's kind of interesting.
So there's a sample app here
where we set some gesture
that little green progress bar.
And we can scrub
We're updating where
And then we can continue
And you'll notice that kind
there's kind of a weird
which we're going
Before we do that, let's look
at what these gesture
On the square, we added
which checks whether or not
And if it is, it checks is
And if it's running,
And if it's not, it's
Pretty straightforward.
On the progress bar, we set
And we're going to just compute
where we are in the pan relative
to the full bounds
And based on that fraction
we're going to update
and the progress bar
OK. So, what's going
There's actually something
[ Laughter ]
And to explain what, I'm
of exaggerated ease-in
So let's say this time,
we pause the animation and
The important thing to note
that you're actually setting
We've just paused the animation.
What you're really
of progress towards
And in this case, we've hardly
Now we're going to scrub
to want to continue it again.
We don't want to jump
of the view that
So, in fact, what happens
to the timing function of
Which means when we continue
the animation is going
So when we go back to the curve
you'll notice that we're
onto the timing function
And it's important to note
and scrubbing, depending
on whatever UI affordance
you may see these
of compensate for them.
OK, let's talk a little
There's three ways
One is you can pause reverse --
and start it up again.
And you'll notice that you're
through the timing function
You can also reverse on the fly.
Which means that, as the
you can tell it to reverse.
And that's kind of like
Again, there's going to be this
And that might be what you
of represent, say, a
or something like that.
But if you don't want that and
you can animate additively.
And in this case, we will
by changing the reverse
to actually change the values
Now what's different
that when your completion
they're going to be called
You've basically
You're no longer going
You're going back towards the
OK, there's some
that we've made available
The first is the
If you create this class with
to get the default core
This was previously
The second variant
of the constructor is
animation curves.
And finally, we opened up all
of the cubic Bézier
on the unit square to you.
And as an example of
this particular Bézier curve,
it would be "speed
And you can kind of go wild
to create for timing functions.
[ Applause ]
We've given you more ways
And, again, consider that
to be influencing the timing.
If you create a
with no arguments, you're going
to get a critically-damped
which many of you
It's one that we use, for
onto a navigation controller.
[ Applause ]
The second variant
to the existing UIKit
with a small difference that
But before we get to
up basically the
You can specify any
and we will effectively
There's a point here though, and
that you specify is ignored.
And we're computing that
of the spring equation.
You're going to see
[ Applause ]
I said there was a difference.
You'll notice that the initial
It's not a scaler.
Most of the time, we're
at the y component
However, if you are animating
we're actually going
and y components of that vector.
And to see why, look at
where we drag a square
And when we release it,
to the center based on the
Now, up until now, the velocity
connecting those two squares,
because my gesture might be
plane, and we effectively
that into account.
However, now we are.
So let's look at
which shows how we now will
and take into account the
You'll notice that,
we're going to take both
It's really easy to do that.
[ Applause ]
OK, we have this great
And guess what?
I want to take advantage of it
for custom view controller
I want them to be
Now, three years ago or so,
and so it's a little
So if you're not familiar
with custom view
please refer to that talk.
But I'm going to give a quick
of how we've extended
View controller transitions
of interlocking protocols --
two of which interactive
and animated transitioning
that you create objects
well, the objects that
The system will create
into the methods
And this will become
But let's remember why
Imagine you have an app
and the pop kind of looks OK.
It's that great,
critically-damped
But, you know, your app
Your app wants to really kind
something that explodes
with a blur effect underneath.
That's what custom view
you do.
And moreover, it
and drive those interactively.
OK. The way we get the
to these protocols are
It might be the navigation
or it might be a
transitioning delegate.
And we're going to ask that
that conforms to animated
present, or a push, or a pop?
And if you do, we're going to
We're going to create one
of these context
which give you all the
to actually animate
And we're going to
passing in that context to you."
Now how do we make
Well, what we've done is we've
called
And if you implement that,
that conforms to
Now this could be a
but it doesn't need to be.
It could be, for example,
say, you implement in
or some other animation
If you do not implement
meaning you only implement a
then you need to
And you would do so very
You take the interruptible
and you would basically
And that's really
to implement animateTransition.
However, we kind of advise
that you use an interaction
to make it interruptible.
And, again, the first thing
or return an object
to animated transitioning.
We will then ask you for
to interactive transitioning.
And we're going to pass the
to us previously as a parameter.
Often times, you want that
to actually drive the
If you do, we're not going
We're going to call
and we're going to pass
that we would have passed
We provide a concrete
that makes this really easy.
Now there was a restriction
where if you implemented
InteractiveTransition,
you actually needed the
of the animation controller to
of the existing UIKit
But now with the interruptible
InteractiveTransition actually
It's just using the
in UIViewImplicitlyAnimating.
And that's it.
So you could actually have a
that's driven by UIPercentDriven
InteractiveTransition,
OK, let's say you already
you already have a
How do you migrate?
Well, one way to do it would
animateTransition method
and build your interruptible
that you just add that
of the animations
Not too difficult.
We did have to extend some other
For example, context
a pauseInteractiveTransition.
That's how you enter into
Prior to this, you
and you ended non-interactive.
Now, you can move
And the way you do that is
by calling pauseInteractive,
Also, the property
and transitionWasCancelled can
and forth between an interactive
We added a variable called
Because now that you
maybe you want your
out non-interactively.
And this variable
Finally, we have UIPercentDriven
InteractiveTransition updated.
There are a few rules.
interruptibleAnimator
we expect it to actually
Meaning don't do something else.
The system might get grumpy.
We're always going to
and startInteractiveTransition
So that would be a great place
to create your interruptible
to be calling it subsequently
and we expect the same
to always be returned.
Finally, the animator survives
It shouldn't become inactive
until the entire
Now, Mike is going to
to use these APIs in a real app.
I didn't give you much time.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Bruce.
All right.
So, let's start with a
We've got an application
that utilizes the
and the additions to
to create a nice
in a basic app.
So, first, we have
that uses a
and has a Collection View
And we have this grid of
When we tap one of the photos,
it will push another view
And that kind of
of your photos here.
And if we hit the Back button,
And alternatively, we can slide
to do an interactive
And this is all available
in UINavigationController.
And as Bruce just described,
that allow you to
And, here, if we want the
of the page, we can do
When we hit the Back
And this was all
In addition to that,
down to start the transition
and then let it finish
So I want to show you
that using
OK, so the first thing you need
in this case, the
that you're going to be
So, here, we're going to conform
to the navigation controller's
so with an
And that's just an object we've
transition protocols.
So, here, we have two methods
The first is calling us
with a particular
We'll save that operation
since we're going to be
And then when we return
the system will call us for
at which point we'll also return
to be the interaction
And once we've done that, the
to be an interactive transition.
So let's look at
InteractiveTransitioning.
Here, the system is going to
on our object with a
and that'll have all the
that you'll need to start
And at this point, we're going
that we'll see a little
But that's the object
to create our transition
And we're going to pass the
that we saved
and a panGestureRecognizer
that transition interactively.
In iOS 10, we also allow you to
in two phases -- either
or the interactive phase.
So if we did start from
we're going to set this
to "true" to let the system know
that we're starting
transition interactively.
And next, let's look
at the animated transitioning
Here, we're not really concerned
As Bruce mentioned, we're using
and that's going to call
as opposed to animateTransition.
But the new interruptible
in iOS 10 is what we're
And, here, our helper
in just a second creates
and returns that for
So, that's where
to add any alongside animations.
And in this demo, you'll see the
of animating along
The system is going to take
to add those animations.
So let's look at the
really quick.
All right.
Here, you saw that we
in startInteractiveTransition.
And that's going to call
There we go.
That's going to call
with some animations, and
of the background
You saw visual effect
And the two view controllers,
We'll talk about the image
later on.
And it'll pass in a completion
up some of those
But, here, let's focus on how
that we returned to the
So we first get a transition
and we'll look at that
And we're going to create this
and a curve of .easeOut.
And we'll pass in those
And we'll create a
and we'll call those completions
But the important thing
to the transition context
to inform the system that, "Hey,
we're done with this
And we can get where we're --
I'm sorry,
the completionTransition
that we can get the value that
So we pass "yes" to that API.
That means we're going
If we pass "no", it means we're
So before I go a
in the transition animator
I want to show you a few
that are made possible by
So if we go back to the demo,
out of the screen and zoom back
But what I didn't show you is
So we're in the animation
and we move into an
So we're interacting
in the middle of
When we release our finger,
and then we can interrupt
So we're free to move back and
and an interactive
So it's really pretty cool.
So before I go back to the
that using the new
I want to describe a particular
understand what the code
So imagine we're starting.
We're pulling down with the
starting an interactive
And then we're going to release
and start an animation phase,
we're going to pause
to interact with it again.
And we're going to
by pulling it back up.
So that's the scenario that
when we look at this
So I've broken that down in
in terms of four methods.
The updateInteraction, which is
that's going to update the
And when our finger lifts,
we're going to call the
And then we're going to call
to either the begin
And then when we
we'll end up calling
So we can do this
in the lifetime of a transition.
We can actually do it as
But in this scenario,
So we look at updateInteraction.
This is a gesture
And when it's called in "state
we're going to look
of the gesture recognizer
that to compute a progress
to the transition animator
And then to scrub those
you saw the navbar in some of
in the background
as setting the fractionComplete
And that'll let us scrub through
for free.
And then we'll call to
to update the interactive
And then, finally, we have
that image that's
When we're in the interactive
we're going to handle
So we have a little helper
And finally, we'll
on this gesture recognizer.
So when we're called, when the
we'll get a "state ended"
and we'll call endInteraction.
If we look at endInteraction,
we first just check is our
And we want to make sure
out of the interactive phase.
And we'll call a
that tells us whether
in the begin position of the
If we're completing in the
to call to the context
we're finishing the
We're going to move to
If we're called with
we're going to say we're
and we're going to move
And then we just animate.
So let's look at the
So, previously, I told you
that the transition
of the background chrome
But, here, we're going to create
And we're going to use
of these images that are
And the reason we do that is
to have a different
than the animations
And we'll see that
So, here, we're just going
Now we're going to
or basically the target or the
And then we're going to start
that property animator
Now, remember, we have this
living the lifetime
that we gave back to the system.
And we just need to make
in the correct direction.
So if we specified a toPosition
to reverse that animator.
And finally, if this is the
through animate here, our
to be in an inactive state.
So all we need to do is start
and we're off to
Alternatively, if it's been
we're going to use
We're going to call in
(withTimingParameters
So continueAnimation lets you
with different timing parameters
and the remaining
And here, we're going to
like to use the timing
when we initialized this
But we're going to
of the continued animation.
And that will allow us to
of this new itemFrameAnimator
above with the duration
of this transition animator.
So the durationFactor
as 1.0 equals the initial
when you created this
And that's all we have to do to
And lastly for this cycle,
let's look at the
And this is when it's
We put our finger down
And we just put a
on that image view
And we're free to do that now
because UIViewPropertyAnimator
view automatically.
So on that itemFrameAnimator
we're going to stop that
of "true", indicating to the
on continuing this animation,
that we'd like the model
excuse me, the presentation
to the model.
And then on the transition
to call to pauseAnimation.
Because as we saw in
we were scrubbing that animation
when we were interacting
And then, finally,
to the transition
out of the animation phase
And so I'd like to show
kind of a little
We saw that this timing is
that for illustration purposes.
But you might want to make
and a little bit more lively.
So if we look at changing
it kind of jumps out of the page
and only the image is
And here, those background
to operate on that .easeOut
So we were able to
and make this feel much more
of code, and we can still
So let's take a look at that
So we come back to
at our propertyAnimator
We'll notice that we're
with timing parameters
And that's what gives us
And a colleague of mine
in here specifying some
to use instead with a
damping, initial velocity.
And that fully specifies
So when we create the
this duration that we're
Rather, it'll be computed based
on the properties we've
And because of that, we have
function here that just uses
that we just saw down below here
So it basically solves that
And we can use that to
of the transition animator.
That's all super simple.
I know this code is looking
but it's really only a
And UIViewPropertyAnimator
So, with that, I'd like to
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Mike.
OK, I've got to speed things
up because we're a
We need to talk a little
We're going to assume that
so that we can actually
If it was "false", we would
We have this property called
that defaults to "false".
And the reason it defaults
to be able to hit
If it were "true", which is the
when you try to touch down
that you saw, we
And perhaps, puzzlingly, it
We don't want that to happen
for an interruptible
Now in this talk below, which
a technique was given whereby
do some calculation to convert
and call "super" so that you
That technique still works.
But now with propertyAnimators
by default, with manual hit
we're actually going to
So that's pretty cool, and
In fact, that's how everything
so far has been working.
Now this doesn't
If you have deep view
we are not going to
So you may need to use
about in the other talk.
OK. We have this whole
for keyframe animations
How do you make those
To recall, a keyframe
of like a regular animation
that you want to animate from.
We want to make those
In fact, we want to do
on this video right now.
We want to pause it, scrub it.
And I guess it's
In fact, you can do it.
It's really easy to do.
You take the existing API
to an animator's animations.
And with that, you have
animations, too.
[ Applause ]
There's one last thing.
I kind of lied.
Interactive
PopGestureRecognizers.
That's the built-in
Currently, if you have an
you can't use that.
But new in iOS 10, if you
on that gesture recognizer
we will allow the built-in pop
and use the built-in navigation
custom interaction.
[ Applause ]
So, in summary, we've
to create interruptible
with a UIViewPropertyAnimator.
There's a whole new range
of timing functions
You can use interruptible
to create interruptible
For more information,
There's a couple of other
about other types of animations,
I encourage you to go see those.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]