[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good evening.
My name is Robby Walker,
by Brandon Newendorp and Corey
First I'm going to start
about what SiriKit is, and at
Then Brandon's going to talk
or two to connect your
And then Corey's going to
and design a great
which is meaningfully different
than designing a great
But first, let's
Who is Siri?
Siri is your virtual assistant,
whether it's by adding
or much more frequently, by
and alerting you to potential
We're going to talk about an
with Siri, and when
we built a fake application.
So we wanted to name it
but we kind of felt like it was
to name it after a very
So we called it Unicorn Chat.
And then because we wanted it
we gave it a really sweet icon.
[ Applause ]
So you can imagine someone
Siri, send a Unicorn
Siri might respond "To whom?"
Then you might say,
of the Unicorn names of
Then you would -- then Siri
to say to Celestra, and then
"Let's add more sparkle
because as everyone knows,
Unicorns love sparkle
But there's a lot of ways to
Someone else might say
saying something
to Celestra in Unicorn Chat."
And then of course, Siri
and then the user would fill
Other users might do the exact
"Unicorn Chat Celestra, let's
Somebody else might say an
which I will not attempt to say.
And other users will be
and might say something
can you please do me a favor
to send a text with the
sparkle transitions."
And despite using 27 words
they actually forgot to
to send the message to.
And then even then, they
and say something like, "My
So the point is, there
to say the same thing to Siri.
And there are also a lot of
So for example, if
and you're pressing the
to provide more visual responses
But if you're invoking
like our friend Cookie Monster,
Siri's going to say
And the Siri experience is
to meet the accessibility
to a lot of different
So in the end of the day,
there's basically a
that people use Siri,
of how they phrase
of how Siri will respond.
And the question then becomes,
how do we make sure we're
experience for our users?
How do we make sure it's really
within a single domain?
And most importantly, for
how do we make sure it's
so that as many people as
of their favorite applications
And the answer is that Siri
and your application just
So I'll go into a little more
The first thing that Siri does,
is understand what
So we take audio and
Then we take that
into a structured representation
to do, something
Based on that intent, Siri then
the user wanted to accomplish.
And then Siri provides
both visual and verbal.
And so there's a lot here.
There's a lot of work that
There's a lot of deep
There's convolutional
There's LSTMs, there's CRFs,
there's SVMs, there's
And we wanted to make sure
you could really
that your app already does, and
The first one is vocabulary.
This is how your application
to know about.
And Brandon will tell you
The second one is app logic.
This is the functionality
And then the last one is of
So let's go through
and see a little bit
So somebody says, "Hey Siri,
please send a Unicorn
The first rule that your
to help Siri understand
So Siri doesn't have
in its database,
So by sharing that information
that Siri understands
This also helps Siri
that Celestra is a contact
because when you provide
you will provide it by saying
or in another example
these are names of photo albums.
Now Siri understands that
to send a message you
of course, just a recipient.
You need a message.
And so Siri will quickly check
"Do you actually require
And if your application
then Siri will ask a
So really that's all your
of specify on an individual
your constraints.
The next thing that happens
that information
So rather than having to
of language and phrasing, and
about earlier, your application
simple object.
And then it hands off to your
you know, processing the intent
And then of course,
Siri provides a user
And you have the option to
to customize the user interface
So that's a very, very high
The idea was to make it
but still connect
of conversational interactions.
And now to tell you a little bit
is my colleague Brandon
also known to me, as Celestra.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Robby, I
to tell you all a little bit
and how you're going to be
when you adopt SiriKit
Now pay close attention
"intents" stuff.
To get started, I want to talk
about how SiriKit
At a high level, Siri
in the idea of a domain.
Where a domain is a
that Siri understands and
For example, things like
and sending payments, are
and are some of the
up with SiriKit this year.
Within a domain,
Where an intent describes
that Siri understands, and can
Now I'd like to break down
with another example, in
than what Robby was
So in this case, we have
Hey Siri, send Buttercup
on Unicorn Pay for
Now Siri understands
in the payments domain.
And specifically,
that this is a send
Now every intent has
Where parameters are specific
understand, and communicate
And there's a lot of parameters
We've recognized that
and that the user is
to someone named Buttercup.
We've also recognized an amount
to be very smart, and recognize
they probably meant US Dollars.
And Siri can use a lot
to understand what we think the
basing it on things like
their Siri locale, and
to our system.
And finally, we recognize
to send a payment
So there's this common language
of intents that describe
that are used to
from your application
So let's talk a little
As I said, an intent
that we're asking your app
that we can communicate
about between Apple
Every intent will have zero to
to vary based on the
and what Siri understands
and what we think is relevant to
And no matter what, an intent
into a domain.
So this is something
about when you're getting
in your application, is look
of SiriKit, and think
to make the most sense
Now we also have
And these are how you tell Siri
that your app just performed.
You're always going
to communicate the result
because there's always an intent
Intent responses also can have
which are used to describe
with that intent.
Sometimes those parameters are
on the intent, and other
because there's something
from your app back to Siri.
We also accept a response code
These are used to tell
about whether your app was able
and there's default ones,
or failure that requires
Some intents and domains have
It's very important that you
code back for your application
to drive dialogue and make
for all of your users.
Finally, we have an
to an intent response.
Now if you're already supporting
you're familiar with
We use NSUserActivities
if the user needs to leave
onto your application.
Now by default, Siri is going to
with the intent and
to your application, so
where you left off from Siri.
If you'd like to, you can
and populate the
with information that's
Just to make sure you create
when users leave Siri and
So those are intents,
They're the fundamental
to your application
and understand what your
on behalf of the user.
The next thing I'd like to
and Siri are going to
Now there's three steps
to go through, while
The first of those is resolve.
We're going to ask your app
to resolve every
And in fact, we will call
for every parameter and
for the same parameter
on what they requested.
The second step is confirm,
to make sure that it's going to
and tell us about
And finally, most
where you perform the specific
Let's talk a little bit more
The purpose of the
is for you to help Siri
and more importantly,
when they started asking a
This is also your
to influence Siri's behavior
over the conversation
with the user of
In order to do that,
to provide a resolution
And there's a number of
for every type of data that
to ask your app to
So let's go back to our example
with sending Buttercup
for that rainbow polish.
And specifically, I'd
to the payee field.
This is used to describe
And it's important that
all agree on what the user
Now hopefully, the most
from your app will be success.
Which means that you understood
what they specified, and
that you successfully understood
to us to tell us
what you successfully matched.
In this case, it means
that Unicorn Pay totally
Now sometimes, your app is going
but it wants to make sure
that the user really meant what
choice about.
So we have a confirmation
This is where you can ask Siri
to have the user double
and provide a yes
So in this case, for Unicorn
that the user meant
when they said Buttercup.
Now there's other times that
to ask the user to pick from
And Siri calls this
If you'd like to ask the user
we recommend five
You can provide a
And then we'll present the
In the case of this Unicorn Pay
if they meant Sir Buttercup,
Buttercup the Bold,
Now one of the powerful parts
to take care of the interaction
You don't have to
So users can use a
of these options with Siri.
They could tap on an item in the
and say "Sir Buttercup", or
and simply say, "the
And no matter how the user
we're going to take care of that
Now there's other times that
from the user.
Maybe they weren't
or maybe your application has
and you don't want
of Buttercup to the user.
In these cases, you can say
and Siri will prompt the
Once the user provides
we'll call the resolve
If the user didn't specify a
to proceed, you can tell
And in this case, we'll
you've got to say something
Unicorn Pay needs to know
You can also tell us that you
user provided, and that you
And for that we have
And just tell us, you don't
and Siri will ask the
And finally, if there's a value
and your app doesn't require it,
We won't prompt the user for
to specify a value,
So those are the resolve steps.
It's how we make sure that
all agree on what they're
to do before we move on.
The next step is confirm.
So the confirm stage is
First, it's a chance
about the expected result
We will want you to
that we can tell the user
It's also an opportunity
to check any required state
to complete the request
Now no matter what, you're going
to provide an intent response
and we want you to populate as
in that intent response,
that to the user
And sometimes, Siri is going to
for certain intents and certain
that that's important.
For example, things like sending
are things that Siri's
with the user before we
So let's think about what
in the Unicorn Pay example.
Now Unicorn Pay has to be
make sure the user signed in,
in order to complete a request.
So we're going to check all
We're going to say, "Can we
Is the user signed
And of course, this is
so we want to make sure
in their account before
Once we've made sure
to handle this request, we
with a success result code,
so we can move onto
And that's the confirm stage
The final step is handle.
And this is the most important
because at this point,
that the user asked you to do.
You're going to perform the
And just like in the
that you provide
as you have available back
of that information so that we
user experience for all
Sometimes we're going to display
and other times we're
of the conversation and
so that they understand
Now we understand that sometimes
of time to complete a
Networking calls might take a
on the other end of your
processing transactions
While we're waiting for a
were going to show a
and say that your app
their request.
We really would like you
within a few seconds, two
And ideally, you can get
in a very short amount of time.
However, if you know
to take a little while to get
we'd like you to send an
This allows Siri
that your app has received the
as you've told us about, and
to process the request
So in the case of our
as soon as we get the handle
to our servers, we're
and then give Siri an intent
so that Siri can tell the
on the way.
And that's what involved
to your application
We have intents,
that are creating
between your app and Siri.
The next thing we're going to
in adding SiriKit
So with SiriKit in iOS 10,
we're creating two
An intents extension, and
I told you this was
We also are adding some API
to help you help Siri recognize
for your application.
And we're going that in form
of what we call app
I'd like to get started
about the intents extension.
This is what's going to
and handle methods that we
Now, at its core, the intents
fundamental part of SiriKit.
This is what we build all
of between Siri and
Your intents extension can
and we leave it up to you to
for your app and how you'd like
Now we encourage you to minimize
so that we aren't
if the user makes multiple
But do what makes sense for you.
It's also important to realize,
that your intent
in the background while
This allows Siri to maintain
and still talk to your app
and communicate about
And as I mentioned, your intent
the resolve, confirm, and
that your app supports.
Now when we built SiriKit, we
about security, because
to everything we do at Apple.
Part of Siri's built in
to restrict certain behaviors
from being taken while
For example, we wanted to
into their device and unlock
or request a ridesharing
And that's a built in behavior
Now we also understand that
that your app would like to
By default, Siri's
like sending messages
but if your app would like to
into their device first, you
like to increase our
and restrict your
And this is simply done
We've also worked to make sure
that the local authentication
for your intent extension,
for additional authentication,
even while the device
If you're not familiar with the
there's a great talk from 2014
And finally, we've made sure
for your intent extension.
So if you'd like to complete
with your users,
to your intent extension and
right above Siri.
If you'd like to
I'm glad someone
I'm excited about it.
You can learn more in the
and Apple Pay talk that
So that's your intent extension.
This is a fundamental part of
to communicate with your app
The next piece is your
Let's go into a little
about what that's all about.
So the intents UI intent
to bring your app's interface
and make Siri really feel
like your users are
You can bring your brand,
as well as other information
And you do that by
to what we call a Siri snippet.
Your intents UI extension
to return a UI view controller.
And you can add anything you'd
like inside that
Now it's completely optional to
By default, Siri has an
that we support in SiriKit.
And we think that those will
of the pieces of information
but if you'd like to make a more
this is your opportunity.
We've also made intents
for certain intents.
Where we think it makes sense to
So there's a number
with an intents UI extension.
You've used it to show
above and beyond
in the intent and
Maybe some information that's
You can also use it to update
of a long running intent.
So if you've provided an
as we mentioned earlier,
to update the user about
in your intents UI extension.
Now no matter what,
to show your intents UI
Siri content.
So we're always going to
and app name at the
We may choose to show some
at the bottom of the snippet,
as well as other
Your view controller is always
Now there's a couple of
for your app to replace
that we're showing
And this is things like
that you should have
to replace the default messaging
that you feel suits your
So you can tell us that your
with your intents UI extension,
and then we will omit certain
in favor of yours.
Now it's also important
that just like the new
intent UI extensions
So you can draw anything you'd
you can play any kind
but we would discourage
in your UI extension,
to interact with them.
So that's the intents
Together these two extension
to add your app's
and bring your experience and
to make a better experience
The next two parts of SiriKit,
are all part of your
So let's talk about what
Now, all of the responsibilities
in the area of vocabulary.
All of your applications
to your customers, and that
to features of your application.
And Siri needs a
in understanding the things
to your app, and the things
that they're accustomed
Some of these phrases are
They're things that every user
of your app knows
Other phrases are going to be
and we have the API to
of SiriKit, and both
to making a great experience.
Let's dig into app
These are words or phrases that
and they're known to every
They're things like workout
that everyone uses to refer to
Now because they're part of your
in a plist that's part
And also, because they're
we encourage you
so that they can be
that your app supports,
that Siri's going to be using.
Let's talk about what goes
because there's a number of
The first of them, are
to talk to your application.
These are kind of
your hero use cases
In the case of our new Unicorn
like start a workout
The common things that
to talk to your app.
Now in addition to that,
where you can provide
For the Unicorn Fit application,
we're going to specify our
Some things that are unique
but known to all of our users.
Now I'm sure you all are very
but if you're not, now
about the term Colorlicious.
It's a particular workout
where you run around
of falling glitter
It's a great workout.
You should all give it a try.
It's a new craze.
So we're going to tell Siri
It's a unique term for our app.
Now, sometimes these phrases
to pronounce.
They don't look very obvious.
So you're also going
pronunciation information.
And this is just a simple
or phrase that you're
And finally, provide some
to use that phrase in your app.
"Do a Colorlicious in Unicorn
of this particular
The other type of vocabulary,
These are words or
to individual users
And because they're unique to
we're asking you to
from your main application.
We ask you to provide
of an ordered set of terms.
Now you might be thinking,
of an odd data structure choice.
Why would we be choosing
Well I promise you there's
We really, we really want you --
we'd encourage you to order
for your users, with the most
that you think users will
Let's talk about that in
where we have an address book
of everyone we can
Now we want you to give Siri
in your application, so that
we'll be able to recognize them.
However, Unicorn Pay
that we've paid most recently.
So we're going to put
of all the other contacts
In addition to that, Unicorn
which are the most
So we're going to
and start off our ordered
followed by our recent
up with the other
And by prioritizing in this way,
your helping Siri better
and make a better
who uses your app with Siri.
There's a few types of
with user vocabulary, and those
workout names, photo
And as an added benefit
if you rely on the system iOS
to worry about this part
because Siri has a
of the system address book.
So you only need to
if your app keeps its own
Now, you also should think about
to Siri as part of this
and only tell us
that you your users
to recognize and know about.
So we don't want you to give
or e-mail addresses in
Just give us simple common
the things that users would
Now it's important that
as data changes, because users
to Siri the instant they
So for example, if the
in your app, make sure you
as they hit the save button.
That way we can ingest the data,
as soon as users hold down the
It's even more important
from your Siri vocabulary
because your users
if they deleted something
and then Siri was still
or a few weeks later, because
that the user deleted that
And finally, make sure
of your vocabulary data from
to reset your application,
Now the other piece of SiriKit
So like many other parts of iOS,
users have to approve
for your app to talk to Siri.
And we do this through
that you're used to
like the camera,
Now your app is able to
into this alert to
of information your app is
This is also a fantastic
about what your app does,
and what cool new features
for all of them.
We also are encouraging
from your app the first
after they upgrade to iOS 10.
We want you to do that so
and have approved the use
of Siri before they make
So as soon as they try talking
it's already approved, and
launch experience.
So that's what's involved
in adding SiriKit
These two pieces of extensions,
and two vocabulary mechanisms.
The last thing I would like to
into the larger world of iOS.
Now Siri is an integral part
It's always accessible to
via hey Siri, via
and many other ways
And SiriKit is just as integral
to the operating
Now Siri integration is part of
that we've created
about communicating these common
between your app and iOS.
And the intense framework
integration this year.
It's part of the
where you can donate
and elevate your application
or telephoning mechanism
We've also done very deep
to make a great VOIP experience.
The most, the biggest
Maps is adding ridesharing
where you can book a ride right
Now we worked very
to create a common
This intense extension and
for Siri, and maps, to
So if you adopt SiriKit and the
to get the maps integration
We think this is a great
and make an even better
[ Applause ]
The last part I'd
is how users talk
Now it's very important
and privacy model of iOS
and making your customers
and your data, it's important
they're going to be talking
and when their data
To make sure that all
users are required to
when making a request to Siri.
Specifically, we're
at your bundle display name.
This is what's shown
underneath your app
Now Siri's all about
and having a comfortable fluid
So to make sure that that's
users are able to say your app
at the beginning, or the end
wherever it fits in
to make a natural fluid
to your app, and to your users.
One of the common
with SiriKit is what we
or taking your app name
to describe a particular action.
As an example of
"Unicorn Chat Celestra order
And in this case, they're
describing the action
And this will, of course, work
In fact, there's a multitude
to your app using Siri.
The possibilities are endless.
So that's what's involved
in implementing a great Siri
But there's more than just
involved in creating a
And to tell you more
about designing a
I'd like to invite Buttercup,
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Hello everyone.
I'm Corey Peterson, and
and I'm very excited
about creating magical
I've got three things I
The first is some of the
to help facilitate the
Next, we'll go through
that you should keep in mind as
And then, I'll give a few
to polish the design, and take
So, let's get started
Now when I say user interface,
about something like this.
A button. Part of
that appears on screen.
Now visual interfaces have
and patterns and
and everyone is pretty
It's part of an application,
and that application gives the
the user is trying to do,
the options that
and the details about
And there's pretty much one
But, as you start to work with
and one of the biggest
that button is gone.
Now, it can be -- feel
on a screen.
So how do we solve this?
Because the user could
or they might not
So we like to think of it as
The context of what's
through the conversation
Siri, and now your apps.
Now, without a visual reference,
to keep all this
So Siri works hard to prevent --
to present just the
to get a task done, and
of the other information.
And, this interface is shaped by
both from the person
And it's important to think
about how Siri asks
And your application
to shape this conversation.
And we'll talk about
So let's go through an
Let's say, someone
and Siri might say
&gt;&gt; Ready to send it?
&gt;&gt; Now people can say a lot
They might simply say "send it."
Or they might decide not to,
or they might ignore
and say whatever they want.
And that's okay.
These are actually appropriate
And the great thing is, Siri's
for you, and send the right
And even better than that,
of other ways that people
Now earlier, Robby talked
that people can start a
and I'm going to focus
Now everyone's familiar
pressing the home button, and
But, another important mode that
where you don't have
to physically touch the
So just by starting your request
to work from across the room,
if your hands are full, or if
Let me show you a
of how the conversational
to adapt to these situations.
So, here, we're going to say
and pressing the button.
So I'll say, "Do I
&gt;&gt; You have five reminders.
&gt;&gt; So as you heard, Siri
and then gave visual
since I'm holding it and
Now, listen to how this changes
Hey Siri, do I have
&gt;&gt; I found five reminders.
The first one is talk about
to say hi to people
then go to the next slide.
Do you want me to
&gt;&gt; No thanks Siri.
So as you heard, Siri
and it gave a smaller amount
of information that's
And at the end, Siri asks me
in control of the conversation
Now we use these same principles
In car play, where you need
And it's also very helpful for
Now Siri is great because you
and its able to do
to find an application and
to get something done,
Siri understands when you have
of headphones, or a
And it adapts what it --
it can recognize settings
which is Apple's
out the visual elements
And it again, adapts
to help these users
So, that's a little bit
Here's a couple things that
Make sure that you're testing,
with many different requests.
Testing different
out things hands free.
And throughout the process,
make sure that your app is
to Siri so that Siri can
And that's especially critical
All right, let's move on
And I want you to think of this
as a conversation
And as with any important
you need to make sure that
that you ask questions, and
So, how do we prepare?
The first thing is to recognize
that your users aren't
Now, what do I mean by that?
You've spent a huge
and designing your application,
of knowledge that's greater
with it, and that's going
to influence how you
So, you need to go out and find
significant others, or maybe
and ask them what
So I'm going to go with
and talk about an
So for this fake
to some real users and they
Some people might say "Get
Siri is going to ask the user
to use, and then can continue
Some people may provide
and some people may provide
some of which may
because as we all know,
than two people on a Pegasus.
Once you have all
make sure that your
Take all of the information
and use that, but they
of the information
So, you need to find
One way, is to pick
so if I were requesting
where to be picked up, Unicorn
that I probably want to
or maybe outside the
You can also make educated
about the user, but
You don't want to pick
or some other default, or some
to be unhappy with later.
So if you have questions
if someone would be unhappy,
to ask the question to the user.
But, with this, you need to
Nobody wants to play a game of
to get something done.
So, only ask for the things
And people may provide
that your app can't handle,
so you need to send
so that Siri can
and try to move forward
There are two types of questions
and Brandon talked
The first is confirmation.
And this is great when you
to check with the user.
And this could happen because
or if there's an item that
So if someone is used to
or small payments
and suddenly they make a payment
you may want to confirm
to make sure it's
The next is disambiguation.
And this is great when
and you need the
So this can be used when
such as the available ride
Or, if you have a much
to send a message to Eric,
in my contacts, I
to just the possible
and let the user pick that.
Siri can present this list both
And the user can respond by
So before you perform
with your extension, to make
And it wants to get all
from your extension, so that it
Now, again, Siri will
and it will provide a UI on
If the user decides to continue,
if the user decides to continue,
you should go perform
return those results back to
to the user and tell the user.
And in the same way that
they started in a conversation
in the conversation as well.
The great thing about that,
It works in car play, it
when somebody's touching
And Siri will again, provide
But, if you want,
your application can provide
of your app into Siri.
I want you to exercise restraint
The person is trying to get a
to distract them
with information
You also need to make sure
for different screen sizes,
up to the biggest iPad.
Here's another example
from our Unicorn
And as Brandon said,
to hide any redundant
As you do so, you
that your custom UI
and that you send all the
so that hands free
when they can't see this UI.
In a few cases, Siri will
to finish a request,
that for a photo search request
where we can show the
And this is great because
follow-up actions.
Now anytime a user goes
you don't want to surprise them.
Don't put any interstitial
in the way, and make sure
that you are only performing the
Okay, next, let's
about polishing your design.
So, earlier Brandon talked about
and the examples
And people can find that
and just asking,
Siri will show lots of
including your applications, and
So I want to give you
to write good examples.
Make sure that your examples
so that people can get to your
Keep your examples short, and
You should provide multiple
that you support, and make sure
that you prioritize
and the examples
If your app works in multiple
make sure that you
in the appropriate places.
And most importantly,
A couple things to avoid.
You don't need to address
and you also don't need any
Just focus on the
And the last thing I
is iterating on the experience.
You want to make sure that
and to experiment in how
Make sure that you
not just what they
but throughout the process
And again, try it in different
or out and about, not
And throughout, make sure
that you are asking,
If you need to, make a
because we want to
where you have a great Siri
So, let's recap what
Robby started us out introducing
of Siri and your applications to
Brandon talked about
and the way they communicate
and intent responses,
of resolve, confirm, and handle.
And also that your apps
of the common things that
And then we talked about design.
Introducing the conversational
the conversational interface,
and talking about the
as you're developing
that will shape the
And last we talked about
to a Siri experience that
We have more information
We have some related
and I want to especially
with SiriKit, which is tomorrow,
where some of our colleagues
about the API and
for an example integration
So thank you very
to see what you create.
[ Applause ]