[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Great.
Hello, and welcome
on keeping your Watch
My name is Eric Lanz, and
We're both engineers
Here you see a screenshot
When you hear the word app, this
but watchOS has many ways
to interact beyond the
For example, your users
as an important part
If you have a complication,
In watchOS 3, we're introducing
This feature allows
of their favorite applications
They can then swipe through
at their data in one place.
This is now also
People are using your
in many different ways and
in sync and up to
This may sound like
but don't worry.
We're here to help.
Today we'll be talking
First, an overview of this API
Next, a walkthrough
of an example application
Then Austen will come on stage
and show you how scheduling
After that, we'll share
for adopting this API in
To close out the session,
of how we adopted this API in
Let's get started by thinking
and our watches in different
In the morning, you can
in line for coffee.
You can then browse the news on
Before you leave the shop,
with the complication on your
For lunch, you use maps again
After a few minutes,
and put your phone away.
On the way to the restaurant,
A quick glance at your wrist
be a few minutes late,
At the end of the day,
to plan your route,
You get an iMessage asking
Use the quick reply features
"On my way," another
It simply is impossible to have
of seconds that users
We need more time,
and background refresh
This powerful new API allows
so you can have your data
To understand what this new API
at checking the weather
Here we see the foreground
at the weather complication.
Our data would have to be
So let's use this API to
to update our UI, but how can
We'll need more time to
from our server.
So let's schedule
But how did we even get
We're going to need
to wake our application
On watchOS, the system
by giving it a task.
The system has a limited
So make the best use
When the system wants to
it delivers one or more
Make sure to hold
until you're finished
The system delivers tasks
by calling the new handled
on WK extension delegate.
We'll go through an example
When you're finished with your
to the system by completing it.
This is the fundamental process
by which you obtain
Now that we understand the
let's dive in and look at
that the system can
First, this is the
This is a generic runtime
to have your application
Within the application
you can do any kind
You may want to update
or download some data from
The URLSession task
out that your data has
and ready to process.
Since watchOS is a shared
to leave our application running
It would be better to allow
and let the system
Snapshots are a very
They are both your launch image
and your preview image
If the user settles on your app,
it will start running
So it's critical
up to date at all times.
The snapshot task is how you
in the background to be
When you complete this task,
the system will automatically
Remember to always
after you finish
or the user won't see
When a notification arrives,
They will then expect your
to be updated to
Users love applications that
of the OS and are more likely
If the user does not interact
than one hour, the system is
to restore your default state.
Default state means different
and some apps have no
Designing great snapshots
and important topic
We recommend you check
for some great advice
on designing excellent
The last task type is
On watchOS 3, we've
with our background refresh API.
This means you can now use
to get data to your
in the background.
Complication push, application
or sending user info will
in the background.
We hope that this
to even richer watch
When your application is woken
use the standard API
First, make sure the
Once the session reactivates,
start monitoring the new
As long as this property
you still have data to process.
Make sure to hold onto the task
until you're finished
It is your responsibility
to the system by completing it.
If you don't do this, you will
and we're going to give
Austen will talk more in the
about these runtime caveats.
Let's quickly review
of using our new
First, schedule a task.
Next, receive the
Now you can do your
Make sure to hold onto the task
until you're finished
You may use this runtime
such as fetching data from
When finished, return the task
Before we continue, I want
to stress an important
watchOS is a shared ecosystem,
and system processes competing
It is our responsibility as
to do our best to use these
Let's pretend the user launches
to make sure you have
in with your server in an hour.
So schedule a task for 4:00
if the user launches
We could update our data
when the task runs, but that
A better approach is to
to reschedule our background
Every app is different, but
like this to help us
Okay, let's start
To help frame our sample
through the timeline of
and show how you can write the
of these life cycle events.
Let's take a look
and pretend that there's
to 9:00 p.m. We know our user's
and we expect them to be
Let's settle on a
for our background activity.
The background refresh
of each type to be in
So to start off, let's schedule
At 7:30, we'll use that runtime
At 8, we'll again
to schedule our next
It is important to always make
scheduled, or you won't know
when you'll next
Here we see the code
for scheduling an
First, let's set the fire date
Use the userInfo object
about why you made this request.
In this example, I've put the
and a reason string
when the task comes back.
This property is optional,
and any secure coding compliant
This completion blog
out that the system has
your task.
Note that just because
it does not mean
at exactly the requested time.
Austen will talk more about when
and why the system
With our application
let's zoom in on our
at only a five-minute window
in which our task
When the system wakes
to get the latest score
So let's take a look at the code
for starting a background
First, create a URLSession
It is important that
as a background session because
Also, set an identifier
that we'll use later
Next, create a URL session
We ask the URLSession
or more download task
as many download tasks as
Keep in mind the
when all associated
Don't forget to call resume
Getting back to our timeline,
we've got the URL
So it is safe to
and allow the application
The system will continue
are suspended.
When our data is ready,
and wake our application
But what does wake our
In concrete terms, waking your
new handle background task
In addition to this call,
we will receive a
on our visible view controllers.
The system coalesces tasks and
We need to process all
So let's get started by
For each task, we can use an
of the types we care about.
In this case, we're
So we need to rejoin the session
with the task.
URLSession is a highly
We need to be careful
until we're finished
We recommend you store
and then drain the
completing each task to
Make sure to complete task types
that you don't specifically
Remember, the system has a
So complete each
We've got our data.
Let's update our model.
You might consider updating
but we recommend you make use
for that type of work.
So before we complete our
to schedule a snapshot.
With our snapshot scheduled,
it's safe to complete
and allow the application
Soon, the system
up with the snapshot
Now is our chance
and get everything ready
Snapshots have a unique
So let's take a look at
for snapshots on watchOS.
Every application must have
This is because your snapshot
and your preview image
That rule means that when
we need to tell the system
Think about your data and
to your users.
In this case, we have another
So let's set our expiration
User info can optionally
about why we made this request.
That data will return to us
WatchOS will give your
to restore its default state
You can tell the system
by setting the
to true.
Doing this lets the system
at your default state, and don't
Apps that have no concept
of a default state should
property to true.
Once you complete
the system will suspend
Your UI will then be
as your new launch image.
This activity will not
We've made it through
of a common background refresh
In case you didn't notice,
at a whole five minutes
our application was only
By chaining tasks, we were able
to maximize our use
You now have a good
of what this new API is,
and how you can go
I'd like to welcome
to give you some deeper insights
into how scheduling
Good luck [applause].
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
I'm Austen Green.
I'm a watchOS engineer.
This morning, I would like to
about how scheduling
I'd like to provide some
up as we adopted background
And, finally, I'd like to
about specifically how we
in our stocks application.
So let's get started.
So the first thing I want
So while your application
you're always scheduled to run.
This means that your
so that you can do things
and draw your UI, and
that your application
Now when your application moves
into the background the
your application.
This means that your
to execute any code at all.
Now sometimes while
in the background, the system
to perform a very specific task.
The system will wake your
to perform a specific task
In watchOS 2, there
that the system could
For example, to handle a
or perhaps ClockKit would
to update its complication.
In watchOS 3, we're adding even
to run in the background.
Now the system is going to
of time that you get to run
These limits are on the order of
to consider the amount of
as the amount of CPU you use.
So it's in your best interest
and as efficiently as possible.
Now in a later seed, if
the system will kill
You'll get a crash report,
and you'll know whether
or the time limits based
on the exception code
Now we recognize that different
So ApplicationRefresh task
and the URLSession task have
than watch connectivity
So in watchOS 2, complications
that your application got
In watchOS 3, we're going to
to get multiple updates an hour
if you're a complication
with what you were
However, if you were previously
to update your complication
you can now request
I'll show you how to do
Also, new in watchOS 3, we're
from your parent iPhone if
It's really easy to take
to make sure that you have a
for your users all day long.
Let's take a look at some code.
So let's say that you're running
that your model changed.
You can now query WCSession,
remainingComplication
out how many high-priority
for the rest of the day.
You can use this information
to tailor your complication
when the best time is for you
So let's say in the
you've got plenty of pushes.
Go ahead and send
The user will see your
almost immediately.
Now let's say that you've been
of running low on, on transfers.
So you might consider throttling
to the watch to make sure
that your user will have
throughout the rest of the day.
Finally, if you don't have any
it's still okay to try and
the data will get sent
Next, I'd like to
of the CLKComplication
like to move into WatchKit.
If you were previously
with getNextRequested
You should now expect the system
with a preferred
that you were telling
Similarly, when ClockKit
it would call requestedUpdate
Now we want to do that
with handle background refreshed
You'll get an application task
to handle both complication
and your application updates.
Now, new in watchOS 3,
We think it's a great way
at their favorite applications
of all of the information
We want your applications in
So we're going to
of one update per hour.
This applies to a snapshot task
Now this budget is distributed
in the dock, and the user can
want in their dock.
Consequence of this is that if a
then your application can
in the background
Also, we keep your
so that resumes are fast,
with your application
as quickly as possible.
Also in the dock,
of a most recently used app.
This application occupies
and the users are given
in the dock by pressing
Now this application
like a user's favorite
that the user has explicitly
This means that this application
tasks and snapshot tasks
like any other application
So you should always make
with the system any application,
any background refresh
Now home screen applications
regular scheduling.
So just keep that in mind.
As Eric mentioned
of your application are
of your application in
There may be times
to snapshot your application
Now if the system
to perform a snapshot
these snapshots don't
and they're in addition
that you've asked of the system.
There are five triggers
to ask your application
If your complication timeline
with one of your notifications,
this means that the notification
and it doesn't count if it goes
When you go from the
and then again, one hour later
to give your application
to its default state,
And, finally, in order to
the system is going to
for a snapshot on boot.
This is your opportunity
to start scheduling any other
with the system.
Now, I'd like to take
with you some best practices
as we adopt a background
So, first of all, the
as much information as
So schedule as often
Every time your application
you should consider
refresh needs and scheduling
You should not feel
If the system calls
for a background refresh task,
maybe you just updated
need to do anything else,
Or better yet, in the, in the
consider deferring
that you've scheduled
You should consider all
that you get to make sure
that you keep your
This means updating
and scheduling background
So for dock and foreground
complication updates,
There's any number of reasons
runtime, and you should keep
and keep your application
So application refresh
point into general purpose
in the background, and we think
for this.
You can do things like
Maybe you need to read
or the calendar database
You can use this to
This is what we do in
If you have known
you can tell the system the
that it would be great
For example, a calendar
or an itinerary application
time transitions.
And, finally, if you were
runtime through the ClockKit
to the WatchKit API's to
Now let's talk about some best
The snapshot is a
of your application's
that data can become stale.
So the system wants to know
You can tell the system
to be updated by scheduling a
Now you should think in terms
when you're trying to
You wouldn't want
like high-frequency
For example, in a timer
down, you wouldn't want
to update our snapshot
This doesn't make sense.
Instead, you would
to update your snapshot
when something significant has
Now I know this is complex,
and I'd like to share what
for how to manage
So let's say that you
Maybe it's watch connectivity.
Maybe it's NSURLSession.
Maybe you just happened
because the user
Basically, anything that causes
All of the operations
for background refresh are in
For example, updating
requesting a new snapshot,
and then evaluating what your
are, whether it's for a
or just scheduling
with a background refresh API.
Now with the dock in watchOS 3,
we think that users
we think that users are
of many applications
than they were in watchOS 2.
Now in watchOS 2, you
to enter the foreground or enter
but we think these
to happen a lot more often now.
So you should make sure that
as soon as possible on
When your application
you don't want to be
You just want to do the
for displaying your
Similarly, when you entered
in the foreground, you should
that you were doing
Now we recognize that you
to complete any foreground
by using NSProcessInfo.
performExpiringActivity.
There's a great session from
and Tricks that tells you
use NSProcessInfo.
performExpiringActivity.
Finally, one more thing I want
Now, typically, a user will put
and unlock it, and the watch
until they take it off at night,
Certain types of data
on the watch are completely
is locked.
For example, the most prominent
So you should just make sure
that you consider
if your data is not
And then I'd like to
The simulator is going to be
As I mentioned before,
but in a simulator,
to enforce any of those budgets.
So you should basically get
that you want them
Similarly, while
we may still apply some
to have the best experience
You need to make sure that
and the resume path.
The system is going to do its
in memory, but in the
the system will have to launch
to request the initial snapshot.
Verify that your tasks
In a future seed, you'll get
to complete your tasks in time.
And it's super important that
because we want your
as possible for users.
And, finally, once you think
strategy implemented,
Make sure that you're
that you want your
You should vary the number
in your dock to make sure
and worst-case scenarios for
Now, I'd like to share
on how we adopted
in our stocks application.
So before we even got
we took a step back and thought
that are interesting
for our stocks application.
We use a URLSession to retrieve
to have a complication.
This means that we know
of our data across the system.
With our complication,
and now our live application.
We know that we want
to be periodic throughout
We want to get regular
but then we know something
which is that once the
for the rest of the day.
It's not going to change at all.
Well, let's talk about how this
So let's say our device boots.
The system is going to ask our
So we'll load our last data,
but before we complete
we're going to schedule a
Now this is our opportunity
to start the background
that we can download the most
Now we're going to use an
so that we can give
about what data we
and the system can put
and download our data
Now URLSession DataTask does
however, it will fail if your
when your application
And because of the time
your application is likely going
to suspend before your
So we could recommend
So a little bit later,
to wake our application
up because we finished
So we're going to
and because we've
we're going to do three things.
We're going to trigger
and we're also going
that our snapshot
for a new snapshot right now,
to evaluate what our next
So we'll figure out what the
and we'll tell the system that.
Now a little bit later, we get
and all we're doing here
URLSession download.
So we complete this cycle
Just keeping our
the system will snapshot us, and
in the dock, we'll have the
in our snapshot.
Well, let's say that the user
So we go full screen,
that our users have the
So we'll download the
because we've entered
And, and once we've updated our
We request a complication
we request a new snapshot,
and then we schedule a
for a later time.
Now there's two things I
First of all, we're
but we're still requesting
This is absolutely okay, and we
We want you to request a
model changes.
The system is smart
when your application's
and when it's not okay for us
The second thing is because
and updated our model,
to evaluate our next
If we knew that we were
in the next ten minutes, but
we can defer our snap, or we
request with the system
of time that we get to run.
To maximize the number
of opportunities
Finally, the last update
We know our data stopped
but we'll complete
This means updating
requesting a new snapshot,
and then evaluating our
So because we know our data
that we can't have stale data
in our complications
We can wait until
for the next background
This lets our application get
and not do any unnecessary work,
which means that there's
for other applications
So to summarize,
It's absolutely critical
If you don't, in a future
to kill your application.
If the system kills
users won't have the quick
that they're expecting,
and users will take your
Use all the runtime that
Consider foreground activations,
of course, the background
Anytime you get runtime,
make sure that you consider
and evaluating your background
Tell the system when
Your complication and your
system-owned caches of
The system needs to know when
so that we won't display the
Users expect to see consistent
your application's data.
And, finally, you need
to consider your
on a case-by-case basis.
There is no one size
You have to really consider how
and interesting characteristics
for how you plan your
For more information, you
and there is some great related
Architecting for
We'll go into some more
in the stocks application.
Thank you very much.