[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
My name is Steve Breen.
&gt;&gt; And my name is Peter Hajas,
on the UIKit Frameworks Team.
&gt;&gt; We're really excited to share
with what we're working
So let's get right into it.
We've got three big topics
Our first topic is going
Now, every iOS app expects
to have great scrolling
and we got some great
to help your apps scroll better
about this is many of these
to no work in your applications.
Next, we're going to talk
about improvements
Now this API was
and we're bringing some great
to make it easier to adopt.
And, finally, we're going to
This API was introduced
and we've got some great
to go over for iOS 10.
&gt;&gt; Let's start off
A hallmark of the iOS device
immediately to the user's
of this responsive user
that as I scroll my
the objects onscreen move
as if they're moving
This is really important
in their applications.
We're going to talk
and some enhancements we've
by talking through a demo app.
As you'll see, this application
that great.
We wanted to scroll like
it's scrolling a lot more
So let's go to the iPad.
I'm going to switch
Just to clarify, blue squares
but we've intentionally
So imagine they're
For example, maybe they
Anyways, we've got this
that scrolling already
and fast, but check this out.
Steve, watch closely.
When I scroll a little bit more.
&gt;&gt; Ooh, ouch.
One star, do not buy.
&gt;&gt; I wouldn't buy it either.
This type of user experience
to avoid.
So what's going on here?
Well, we said before that these
squares to simulate to really
in your app, and that's running
and the fact that it loads cells
Let me show you what I mean.
We'll reload our data
on a view that's going to show
in the CollectionView.
So you can see those bottom
up beyond the visible bounds.
Now watch what happens
We're bringing in an
This is what's leading to that
In performance terminology,
that the app is dropping frames.
Let's switch back to slides
&gt;&gt; So what exactly do
about dropping frames.
Now, in your applications,
the users expect a smooth
which means your app wants
of 60 frames per second.
Now if we do the math,
that means that for every time
to hit that window
OK. So let's look
Here we have a diagram that
In our first frame, we got
Now as Peter mentioned before,
up and down the display.
It's a highly optimized
So it's superfast.
Not much work to hit, and
scrolling performance.
That's a good frame.
However, in the demo, it
Occasionally, we'd
where we have a lot
Not only do we fill
we went into the next frame.
This is our ad frame.
We drop a frame, one star.
Let's look at this in a
Now on this graph, we can see
We have the region on the top,
which we're going to
This is the area where we miss
that magical 16 millisecond
Let's check out the labels
So on our y-axis, we're
on the main thread,
this is the display fresh events
OK. So let's look at a graph.
Alright. So in this graph,
this shows what Peter was
where we have these visits
where we're dropping
look at these quiet times
where the CollectionView's
but then we have
to the red zone at the end.
So what if we could change this
out the amount of work we're
OK, cool. Look at this.
So now instead of these
and those periods of quiescence,
of work, and we're spreading
&gt;&gt; To help talk through
to flatten these peaks
to create this nice, consistent
through the life cycle of a
We're going to go through the
It's beautiful.
Let's bring our CollectionView
and we're scrolling along,
to bring in a new cell.
We'll take it out
and we'll call prepareForReuse
This gives the cell an
to its default state, ready to
Next, we'll continue calling the
This is where you should
of your work populating
You'll access your data
and return them back
Now, right before that
we'll call willDisplayCell.
This will give your app a chance
to do any other last-minute
that cell goes on screen.
And for any outgoing cells,
&gt;&gt; OK. So that's the life cycle
Now let's check out what
So here we have the
that Peter just talked about.
The single column.
It's simple for demonstration
So now as the user scrolls up,
notice here that well
to be displayed on screen,
in from the reuse queue.
And then following that familiar
we're going to send
and then construct the rest
with cellForItemAtIndexPath.
Now as the user continues to
Now we didn't call
when we created this cell.
We have a hesitant, hesitation,
we're going to call
OK. So now the user
We're going to fade away
on the lifetime of this
about to exit the visible
So we'll send it the
Now what Peter was talking
the cell entered the reuse
To display the data in
we'd have to go through the
to cell and call
But in iOS 10, we're
onto that cell just
So if the user scrolls
and then says, "Oh,
That was a picture of
I'm going to scroll back
onto that cell, and send
Now the content will
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So notice as Steve's showing
to multicolumn layouts.
We're going to be bringing in
of all at once to get better
&gt;&gt; That's right,
these cells aren't actually
They're still off the screen.
And now that we sent the
the cellForItemIndexPath,
now we're going to send
to both right before
&gt;&gt; While this may seem
it's actually a lot
By adopting this new
we get automatic faster
Let's go back to iPad.
So I'm going to switch back
that same CollectionView we
Remember, scrolling existing
but when we have to
that's when things get choppy.
Now, while preparing
we also prepared one in the
So I'm going to switch
and here we've got the
with those same really expensive
We can see that scrolling
fast, and fluid, but
&gt;&gt; Alright.
&gt;&gt; When I scroll
&gt;&gt; Oh, that's great.
Five stars.
&gt;&gt; That's exactly right.
[ Applause ]
This is because we're using
The application hasn't
I'm going to turn on that
to show you all the cells
to help highlight
So let me turn that on.
So here you can see
of cells is just peaking above,
but watch what happens
Instead of bringing in a
we're now spreading that
This is what leads to that much
Isn't that great?
To learn more about this,
&gt;&gt; So this is pretty great.
So today we're very pleased
to announce UI CollectionView
Now this is enabled by default
when you compile
There's no step one.
Now for any reason you need
to use the old life cycle
opting out is easy.
Just set the new property
to isPrefetchingEnabled
Now we've got some
for adopting this
The first thing we want
to do all the heavy lifting
All the, all the content
Everything should be centered
Additionally, we want to
willDisplayCell in
And, finally, it's
that cellForItemaAtIndexPath
actually displayed.
The user may scroll away before
to be displayed.
&gt;&gt; So this is great.
By just recompiling in iOS 10
and doing what you're likely
of your work in
you automatically get better
But we wanted to
We understand that there's
which has a simple question for
What do I do about my
The fact of the matter is
that many CollectionView cells
access to create.
I'm talking about things
talking to your database,
out of your core data store.
And we understand that for
we don't want to show things
like template cells while we do
To help solve this problem,
in iOS 10 to help inform how
Since its introduction,
UI CollectionView has always
The data source and
And new in iOS 10 we have
It's optional, and it's
There's just one
It's really easy to implement.
ColletionView prefetchItemsAt
This will be called on
when it's time for
from your asynchronous model.
That argument index paths is
so earlier items in that
You can use this to influence
There's a second optional
CollectionView
indexPaths.
This will be called on
when we determine that we're no
of index paths.
You can use this to cancel
or lower the priority
Now there's something really
that I want to highlight.
This is not a replacement
that you've already written.
Instead, it works alongside your
that you've built for
What you'll do is use this as
to load content in
&gt;&gt; So let's tie all this
that shows all of the concepts
and we're going to introduce
&gt;&gt; Check this out.
Steve's about to
&gt;&gt; Science, man.
Alright. We're going to
which we showed before.
OK. So here's the demo app
but we've hidden this really
science panel.
Alright, so I'm going
OK. So we have these two
We've got that red zone.
That's the one star bad
that nice fat green
where we get the super
So what I'm going to do
through with the iOS 9 version
to play back a scrolling
to show you what this looks
OK. So here we go.
Scrolling along,
Chop, chop.
OK. What do we have here?
So check out this graph.
We got eight visits
Eight dropped frames.
But also we can see that
of quiescence like we
So the area on the graph
and then going back
Let's see what this
OK. I'm going to switch
that Peter was talking about
to playback that same scrolling
Check it out, Peter.
&gt;&gt; It's a lot smoother, Steve.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that definitely
See what we get.
Hey, look at that.
No missed frames.
Pretty great.
Now check out what we've
on this particular graph.
Instead of those peaks way up in
we've blended those together,
and now we have this
that makes your app much more
OK. You ready for this, Peter?
&gt;&gt; I'm set.
&gt;&gt; Let's do it.
OK. So now we're going to
but we're going to have
that Peter talked about earlier.
We're going to adopt
Alright. So I'm all
I'm going to play back that
Whoa, Peter, look at that.
&gt;&gt; Now that's butter, Steve.
&gt;&gt; That's looking pretty good.
Five stars.
And the science agrees.
[ Applause ]
OK. So, but, Peter, something's
The area on the curve between
and the prior version
This is a lot lower.
What's going on here?
&gt;&gt; So if we're adopting the
we're probably moving
onto a background queue
&gt;&gt; That's exactly right.
That's what's going on.
So now we've moved all that
and we no longer have to
Let's switch back the slides.
So next I'd like to
about some pre-fetching API tips
in the best possible way.
The first, when you
you want to make sure
on the background
Now we've got two great
GCD and NSOperationQueue.
Now it's also important
that pre-fetch is an
Now what do I mean by
Well, remember when we talked
and how pre-fetch takes
by doing additional work.
There are times in
where the user's
that there's no quiet times.
During these times when we have
to update the display
we will not do pre-fetching.
[Inaudible] And, finally,
to adapt to your
Now it's possible that
up in their CollectionView,
with the content, but then
and move in another direction.
We will notify you of this
so you can deprioritize
on the new content that
&gt;&gt; So this is really
By doing no work at all, you get
and by doing just a
and using the classes
you get even better
And if you're using
You're not chopped liver.
We've brought the exact
[ Applause ]
It's got a very similar optional
object with a similar
TableView prefetchRowsAt
Again, index paths is an array
to the table's visible area.
So earlier index paths
Just like with the
you can use this to inform your
And it's got that same second
TableView
indexPaths.
As Steve just mentioned to
to cancel or deprioritize
And this is what's really great.
Just like with the
this works alongside your
model solution.
You don't have to
Instead, use this to inform the
So that's it for cell
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So we're really excited about
I mean, we can't wait
with the smoother
So next up, we're going
about improvements we've made
This API was introduced in iOS 8
and we're bringing some
year to make it easier
Now, before we get
over the existing API,
So we shift a concrete
in CollectionView called
and we have full support
for self-sizing cells
To enable this, we just need
to some non-zero CG size,
that you want to, you want to
as content is displayed.
Now as far as getting the
there's three different
The first method is
If you can fully constrain the
to the content view of
we'll ask the auto
that cell should be
Now if you don't
or you need more manual control,
And, finally, for
you can override
FittingAttributes, and provide
but also you can
like alpha and transform.
&gt;&gt; So specifying the
of these three mechanisms,
Most apps will use auto layout,
they can take on
with the second two
But we found that
picking a good estimated
out to be really challenging
because sometimes it's
I mean, sometimes
50 by 50, 100 by 100, even more.
It's hard to say.
For these types of layouts,
if flow layout could adapt
on your behalf and instead
from actual sizes of
So in iOS 10, we've got new
All you have to do is set your
to a new constant,
UICollectionViewFlowLayout
By setting your estimated
you'll indicate to the
that it should do
It'll keep a running
that it's already sized, and use
that to influence its
As we'll see in a minute,
this makes the flow layout much
your CollectionView cells
and a more accurate
So we're going to do a demo
of UICollectionViewFlowLayout
So I'm going to switch
Now here we've got a
flow layout.
Each cell represents a
Just to clarify,
that you build a text viewer or
but this does make
I'm going to put
where we can watch
as it sizes each
No user would ever see
for visualizing the
Let's start out with
like we'd use on iOS 9.
So I'm going to turn
Here, you can see that
with that initial estimated
And I'm going to size the first
and watch what happens.
So we size Lorem, and now
but notice the CollectionView
to what its destination
We didn't use that estimate
and everything else is still
that we passed in.
Now this continues as we
in this CollectionView.
Notice how we're not actually
of the other cell sizes
that we've already computed.
This is especially obvious
in this run of text, Fusce,
you'll notice that we slide
invalidating their y-positions,
and we haven't used the
of text to influence the sizes
So now I'm going
into iOS 10 mode using
automatic size.
So let's switch over.
OK, great.
So we've seeded this with
to help you visualize
I'm going to size the
and watch what happens.
Wow. So we size that first
as a running estimate for all
Now the layout's not
but notice how it's a lot closer
In fact, the heights
in y-positions are
And notice that as I size this
that estimated size, making
for your CollectionView
And notice when we size the
we're no longer invalidating
of all the other cells.
This is really great
when you're doing things like
Now due to the nature of this
for your buck using
if your cells have
So that's it for self-sizing
Let's go back to slides.
[ Applause ]
So that wraps up our
and now we're going
about an API we introduced last
Now, this is a familiar
to users of TableView cells.
They like to, users might grab
and rearrange it
So we brought this technology
with a new interactive
Let's run back over to the iPad
and see what this might
Switch back over to the iPad.
&gt;&gt; Alright.
&gt;&gt; Here we are.
OK. So we've got this really
Oh, man, look at
&gt;&gt; We probably adapted
which is really easy.
&gt;&gt; That's probably it.
OK. So check it out.
So let's say the user
but they want to rearrange it.
Might drag their finger around
around the CollectionView,
and notice how it
And not only that, if
that has a different
to do the right thing.
Now when the user's done
Smoothly animates into
Let's switch back to slides, and
&gt;&gt; So that's interactive
on iOS 9, and this
To start an interactive
to call CollectionViews
MovementForItemat indexPath
where index path represents
that we'd like to move around.
If you're doing this in
you can hit test the
for item at location.
Next, each time the gesture
to update the cell's position
For this, we're going to call
TargetPosition.
Passing in the location
in the CollectionView's
Next, when we'd like to end
and confirm the reorder,
we're going to call
on the CollectionView.
CollectionView will
handling all the layout
and then message back to
so that you could do the
Now, if the gesture cancels,
or if you'd like to not allow
you can call CollectionView's
Here, we'll put everything
and we won't call
Now for those of you using
this is even easier
You just have to set the
for interactive movement
and CollectionViewController
that will call these
All you have to do is
&gt;&gt; So that's the API that we
This year we're very proud
to add paging support to this.
Now there's no new API, which
and since CollectionView is
all you need to do is set
of the ScrollView's
and that'll enable the support.
Let's switch back to the iPad
&gt;&gt; And here, we've
scrolling CollectionView.
This is currently
It's just continuous, and look
at that smooth scrolling
&gt;&gt; Hey, hey.
&gt;&gt; So in reordering when
we pick up the CollectionView
of the screen, and then we
scrolling behavior.
This is familiar to users
of many CollectionView
Now I'm going to turn on
that CollectionView now advances
This is really natural for
Now here's what's new.
We're calling the
but new in iOS 10,
that reordering works
So as I move my cell to
we're going to automatically
This can give your app a
reordering experience.
I'm going to let
[ Applause ]
Let's go back to slides.
&gt;&gt; So they're a little
So while we were developing
Pete would often come to my
"Steve, I'm working
Developers are going to flip."
He's like that.
And I agree, it's
I can't wait to show it
So during the run up to WWDC,
to land this particular
and share it to people.
So even a couple days ago,
he made the pitch again,
So I said, "OK, fine."
Two slides, ninety
Can you get it done?
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Steve.
It'll just take a minute.
Another feature that I'm
in CollectionView in iOS
That's right!
UIRefreshControl is now
of CollectionView.
But not only that, it's also
of UITableView without
And not only that, it's also
because RefreshControl is now
It's really easy to use, too.
All you have to use, do is
add yourself as a target
and set it on your
and you'll be pulling
Thanks a lot, Steve.
It means a lot to me.
&gt;&gt; Hey, great job.
Great job.
It's like the summarizer
We went over the brand
pre-fetching stuff,
to see what you guys are going
And then we covered the new
for Collection and TableView.
Next, we covered
to self-sizing cells with the
And then we chatted a little bit
about the iOS 9 introduced
and the new paging
You want to check out the
for this app, for this session,
on the developer website.
We got some great
with these technologies
We want to thank you
Have a great --
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much.