[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Welcome to Leveraging
My name is Dominik
on the UIKit Team,
about how you can make the
in Multi-Touch and
First, let's go over our new
Since last WWDC, we
For example, 3D Touch with
which gives you access to
I won't talk much about this,
but you can have all the great
in the session at A Peek
We introduced faster
with iPad Air 2 and iPad Pro,
giving you a temporary
of twice the refresh
We also introduced Apple
and this amazing device, thank
at a [inaudible] accuracy
It has an even higher temporary
It gives you access to its
of course, all the force.
And our algorithms team did an
So you can rest your palm
and don't have to
We also released Apple
and its track mainly
and your interactions
But you can also access the
Controller framework for both
or also getting the absolute
And, finally, you can
in indirect touches in our
I won't talk much
but there are the great
and there's also Game Controller
What am I going to talk about?
I'm going to talk about how
We will build a drawing app from
about all the new
so you can access all
We will talk you
and show you all the different
on what you see,
of this app is completely
So you can just relax
and play with it later.
So say hello to SpeedSketch.
This is our sample.
SpeedSketch is one sheet
It has full support for
and 3D Touch on iPhone 6S.
It also works on all
So let's first talk
So this is a stroke, and this
Each of those points is one
of a mutable UI touch.
You get handed down in
And we will model our data
And because of the UI touch
of one touch sequence,
out of this UI touch in
into something more static.
So we will build a stroke sample
of our data structure, which
location of this, of the
we will fill in all the
And we will put those
Let's just an array
and we have a little bit
And because we want
as our main data capture
So it can be active while
when the user is done,
if a different user interaction
So we can throw it away
And, lastly, we put this
which will just be an array of
down strokes, and to make it a
we will have the active
So we can use the
as our data model
So next up is where to
So, essentially, you have
The first one, is a
a custom UIGestureRecognizer
The next place to look
where the touch goes down, and
up the responder chain,
I want you to think
If you can do a
or a custom subclass do that.
Second, do a UIView as close as
and only if you have to
So this is what we going to do.
We are building a stroke
to a subclass.
We will target our
and then in the action methods,
of our view with a stroke.
So let's start building this
The first thing you
to import the
This exposes the internals of
so you can do subclassing.
Be aware, though, that these
outside of a
For example, the state setter
and you shouldn't use
Otherwise, the gesture system
and you will have
So let's add our stroke
in our gesture recognizer
and implement the
And since we do various
in all the four touch
we will have a helper
into the set of UITouches.
Determining if we are interested
Adding that to our data model
as a sample at the
if you were interested in those.
We will use this helper
and set our state to begin.
For UIGestureRecognizer, that
between the state possible and
that different gesture
about have, handing
However, for our stroke, we
when the touch goes down.
So this is exactly
In touchesMoved, we do the same
Note that in a gesture
each state change
even if it's for the same.
And we do the same for
And, finally, we have to
and replace the previous
so we can catch on the next one.
And as a good citizen, we
Let's use this in
In our viewDidLoad, we set up
ourselves as the target with
and then we add it
And in the update callback,
from the gesture, and
That's all for now.
I told you about the
but just to bring up, I
So let's see what this gives us.
I always like this moment
when the first time
So what you see is
of the pencil on the display.
Let's have a look.
Oh. That doesn't look good.
What happened?
Let's have a closer
That's really not
So let's, what did we see?
We have the position
We have a really,
to the last line we drew,
and the lines we drew were
That is not what I,
We have a really good
Why does it look this way?
So, obviously, we
and we missed some events
One of them is our drawing
very naively.
It is drawing a complete bit map
and that is not quick enough to
And we will talk about
And the most, more important
iOS 9 API that we have
to actually get to
And for that, I want to look a
So let's see that again.
Here are all the rich samples
And in our touch handing
and the ended, but in
And we don't get all of
in as a sample, and
If we would deliver to you
if you would block
you would see something
of the touch interaction, and
that's not at all what you want.
You want the most recent
and that's what we do generally,
and that's what we
We actually dropped
If you weren't quick
then you just didn't see any of
we give you access
And the other reason is as
than the display, we don't
for each datapoint we have.
So you do too much work.
So we try to coalesce
into one delivery per
So what you can do
using the life touch
ask for the touches you missed,
and that includes the touch
So you have a complete
And those touches are
And you do that for
And you do that also
Because you have to
Either you handle
or you handle the
Because there are methods
that reference the previous
then you into problems there.
So now that we know how,
let's do this in code.
The method is coalescedTouches
and you get the event in
And now that the optional
because we will give you nil.
Anytime if you only
and we don't have
it's because you could ask for
of the event, and then
You're guaranteed to
at least the one you put in
So you don't have to do an
So let's use this in our code.
In our code where we look at
we did appendTouch, and all
over the Coalesce Touches
That gives us all the data.
Let's have a look
Nice. Now we really
Let's have a comparison.
And, again, in slow
So what are you seeing here?
This is in [inaudible]
on the glass currently.
These are the Coalesce Touches
Now debugging drawing engine.
The black one is also
but the one corresponding
And what you also see is
that you see too many
If our digitizer is running
of the display, you see,
you should see an average three
These are way too many.
And we still have this
which leads to lag,
So what did we see?
The speed is still lagging
We didn't address this up
by coalescing the touches,
and the final drawing really has
So if you only take
then use Coalesce
to have the rich
So what is the problem
You should not draw
because the display
Although we try to actually
frame, you can draw, that
because if you mix
or have other events coming in,
we need to deliver
And so you need to be
than you can, than
And do not try to draw faster
because this is just costing
and doing work that doesn't even
So when should you render?
In our example, we are using
graphics, and in that case,
you should just use setsNeeds
marking that view is needing
to actually call the draw method
of your custom bit drawing.
If you're using a GLKView or
into this behavior
by setting the enableSetsNeeds
That way those views behave in
If you need to draw at a
at a steady pace and not
and you can do so
and GLViews internal
so using a CADisplayLink
in the wake of your DisplayLink.
What we did was we had
in our strokes [inaudible] just
with drawImageAndUpdate.
This created the
So let's just do
and move the drawing code
If you're using a regular
You can only mark the changed
that also needs some kind
because your drawing might,
than the changed touches,
and the touches change
You can look at the sample
of how you could do this
And even further, you can
on the layer.
This puts all the drawing you
up to CA, and CA draws it
which opens your main thread
and you do so by simply setting
or your diffuse layer.
Let's see how far this got us.
Again in slow motion.
So now we have the steady amount
of Coalesce Touches
about three Coalesce
But we still have some lag.
It however, it's way smaller
at the display speed, and we
And how can we improve that?
So we have a facility called
and Predicted Touches give
You use the same way as Coalesce
for the Predicted Touches for
of touches that are
And what do you do
You add them to your data
They change on every
So you really have to do
And you choose their appearance,
I highly recommend that you make
and look at the result, and
by too much, then tone it down.
It makes them appears tentative
to still get the closer
Let's look over that in code.
So now in our touch
after you added the
you add the Predicted Touches
to make sure that you remove
So I will show you a video of
of what you should do.
I will highlight the Predicted
if they are good
And, again, in slow motion
So these are the Predictive
to the actual Pencil position,
for perceived lag
And as you can see
this really worked out fine.
So we will just use them
and draw them the same way
So have we seen so far?
We have seen how to collect
UIGestureRecognizer, how to
how to make the rendering faster
how to use the Predictive
All of those techniques work
We used them for the Pencil
but they work overall.
Now let's go on to the
So let's begin with touch types.
With Apple Pencil UITouch
and UITouch type can
It can be direct, which would
know about.
There's indirect only for
and there's stylus
And the first thing
with Apple Pencil is
and you do so by using
and you also have the precise
You should use those whenever
for something like a drawing.
If you want to do hit testing,
you should still use the
and previous location in.
But for drawing, this
Without the precise locations,
you will add some staircase
which you don't want to see.
And you can ask all kind of
You will just get
Next up, there's force.
Force is exposed as a
and a maximum possible force.
Those are CG floats, and they
to the maximum possible force
where 1.0 represents
So these are not
So you shouldn't do
to the actual force,
to affect your drawing.
And on all previous devices
it will always return zero.
A quick note on force.
Since we added force to
in touch handing, and that
more often.
Because you want to
if the force value changed.
We will send you
Previously, we were
to only send you touchesMoved
when the location
and that is through
not even the precise location.
And that has implications
So, for example, we've seen
If you did in touchesMoved,
if you just cancel a tap
That doesn't work anymore.
And what you see is that
or with the Pencil,
really just slightly
then this is what you're running
at your touch handing code.
What should you do?
You should actually use a
if you can because
of our knowledge there, or the
to remember the location
and only cancel it if you
from the original location.
So let's add our force to the
and we just do that by an
We will add all the other
and I won't show
So let's see how the force
Nice. What did we do?
We just changed the
So next up is tilt.
Apple Pencil gives you access
and this is measured in an
and the device which
And the altitude angle is
It's a CG float.
It reported at angle at
from about 10 degrees
And that second part
The orientation is measured
and it's measured between
and the direction the
And this is called azimuth.
Together, azimuth and tilt form
and you can drive your
for your drawing with it.
So azimuth is depending on
So you have to call a method
and most of the time
to use a vector anyways.
So we exposed the azimuth
which will be a vector pointing
in the direction
from with a magnitude of one.
Next up, force.
So force, for the Pencil
than 3D Touch force, and that is
axis of the Pencil.
With 3D Touch, the force
and perpendicular to
That makes for some difference,
out if you want to
all the perpendicular
because it really, it
Luckily, it's easy to
and here's the code for that.
So you can get the perpendicular
through the sign of the altitude
in the same range, you
to the maximumPossibleForce.
And there's finally
for Apple Pencil with the force.
It's measured inside the
over the air to the iPad, and
of over-the-air transmissions.
That means they take
of time, and data can be lost.
So instead of making you wait
for the over-the-air
we decided to give you
and update them later so you
So for that, we exposed
which is of the type
So estimated properties
which for Apple Pencil
for the first event you get.
But also the azimuth
and altitude can be
That happens when you
and we not hundred percent
or if you draw very
because our senses can't really
And we tell you that
so you can do something with it.
For example, when
you could back fill them
and in the sample I gave to
as to illustrate that point.
And there's also the location,
which is an estimated property
which gives you an easy way
to determine Predicted
And for the updates, we also
expecting updates.
This is also of type
and currently it's only force.
It might be in the future also
currently, it's only the force
we will send you updates in
so in our new responder
PropertiesUpdated, and we
So we will send you
and then send you updates later.
Let's walk through this.
So what do you do?
[Inaudible] touches
you check the
ExpectedUpdates on your touch,
you use the property
on the UITouch, which is
for touches that either expect
and use that to store your
your current touch
so you can look it up later.
In the touchesEstimated
up your sample, and using the
you get an update
that were expecting updates.
Note, though, that some
after touch has ended.
That's a life cycle thing
If you don't keep
around after touch has ended,
at the end of your stroke,
So let's go with that in code.
So we have touchesEstimated
and we go through our touches.
We look up the estimation index
We can just implicitly
We find our sample
We update the sample,
we update only the
that we're expecting
And then we update our
we check if this touch
and only if it doesn't we
So let's see this in action.
So I tried to use
to do a calligraphy
And now that we have all the
without the debugging mode.
Doesn't that look nice?
And that's literally just me
from the hardware.
That is not interpolating
or doing something fancy
like your drawing
So with that, let's add
to the final app.
Up to now, we just drew
We don't want to be
So let's support our
For that, we include our stroke
add a little bit of
that into a [inaudible] draw
Not quite.
So now we have to think about
because the [inaudible]
with our stroke gesture
If we change nothing, then
and we can never scroll.
This is not what we want.
So one way around this is
to disable scrolling
This would be useful for
where you would always like to
and specifically disable that.
You can do that because
to UIGestureRecognizer.
UITouch types is an array of
and it defaults to all
So what we are going to do here
in this example is we would
from our scroll view, we will
to only allow direct touches
and we will change our stroke
So this obviously is
In the sample code, you
but switches dynamically
and is a little bit
but it illustrates the point
that you can restrict
to either the Pencil
And one final note on this.
There's also a new property
that is called
and although our gesture
to all the touch types, if
to recognize, they are
That is so you don't
with a Pencil and a finger.
This is the regularly what you
If you don't want this, you set
type to force, and then
between fingers and the Pencil.
So to summarize, I showed
of UITouch so you can
I showed you how to use the
to both have the richest data
and to have the least latency.
I told you about property
and how you actually
to the full rich data the Pencil
to adjust gestures to either
And this is a screenshot of the
that does the nice
and more interesting to you,
it also has the debug mode
of them.
So you can see how your
how they are estimated at
and azimuth, and just play
of our touch handling works.
So the full information of
at this URL.
We have controlling game
for Siri remote handling.
A peek at 3D Touch will show you
with the force in 3D Touch to a
and to get, to know more about
you should have a look
on iOS from last year.
And with that, that's it.
Thank you very much.