[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning guys, how's
My name is Kevin, I'm one of
and Brent is going to join
And what we want talk to you
which is how do I make one app
on all our devices right,
And so that's what we're
And I'm going to give away my
If there's one thing that
when it comes to adaptivity
of the work for you and so
I'm going to tell you what the
that would be nice to know.
But also how you guys as
and plug into that system.
But before I do I actually
to give this a little bit of
to tell you why this statement
So Apple had a pretty big mouth
on this last year we
I don't know about you,
like mind-boggling to me.
Now you make a fair point,
when it comes adaptivity
Fair, I'll give that to you.
But we know that it's
it's not all 1 billion
so that would be
Over the years Apple has
of various form factors
and shapes, I mean even colors.
And at Apple we also
of what device you have you can
that be in portrait
But beyond the physical devices
features like slide over and
as well that just increases
that your application can be in.
Don't forget things
where the user can
and all your applications
out right, you're
And then we also have features
like the language
to right or right to left.
We also have the display gamut
that we released this year.
And Apple TV we also
like the interface style
So kind of a conservative
of combinations that your
in iOS applications like
That's a lot.
So that's why this statement
for you is really good news.
Now the keyword here is most.
There are a lot of ways that
and customize this experience
because you want your
And that's what we want
So first we're going to talk
of adaptivity, which we
And then Brent's going to come
of how we've improved
with building adaptive
And that's what we're
which is today's session.
You're definitely going to want
because we're going to give
of all these additional
that you guys can use to make
And then we're going to put it
to give you guys some
and examples in code.
All right, so let's
about the fundamental
which is called the trait system
and there's three particular
to you guys about this.
The first thing is I'm
by telling you what it is, it's
And then we're going to laser
of the trait system, which
And I think it would be a
of give you guys a
about how the system works
because that will make it
to interact with it.
So what are traits?
Traits describe the environment
that your application
So here's an example of a
And this just describes what
for the available space of your
you have a little bit of
Now a trait by itself doesn't
with it and that's where trait
You can think of
as pretty much a
which are traits to values.
Most of the traits have
of possible values, so you know
about as you're building
Now trait collections don't
that would be awesome, usually
And even the three that you see
on the screen here is even
of the trait collections that
with and making your
Let me give you a
of what some of the traits are.
So we'll talk more
There's also dynamic type
There's also the
so left to right, right to left.
And the three up here are
Traits can also describe
So what gamut is the display
or for Apple TV what
is it light or dark.
But traits can also
So for example, whether
that you're using supports
If you want a full list
that you can make your
out UITraitCollection's
But now I want to
in on talking about
Your application can be in
This is humorously
of what some of those sizes are.
And when you look at this
of customization that
So first is the screen size,
and third would be something
this would be like which
So one way to do this without
to look for and respond
of these things, but
And so what will you do
on the available space for your
of those three axes
So what do I mean by
There's kind of two
to available space given
So there's coarse grain changes
from within iPhone to an
There's also fine grain
of like going from iPhone
And for each one of
or coarse you're going to
different technologies
Let's start by talking
I think we're pretty
it's of my favorite quotes.
We as engineers love to
to help us solve problems,
to make things easier,
So size classes is a
Now layers of indirection
of higher order behavior.
So what's the higher
that size class is describing
Let me give you two
So first will be the canonical
time right.
On iPad we have a master detail
where the information is
A change in the master
on the right-hand side.
However, on an iPhone where
that way that we present
We instead use a navigation
of a drill in way of
News would be another example.
On the iPad we have this awesome
on your couch and just be able
But on my iPhone
where I can just quickly
So experience comes down to how
and when you think about
in your applications think
the ways you're presenting
or not or how you're going
So let's get specific for a
of some higher-order things.
What specifically
And this is where we bring
So size classes is two traits,
and there's verticalSizeClass
and there's two possible
Compact just simply means
And so you're going to
in a more compact way.
Regular means that you're
and you should totally feel
up to the edges of your
Now this means that we
of traits and possible values.
Now I just want to point
of the notation that
because this is notation
in Interface Builder
and elsewhere in the system.
So this is describing a
and there's two things
First, it says there's a W
and then the value C or
And then H is for the height
that again, has either C or R.
So you're going to see
and you're going to see
and I just want you guys
So how do some of the devices
Well, a compact with experience,
of that is going to be
iPad in contrast is going
in both orientations
You're going to see
in landscape with the notable
which is actually regular
in landscape, which is why
in for example mail when
How does this actually
How does this make
Well, one obvious thing is
of 300 combinations you
but wait it gets better.
You really only have to
because the width class is
or trait that you're going
If we think about all the
the layout traits are the
of traits that you're
And within the layout traits
layout trait that you're
And then specifically within
by far the most common class
that you're going
Which means that as you're
and thinking about how you
between iPad and
about the differences
Now certainly guys you're going
to have custom applications
to do special things,
But certainly that's the most
about the width class.
Now the system gets to decide
and adaptations fit
And what's interesting
that these combinations can
as the users interacting
I can bring over slide over,
I can change the
And so if you're
and you're expressing your
the system can do a bunch of
through all these different
and adaptations past,
And that's really, really
to make it much easier
to make your applications
Let me give you two examples
of changes that can
So here again, we're going back
to our split view
And when I'm on an iPad
to have those two view
but when I go to an iPhone,
into a navigation controller.
If you're using UI Split
to get this behavior for free.
Now besides just view controller
to presentations.
So if I have an iPad and I
to be this callout style.
But if I move to an
to be a modal presentation
So again, if you're
and the kit presentations
to get a lot of behavior
The size classes
and your application is going
to automatically adapt,
So let me talk to you a second
I just want to say one
within the same size
to use Auto Layout to react to
Withy Auto Layout you can
in a very declarative form
and then the system will
and resize things for you as
at a more fine grain level.
Now there's one more type of
and I call that medium
I'm not going to tell you
to keep the suspense high
for part 2 and they're
about medium grain changes.
All right, so we've talked
we have given you kind of an
What I want to do now is just
about how the system
as developers you're
In a nutshell or in
the way the trait system works
and it propagates it
down through your view hierarchy
chance to react to
So it all starts at the screen
to have a trait collection.
What's important to note about
and orientation and
to have a fully specified
And what I mean by that is
that all the different traits
Then the screen is going to
that are on that screen and then
to its root view
then down to its
and subviews and so on.
Now each stop along the way
to UITraitEnvironment and the
method called
So at each stop along the way
as this trait collection
down it's going to call
This is where you as
and make your applications
So traitCollectionDidChange
And you're almost exclusively
at the view controller
Now that was a pretty simple
bit more complicated example?
So let's go to an iPad
We have our screen, just going
to the view split view
Now here is where we see a
and that's as the trait
down you can actually
as it gets propagated to
So the split view controller
So what it's going
to change the trait
to the master view controller.
It's going to change
to a compact size
to pass the regular
You guys can do this too
as you build your own custom
but most commonly you
Here's an example of what
look like.
I'm going to walk you
First, in order for the system
you want to make
Next, you want to only
that you're interested
Now I hear you questioning
traitCollectionDidChange
that traits are changing?
That is absolutely true.
Trait collection gets called
Typically, your application
in a few traits and most
size class.
And so you want to make sure
that you're not doing any extra
that you're interested
Next, I'm going to switch
for the horizontalSizeClass.
As just a side note here,
I really prefer using switch
with enumerations in both Swift
that if the definition
if a new case comes in I'm
if I'm using an exhaustive
So I would just really encourage
that's really saved
So then for example if
then I would go off
So for any view, for any
to be adaptive I would need
to override
So again, this is going
that conforms to
And this is where you're
Now it might seem like
to implement
for every single view
for all the possible
A lot of things can change.
So that's why there's a number
to traitCollectionDidChange
So for example, one system
If you're using Interface
and you're using
within Interface Builder
to automatically apply that as
Another example would
You can specify images
for different size classes,
and those will automatically
in traitCollectionDidChange.
And then finally, UIAppearance
for trait collection.
So you could for example set
for light and dark mode in Apple
automatically be applied
in traitCollectionDidChange
So you really want to take
that respond to this for
to be very declarative about
to react and to adapt.
And it makes it really easy
So just to recap
that we've seen so far.
Traits describe the environment
in and a trait collection is
with their associated values.
These could be layout traits,
they could be capabilities
You want to override
to make your application
and you want take advantage
to traitCollectionDidChange
The size classes describe the
how is your information
And then just to drive it home
to be able to do so
if you're taking
that we're giving you.
Now I could draw on
about how awesome aptivity is,
but really to see how
to see it in action.
And so I want to bring up
of the changes that we have
to improve our workflows
So the one and only Brent Shank.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Kevin.
So now that you understand
of adding adaptivity
So that's traits,
and size classes I'm going
and the Interface Builder editor
So let's go over to
It's a long way over here man.
Okay, so I thought
to build a really simple view to
of using the trait
to add a little bit
So here's what we're
This is simple, this describes
you should definitely put it
on your bucket list
in Yosemite to see one day.
So this view shows
and at the bottom is
And notice that on
of different changes,
that aren't present on iPhone.
You see at the top the label
and in fact, there's
that appears just on iPad.
So we're going to build
and you'll see how easy it is
So I've already created
over to this other tab where
So there are couple
at in the Interface
First off, is look how
It looks like an iPhone
because it actually is.
We're actually using
to render this content,
so you now get pixel
in the design canvas.
We think this is going to be a
as you try to take
from a designer and translate
The other thing to point out
The other big changes
in Interface Builder canvas
in the dimensions of actual
of their configurations
from previous versions of Xcode.
Let's take another look at
I'm going to zoom in
so you can see everything here.
So this is the bottom button bar
it's been around
Over on the right-hand side
for adding all the
I hope you're familiar
And in the middle are the new
And if you haven't yet installed
it's amazing to be able
at any magnification
So definitely check
[ Applause ]
But today I'm going to talk
So it says View As
in parenthesis it's got
if you can't read it back
So this is telling
of the current device
that I'm looking at.
It's an iPhone 6s in portrait,
which means that it's a compact
So it's a little bit of
and I'll show you how you can
So the scene is currently
in portrait what if I
Well, all you need to do
and it opens the new
This is brand new in Xcode
So I zoomed in here so you can
So there are a couple
and the leftmost stack
device sizes that
So we have the largest
and the smallest
And next to that is
that lets you select the
to view the scenes in.
So I'm going to do
I'm going to switch
So right in the design canvas
of these devices
and see how your content
and rendered, which
Thank you.
So iPhones are interesting
but iPads are even
I'm going to select
and you can see what happened
of icons that appeared and
So for iPhone there's
for each orientation,
For iPad it's more
your users can choose
in slide over or split view.
So that's what these
So if I select this one you can
as the app would if
in slide over on iPad.
So think about this right in
through all of these
all these orientations,
and see how your content
I mean, this is a really
it's going to save
[ Applause ]
Okay, so those are some
in Interface Builder in Xcode 8.
Now let's get down to the task
So here's what we're
We're going to add this label
in such a way that it applies
This is probably
of the time in Interface
You're usually not making
on size classes a lot.
So let's do this right now.
So I have the Device
and iPads selected there,
it doesn't really matter what's
to do is going to
So I found a label
in the Interface Builder
And now what I'm
to add some Auto
And as Kevin said, this is one
that actually makes
to all different
So I'm going to add
I'm going to pin this to
I'm going to center it
and I'm going to add a vertical
and the image view
And I've got some
and it looks like that's right.
And I had a constraint
and the top layout guide,
because I've added a label,
So how do I know that
and added the right constraints?
Well this is where the Device
in because it's really easy
to see what it looks
And you can see that it's
as I cycle through all
through different
So that's an operation
in Interface Builder
So now let's start
some customizations using
So what are we going to do now?
We're going to change the label,
the font of this
And you see my designer
to be System Semibold
So let's go back
So when you think about
for a device you
about adding a customization for
or in this case a size class.
So we're all given designs for
but as developers you need
that into size class that
We make that really
So for example, I have an iPad
and the size class and I'll zoom
it now says regular
Okay, so you don't need to guess
about what size class a
is you just select that
and Interface Builder
And that's another great
So now let's introduce,
let's vary how this label
So I'll select it in
over to the Attributes
which I actually have
And I'm going to
so you can get a closer
So you might see out there that
that is a big cursor, have
And so the + button means
that particular attribute can
collection system.
So let's do that right now.
I want to change the
And the menu comes up
to add a customization
for regular width
Well why is it doing that?
Well it's because I
regular height device
so that makes sense.
So we'll do that
that the Attributes Inspector
for font.
And again, it has
in the Attributes Inspector
Okay, so that's why
that what's here is you
Okay, so let's make the change,
I'll select Semibold and since I
me to do 36.
There we go and I'll click Done.
And you can see it rendered
If I select an iPhone what I
the font remains what
because I only targeted regular
for that particular edit.
Okay, so that's an example of
to add a customization
So that's the first
Let's add another one and this
and I want to do it
So I'll go back to the
to add this customization
for iPad I should select
And let me draw your attention
that says Vary for
So when you click this button
and ask you how we want
what kind of traits, the trait
So what does this mean?
Well I have a regular width,
regular height size class device
to customize for regular
if I hit click both
But I also can choose to
and any height or for any
So I think what I want is to
and when I do that the bar
to tell me that I'm going
to be making customizations
Let's take a closer look
I'll zoom in here.
So you can see it says I'm
devices, the device
I see iPads both in portrait
of the slide over configurations
But I also see an iPhone here,
Well if I put the mouse cursor
over this I see this is an
and as Kevin said,
so big it actually uses the
in landscape.
And this is great and you'll
and provide a different
in that configuration,
but in this case I
I only want to make the
So what do I do?
Well I can go back into
and this time I'm going to
and regular height and
that the iPhone disappears
So the edits I'm about
to these particular
So let's do that now.
I'm going to drag out a label,
and I'll add just a
to make sure it stays in the
Now I'll click Done Varying.
So let's go back to the
because I want to focus
that you've maybe seen before,
I want to make sure you
all about.
So I varied for traits, I
which means I configured the
for regular width,
And so when I did that
I added it to a view hierarchy,
for regular width
So that's what this
Most of the time
to your scene they'll be
so they'll appear on all device
of the size class.
But when I'm in this mode when
or when I add Auto Layout
installed only for the
that I'm targeting
So that's important
So again, to prove
through iPhones using the
and the label isn't there.
So I did the right thing I added
for regular width, regular
So the next thing we're
to make a more surgical
And as you can see when I cycle
through to an iPhone
between the top label here
Now in fact if I go back
to the design my designer
So how do I do that?
Well what's really cool is
that you can actually customize
constant using a variation
by targeting a size class.
So let's do that right now.
So you can see if I
remember I added this
between it and there we go.
Okay, so I've clicked
and I see this Auto Layout
of its attributes here.
You can see the constant
So this is the problem
Well I can actually edit
for iPhones for compact
with regular height
Again, I can click Vary for
and on height and you
of the bar show me iPhones.
But what are all these iPad
Well remember when your user
or split view there's
Your app will be
So you really want to
on iPad in that case.
So this actually makes sense
that you see here
with regular height
So this is good, this
Okay, so I've gone into Vary
and now I can select
There we go.
Now notice I'm going to
and I'm going to draw
to the Attributes Inspector.
So what happens when I
like what happened
for font Interface Builder added
And you can see this is
that I configured in the bar.
So I've changed this --
I've added a customization
by starting an editing
but I'm making the edit
So that's really cool.
And as I cycle through these
but it's still not
So how do I fix this?
Well you might think that I need
and try to make the
And that's not quite
So what's important
when you're varying for traits
based on size class.
But you don't use this
Instead, wouldn't it be nice
that customization in
So I have an iPhone selected
it also knows that I have
So now when I go to edit
out where I want the data to go.
So if I changed 45 to 30
in the Attributes Inspector
for the size class because it
based on that.
So we think this is a really
It lets you introduce
but then you can
in the design canvas directly.
And with that I want to
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Brent.
&gt;&gt; Thanks.
&gt;&gt; So I just wanted to
that Brent had talked
So first we introduced the
where you can see
and you can see your application
We also have a new workflow
between the different traits.
So you can do very surgical
Attitudes Inspector.
And the Attributes
where you can see all the
So if you're ever questioning
you can always go
to see what the customizations
But there's also this
where you can do kind of
style changes.
And as Brett mentioned,
to note this mode is important
for introducing new
Once you've exited this mode
know how to update
that you've made
that you're currently looking at
and it works really
Now these changes
but these workflow changes
as well in Interface Builder.
So just in summary
So I talked about
of the trait system.
We talked about how traits
how you're going to override
to do all your adaptivity
of the systems that
And that size classes
that describe the experience how
Brett gave you a demo of the
and how Interface
to both see your interface
in concrete devices while
to edit all the underlying
and the traits that you want
to make your application
So this was part 1 and again,
that the system is going to
There's lots of ways that
as developers take advantage
to see what you guys come up
Now come back tomorrow
to give you even more.
We're going to give you more
for making applications
to put it altogether
Besides the session tomorrow
on Auto Layout that you're going
of the improvements we've made
with some of those
And with that have a great
of your week and a great lunch.