[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
Welcome. My name is
I work on the Siri and Search at
by my colleague John
to show you what's
and how you can make
As you know, Spotlight has been
tool in recent releases of iOS.
In iOS 8 we introduced
through internet sources, like
And then in iOS 9 we
scope and introduced
currency conversions,
web, and much, much more.
Perhaps most importantly,
and powerful ways in which we
searchable through Spotlight.
So in iOS 10, today we
of these Search APIs that will
of your app's content.
We've also made Spotlight easier
So let me start by showing
that we've done to Spotlight.
Spotlight is now present
which makes it a lot
Let's look at an example here.
User receives a message
Very typical thing that happens.
And they want to run
Instead of having to quit
pull down Spotlight, they can
of messages, run their
It's super convenient.
We've also introduced Spotlight
to quickly preview
That's see what this looks like.
Suppose you're having an
on where Steph Curry was born.
You can go to the Lock screen,
run your search,
see the result, and now you can
and find the one you
which is Wikipedia in this case.
Really, really convenient.
And, of course, when you're in
that you present are public
Now, another neat
to Spotlight is query
in the quick type
when you type in the query.
Let's look at an example.
Here the user searches
based on past queries,
for banjo are banjo
So if the result that they
on the screen, they can pick one
This will make a lot
to execute in Spotlight.
Now, we've done many
We've improved spell correction
We've improved support
and Chinese scripts on device.
And we've made relevant,
And all these changes,
apply to content that's
So now let's turn our
Now, as many of you
we introduced three
There's CoreSpotlight,
to insert user specific or
on Spotlight's device index.
We also introduced
a searchable version of this,
to index everything that the
so that they can search for
And finally, we introduced
which is an index on the
that we have discovered
And we designed these
so whether the results
or the server, they
to provide a seamless experience
I'm happy to announce
in the App Store have
It's really incredible.
[ Applause ]
I think something really
who Search APIs have improved
that our customers are having
with your app and
I have some of my
that I'd like to show you.
This is actually
I'm planning a trip to
and I've been planning this trip
Now, various pieces
like hotel reservations and
on my device, and typically
to the app or the website,
or dig through the
But with Search APIs, this is
The apps that I've used to
have added salient
to Spotlight's index
So I can see my flight ticket, I
through Hotel Tonight,
and a couple dinner reservations
I can find more information
like what is my check-in time
or address of one of
And you'll also notice
that I have some results
I've been using the
to explore the things I
Now, Pinterest uses
to index everything that I have
and I can tap on one
And continue my exploration.
So this is a really
for doing travel search and
that I know exists on my device.
And what we've seen is, in
that your users want to get back
Another example I want to
Contacts is one of the most
in Spotlight.
Here I'm searching
I see his contacts, which
but I also see his Skype profile
that I'm having with him
and I can easily get back
And this is so powerful because
of centralized view of people
to have conversations with them
Now, what we have seen is
to Spotlight for all the things
that Spotlight supports
and if you have content in these
to broaden that search
as well as drive
Now, finally, let's
of Universal Links index.
wikiHow is a high quality how-to
of thousands of articles
Here I'm searching for a
how to perform CPR, and
of results from web, YouTube, as
Now, wikiHow uses
and they have a popular app.
So we have indexed their
and we present them for
It's pretty comprehensive
of these results, I go
illustrated article.
The index of wikiHow has really
to Spotlight, which is what
With that, let's start
in Search APIs in iOS 10.
The first feature we are adding
in App.
And for a lot of queries
at a larger result set, or
to add the right result to
So for now apps have an option
Out on the top right corner
of their section,
And tapping on this takes
with the search query.
So you can continue the search
It's super cool.
The second feature we are
Search API.
It's a slightly overloaded name,
that you're adding
to Spotlight's search
Wouldn't it be awesome if
to power search inside
I think it would be.
And this is exactly what
you to do.
The third feature we
to estimate popularity of
privacy, the technology that
We will discuss this more later
And finally, by popular
to our web markup preview tool
that lets you visually inspect
you put them in a
And in addition to these we
to Search APIs based
And now I will invite John to
and do deeper dives
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Let's start talking about
In the next half hour I'm
that you have to do for your
with Spotlight, some
to give users a great
that we've added to
to accomplish what you need.
So roughly in the order that
I'm going to talk about
into the index available
and keeping it up to date.
Presentation and
launching into your app,
or for search continuation,
about the new Search API
to give you an overview ranking.
So we have three technologies
that together cover
CoreSpotlight, for all that
NSUserActivity for app history.
And Universal Links
for public online content.
Of course, you can use
As an example, consider
It provides an interface to
There are hosts on the website,
The app may also have
and for that you would
Your users will want
that they've looked at,
so for the best experience
through NSUserActivity as well.
All right.
For those of you who
instead of conducting Search
about indexing content, and
CoreSpotlight is an API
It's on device and
So you can index the
Your app is in charge and
to add to the index.
You can index all that your app
and bookmarks, messages and
music, videos, game
in your app, and much more.
So there are two
First you need to add
To do this you create a
This contains the metadata and
Then you set at least
In this case we're
You create a searchable
You use the uniqueIdentifier,
to identify this item
and which is also used when we
And the domainIdentifier,
and shared property
which can later use
And then you ask CoreSpotlight
When your callback is called,
the item is then safely
or an error will be passed
For deleting content
You can delete a specific
For example, if the
You can also delete groups of
that I mentioned earlier.
This is great if the user
ends a subscription, or
Finally, you can delete all
This is useful if
like an incompatible
to clear the index and
And this is also
if your app gets uninstalled.
Now let's go over
and some more advanced
We'll cover registering
using CoreSpotlight client state
some performance considerations
and creating a CoreSpotlight
You want to register
because this lets
when your app is first
perhaps after restoring
when the user installs
for disaster recovery.
It also lets Spotlight
that you reindex
This is commonly because
and Spotlight wants to check
So to be an index
to implement the
protocol.
This has two required methods.
ReindexAllSearchableItems,
to add everything to the index.
If you track indexing
in your own database, you want
when this call is received,
unless you're using
as we'll discuss in a moment.
The second call is reindex
When this is called,
that Spotlight is requesting
or delete them as appropriate.
For both methods you call the
when you're completely done
for any work you
This ensures that we know that
and that we don't have to
If you don't call this,
and if you call it early,
you might not get a
For some applications we found
to use client state than to try
with your own database
The client state provides
of keeping your content
Because it's asynchronous you
consistency model, but you
with your own database
The client state is an
in the Spotlight index that
and then fetch back when
Typically, the easiest way to
in your own database, for
that you then as a client
After relaunch you would
and if it doesn't match
you would index any
with a sequence number higher
than the one you fetched
Another approach is to use
of knowing where to start
This can be really, really
up to date, asynchronously,
that you don't use
So to work with client
to create a named
The name lets us know what
You can only get the client
but you may have more than one
and then you would
for each of those databases.
With the index you
You'd add searchable
The completionHandler is not
because you'll get a completion
You compute your picked state
when you finish the batch.
And here you do need
to the completionHandler.
When your app next launches,
and you figure out what
to bring Spotlight in
Because the client state
into the index, it
You can replay exactly
to bring them both into sync.
So when your app next starts,
you create an index
you fetch the client state.
And this is an asynchronous
So in the callback you
and check whether the state you
If not, you call the method
Now let's talk about some
Spotlight is really, really fast
on your side to make sure
You want to optimize any
and pay careful attention
Do notice that each call to
so pass batches of items instead
And just making batches as small
as ten items will still
by an order of magnitude.
Since your app will be
user is using it, make sure that
And finally, to avoid
on a background thread.
All right.
Let us talk about
The extension can index
This lets you catch up after
or when your icons expire.
Spotlight can reach out to your
out to your application,
because your application
The interface to the
as for the index delegate.
So if you can factor your code
so that the index delegate
to implement the
To make content available
to your extension you
To find out more about this,
take a look at last
on App Extension Best Practices.
Next let's look at
As I mentioned, you can
to keep stale content from
CoreSpotlight will call your
and you can update
or update the data for
If you need to get new
you can use background fetch.
This will allow your app to
letting you take care of adding
Finally, if you have more of
or infrequent updates, you can
to let your server tell you
To find out more about
and silent remote notification
with Multitasking
That's it for indexing
Next let's talk about app
NSUserActivity was introduced
It lets you create
of your application's current
to another device,
in the Spotlight
You submit the activities as
for content that the
and want to get back to.
So the question you
about when the user activity
the user want to
If the same item might be
then the answer is
The 2014 session on Adopting
on how to use NSUserActivity.
To make NSUserActivity available
as searchable and add index
of the metadata using
You mark it as searchable
by setting the eligibleForSearch
You can also mark NSUserActivity
to make it a candidate
as Vipul will get
This done, it will show up as
and your application can
when the user selects
Your users just have to
from what they saw to be
to the content in
All right.
So, as I said, you can use
for the very same content.
The difference is
that NSUserActivity reflects
in your application.
CoreSpotlight is about
So if you use both, you
to the CSSearchableItem for the
and avoid duplication
This is done by setting the
in the AttributeSet to
of the CSSearchableItem that
This also ties the lifetime
to the CSSearchableItem,
against leaving data
after the user has
However, not all data is
For example, for the recipe
about earlier, you may want
to a possible CSSearchableItem,
something that the user might
If you were to use the
CoreSpotlight would immediately
as you try to add it because the
To solve this, we're
weakRelatedUniqueIdentifier
to the CSSearchableItem.
It can exist before the
when the CSSearchableItem
As for the
you simply have to set the
for the NSUserActivity.
Now, the downside is that when
the NSUserActivity remains.
So if you have concerns
of the searchable item
you do need to delete
Fortunately, in iOS 10
We're adding domainIdentifiers
It's part of the
and it allows you to
by the domainIdentifier,
just like you can
If you use both
and NSUserActivities,
to use the same
So that's indexing with
Next let's talk about
The content driving your
not locally inside the app.
If this content is public,
to make a searchable
for Spotlight via the
This is perfect for content
and available in your
when your content is too
Because your content has
results can be displayed to
which lets you reach new
Finally, these results can
and Safari, which makes
to even more users.
So to implement indexing
with Universal Links you
Allow Applebot to call your
and let Apple Note
Specify the call URL
when submitting the
For deep links we strongly
For this you need to
for the website and the app.
Implement the
in your app delegate to ensure
when the user selects
Markup your content with
to provide a rich display for
And use the Search
to test deep links, markup,
Take a look at the Introducing
and the Developer documentation
So these are the schemas
and we plan some
Pay attention to interaction
These are very useful for
Apple provides a test tool at
that you should consult
if you implement the
It now displays a visual
including supported
The information from the
visualize pieces of information
that the Applebot web
including the title,
Now you've seen how to index
and there's a good
to use them all together
So the most important
when using multiple APIs is
to link items representing
across the APIs.
By setting NSUserActivity's
to CoreSpotlight's
CoreSpotlight's content URL, and
to the URL of the webpage, you
in the index represent
which allows search
It also provides strength
All right.
Now we've covered three ways of
CoreSpotlight for content,
and Universal Links
for public content
Next let's talk about how
to present this information
To get a great presentation
to set a good thumbnail.
By default Spotlight
which makes it hard to
This doesn't matter much
to get a single result,
it makes a big difference.
Just as important
and perhaps more, is the title.
A good title is not
it's also what users most
After the thumbnail and
to set other fields that are
A description is great when
rating description, date
that are time bound, such as
reminders, events, and so forth.
For documents, general
and page count, are
If you set the right content
Spotlight can also do a
Let's look at some examples.
The Hotel Tonight app makes
showing an easily identifiable
and informative description.
You can get the same with web
og:title and og:description.
Open Table uses the title
with rating description
to let the user get
to choose the right result
In making the same attributes
you ensure that the user will
whether they're getting the
or from the local device index.
A great user experience is not
but also about what data you
Setting attributes that
and remember makes your
Conversely, setting misleading
or stuffing content and keywords
with dictionary words will
up frequently, but
which will annoy the user
and have a strong negative
Another aspect of a great user
to the salient part
in as few steps as possible.
Enabling quick actions,
has significant value
Finally, when a user
you want to launch directly
and without interstitials
or multistep builds
Let's look at some examples.
Redfin's app provides
and by setting the latitude
and enabling navigation, the app
to Maps to go look
Similarly, here is a great
You can get the same by setting
and support phone call
On seeing the result, a user
with the location
and reserve a table.
For web markup you can
by using the postal address
Next let's talk about
For both CoreSpotlight and app
to restore the state.
Your app delegate
with continueUserActivity.
You examine the NSUserActivity's
and the user info
If you're being launched
CSSearchableItem in Spotlight,
the activity type will be
and you retrieve the identifier
by using CSSearchable
The 2014 session Introducing
on how to launch
and activity type.
For Universal Links, once
So your app delegate
with continueUserActivity.
As usual, you examine the
which will be
You parse the URL
to the part indicated
That's launching.
Now let's look at a new feature.
In iOS 10 we've added a
to continue search
Conduct human results
to display will show an
for Spotlight Search
so the user can go
If you already support
It lets you leverage your
and has been widely adopted
It's another great way of
with your application.
The user is taken
into the search experience
Now
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
To support this in your
to add a key to your
that you support the feature.
Your app delegate will get
CSQueryContinuationActionType,
and the new query string will
and a CSSearchQueryString key.
At this point you can
with the same query string,
letting the user continue
To avoid confusion, it's
that your search results
with Spotlight.
Since Spotlight is based on
that you use similar
And if you can't support prefix
to a completion interface.
Another way of ensuring
to use CoreSpotlight's
which is the approach taken by
CoreSpotlight Search API
to implement search
It uses the data that you
for Spotlight Search.
It writes consistency
and is already used by many
including Mail, Messages
It avoids overhead
to maintain an additional
as it's the same index
The index provides full
If all your content
CoreSpotlight can be a
If you have a mixture of
you can combine queries
getting responsiveness from
and completeness from
Mail uses CoreSpotlight
but also to create
and to make complex queries.
This is a great way to
of CoreSpotlight Search
interface simple.
A CoreSpotlight Search
that you've given Spotlight,
from other applications.
The query engine is
so you get excellent
The query syntax allows
as well as range searches,
and a set of powerful
For those of you
with the metadata
this syntax will
Here's an overview of the most
As you can see, CoreSpotlight
of search comparators, as well
as the Boolean operators
In addition, CoreSpotlight lets
to suit your needs.
If you want case insensitive
If you want to ignore
if they are not important
in the current language,
And if you want to match on
of anchoring your searches at
you specify the w flag.
This, by the way, is
And if you want multiple words
then you pass the t flag and the
So let's look at an example.
We're implementing
that takes the user
We make sure to cancel any
so that we don't have multiple
as this will slow
Because we're dealing with
to escape the query string.
We use the double star syntax to
on either content or metadata.
The escape user input is
and we had the cdw
which creates a case
diacritics insensitive, word
With a query string we
We request the display
and this will be available
of the searchable
We set the foundItemsHandler,
of searchable items if there
And a completionHandler
either with an error or when the
In our completionHandler
to display finish any
And all that remains
CoreSpotlight will call
and then call the
So let's put this into practice.
We've built an application.
There is a simple
It already supports
and it already supports Search.
So the first thing we're
for Continue Search in App.
This is very simple.
We go to the app's info.plist
and we enable
That done, we go
and in our user activity
support for Continue
As you can see, the
CSQueryContinuationActionType
by inspecting the user info
We can then activate
with the search query.
So let's see what
All right.
Here we have our picture
down Spotlight and search for
to be popular in this gallery.
So we get two results and a
So click search in app and
[ Applause ]
Now you might observe that I
but only one result in my app,
and this is because I'm not
The search is a simple
So let's fix that.
In our view controller
I'm going to remove the
that we already had and start
First we want to add a variable.
A query object that will keep
We want to cancel the
escape the query
create a query object and, of
Oops.
All right.
So now we have a query string,
to set the foundItemsHandler.
The foundItemsHandler creates
to our list of results.
Now, since the query's
I need to implement an adapter
and creating something that
So let's look at what
So I have what I call
What this does is
that our query made
that whenever possible.
When that's not enough,
and gets the picture
stores that away for further
and that lets it return
that are not available
By doing this lazily we ensure
without having to go
which is great for performance.
Let's implement our
In the completionHandler
jump over to the main queue to
and then we call our
With that, all that remains
And let's see what
All right.
Now since this is using
and I've made the query very
to type any word that I see
and I find anything
in the metadata or
All right.
That is how easy it is
to implement search
And with that, I'd like
to talk about ranking.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, John.
That was a fantastic
As you are thinking about
in your app, it helps to know
and how you can positively
at ranking in Spotlight.
Now, Spotlight's goal's
to present the best results
and this order is determined
The two most important
and content popularity.
Let's talk about
Engagement ratio really is a
from your apps are being
when they are presented,
and Spotlight maintains
of these engagement ratios.
One is maintained on the
On the device the engagement
users' personalized
The server will maintain an
which is based on every query
for which your results have
and using this Spotlight can
for a particular query.
And then finally there's a
based on all interaction of all
with your app, and this is used
when there's no query level
A couple important
One, you don't get
for a particular query have
and they're sort of under
The best practice here really
descriptions that really
that you're indexing
to the same content.
The second important thing
In general, items
tend to be ranked higher.
And Spotlight can
of items in three ways.
If you use Universal Links, they
at the structure
out a reputation for your link.
You don't have to
All you have to do is
If an item has an
Spotlight can track how often
on the device and then
Now, if you use both
and public NSUserActivities,
for public indexing, iOS 10
entire iOS population has
and this is used in ranking.
And this is done for
of differential privacy.
Let me show you how that works.
So in this example Yelp has
that are eligible
as well as Universal Links.
When a user encounters
iOS computer hash adds some
and then sends this
And by itself this
It doesn't contain
But once thousands of users
Apple servers are
that have been viewed thousands
which users reported
So this really provides a
like aggregate behavior of
about individual
Once popular deep links
they start getting ranked
So this is very cool.
So let's have a quick look at
John showed many best practices
for indexing your app's
You should follow these because
search experience for your app's
to Spotlight to search
which will then impact
If you have app content,
by using Universal Links and
to users that don't yet have it.
So you know content
so link both Universal Links
and CoreSpotlight items
We introduced
year to help you do
And also, I'll repeat this
that the title, description
of items you're indexing
that that item would go to.
Pay attention to
We know that well-presented
engagement rates.
And finally, when appropriate,
as it allows the user
to complete a search
So in conclusion, key takeaways,
I think Spotlight is the new
and in iOS 10 we made it more
And users are increasingly
to be searchable via Spotlight.
So if you haven't adopted
that you consider doing so for
And if you've already
then we would recommend
that have been introduced today.
Some related sessions,
on Proactive Suggestions
of you should go to
in search applies
to Proactive Suggestions.
We also had a fantastic session
You can find this on
And we recommend the session
that covers differential
And like all other talks,
at the first URL, and we
documentation on
And that's all I have.
Enjoy the rest of the WWDC.
[ Applause ]