[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
Welcome to "iMessage Apps
My name's Alex and with me today
He's going to do the demos.
So, in the first part
and Lily introduced
and simple iMessage apps focused
on providing sticker
Today we're going to talk
and we're going to dive
and the Messages framework.
So, what are interactive
Well, you can see one
in the Messages transcript.
This is a special type of
by a Messages extension and
in the screenshot highlighted.
Messages extensions
to compose interactive messages
to insert them on the
They also allow a user to
by tapping one in the transcript
and in this point an extension
as shown here.
The user can interact with this
Your extension can then
into the messages and it will
and the user can send it.
So, now we're going to
and he's going to show
in the simulator.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; I'm going to show you a
that I've written to demo all
to learn in today's session.
If you look here in the
from my iMessage app
When I tap this, my iMessage
within the context of Messages.
All of the UI with this
is UI provided by my extension.
Now, my iMessage app is
sticker-building application
of ice cream stickers
When I tap this Add button here,
to take the full screen and I'll
experience here.
If I choose an ice cream cone,
and stages an interactive
in the input field
Now, on iOS 10, we've
for you to develop and test
within the simulator.
If you go back to the
you'll see two ends of a
Tapping the second one shows
When I tap this, my iMessage app
in the ice cream
I can select my favorite
stage that message, and send it.
Now, if I go back to that first
of the conversation
and select the final part of
and send it, I now have
that I've built.
In fact, now when I go
you'll see that it appears
as a sticker that I can then
And that's a quick
with interactive messages.
And now back to Alex.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Stephen.
That was just a great
of the features of
So, let's talk about how we can
I'm going to go through
One of them-- so I'm going
of the API followed by
into the extension lifecycle.
Number three, we're
to compose a message
Number four, we're going
about how the message is sent.
So, starting with
We have our iMessage
shown in compact presentation
Extensions have a
and for iMessage apps
of the
Now, ultimately,
the MSMessagesAppViewController
of UIViewController, so it's
Above the extension, we
and specifically the
This is represented in our API
And finally we have
We have this bubble
and this is represented
Also, you'll note in this slide
shown, the MSSession and
These provide some control
and how the message
So, let's move on and talk about
Here we have a timeline and
perhaps from the app drawer,
Shortly afterwards, we'll
with conversation and
in a conversation object
that represents the conversation
And since this is a
we'll also call will--
as your extension
Now, what happens
is removed from the screen?
We're going to call
and what happens is first you
viewDidDisappear calls
This is followed by
this is followed
by a willResignActive
At this point, we're about
between Messages
So, this is the last time
with the conversation.
And then at some point later
and this-- just to stress-- is
on extensions and extensions
and they're terminated
So, let's see now that we have
within Messages, your user is
and build a message and
to deal with that in our API.
Well, the first thing
to do is create an MSMessage
to set some properties
In this case, I'm
so the message is URL property
about the ice cream
in the query string of that URL.
The only platform that is
these messages is iOS, but
to macOS and to watchOS.
When they're delivered on
in full fidelity in the
and clicking on a message
and get this URL and open
So, if you provide an https URL
to show-- should be able
of the message for
Moving on, we have an
property here.
This is used by screen readers
So, I'm setting this
of the message bubble
who use screen readers get
of the bubble as it is
And finally I'm going to talk
And I'm going to talk about this
The layout object is how
of a message in the transcript.
Right now we only
and that's the
We can set some properties
and this affects how
So, right here we
and this takes a UI image
for the area highlighted
We also have a mediaFileURL
The mediaFileURL also provides
as the image, but here you
supported by UI image.
For instance, you could provide
A short video would be then
of the message bubble
Let's take a second to
on these two properties.
We should note first
and the URL are both provided,
to take precedence over the URL.
We had some recommended--
of the assets provided
We're recommending that
at roughly 300 point
You can provide slightly
and slightly smaller assets
to experiment with asset
to find what best suits
All of these assets, as with
and Messages will downsample
when they arrive on other
for the screen resolution on
In the mediaFileURL, we support
When I say video,
that we support any
with our media player frameworks
to the media player
to find out more about this.
The other thing that
with this media is we're going
to transcode the assets
This is in order
for transfer over our networks.
And finally I'd like
to avoid rendering
As I said, these images
on devices with 1x and 2x
to provide them at 3x.
If you were to render
particularly small text, when
the text could be rendered
that we actually do show in this
of the image, so let's
without degrading quality.
The layout has some additional
the two that provide images--
They're transformatted with
on the receiving devices
on the receiving devices as
We have here shown
and this is text that's
in the lower left hand corner.
We have an image subtitle that's
right below the image
And we have these
and these are drawn below
That's this gray area onscreen.
So, we have caption,
and trailing subcaption.
Now, if you look at the caption
to omit these altogether
If you do that, then
that doesn't have the
and it'll look something
And one last thing to
We have an icon in the top
This icon is provided and
of your content and
to be the iMessage app icon of
So, let's move on now and talk
that we've constructed.
To do that, we're going to need
to get an MSConversation
You can get this from
active conversation.
Once you have a conversation,
you can call the
pass the message you
that you handle any
Doing this will cause
to appear in the input field.
Of course, as mentioned
you can also send some
We support sending
and of course stickers.
Once you've got your
the user is able
by tapping the blue Send
that there's no way
to actually automatically
and we always want the
as to what gets sent
So, now I'd like to hand
who is going to show you
in our sample project.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks again, Alex.
OK. I've taken the
that I showed earlier in
down to a very basic minimum
Here we still have our
that have already been
that if I tap the Add
Here in Xcode, I have my
subclass shown.
I override the lifecycle
with conversation, call super,
and then call present
which is a helper
which will instantiate an
and add it as a child
And that's all I have so far.
Now, what I'd like to do is
when I tap this Add
sticker-building process.
Now, this ice cream history
protocol and I have an extension
which conforms to this delegate
by implementing the method
AddButtonTapped.
This is where I'm going to
and I'm going to also start
by adding a helper method called
which will take an ice cream
into an MSMessage for me to
To do so, I'm going to create
and set the query items
to be a query items
Next thing I'm going to
of MSMessageTemplateLayout and
to be a rendered
I also want to set a
and I'll declare
Now I'm ready to create
I'll do so by declaring
and set the URL property
to be the URL representation
Then I'll set the layout
For brevity in the
to reuse my message caption
Now that I have my message,
I'm ready to stage it
I'll get a reference to
and call conversation.insert
to insert the message
Now that I've written my
here I'm ready to call it
from my historyViewController
And I'll start off
or passing a new ice
Now when I run this
and launch my iMessage
wait for that debugger to attach
My message is staged
Now, because I haven't actually
I just have a placeholder
and you see my caption
Now, this is a great start,
to that final demo that
When I tap that Plus
into my sticker-building
To do so, I need to introduce
Here my iMessage
in a compact presentation style.
I can choose to have my
in an expanded presentation
Instead of calling
for iceCream here, I'll call
request presentation style
This will trigger a lifecycle
willTransition to
I'll call the super
and then I'll call
to present the right
for this presentation style.
Now,
my presentChildViewController
cream history view
to change the logic to take into
so I present the
First, I'm going to add a
which presentation
Then I'm going to change this
to only present my history
in the compact presentation
If I'm in the expanded
to declare a new instance
and let my controller
of an ice cream builder
to which I'll pass
Now, lastly, before I add this
I need to remove any previous
to clean up my view hierarchy.
Now I need to update the call
Here I'm going to add that--
pass that pending presentation
with conversation method,
I'm going to pass the
which I can get as a property
Should be right.
Lastly-- actually, let's see--
let's see what this looks like
And I tap that Plus (+) button.
My iMessage application
and I'm presenting that ice
However, you'll notice that
happens yet.
Now, this is because my ice
also has a delegate protocol
on my view controller here--
so fast-- that implements
by implementing the method
didSelect iceCreamPart
This is called whenever that
So, this is the right
that helper method I wrote,
in the updated ice cream
The other thing I'm going
because my iMessage app is done
like my iMessage app to dismiss
and display the staged
Now when we launch this,
and select an ice cream cone.
I dismiss my iMessage app
and the correct interactive
for the user to send.
And that's a quick
like to send an interactive
Now back to Alex.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Stephen.
Great demo.
So, Stephen has introduced
to use our APIs to
into the conversation
Stephen also introduced
so we're going to
at that in some more detail.
We have two presentation
Compact one is shown here
So, there's a couple
between these two
In compact mode, you don't
You also don't have access
swipe gesture recognizes.
This is because in the compact
and right to switch between
However, you do have
so whenever insert
in compact presentation style,
the message will
into the input fields right away
and the user can
Subsequent calls to insert
message to be replaced
so what you can do
to iteratively build a
on the input field,
with it they can send it.
To contrast, in expanded
don't have access to
but we do have access
to horizontal swipe gesture
and you can use the keyboard.
The user can always
between these two styles by
from expanded to collapse to
and when in compact they can
of the screen to expand your app
into expanded presentation
So, when you're using
you need to be very
in which your app is displayed.
Whenever these transitions
to get some callbacks
The willTransition to
as the transition
when the transition is complete
presentationStyle).
As Stephen showed, you can
expanded or compact by calling
method on your principal class.
And again, as was shown in
and this will dismiss
and show the keyboard.
So, let's move on and talk
We have two cases here to cover.
One case when your extension is
in the transcript that the
to look at that first.
We'll come back to
So, looking at our
this should be very familiar.
The bubble is tapped by the user
and your process
And now we go through exactly
when your app is launched
You'll get a didBecomeActive
by the viewWillAppear
When this is done, you'll--
your app will be presented in
We always present apps in
when the user taps a button
taps a bubble in the
Now, looking at our second case,
In this case it's showing UI in
So, looking again at our
the bubble is tapped
So, we're not going to
or didBecomeActive.
Instead, you'll receive
to presentationStyle expanded.
This is followed by a didSelect
This is called on your principal
that the user tapped on a
and selected a message.
Then finally as the transition
to expanded presentation
didTransition to
So, now at the end of
your app is presenting the UI in
and you'll want to get that
so this is done using the
property and you can get this
from the current
on your principal class.
You're going to want to show
and allow the user to
Now I'd like you to hand
for one final demo
to implement reply
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; OK, so we left off
with a staged message
which I'll go ahead and send.
And now if I go back to the
to the other end of
that received message.
When I tap that message,
my iMessage app is
my ice cream building experience
in the ice cream
I'm not ready to select ice
because every time
that I currently present
I'm always passing in a
What I need to do is look
on the conversation and use
from that selected
So, I'll go back up here
that ice cream builder
to my active conversation
initializer here that looks at
and if that initializer
that I don't have anything in
that new ice cream model, but
in the in progress ice cream.
The other thing I want
that I am passing the
on the ice cream part
To do so, I'm going to need
into this method, which is
Now, this message caption here
of the string type and
on the selectedIceCreamPart
to choose a correct
Oh, and I also need to update
to pass in that new parameter.
Now when I launch my iMessage
send that first message and then
and to the other end
and now I'll tap the received
that my ice cream builder view
up to pick an ice cream scoop.
Now I can select some
go back to the other end
of the conversation once
So, now you can see
like to send interactive
and accomplish a
However, you'll see that
my partially built ice
to pollute my conversation
I don't really need to see the
I only really care about
What I'd like to do is
and maybe leave behind
of those messages.
To do so, I'm going to make use
to group messages together.
Here when I'm composing
I'm going to move my reference
to my active conversation
when I declare my session
if I have a session already on
that if it exists so that it
Otherwise, I'll create
I'll then pass that session here
into my initializer
Now, the other thing I want to
of messages when
Here I'm going to
or declare a variable
and here I'll choose the right
ice cream part that was chosen.
Now I could take that
on my MSMessage object.
And that's it.
Oh, maybe I should
There we go.
Now when I launch my iMessage
of building an ice cream--
doesn't ice cream
I can pick my flavor of
that that summary text has
for me there when
Now if I go-- sorry-- I'm going
of the conversation, tap
I think chocolate sounds like
Now when I send that I have a
but I'm only showing the one--
the one image here and I have a
transcript there.
Also, when I go into
you'll see my newly completed
to use however I'd like.
And that's it.
We have a completed
Now, this was an example of how
to build an interactive
but you could take
You can build-- you
with wonderful services
and build nice awesome
and I can't wait to
Now, back to Alex.
[ Applause ]
Thanks, Stephen.
That was another awesome demo
and Stephen implemented
and also introduced
So, let's dive into
What we saw in the demo was a
of half-completed ice creams
to take that and turn it into
like this, which is a lot
It's great.
So, to implement this, we
We created an MSSession and
that was part of the session,
into its initializer and we
We can set some summary text
and then we send it using the
as we've seen before.
When we're replying to a
to create a new session; we
and we can get the
from the current conversation
so the activeConversation
The selected message will
if it's a session message.
Then we take that session, we
the messages initializer,
We see here the summaryText
for the message summary in
You can now also omit this
and if you do that then there
in the transcript, but your
in the session behavior.
So, now we've covered the basics
to build a very simple
that sends interactive
We're going to move
of the more advanced
We'll start by looking at
on your principal class.
We'll move on and talk
and finally we'll discuss
of a particular message.
First, when the user
we realize that your app may wan
For instance, if you're a game
we need to know when to update
and that should really
when the message
So, we have a
on the principal class
when the user taps
Now, this is important.
That message-- that
that the message has actually
All it means is the user
and it communicates the
We also have, similarly,
This happens when the
in the top right hand corner of
didCancelSending is your
up any resources that have
composition of that message.
And lastly we have
didRecieveMessage happens-- is
or active and a message has come
one of the participants
And it's a-- this is useful,
if your user is editing
and another message comes
it's an updated state and
that represents this state.
So, let's move on and talk
iMessage apps are going to be
so you're going to
that when you're building them.
We have here an example
between three friends:
Ben's getting ice cream
out a question to
Which topping do you-- would
Chocolate sauce or sprinkles?
Amber is going to reply
and Chris here is going
Both users send these messages
Let's focus a little bit now
on his device as
First, Amber's reply is going
and this is followed
by the reply from Chris.
So, you note Amber's reply was
and Chris's reply is shown
as the last bubble
This could just as easily have
and we should note that only
to your iMessage app, so
to Amber's reply in our example.
How do we deal with this?
Well, right now we're
that you store state in
that the URL property of the
and from the participants in
only needs to take a token
and then you receive the
when the user taps on a message.
And when a user sends a message,
you should push the
of the session up to the cloud.
Moving on, we're going to
Here we have a conversation
between Amber, Ben,
In this scenario,
with a preference
Chris has not yet replied.
Focusing again on Ben's
and we don't know who to
out some information about that.
Now, what we have here are some
sorry, let me rephrase that.
What we have here are some
Apple is very, very
and we really very highly value
so we don't expose
at all to iMessage apps.
Instead, we provide these
On Ben's device, he has a
and this is a UUID that
He also has two remote
These represent the
in the conversation.
In this case, we have two.
We have Amber and we have Chris.
Looking at the incoming message,
we see that the message
and this will map to one
of the local participant
Moving back to the big
and Chris's device, the sending
and these map to the local
that sent that message.
You can use these identifiers
of participants in
You can attribute
so once you've received
with a particular
and you receive a second
you know they've come
They can also be used in
They can be used to
And one more thing.
You can use these identifiers
of these identifiers prefixed
of the text passed
to the MessageTemplateLayout's
You can also use-- similarly,
in the text passed to the
When Messages displays the UI
of formatting in their text,
with the contact
that their identifier maps to.
These identifiers are
If you noticed on the
for every person the
And they're scoped to the
and what I mean by this is
that the identifiers themselves
but if the user removes
and then later reinstalls it,
you'll get a completely
within the same conversation.
You can get the sender
from an MSMessage using the
property and you can get the
conversation using the
property.
And you can get the list of
from the
property.
So, that wraps our more
We're going to talk a little bit
Interactive messages will be
watchOS 3, macOS
Of these platforms, only iOS 10
On macOS Sierra, the user
in the conversation
to the Messages URL property
That will only be if it's
On watch, you can hand off
where you're able
We also support some
These messages will be
iOS 9, and OS 10.11,
in a fallback format.
There's two separate messages.
The first one will be
in the template layout.
The second one will be a URL
Now, again note if this is
If it's a data URL, we won't.
So, we only-- we'll only
in the fallback message.
So, that wraps up our talk.
In summary, we have-- this week,
we've introduced the Messages
In the first part of this talk,
to sticker packs
to create simple iMessage apps
Today, we've created
that send interactive
about how they work
and a few other things.
Now I'm really excited to
and make with this API.
I can't wait to see what you
[ Applause ]
For more information, you can
on developer.apple.com.
We have a related session.
If you haven't already seen
Part 1", then please go
And that wraps up our talk.
Thanks to Stephen
Thanks to you guys for coming.
[ Applause ]