[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
My name is Vineet Khosla.
And today, I'll be joined by
as we walk through the process
of extending your
In the introduction session,
we learned there are
to a SiriKit-enabled app.
You have the Intents extension.
You have the Intents
And you have, of
With the Intents extension,
You have the Resolve,
In this session, we are going
We're going to talk about how
to prepare your application
And then we will talk about how
to add your first
and finally we will talk about
user interface and style
by writing your Intents
For this session, we are going
to use our favorite chat
Some of you guys
It's a favorite app that is
to chat with our unicorns.
It's a standard messaging app
of messages, but it
of unique corniness, which
And we will add SiriKit
So, SiriKit is built
But before your application
there are number of
to help it adopt SiriKit.
I'm going to cover a few
We will talk about preparing
of your code to embedded
Embedded frameworks are
between your application
Having moved some of the code
to embedded frameworks
with a great opportunity to
And finally we will
about what is an
for architecting
on the intents your
So let's dig a little bit
Your extensions will need
to do everything your
It will need to handle the
to render UI when
And using embedded frameworks
between your application,
because you want to ensure
that your users get a uniform
in from your application
or whether they are
In the case of UnicornChat, we
that made a lot of sense to
We took a look at our
This is everything that
and receiving of messages.
And we realized that this is
to move entirely to embedded
by my application as
Having done that, we took
Your application as well as your
the same data model.
In the case of our chat app
as well as the data accessor
that could be moved to
so it could be reused by
After moving that,
at our decision-making logic.
This is the business
In the earlier sessions
that we have the Resolved,
These three methods
to the real business
And you would always want to
as well as your Intents
gives your users the same
to complete that one
of where they come from.
So we moved our decision-making
to an embedded framework.
And finally, if your application
that requires it to rend
into the SiriKit, that
into an embedded framework.
So you can reuse,
provide consistent experience
Whether they come in
or whether they are coming
I also recommend everyone
App Extension Best Practices.
I watched it.
I found it really useful.
So after having moved all of our
or some of it, it provided
to write some quality
Now I know I'm preaching
And all the engineers
we write our unit
We all follow test-driven
It happens every
But having moved
to an embedded framework
with a new opportunity to
More specifically when we
What you can do is
and then write tests to
as well as your extension,
You don't need a real
You can just mock
that you expect to
And you can write
Finally, let's think a little
for the appropriate
Typically an app will sign
It will want to do
In our case, our UnicornChat
with SendMessageIntent, but
to its capability, and
and video calls with it.
At this point the question
our extensions?
Should we put intent handling
of all these intents
But that might make our code
We could do an alternate
where you can say
to start putting all
in a separate extension
That is great, but you
of boilerplate code and also
than is necessary and creating
not needed.
So, in the case of UnicornChat
and I'm sure this is what
is think about which intents
In our case, we found
and the video call intent could
because doing so let us maximize
of messages intent could live in
In other words, there is
You know your application best.
You will know which intents your
And you will need to choose
that you have a manageable
you don't create too many
memory pressure.
And having taken care
your application is now
And to help us write our
I invite Diana onstage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Vineet.
Hello, everyone.
My name is Diana Huang, and I'm
about how to create your first
with Siri, now that your app is
I will also show it to you
in Xcode using the
So to get started,
that you want to follow.
First, you want to add an
to your app.
And next up, you want
to configure the
And lastly you need to look
at the principal class
Let's talk a little bit more
To add an Intents
you will go to Xcode,
And then pick Intents
For those of you who have
it's just like how you create
And then, let's take a look
at the Info.plist
So we have the existing key of
we have NSExtensionAttributes.
And in side that dictionary,
we're introducing two
The IntentsSupported and
So IntentsSupported is
to specify your extension's
In other words, you want to put
that you want to
into this array, for
IntentsRestricted WhileLocked
to specify your locked
So by default, Siri already
to not be easily invoked
For example, the payments domain
But if your app has a tighter
then you can put the intent
into this array, for
And this is to tell
to unlock the device before
to handle the intent.
So now our Info.plist for the
Let's now talk about
So the principal class of your
subclass of INExtension,
to the INIntentHandlerProviding
This protocol has one and only
So the method name is
You're given an Intent
to return a Handler Object.
And do note the Handler Object
to the specific intent
So for UnicornChat, we're going
So whenever we're passing an
we will return a
to INSendMessageIntent
So now we have covered
Now let's actually go follow
So here we have the
and in the interest of time,
I have already created
So let's go take a look
which is to configure
So first thing, let's
in a little bit to see better.
All right.
So here we have the
If we expand it, you can see
dictionary.
And if we further
you will see the two new
IntentsSupported and
First, in order to support
let's add an item inside
And we will put in
which is INSendMessageIntent
And next, let's take a look
So because UnicornChat is
for private communications
like to enjoy some privacy,
that users will have to unlock
can send a UnicornChat
So to do that, we will add an
WhileLocked array.
And again, put in the
INSendMessageIntent here.
And now we're done configuring
So the third step is
at the extensions
So when you create the
a principal class will be
Here, I have renamed
to UCIntentHandler.
It is a subclass of INExtension.
And we also have the handler
So you can see that the default
which is returning an instance
But just to make our
and make it more extensible.
If we're going to support more
then we're going to create a
So we're going to do that by
UCSentMessage IntentHandler.
And we will also import a few
in the class declaration.
So here we are importing
which hosts a lot
We're also importing the
which is the embedded
through to share code
and the extensions.
And here we have the
class that conforms
to INSentMessage
All right.
Now let's go back to
and replace the implementation
of UCSentMessage IntentHandler
that is, of type
And for all the other intents,
And that's it.
The three steps that
and configure your
Now let's talk about
So hopefully from the
as well as Vineet
your Intents extension's
with Siri can be divided
Resolve, Confirm and Handle.
Let's talk about Resolve first.
So Resolve is the stage
and clarify the intent
So we have provided for
we have provided
in the intent handling protocol.
So you may ask which ones of
Well, think about this.
Would you need Siri's help in
on the final value of
If the answer is yes,
to implement the Resolve
Let's take a look at this in
So to send a message,
And in order to decide on the
we need to perform a contact
address book records.
There could be a few potential
In the most simple and
we will find exactly
Then we're good to go.
However, it's also
or more matching contacts.
In that case, it
if Siri can help ask
from the candidate list.
It's also possible that we find
And in that case, we would also
so that the user may pick a
So after having a recipient,
So in this case, we simply need
If the user simply hasn't
really like Siri to help us
So considering all these
like we should implement Resolve
and content, as we
to take further user
up with the final values
So now the parameters have
we get to the Confirm stage.
So this is the stage where
Think of it as if you were to
Do you have everything
Or are you able to
So you want to tell that answer,
along with some extra
that you can gather while
So that then Siri,
can communicate all this
And finally user can make the
to proceed with the
So in UnicornChat, because
that we have, we need users
to reauthenticate themself
So Confirm is the
to check the authentication
And either way, we want to tell
to Siri so that either
to proceed inside Siri
to the application in order
All right.
So now the intent is also
to the stage of handling it.
Hopefully this is the
for you to understand.
You simply need to
and tell Siri how it went.
So in the case of UnicornChat,
and then report back
if the message has
So now we have covered
and Handle methods and concepts.
Let's actually go
So this time we're
into the IntentHandler class.
So before I start,
All these simple code will be
through some of the details,
as important for you to read
through every single
But if you're interested,
and check out the simple
All right.
So as we have mentioned, we're
Confirm and Handle methods.
For Resolve, we are going to
for recipients and content.
So let's start with
So in this method
on the recipients
by an array of INPerson.
You can also tell from the
to callback with the array
So there is a one-to-one
between the recipients array and
meaning that for each
to create a
The only exceptions
to create
or ResolutionResultNotRequired.
Where these two types of
for a parameter level resolution
versus the other
targeting towards the
So the first thing we want
is to try unwrapping
And then we're going to loop
and then call our API
to find the matching
And next, we're going
on the matching contacts count.
And as earlier, we're going
to cover the different
The case where we have two
The case where we have
And the case where we
So in the case where we find
we're going to create
Result.disambiguation with the
In the case where we find
we're good to go.
So we're going to
by creating a
with that one person
And in the case where we
we're going to create
Result.unsupported.
So that is the end of
You might have noticed
through the code pretty fast, so
through every single
That's perfectly fine because
to know that we do have
that are appropriate to
So when it's time for you
for your result methods,
out the documentation
of resolutionResults.
And then and also
All right.
So now we have all
that we have created
Let's call the completion with
And that marks the last line
to get some recipients
But in the case where the
recipient, then we're going
to create a PersonResolution
and call completion with that
to tell Siri please prompt
And that's it for our
So next, we're going to cover
where we are simply going
And if there isn't,
to kindly help us
So the first thing we
is again try unwrapping the
if it's truly not empty.
If a content is indeed given,
we're going to create
with the given content.
Otherwise, we're going to create
just like we did in the
And then call completion
So now we have gone through
Next up is the Confirm
to check the authentication
So in the Confirm method, we're
in the UnicornCore
if the user still has a
If he or she does,
to create an
with the code success
I will talk about the
But now let's move onto the case
where the user is no
Well, in this case, we're going
with a code
So this is to tell Siri,
for users to maybe proceed to
to log in and finish
All right.
So that's it for
Lastly we're going to implement
So in Handle, we're simply going
to call the shared API
to send the message with the
We're also going to get the
So if the message is
we're going to create
with the code success.
Otherwise, we're going
with the code failure.
And then we're going
with the IntentResponse.
So we have just gone
and Handle methods together.
Now, as promised
about the NSUserActivity
that those IntentResponse
So let's step out of
So NSUserActivity.
In the context of SiriKit,
to help your application
when it gets launched by
By default, Siri creates
if you decide to pass in nil
into the IntentResponse
And Siri will create it with the
class name.
You can also choose to
if you want to pass
But either way, Siri will help
property on the NSUserActivity
This property is newly
And this object has all of
as well as the intent
And Scott will talk a little bit
So now let's take
of NSUserActivity
So if you have paid close
you might have noticed
and Handle methods we
for the userActivity into our
This is perfectly fine,
if our main application will
that Siri creates for
of the INInteraction object.
But in some cases,
to give our application
from the extension process.
So, for example, in the
out the user is no longer
Then we do want to
to our main application.
We're going to do that by
and populate the
with the custom error
to our main application.
And then we're going to replace
that we have just created.
All right.
Great. So now my UnicornChat
these custom error strings and
if the user or Siri chooses to
So now we have finished all the
Let's actually go see
Send a message to Scott using
for your presentation?
Yes.
[ Applause ]
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah. It's very exciting.
We've just sent our
through Siri.
That's absolutely awesome.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
However, inside the
when I sent messages
I actually often refer to
So really I want to say
to Sparkle Sparkly saying
Where Sparkle Sparkly is
So in order to do that, let's
which is user-specific
All right.
User-specific vocabulary.
So these are custom words or
to your application and that
In the example that I just
as other unicorn names can
vocabulary here.
So in order to help Siri to
when they speak about
you need to provide
And you will do so by
from your main app.
Let me repeat this.
You need to call
from your main application,
All right.
Let's take a look at how
So in UnicornChat, we have
which manages UnicornChat's
And we have created this method
to update Siri's knowledge
And it will be called whenever
deleted or updated.
The first thing we want
to get a sorted list
And we put the more important
and leave the less
of the array.
So we prioritize like
to better prioritize
for these Unicorn names.
After gathering this sorted
we're going to provide them
by calling the INVocabulary
We will also give it
of these strings.
In this case, the Unicorn
One last thing that I
to about this block of code
to send all these operations
This is because operations
of contacts can be quite
to block your main
So please do take
and dispatch those
into a different view.
All right.
So now after adopting the user
I can now send messages to
Buttercup and all
That's absolutely great.
So now I have yet
Inside UnicornChat application,
of the application is actually
than what you see here in Siri.
So can I make my UnicornChat
as colorful as that in the main
To tell you all about it, I'm
Scott a.k.a. Sparkle
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
I'm Scott Andrus and I'm
And now we're going to talk
like an interaction
And to do that we're going
to build a UI extension
In iOS 10, we've introduced
which can allow you to create
that provide custom
within the Siri experience.
And so, let's get started.
The reason why you
because UI extensions increase
on the user.
By importing a UI extension,
you're showing your view
And then you can show custom
to your application alongside
This gives you a lot of great
with your app that are
out from the rest of the pack.
You can also offer
So you can engage with
And finally you can
that Siri might not
which is a really great tool
And this is what it looks like.
So to get started all you need
to do is add an Intents
Add that to your project.
And embed it inside of
And you'll see the
that Xcode generates for you.
And inside, you're
for the new IntentsSupported
to the one you've seen
And inside, you'll register
like to show custom
for in the Siri experience.
The anatomy of the UI extension
in SiriKit is actually
SiriKit calls into your UI
with interaction method,
in SiriKit UI extensions.
Your UI extension has
which is the UIViewController
to the INUIHostedViewControlling
And it will be passing
to your UI extension for
Now, as Diana mentioned,
the INInteraction
that encapsulates three
The first is the Intent
or handled by your
Next, the Intent response
from your Intents extension
of the Confirm and
And finally, there's an intent
value that describes the
between your application
As these are all really
as you build your user
Your view controller is the
as the principal class
to start building your
Because it's a subclass
you've got access to all the
may be used to when
for Cocoa Touch applications.
And you'll configure it
that Siri sends you
with interaction method.
There are a couple of other
to take note of in this method.
One of which is provided
And in an iOS 10, this
which is one of two values.
Siri snippet or maps card.
And so you can configure
for these different kinds
of modal interactions
And this can be really
if you're making a
Finally. You'll have a
to let Siri know that you've
of your user interface and
which tells Siri how to size
So now I think we know
to get started with a demo
of building a SiriKit UI
Okay. So we're back in the great
up for us, with our Siri
to plug our app into
And we're going to
within Intents UI extension.
Now when Diana created her Siri
to create an Intents UI
An Xcode created this
in our project navigator
So we open that up.
We can see a few great files
with our Intents UI extension.
The first is the
which is the principal
And then we also have a
and then an Info.plist, and
to register for our
So inside we've got a great
the NSExtension dictionary.
I'm going to go ahead
Now what we'd like to do
with our Intents UI extension is
of Siri during Siri results
for sending a message
And when we show this
to be a chat transcript
that really displays the
So inside I'm going
for the INSendMessageIntent,
in fact show a user interface
when Siri handles this
Great. And we're all
so we can start implementing
So I'll zoom back out here.
And here we've got our
Now you notice this is
of UIViewController conforming
to the INUIHostedViewControlling
As part of that conformance,
with interaction method which
Now the very first thing
to import the UnicornCore
as a module into my Swift file.
Now again, this UnicornCore
that we implemented for our
of our Unicorn apps, like
It's a great way to share
and for all of our extensions.
We made great use of it in
to share our business
and Handle in our extension.
And now we're going to use
for our UI extension
so we can have the
of sending a UnicornChat
So let's start implementing
with interaction method.
So inside I'm going to go ahead
which I'm going to send back
to Siri once I've
And now I'm going to check
if my interaction.representsSend
This is a convenience that I've
on INInteraction in my
Then I'll instantiate a
And this is what we use
to represent a message
and we're using both
And we'll use it here in
And we'll start configuring
with .messageContent from
which I'm again using
to get from the interaction.
I'm creating a UC contact
on the interaction's properties,
that model object to
to show the recipient
And then finally
on the intentHandlingStatus
And we can use this to configure
based on whether or not
And so in this case, if the
the intentHandlingStatus
inProgress or ready.
I can set the isSent property of
indicating that I should
and show that to the user.
Otherwise, if it's done, I
of my chatViewController
indicating that I've
and letting the user
Finally I can present the
of this principal class
which is a really useful way
to implement different view
of intents in my UI extension.
Finally I can use the
of my Intents UI extension in
And I'll use this by default
If for some reason I couldn't
I'll make use of the desired
which is good enough for me.
Now that was the happy path.
Let's say that something went
that we didn't expect.
We can set a size of
to draw our UI extension's
Okay. The last thing I'm going
that I've completed implementing
and configuring my
and that should go ahead and
Okay. So I have a version of
Let's go ahead and see it now.
So as you can see here, I
I'm going to send
Send the message to Diana using
on your presentation."
[ Applause ]
And so we've got a great
but also you noticed that
And so we'll take
So we've just shown you how
to boot strap your UI
And that's really great.
But you'll notice
there's something not quite
that we're showing
And thus that we have a
interface being shown
By default, Siri shows the user
of intents, and this
that we've just used to send
As such, what we'd like to do
for our UnicornChat users is
interface to let the users have
when they send messages
And so we can do this in iOS 10,
By implementing the
protocol, you can let Siri know
that you're drawing
within your UI extension's view.
And thus, you can opt-in to
of particular content
and then taking over that
Ultimately when you do this,
Siri will accommodate
and so you should make sure
that you do accurately
on behalf of the user.
So let's take the
that we were just working
Here you can see that
INUIHostedViewSiriProviding
we can implement displaysMessage
indicating to Siri that we are
in fact displaying message
And this is all it
to implement your own user
So let's see a demo
where I have a version
that does exactly this.
So we're back on my device.
Now let's send another
Send the message to Diana
"It's pretty tough to type
And now we see exactly the
and what we want
[ Applause ]
Our interface is unimpeded by
And this gives us a great outlet
that really reflects
on the unicorny style
Now some final thoughts
on implementing UI extensions
And the first thing I'd
that you should consider
UI extensions.
Because extensions, by default,
to the user for short
the system enforces
than you might be used to
And so usage of views,
can be especially
and you should use
when building your UI extension.
As we saw, we have access to
within our UI extension
And this is also
if you're designing
and your UI extension
in various different
But desired size that you then
A desired size.
And so, if you're making use
you want to make sure that
so that it can look good
or the maximum size, no
So we've seen a few
to extending our
And the first is preparing
and that's by making use of
like embedded frameworks,
to be able to properly test
that Siri might send us.
And then architecting
to use the right
We solved how to add our
and implementing
and Handle business logic
that lets our applications
And finally, we showed how to
to bring the custom, unique
into the Siri experience.
The sample code from this
and some great documentation
are available on our website.
And then we had an excellent
Introducing SiriKit,
about what we want SiriKit to be
And we had a great session about
from WWDC 2015 that I'd
if you intend to implement
And I hope that you find
extensions and your
as we did with UnicornChat.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]