[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and
What's New in CloudKit.
My name is Paul Seligman.
I'm an engineer on the CloudKit
to be with you here today
and new features in
So, what are we going
We're going to start off today
with a quick overview
We're then going to switch
a new feature which
to visualize how your
are behaving.
We're going to talk about
and their availabilities.
And we're going to talk
which gives your
to share their data while
over who has access to it.
So, what is CloudKit?
CloudKit is a technology
to have your application data
and your user data available
CloudKit is a framework
to a database stored on iCloud.
We use CloudKit extensively
This gives you the confidence to
and it gives us the confidence
to hundreds of millions
CloudKit is available on
Now, I'm going to quickly
to CloudKit, covering topics
in introduction to CloudKit.
I recommend you go check out
if you'd like a broader
I'd also like to mention these
about specific aspects
You can use these to
and your application can use
Now, all the sessions
from
Here we see the list of objects
that every developer
to be familiar with.
Let's step through them
A Container is the mechanism by
So, notes uses a Container.
Photos uses a Container and your
of CloudKit, will also have
If we look inside
we see that Containers
And until last week
A Container had two databases,
With the introduction
we introduced a third database
More about that in a little bit.
The basic unit of storage
A record is a group of key value
to an object model, an
Now, we don't store records
Rather, we encapsulate
Many records can exist
and many Record Zones can
Different databases support
The public and private databases
This is where all your
up unless you specify otherwise.
Your private database can also
which are zones that
and uploads into the database.
And lastly, the new
of shared Record Zones.
With the introduction
we're going to add one new
The concept of a Share.
A Share is a subclass
lives alongside Records
You can think of a Record as
to share and Share representing
things like participants
Again, we'll get more
Just know that it exists.
Now, I mentioned that we use
of Apple and I wanted
to highlight some
In the public database
that you've probably used,
The News App in particular
etc., in the public database.
And it's a great use
Storing content that you
to all of your users.
And we can contrast this
The private database
to store the user's
We have several clients
of Apple including iCloud
iCloud Photo Library and Notes.
And I'm happy to report
Notes Collaboration and
on top of CloudKit Sharing.
So, as such, the Notes
and Activity Applications are
Two years ago we
by providing two
one on iOS and one on macOS.
Last year we extended that
for tvOS and two web
and CloudKit Web Services.
The web frameworks give your
whether they're on the
that doesn't have a native
And this year we're going to go
by adding a native
With this, we now have a native
across all of Apple's platforms.
Let's take a moment and step
through some notable
this year.
Starting with macOS.
The big news that we
that you no longer need
to distribute your application
to take advantage of CloudKit.
[ Applause ]
Using the new iCloud for
you can directly entitle your
and other iCloud services via
Next I want to talk
This is a feature that's
for a few months now and it's
to have your servers directly
as administrative users.
Your servers can
to CloudKit using a
previously established on
And you can set your servers
to the public database.
This is a great way for
from your servers into
from CloudKit to your servers.
Or to keep two sets
between your servers
With the introduction of
on watchOS, you now
to keep your watch Apps and
In that way, you can think
to the watch connectivity
And CloudKit comes with
That is standalone
CloudKit uses NSURL
we're going to send our network
over the best available
If your watch is
we'll send traffic
But the watch is also
to CloudKit servers
Now, we are presenting
of the CloudKit API.
With the introduction of
on watchOS, you now
to write similar application
across all of Apple's platforms.
The Activity App for
to write similar CloudKit
to provide the activity
Now, notice I said similar
As you write code and
of Apple's platforms,
that the strengths and
In other words, you're going
to hit limited resources
You need to keep in mind
the storage capacities and
such as latency and throughput.
You can use this in determining
to the servers and how
to send over the wire.
As always, testing
to tune your App appropriately
that your users are going
to have the best
Now I'd like to change gears
Telemetry is a new
to visualize the behavior
of your CloudKit-backed
We surface Telemetry as a series
on the CloudKit Dashboard.
You can use these charts
in the public database or an
across all users'
You can scope these charts
on an hourly, daily,
And you can choose to view the
or scope these charts down
So, let's go and see
Here we have the
which you're probably
And I want to call your
in the lower left,
When you select the Performance
to a series of charts
about how your clients
They fall into two categories.
The first is performance charts
such as the number of
and the average size
And again, you can scope this
in the public or private
of timescales and potentially
The other type of chart that
Correctness chart.
And the one I want to call
This tells you what percentage
that have resulted
Now, a client error is
that you might receive
And it is that subset which we
able to resolve and
So for example, maybe you
and there was a conflicting
Or perhaps you attempted to
that the server doesn't
Both of these would be
and would be surfaced
By being able to
we hope that you can
when your client's, situations
when your clients are seeing
of errors.
Now, we've said in the past
for a CloudKit-backed
The difference between
that handles errors
between a functioning App
It's that serious.
It's an integral part in writing
So, we hope that you can
out situations in which you need
to go examine how your clients
For more information on
I want to invite you
CloudKit Best Practices.
We'll spend some time diving
Next, I'd like to talk to
to our APIs, all of which
And really, there's four that I
Starting with Long-Lived
Long-Lived Operations
by which you don't
that you've already
So, as it stands now, when your
Any operations that
on behalf of it are torn down.
Even if that operation was
By making your operations
your operations can outlive the
They will continue running
to cache responses from the
When your Application
you've resumed the operation.
And we're just going to go
out of our local cache.
In many cases, this can
for another network round trip.
We're going to talk about
in more detail at tomorrow's
I hope you can join us.
Next I want to touch on
of from our developers
with CKOperation
And the picture I want to paint
for you here is we've
The device has network
but we're not getting
over in either direction.
And as a side note, you
and replicate the scenario
conditioner, a great
for replicating behavior
Now, a CKOperation is a
And as such, as a
If your operation is
or user initiated, then on a bad
down after 1 minute and give
If your operation has any of
we're going to go ahead
and continue attempting
It might not be what
What's more, if you choose not
to set an explicit
on your CKOperation, we
and we choose utility.
So, if you add all
of developer reports saying,
why is my operation
So, we want to address
to address this with
The first covers network
as the timeout interval
for request property
It defaults to 1 minute
that we're willing to wait for
If we don't hear any traffic
of time, we're going to tear
that the network timed out.
We're also going to expose
and we expose this as
for resource property
This defaults to seven days and
that we're willing to wait for
from your device to
and its completion
Now, I want to make note
that a CKOperation may issue
as it's going about its job.
So, a CKOperation may take more
as you are making
Next, I want to talk about how
of record changes when
up on the server.
As we'll learn when
your client may see more
in the past.
So, our answer to this
to fetch the entire
from a database using a
There's a couple
We don't want you to poll
to fetch the entire list of
So, we're no longer going to
and we're going to replace
The first,
This is a new subscription type
that will fire whenever
of a database.
Even in a Record Zone that
And we're going to couple
that with a
operation.
This is an operation that allows
of Record Zones that
since some point in
Okay, so now you have a list
to go fetch changes for.
How are you going to do that?
Well, the old way was
CKFetchRecordChanges operation.
You'd pass in a single Record
for that single Record Zone.
We don't want you to have
sequentially through all these
and deprecated this
And we've replaced it
with a very similar
the CKFetchRecordZone
This is essentially a batch
and it gives you the ability
across multiple Record Zones
So, let's go ahead
Here we have a database,
each Record Zone has
And the client, which
with all of these changes.
Now, along come a
Your client, by virtue of
CKDatabaseSubscription, will
on the server and
Next, using a
operation, you can ask
of Record Zones that
In this case, the
Now, armed with that
you can issue a
operation requesting all
of the change Record Zones in
And lastly, I'd like to talk
about how do you
when there are many
in a Record Zone
If you've used CloudKit
then you're familiar with the
on a CKFetchRecordChanges
that not only have we given you
up on the server that
with a subsequent
Now, there's a couple
The first is that we've
of check the flag and
to all of our clients.
It's another potential
And secondly, while you're
to fetch and cue a new operation
CloudKit is sitting around idle.
We want to address both of those
that we made a brand-new
CKFetchRecordChanges
Instead of us telling you
when there are more
you tell us what your
fetchAllChanges property.
When this is set to true, then
of changes from the server,
and then immediately
for the next batch of changes.
This allows us to keep
pulling network data over the
Now, we think that this is going
that we've gone ahead and we've
for this new class.
So, new CKFetchRecordZoneChanges
by default will fetch
down from a particular
As you might imagine, if you've
your user's iCloud Photo
this means that the subsequent
in the Record Zone is going
to take a very long
We want to make sure that
of operations that
We don't want to have to go
that we've already
So, we've added a new
RecordZoneChangeTokens
And after we hand you a batch of
and tell you about an
And your code is going
for doing two different things.
First, you're going to go ahead
and commit all the
that you've received
And secondly, you're going to go
that server change token.
If the operation fails at
you can issue a brand-new
operation, pass in this locally
and essentially pick back
No need to re-download
that you've already
And so these are just 4 of the
that you can take advantage of
by iCloud, backed by CloudKit.
And with that, I'd like to
and invite up Jacob Farkas to
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Paul.
My name is Jacob Farkas
on the CloudKit team.
And today I'm going
about how you can add CloudKit
by only writing a
We've introduced a new class
It's a subclass of CKRecord
for storing two important
One, what is shared, and two,
what that record is
So, let's look at
We've got our private database
in the private database
To do that, we're going
and initialize it using
You always need to create
so there's always
Next, we're going to save
to the server at the same time.
You want to do that because
on CKRecord that's a reference
to the Share that
By saving the root record and
that reference will be set to
So, now we've defined what
to define who we want
To do that, we've created a
This lookup service takes a
into a CKShare participant.
You can set the Share
save that Share to
that person's iCloud account
We also support looking
or CloudKit user record IDs.
Now, we want to let users
in their shared database so
to just instantly appear.
The user should have control so
that Share and join it.
But that means we need a way
that we've made a share
and that they need to join it.
And we do that via URLs.
Every share has a URL which
If the user taps on this URL in
we're going to show
We're going to ask them if
And if they do, they'll
and shown the items
The great thing about a
on an older platform
that doesn't support sharing,
this will take them
And we can show them
and tell them how they can
So, let's put this URL into
to the other participant
They're going to receive the
in their Shared Database they
that we created and
The great thing here is that the
a view into the owner's
So, if this other user has
if they update that
that same change happen
So, let's take a look at what
All right, we've got Notes
to Notes in macOS X Sierra.
By using the same
that we're making available
So, you'll see that there's
up here.
And if we tap on that,
that lets us choose how
When we hit Share, the system
and telling Notes that it
and the root record
Once it's done that, the system
We can invite the other user.
We hit Send.
And the system UI is actually
looking up the participants
and sending the email
So, if we switch over to our
we see the email we just sent.
We can tap on that URL.
And we'll be asked if we
When we do that, we're
The Share shows up, the Note
that Note with the other user.
If I make changes on the
let's say I check off avocados
as something else to pick up.
We'll see those happen in the
So, let's look at
You're probably all familiar
with the CloudKit framework
and the new CKShare object live.
If you want to use this new
to find that on macOS in
We'll start by looking
Before we create a Share,
we need to create
So, we'll create a Share
We will set a couple properties
title and a thumbnail.
And then we move on
a UI cloud-sharing controller.
We initialize that with
and we pass it a
This preparation handler
when it's time to
in the record to the server.
So, our handler here will create
Save the record and Share to
it will call the
Next, we might want
on this UI cloud
One of the properties we can set
We can say whether we want that
or maybe we only want
read/write permissions.
We also want to set the present,
presentation controller source
in the same place as the button
We'll want to set
so that we get callbacks about
And finally we call Present.
And when we do that, we're
that looks something like this.
Now, if you've already saved
you can call UI cloud sharing
And it will present a
and let them manage
and stop sharing if they'd like.
Everything is taken care of
The macOS sharing API is really
to go very quickly and
First off, you create
and you register your
This handler looks the
You save the Share in
and when you're done, you
Next, you're going to
That sharing service is
that you set yourself
with the NSItem provider
Finally, NSSharingService
So, if you want to set options
you'll do that with callback
On macOS, the Share create
And if you want to
on a Share, it'll
Next, if a user accepts a
your Application is
and it'll receive this callback
CloudKit Share.
That callback will contain
about the Share in
that the user just accepted.
It looks really similar
of using UIApplication
And finally, you need
that your Application
And you do this via the
in your info P list.
We're also happy to announce
that we've added
to our CloudKit JavaScript
you can create Shares, accept
that you can use to
You can try this all out right
So, I'm going to hand things off
who is going to tell
about sharing in depth.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jacob.
Hi. And good afternoon.
My name is Vanessa Hong
on the CloudKit server team.
So, today we will deep dive
at some common use cases.
We'll start with the
and then we'll go
down into the internals
Then I'll talk about how you
if you want to create
And then finally we'll close
So, let's get started.
Jacob showed how to
But the item the owner wants
to share may not
It may consist of many records.
Possibly already
And your application
to see only a subset
This is why we introduced
on the CKRecord called
Set the Parent Reference on
to be included in
And you can set this up
to share.
When the user does share,
you will create the CKShare
Then, all of the all
that are linked to the root
are automatically included
So, let's see what this looks
A shared database is only a view
into the owner's
So, it doesn't contain
When a participant
they only see what
So, they see the
This means there's no two
There's only one copy
in the owner's private DB.
So, this means the owner and all
with the same set of records.
This kind of contention may
To learn how to deal with
to a past WWDC talk called
Now, a read/write
remove and add records.
But we don't want
to add just anything they
For instance, they cannot
They also cannot add a record
even if it's somehow linked
So, the correct way to add a new
is to set a Parent Reference and
So, even though you're
for the participant via
that new record lives in
So, what this means is
by the participant are counted
So, the producement's
and your developer
The owner's private
that we store these records
against the owner's quota.
And that's how you
Let's take a closer look
So, here we have two Shares
but the Shares have
so how do you tell
Well, we glossed over a very
that all records in
And a Zone is identified
The Zone name is the name of
in the owner's private DB.
An owner name is the
So, in our example, the two
but different owners.
So, let's say the first
but in a different Zone.
So when you call the
you will see this
And then when you call
you'll see the new
Now, let's say the second
but in the existing Zone.
Well, this Zone already exists
We'll just reuse it.
When you call the
that this Zone has changed and
And that is our shared database.
So, let's take this
at the CKShare object.
So, before the owner
they must do something to Share.
So, the records describe
And the CKShare describes how
So, we're going to be
So, as Jacob mentioned,
but it has some additional
And we've been looking at
to the lifecycle of a Share.
So, we're going to
and the owner will
And the owner has to decide
for the Share.
So, in this case the owner
because he wants to
And let's say he
Their status is automatically
And then the owner
to give to each participant.
Then, the owner saves the Share
and then he gets a
So, there are two
One is that the Share
And the State says only these
the Share.
The owner is the one with the
to tell people about this URL.
So, even if he tells 100
only these two participants
So, when a participant
they accept via the URL.
And after that accept,
their acceptance
And then the permission
in the Share is exactly
So, now let's say
to create a more open share.
So, let's start over.
The owner sets up a
that the public permission
or read/write.
He doesn't add any participants.
He just saves the Share.
And then he gets a
So, there's still
One is that the Share
and it says anyone can join.
And the owner has a URL.
And it's his responsibility
So, if he tells 100 people,
So, when they join, they
and then that participant
in the Share and accepted state.
Their permission is inherited
from the Share's
And that's how you set up the
So, the next phase of
when a participant leaves.
And a participant
by deleting the CKShare
This will also remove the shared
So, to be clear, the
It exists in the
It's just that this
in the Share in accepted state.
And the owner has full
so he can remove
Let's say he wants
He would do that by
from his private database.
This will also remove
from the root record
And now the owner is back in the
So, let's move on and talk about
So, if you've seen this object
you saw the acceptance
But now let's look at
This has a look up info.
And the look up info is how
to the share.
So, it will have their email,
And the name components
and this is populated with
the Share.
Every CKShareParticipant is
So, let's say the owner invites
to find iCloud accounts for
for participant 3 and 4.
This is perfectly okay.
CloudKit will create a
for participant 3 and 4.
And the only people who can
and 4 are the ones who can prove
that they owned the email
that the owner invited
This is called the
This will link the email
so that they never have to go
through the verification
And that's all the objects
So, now let's move on and
So, if you want to
you can call our APIs.
And there are two
So, on the behalf of the owner,
you can help them
On behalf of the participant,
On watchOS and tvOS, there's
So, you can ask your user to go
up a Share and accept the Share.
And then the Share data is
Alternatively, you can
And this is how you do it.
On behalf of the owner, you
You would have to look up by
and then translate that to
Once you have the
add those to the share.
And then call CKModifyRecords
Now your application
And it is up to you, the
to tell people about the URL.
When a participant
we always start with the URL.
You first have to convert the
and then pass that
to the CKAcceptShares operation.
Now, the participant will show
Now, there are some
For privacy reasons,
to you their name components.
And the verification
So, if you get this error
or if it has iCloud
then you can ask your user to
This will trigger the system
through the verification flow.
And that's our sharing APIs.
So, now let's talk
A user of your application can
email or any phone number.
Now, what this means is
for your application
than your current user base.
So, these MIT's may not
operating system.
They might not even
So, when they click on the
And in the example for Notes,
They will be asked
after which they'll
And they can interact
like they would on a device.
But this is the Notes
that lives on iCloud.com.
What about your Application?
Well, by default, your users
It has your App icon
to go on the latest device.
Which is not the
So, I do have some
You can go to your
and configure a fallback URL.
So, when an invitee clicks on
we redirect them to
We'll append the token
for the Share so that you
to accept the Share and then
Now, I hope you're excited
There is just one last
A CKShare is of this
and this record type
like any other record
You can create custom
You can run queries.
You also have the first created
And the easiest way to create
in your dev environment
from your private database.
This will trigger the
And then go to your
and deploy your scheme
If you don't do this, then users
in the production
when they create the Share
because the record
And that wraps it up.
So, you learned today that
of our platforms including
on the web via CloudKit JS.
Telemetry is available on
It's a great way to visualize
including error trends.
There are many API improvements
[inaudible] and the
And now you know all about
You've seen this system
to create your own custom UI
And you've seen all the
in sharing including
And I bet you will go back and
So, I want to thank you for
I want to draw your attention
It's tomorrow at 9 AM.
It's a great session on how to
Thank you and enjoy the rest
[ Applause ]