[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon
to Architecting Performance
My name is Tyler McAtee
and shortly you'll be meeting
Today we'll be discussing the
about performance and where that
We'll start by talking about
how it helped influence
and what that means for
I'll then talk a bit about how
performance and, showcase
that will help reduce
Finally, Todd will come on stage
and show how we've taken
to them the stock's
So let's start with
We've focused on this idea
for what an interaction with the
So what is a 2-Second task?
A 2-Second task is something
or learn by looking
These tasks should only
And these seconds should be
of the interaction
from the moment the user
at their Apple Watch, to the
Some examples of a 2-Second task
setting a timer or
Today I'm going to
of the key changes
and explain how these
as a developer should
in your WatchKit application.
Now, one of the first
in accomplishing a task on
of navigation it can take to get
The quickest way to
on the Apple Watch is by
We only encourage developers
if they had relevant
A lot of our apps,
Mail and Phone had
In order to increase
on the Apple Watch as well as
to customize, now
of our applications
These launcher complications
to your very favorite
from the watch face.
We encourage you to
for your application as well.
Implement a complication whether
Additionally, new in watchOS
Just by pressing the side button
up their dock and
of their favorites applications.
Navigating to and from these
and easy.
Now we want our users
to these favorite applications
and loaded, instead of having to
as the application
In order to address this, in
that a user chooses to
or in their dock will be
in memory by the system.
That way when they go to
they only have to wait for
But the system still has
and as an application
you'll need to be
Because there can be up
up to 5 complications, as well
as the system application,
You have to remember
of a large ecosystem, so
as you absolutely need.
Now the system, because of
our system does impose a fixed
that a WatchKit application
If you exceed this limit,
our system will terminate you
down so that the memory can be
This limit isn't a goal, and you
up all this memory
it should be nowhere
The current limit, as of watchOS
application, but this
So what are some good tips for
Use appropriately sized
not only does this
but will help increase
because the watch won't have
to do the extra work
Use appropriately sized data
of data if you're only
on screen.
And if you're only displaying
don't download or keep
around all the other
If you have control over
to download the data
to build separate end points
since the watch will probably
of the information.
This will help save on the
that your watch has to
of transient data and memory.
Finally, it's important
to release objects
Take the time to go
and make sure you're
around things you
Now, because the applications
on their watch face and
and suspended in
they will be resumed much more
Because of this, for watchOS 3
on optimizing is resume time.
Now apps won't only be
because they're kept
but also because
When the user scrolls over to
the application will be resumed.
When the user scrolls away, the
This behavior of resuming and
for applications in watchOS 3.
So it's important to understand
which lifecycle methods
and which lifecycle methods
So let's talk about the
that the WatchKit
ApplicationDidFinishLaunching
that your delegate will see.
This gets called when the
and is a good place to perform
of your application
that only need to
The second method that
is applicationDidBecomeActive.
This gets called whenever your
application on the
that were previously paused or
refresh the user interface.
Once the application
to the inactive state
applicationWillResignActive
This can occur for certain
such as an incoming phone
when the user presses the side
or when the user
and it starts its transition
When your application is no
to go to the background
applicationDidEnterBackground
And when your application
to the foreground you'll get the
call.
These methods are only
from background to foreground or
so it won't be called
In addition, there are
with the interface controller.
AwakeWithContext gets called
when your interface
This is a good place to do work
willActivate is called when
and able to be updated.
It can be called before the
to the user.
Once the interface is
you'll get the didAppear method.
If you have work
these methods are the
If the work is heavy
to dispatch the work out
so that these methods
and your app can
Once you're application's
you'll get the willDisappear
on your interface controller
about to be no longer
Once the user interface
and no longer be updated you'll
These methods are a good place
that you may have started in
It's important to understand
that these methods can get
I'd like to now walk
of how an application might
its lifetime.
We'll start with an application
of this talk is not
When the user taps
the first methods will go to
didFinishLaunching,
The interface controller will
willActivate and didAppear.
Now your application is running
But what happens when the
to bring up the dock?
At this moment your application
application on the platform,
So your delegate will get the
call.
While the user's still settled
you'll still foreground
you're getting CPU time,
your updating your user
As soon as the user scrolls
the system will suspend
So your interface controller
and didDeactivate
application didEnterBackground.
Now here your application has
so the system might
for a background snapshot task.
To learn more about
check out the talk
Keeping Your Watch
Your interface controller gets
and didAppear, before your
to handleBackgroundTasks.
And then your interface
willDisappear and didDeactivate.
Now your application
and it's handled its
Once the user swipes
you'll get your
and your willActivate
Your application is
and foregrounded in the dock.
It's no until the user taps
that you become the active
and get
Now a lot has happened just
swiping away from your
That's why it's important to
and understand that as a
application may be seeing these
So what are some other tips
You should use discretion when
Every time you set a property
on WKInterface object the system
packs it up, and dispatches
where the UI is updated.
It may be tempting to build some
of your application updates
that every time you resume.
But setting each property
Even if the property isn't
in unnecessary traffic between
It's worth the effort to
if they're changing, so
You should also not
that WKInterfaceTable does not
The phone has a lot more memory
for storing a lot
and UITableView is just
through these larger data set.
The cells are created on demand,
With WKInterfaceTable however,
all the cells are created
So the amount of work
to do scales linearly
Because of that it's important
to keep WKInterfaceTable
The watch is not the appropriate
through hundreds of records and
to keep WKInterfaceTable
You should avoid reloading
possible as well.
This is an expensive operation.
If it may be tempting to reload
or when your data set
and remove rows, it's better
to use the insertion
I'd now like to talk
Thinking about the right
on the watch form factor
to display it can
In watchOS 3you should
to be glanceable.
The dock lets users quickly look
through their favorite
So your application may
for a brief moment in
from one application
So focus on showing only the
and display it as
Part of making your application
with a focused purpose.
The watch is not the appropriate
through large amounts
or looking at complex
By only showing the most
you tend to get better
Since you're displaying less
and processing and need
to stay up to date.
Lastly, it's important
I've talked a lot about how
on a system level, but
to consider navigation on an
In order to help with this
pageing API.
A standard setup for a WatchKit
data view where you have a
of the cells drills into
The problem with this
to see the detail
you end up tapping
In order to solve this, our new
quickly scroll from
just panning along the screen
To learn more about how to set
as learn about other quick
released, for developers,
check out the Quick
for watchOS talk
But in this talk I'd like
about the lifecycle that
through as part of this API.
Because it's important from
So here we have our table with
The detail paging API works
to interface controllers.
So when you tap one of the cells
When you tap the cell,
your master interface
to get the method
withidentifierinTable row index.
This is where you're going to
that gets passed to your
and it's awakeWithContext
Your master view controller
for the cell you
and every cell in the table.
We prepare the context for every
away so that when we
so that we can instantiate
That way when the user, goes
to their first one
through all of them.
Your first controller
first one to get its
as well as its willActivate
However, this is where
for the scroll view.
We'll preheat the
to the selected detail
so that the users can
So the other colors are going
to get their lifecycle
They're going to first get
and then their willActivate
It's important to be smart
on these off screen
Don't start long CPU intensive
Because this may cause a lot
if you have a lot
Now as the user scrolls
to the other your previous
first to get its willDisappear
didDeactivate, and didAppear.
This keeps your interface
in a consistent state.
Those that are on screen
didAppear call and those
that are off screen
didDeactivate call.
That way when you tap back to go
to the master interface
only one interface controller
on it, the one that's visible.
It'll get its willDisappear,
Alright, I'd like to
about how we've applied
to our Stocks WatchKit
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
I'm a watch OS engineer,
as a case study to
So many of you may
but Stocks is a watch
At Apple we wanted to
with WatchKit development,
and we felt that Stocks
for WatchKit development.
I have three topics that I
in regard to Stocks and
I'm going to identify our
then I'm going to discuss some
of the implementation details
use cases.
Finally, I will talk a bit about
to help with our resume time and
So, we'll begin with
When we thought of Stocks,
we thought of three
the first is you
to view how a favorite
right now.
This can of course
with a complication.
But with the dock, we're able
with that 2-Second task.
In particular, we felt
that another important 2-Second
favorite stock's current
in a chart.
Lastly, we felt that it
to see the current
So we'll start with
Now of course the
to see data on your watch.
That data is always present and
to look at the time
The important piece in that, in
in sync between the
Now for more information on
to check out the Keeping Your
that occurred this morning.
So now we'll go and
of the other 2-Second tasks
So in watchOS 2, you
and you could see the
that you were interested in or
But if you wanted to see how
that stock had been
you would need to
and now you're presented
It's a little bit
but it still doesn't really
that stock price had been
So if you wanted to see that,
down a little bit, and
We had four options, for the
the one week, the one
So odds are the first
down there you're probably
that you care about which is
So that would require you
very small buttons and
And then after that, you would
down below that a lot of the
for when you're glancing at
And of course if you wanted
and how they're performing
you would have to navigate
much like Tyler should you
So let's look at watchOS 3.
Now here's the new watchOS
first of all, still a list
But the font is much larger,
of a simplified interface.
To me it pops and it's easily
like you would see in the dock.
So if you wanted to see
today and how the performance
on Apple, again, but now you
And we just assume
to see the one day chart.
There are instances of course,
much like index funds
But we can fall back to the
across those, and that's
that you would like
We also got rid of some of
Now this gives us
One, it eliminates a
up our loading performance.
And two, it allows us to adopt
API, so then that
through multiple Stocks either
or a swipe of your finger.
And of course, if you
of a stock's performance you
that we had before such as the
You can view that using
you're able to setup a
that off to your iPhone.
So we feel that the watch is
and that the iPhone
you know like a view
or a little bit too convoluted.
So the good thing about the
it's very readable in the
we decided to reevaluate what
So if you attended some of the
that there is a concept of a
So we took this to mean that
And what I mean by sticky is
if you're looking at the
to Stocks either in the dock or
you will see the stock list.
And this is also the
up to date throughout the day.
However, if you were to tap
and returned to look at
into the app, then you're
Now there's one caveat
so on Stocks you can set
and that's the stock
of course on your complication.
So we took that to mean
that that's most likely
So once you set that,
that we try to return you to.
So if you open up Stocks and
to the Facebook stock, and you
in about an hour, when we get
for our snapshot, we will
to the Apple stock.
Because we take that to mean
as your complication
that would be your favorite
that we want to return you to.
So we want to make a
and always return the user to
to see after a certain
So let's recap what we've done
in our 2-Second tasks
The first thing, we made sure
between our complication
The next, we simplified
we made it a lot more
and much more usable
through the detail pageing API.
And that lets you look at
of having to do the
So next, we'll talk a little
and I would like to
about how we implemented
So when we started implementing
we came up with two questions.
One, how often do we need
to update our information
And two, what data
to keep our app up to date?
So determining how often
in Stocks was a little bit
At first we felt that updating
pretty good start.
This would leave us updating our
day, however.
And many of those updates could
like when the stock
of the day or over the weekend.
So let's take some
because we felt we
in how we implemented this.
First, markets are
of time throughout the day.
So for an example, let's
on the New York Stock Exchange,
and we know that the New
at 9:30 a.m. Eastern and it
So if we limit our
basically when the market is
down our number of updates,
for other applications.
And it's also going
of not updating our complication
when it would be ineffective.
So that's also nice as well.
So let's look at a little pseudo
and how would we decide
for Stocks should be.
First, we're going to enumerate
then we're going to check and
basically if the
Because if we know,
if the markets are all closed we
that we have in our stock list.
Otherwise, that means at
so we should fall back to our
So we'll look at a
The first thing that I'll
this is just a function
for scheduling our
and it takes an optional
We use the
instance method in WKExtension,
in this preferredDate here.
Now that preferred date is
but that's at least how
refresh time.
So I'm kind of working
So let's see what happens in
That function has a guard early
to call our function
And if it returns nil, then
and bail, because in
we would return nil
if you didn't have any
Because at that point
in doing a background refresh
because there's no
So now we'll go ahead
nextRegularRefreshData,
so that's just our update
And then finally, we'll
So we take that
and we'll do a later
against our regular
Now our
also has the added benefit
if the market is currently
So the later date would
in that scenario.
So let's look at that
method.
First we're going to
and then we're going to
And so if it's 0 again, we're
there's no use in doing
Then we're going to iterate
If any of the markets, are open
and return the distantPast.
Otherwise we're going
And we're just going to
and find the
And so I mean, I just wanted
because we feel that
of limiting the number of times
that you're doing
with not a whole lot of code.
So let's talk about scheduling
Because in particularly with
that we hit to keep our
So we have endpoint A, which
up to date, and then
for updating the complication.
So if we're going to schedule
we do that.
Once we receive the
we'll submit our
submit our endpoint B request
and we'll schedule our future
So what does that look like?
Well, we have our handle
in our WKExtension delegate.
We're going to iterate over
We're going to go ahead
if it's an application
And if it is, we're going
that data update request
where we actually
The next we'll do,
and schedule our next
using that handy dandy
And then we'll complete
The last part of this, I'll
that URL session
Now you will get one of these
when you trigger a background
So it's our job here
where we can complete
that request is finished.
So now we've talked
about what it actually looks
like when we schedule
just at a high level.
So we're going to schedule
and then when those
we're going to schedule
reload the complication,
to complete our refresh
So the first thing we'll
and the complication
Then we're going to setup
Now the finish update handler is
a block that I set so that
delegate method for finishing
called, I can call that
and that'll call
So then we have our
which is essentially just
and calling resume on the tasks.
Now once the task is complete,
that task from our URL sessions
We'll schedule our snapshot,
and we'll go ahead and
And one last thing
out here is our
to show you that whenever
we just grab the identifier
and we call our
And so that kind of
of how you can run multiple
up to date if you have
and your complication.
So the first thing,
to optimize how often
for your app when you're
That's goal number one.
And if you're updating
try to use a single
if you have control over that.
But if you don't, it is possible
to submit multiple requests
So now let's move onto
So when you optimize your resume
to be optimizing
as well, which is very nice.
So let's talk about
As Tyler I mentioned earlier,
we can minimize the work we're
and didAppear.
So you know to do that,
of course we avoid
that are triggered
We'll do a smart loading
and of course as he
to set properties on
that have actually changed.
So I'll start this off
and this involves implementing
So as Tyler mentioned before,
neighboring detail pages
and you also want to
in willActivate for
But in particular, there's one
in this view.
So it started with a
but essentially we got
a slow loading chart for a stock
when you first entered
And other detail pages never
or were extremely slow.
So we kind of looked at
and see what was going on, so
of a stock interface controller.
But if you'll notice,
in willActivate we're calling
which was, basically an NS
and doing a lot of work to get
So what can we do to
Well, so we know that in
when that interface
to the user and it has settled.
So how about we start
that chart data there?
And then what happens
through those quite frequently?
We don't want to continue
that chart data for a view
So we'll go ahead and we'll call
which is just a method
that takes the operation
So, let's look at, again to
because I have to learn
We want to avoid triggering long
And if possible, it's
of cancellable operations,
so NS operation is a nice
So we'll move onto the
We know that all rows
and we know that there's
to the number of rows
And, of course there's no reuse
So I'm going to show a graph and
that I had done in Stocks.
And this for the initial
not resume time, any of that.
But it's kind of important to
in the list, so an
so just under 5 1/2
If we added one stock it
to just under 6 1/2
a little over 6 1/2 seconds.
And if we had 10
to creep up towards 7 seconds.
So if you have a
in your table you're just
that interface controller
So what can we do to improve
Well first we can limit the
And we can also try to do
when row deltas occur so
So let's look at our initial
We'll go ahead and we'll grab
and then we're going to set the
And then after that,
we'll populate each row
Now it seems pretty harmless at
Well the number of stocks isn't
it would be 20 rows, if you had
And we were always using
And if just one row is being
of rows you're essentially
out what you had there before
So it's inefficient.
So let's look at
to be a little smarter
So we grab the stocks like
and check the count, and
and cap that at a max size.
So in Stocks' case, 20.
Then we're going to
to see what the difference
And then we're going to call
which I'll get to in a second.
And then one last
to make sure we're not doing
We'll go ahead and check to
that max Stocks list size.
So let's look at that
So the first thing we're going
to do is calculate the row
to check the stock row delta.
So if it's greater than 0,
if it's less than 0, then we
And the important thing
to be a little bit more
and do smart updating based
on how much the list
But we found, for
just doing a simple insert
starting at index 0, seems
So let's not do more
Alright so to recap,
in your stock list, or in
in your case, I'm not sure
but keep the number of
at something reasonable
Next, when you're inserting
to be much more efficient than
of rows method on
So one last thing here,
over the entire table when
So think about it this way,
like what if we're updating
in our table list or
Instead of going through and
when we don't have to, we can
at index so that way we only
that we care about.
Or, you can even do something
to that rowController
So now we're going
about updating your UIElements.
So as Tyler mentioned before,
they're modified in
and updates to these
from the extension
And the app process handles
So let's look at
and this is just
But we have the platter
which has just the
Then we also have the list name
and so that's just
of the company name,
The change in points label,
and that's just the
And then we have the price
So let's look and see
When we would go to
we had this update method
and it would just take
and it would set those
Now that's bad because
on the interface object
And setting a property on
to the app process every time,
but I want to emphasize
On average, in my profiling
in Stocks it would take roughly
to move from the extension
And that doesn't really
in some profiling, that I
I saw a pretty staggering
a worst case scenario
of those messages to get sent
over from the extension
So it's a big difference.
So what can we do to
Really just cache those values
and then only send them
So let's do a little recap of
We want to minimize the work
and our didAppear, and
of cancelable operations
It's also important to note,
that overly complicated user
to lead to slower load times.
So the more data that you're
and update on the UI,
And of course, we'll only want
when necessary, so only
So to summarize the Stocks
like for you to take from
Keep your tasks small
You'll want to simplify your
to make use of the new
Focus on resume time in your
to the WKInterfaceController
especially willActivate
And make use of our cancelable
and optimize when updating
by not sending redundant
For more information, you can
Our session number is 227.
Some of the related sessions,
unfortunately have
but some of these I
to not only WatchKit development
on GCD in Swift 3, so that's
So thank you and have a
[ Applause ]