[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and
I'm Tyler Fox and
by my colleague Peter Hajas.
We're both engineers
and we're really excited
how you can adopt 3D Touch
to take your app's user
We'd like to start
of the fundamentals of 3D Touch
and showing you how it
From there, we'll talk about
Home Screen Quick Actions
that you can add 3D
They let users jump straight
right to those key
From there, we'll talk
Peek and Pop are a seamless
and navigate content
We think that most apps will
for adding support with Peek
Finally, we're excited
about UIPreviewInteraction,
that allows you to make 3D
It's for those of you
of the 3D Touch interaction
and it lets you use the
that we've honed for Peek
in your own custom
It's really great and we can't
So with that, let's get started,
Devices that support 3D Touch
that precisely measures
of touches on the screen.
Now iOS has always let users
on the user interface.
This has been a hallmark
since the original
with its multi-touch display.
But 3D Touch extends this
to connect even more closely
Let's take a look at some of
up across the operating system,
When you press on an app icon,
we reveal the Home
As you can see here with Camera,
into some of the key
that you come to perform.
For example, taking a
using the front facing camera,
with the rear facing camera,
recording video or
Now, new in iOS 10, if your app
show right alongside the
when the user 3D
And something else to note
on each of this app icons,
the device is playing haptic
when you've reached
where the quick actions
Now let's move into
at an example of Peek and Pop.
Here in messages, you can
in a conversation with a friend.
If I start to lightly apply
I can peek into it to
of that content.
Then if I continue to apply
to that photo, which takes it
with it, just like
Peek and Pop is really
to preview content and
and release your touch
to go tap the back
Now, one thing to
as we're crossing these two
and Pop, the device, again,
to let you know when you've
That's Peek and Pop.
Let's take a look now at Mail,
at some of the interesting
I want you to notice
and interruptible 3D Touch is.
As I modulate the
on the screen, as
We're using blur and scale
that you can continue to
And note how fluid
and responsive the
This is one of the
that differentiates 3D
and gesture based interactions.
So you might be wondering,
why should I support 3D
Well one of the best
that it can quickly accelerate
that your app already provides.
You saw a great example of this
letting users go straight
within your app just like deep
into the action that
But another really great
that it makes possible, brand
that were never before possible.
We're going to show you a
when we go through this new
Finally, we've adopted 3D Touch
And so users expect all of your
Let's go ahead and talk
about how you can start
with Home Screen Quick Actions.
And to do this, I'd like to
AppChat is a sample app
on to highlight some
of 3D Touch in our application.
Here you can see that 3D Touch,
sorry AppChat is an [inaudible]
You can take a photo and send
and here you can see
of different chats
I can tap on anyone of them, and
Just like that.
AppChat is a very
And we'll show you the different
for 3D Touch to it, starting
So when you press on
we'll reveal some Home Screen
You'll note, I can choose
that will open the Camera
and then choose one of
But alternatively,
of these bottom 3 quick
that will let me send
of my top three friends.
The friends that I communicate
So there are actually
of Home Screen Quick Actions.
Let's talk about them now.
The first type is Static Quick
by your app at build time.
And they're great
that are always available
For example with AppChat, we
I can always create a new chat
and then send it to
On the other hand, we have
Dynamic Quick Actions are also
to customize and
that are shown to the user.
But let's take a quick look
Static Quick Actions are defined
As such they're available
as your app has been
Now let's take a
of how we add a Static
Here's our info.plist file, you
of code, that we
and add this New
I'd like to call out
You'll notice we're specifying
that your application
on when the user selects
to know how to handle it.
We also provide a title,
And, also an icon type which
of system provided icons
So in this case that's how
One thing to keep in
to localize any user
in your info plist.strings
That's Static Quick
at Dynamic Quick Actions
So these are defined by your
from your app to the
As a result though, they're
launched your app for
Now, Dynamic Quick
after any Static Quick
You'll only get to
of four quick actions
So you'll want to
for any Dynamic Quick Actions
You can also include an
a custom icon using a template
Or you can even create an icon
from the user's address book.
This is what AppChat
in those nice profile
of those three Dynamic
for the top three friends.
Let's walk through
to see how we can
Well for this example we'll
that matches our
The first thing we want to make
from the user to
Assuming we have that
and actually query their
that matches this friend's
If we get at least one match,
to our UIApplicationShortcutIcon
That will go ahead and create
with this quick action.
But of course we may not
permission to access
or we may not have found
So we'll want to
in this case we'll use
to display as the icon.
Now that we have
and create our actual
In this case we'll need to
to how you saw with the
As well as a subtitle,
and then we'll pass all of these
over to our [inaudible]
initializer to create our
From here, we can continue to do
to create any additional
And when we're done,
in a nice array,
to UIApplicationsShortcutItems
This has the effect
of registering these Dynamic
so that they can display
One thing to keep in mind is
that this shortcutItems property
only contains your app's
or Dynamic Quick Actions.
The Static Quick Actions
in your info.plist and won't
Let's take a look at how all
of this comes together
Fantastic, with just those few
to create one Static
as well as three different
One for each of our
There's now one more thing
that's of course to
when the user selects one.
There are two different
The first one is if your
and is being activated,
in the inactive or
In this case we'll
on UIApplicationDelegate,
application
completionHandler.
In here, we'll use the
in to actually handle
Now this could mean many
and which quick action you have,
but generally you're
to a particular screen
If you handle the quick
to call the completion
that indicates whether or
Great, that's the
The second scenario
if the app was actually launched
So in this case our
Here we'll use the
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
on UIApplicationDelegate.
Inside, we'll access
of the launchOptions dictionary
if our app was launched
If it was, we'll go ahead
just as we would
And then we'll make sure to
that tells the system we did
here, and it will prevent
on the previous slide.
That's pretty much all there is
and handling both dynamic
But let's review some of the
First, every app should
as you see here they're
and they provide great
on the Home screen,
to those key activities
As such, you'll want to focus
to the highest value tasks
Remember you only
to display quick actions.
So decide wisely
To help you with
to use Dynamic Quick
to keep your quick
Users are going to be quickly
Actions and choosing one.
And if you're doing things
that'll probably
and they'll find a
One interesting thing to
you should be prepared to
from a previous version
The reason is, if you remember,
Dynamic Quick Actions don't
and has the ability to
So if your app was
it will still be showing
from the previous version.
As a result, if the semantics of
it's a good idea to keep
and to do this you might want
to consider including
in the info plist, I'm sorry,
that you can include with
Finally, try not
to add functionality that's only
And remember, not all of
and even on ones that
to disable 3D Touch
in the accessibility
With that, I'd like to invite
about Peek and Pop, Peter.
[ Applause ]
Go for it.
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tyler.
I'm really excited to talk to
As Tyler showed you earlier,
to quickly preview and navigate
And I can speak from
that it changes the
We're going to talk through
that Tyler showed
As Tyler showed you,
AppChat is a standard UIKit app.
So tapping on one of the
brings me to the message so I
A general rule of thumb
to your app is that if user
to navigate to it, it should
So let's apply that
That means that when I apply
in this table, we
In our API, we refer
because we're getting a
that we could navigate to.
Now if we continue
that'll Pop full screen,
In our API, we refer to this as
to navigating to
Cool, so let's go
of a Peek and Pop interaction.
First and foremost, we have
this is the View Controller
that contains the user
that we'd like to preview.
In our case, these are
Each registered View Controller
these are individual
that each have their own
In AppChat, this is a natural
Finally, we have the
this is the View Controller that
which represents the element
Usually this is the same
after tapping on that content.
So tapping on it, and previewing
shows us the same content.
So with that, I'd like to
how we adding Peek
which will closely
and Pop to your app.
So we're going to start off in
Remember this is that
which contains our
We're going to conform
to the
Delegate protocol.
This delegate will
at various stages during
to provide information
It's really easy to implement.
Next, we'll want to make sure
A great time to do
We're going to
with ourself as the delegate,
passing our tableView
Because the tableView
for all the interfaced elements
Now let's go ahead and implement
methods in the previewing
The first is for providing
This will provide
for a particular location
The method is called
ViewControllerForLocation,
First, we're going to find the
that we were passed in
We can do this by hit
Next, we're going to
with the model object
this is logic that you
and did select row at indexPath.
Next, and this is
we're going to set
of the previewingContext.
Remember, the sourceView
and we want to make sure to
screen, in that beautiful
that Tyler showed you.
By setting the sourceRect the
out that element and
it looks really great.
Finally, we'll return
to the system.
Now there are two
about this delegate method that
The first is that this method
think we're going to
As Tyler said before, we want
and fluid, so we're going
to make sure everything's ready.
As a result, you need to make
when returning a
If there's asynchronous
in the background, before
do that there, and don't
This will keep things feeling
as we apply pressure
to interface elements
The second important piece
about this method,
UIViewControllerOptional, that
If you return nil
we won't lift any
we won't do any blurring, we
we won't do a preview.
But you should make
if there truly is nothing
You should make sure that
in your app is previewable
this way people won't be
to get a preview, because
previewable similarly.
Great, so with that,
we've implemented the preview
But we're not done yet.
We need to implement the
on this protocol, which is
This one's even easier
it's called previewingContext
This will be called by the
we've crossed that
we're going to place
so let's get the
Here, we're going to do whatever
that ViewController on screen.
AppChat is a simple UIKit app
so we're just going
This will have the
of pushing the ViewController
But there's something really
UIKit has made it so that
of ViewController transition in
onto the navigation stack,
even move the ViewController
Do whatever it is you need
that ViewController on screen,
and UIKit will handle the
So great, we've implemented
and now we've got that awesome
to navigate full screen
and begin interacting
Now we've added Peek
but we can do a little
to take the experience,
Another aspect of Peek and Pop
quick actions.
And by adding these to your
to access the most
with the content shown
This is really powerful
to use your apps even
If we go back to our
we'll see that these preview
by the previewed ViewController.
This is the ViewController
to these actions because these
in that ViewController.
These are easy to add.
All we have to do is override
function, in UIViewController.
This returns an array
We can create UIPreviewActions
probably familiar with.
It resembles UIAlertAction
You just pass a title, a style
that closure when the action
Next, we'll just
of actions back to the system.
Now we've got one action here
but AppChat lets you reply
So what we really want to
into one group action.
We've got API for that too,
All you have to do is create
here we have them for all of
And then create an action
and the array of those actions.
This is a great way for you
to group related actions inside
There are two other
for the preview action
And this is through
on preview action item.
The first is the selected style
which will show a little
to let the user know that
that option previously.
Now before we came
that check mark was
so you'll be noticing that it's
but rest assured that
The other style that's
to use is the destructive style,
that an action may
You'll see that here behind
So by adding Peek and Pop,
we've taken the experience
to the next level and
that your users can have.
Let's review some best practices
for adding Peek and
First and foremost,
content that can be tapped
and Pop.
You can look to Apple's
for a great hint
Next, make sure to return
consistently from the
Similar looking content in
in a similar way.
In that same previewing
to take too long.
Remember, we don't want
because we want this interaction
Make sure to set the sourceRect
to lift the appropriate user
So, that's it for Peek and Pop.
Now I'd like to turn
to some super cool
UIPreviewInteraction.
UIPreviewInteraction lets you
which is force processing
but bring your own
And as we'll see in a moment,
Let's look at an example.
In AppChat, in our
we've got this handy Reply
On a non-3D Touch
we can tap on that Reply
of the emoji we can reply with.
And then we can tap
to send it back to our friend.
But on a 3D Touch
we can make this
and a lot more fun.
With just a few lines of code
we added something really neat.
We can apply pressure
and interactively
notice how the blur
Then while keeping my
I can slide around to pick
Hopefully we don't
And then we'll send
This type of one touch
that 3D Touch is perfect for.
Another thing that
with is accelerating actions
that can live closer
In iOS 7, we added
as an alternative
And this is more convenient
to where your finger is, you can
of the screen and slide back.
And by using 3D Touch, we
to your app's interactions.
So we can actually 3D Touch
to interactively bring
and then we can actually
by applying some more force,
and then pick an
This type of rich interaction
that can make things feel a lot
is exactly the type of thing
with UIPreviewInteraction.
UIPreviewInteraction
and Pop force processing
for the system provided
and the automatic haptic
through the stages of the
to bring the user interface.
And what's really
that people can now build
and apply that same
in the system standard
but also in the custom
with UIPreviewInteraction.
And that muscle memory will
this is really cool.
So let's walk through step
by step how you might add
We're going to start
to the
protocol.
This delegate will be informed
at various stages during
to let you know what's going on.
Next, we'll want to make sure to
Again, viewDidLoad is a
Here, we'll create our preview
and set ourselves
Now, preview interaction is
so let's talk through how
When the interaction starts,
if your delegate implements the
should begin callback, we'll
we'll begin the interaction.
Now, as the force moves
of the interaction
we'll message back your delegate
didUpdatePreviewTransition
Check it out.
These force progress
as a normalized value
And what's really important
to highlight is this is not just
Because it's using the
for Peek and Pop, we're actually
So this is not just some
As we move between these two
at every step along the way
through the interaction.
And once we reach the
we'll hear about it because
and will passed true
And, the device will
haptic feedback.
Let's go through a sample
Again the method is
didUpdatePreviewTransition
And here we're just
for the current progress
Now notice, this is actually
of UIKit technologies.
We can use it to drive a
a percent driven
or even a UIKit dynamic system.
These instantaneous updates
with all these technologies.
And if the interaction ends,
we'll want to show our
This is the first
on UIPreviewInteraction.
The second is for
it's called
This will be called whenever
or if the interaction should
For example we got a phone call,
to zero, and reset ourselves
But notice that we're doing this
we'll want to animate
to avoid things flashing
So that's how we can respond to
But remember in AppChat,
to the commit state transition
for sticking our
We can implement the
previewInteraction
:ended, to respond to our
So, when we're between the
and the preview state,
we'll call back
And once we reach the
we'll pass a progress value of
And we'll also play
then we'll begin
to didUpdateCommitTransition
from preview to commit.
This is the same sort
of progress update normalized
And, once we reach the
we'll pass a progress
and we'll play another different
Let's go through a way in which
So in our implementation
of previewInteraction
:ended, here we're going to
Again, this works
of UIKit animation
And once the interaction ends,
we'll just show our
So that's it for
Now if you're building
there's some low level
This API provides
to the force values coming
through two properties
force and maximumPossibleForce.
These values will be
that support 3D Touch,
from an Apple Pencil that
And we won't get into them
I encourage you to
for the leveraging
It's a really great talk and
So let's review.
As Tyler showed you earlier,
Home Screen Quick Actions allow
into action with many
of the common activities
And most applications
from adding Home
Next, I showed you how Peek
and quick interaction like never
with your app in
And we think that many
from adding Peek and Pop.
Finally, we looked at
which allows you to explore
that is 3D Touch, and
into the next dimension
Finally, it's important to note
on their device to
so we would highly encourage
For more information and to
that we showed you
which uses all these
check out the address behind me.
There are a few related
one on the new
which works great with
And another for leveraging the
And that's it, thank you so
of your conference, thank you.
[ Applause ]