[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
[ Applause ]
Good afternoon everyone
to app development
There are many amazing
on the App Store
And some have even been
to give a unique experience
So today I'm extremely
to tell how you could bring your
And this is done by extending
and also the functionality
This will basically let
with all your own
TVMLKit is a thoughtful
to make sure that there is some
as such that only
that you have to worry about.
In the first half of
to tell you guys how you can
in TVMLKit by extending
In the second half, my colleague
how you can enhance your apps by
to the JavaScript engine
So, let's talk about
The very first thing
when they use TVMLKit is
these are defined in the
They use XML as a way to
and when people encounter
I know this this
I can assure you we are
What TVMLKit is however, is
but that doesn't mean you are
In fact, Apple's own apps
in really subtle ways that allow
of the framework and
Let's look at, take
this is the App Store app.
The App Store theme had a
within a shelf, as you can see
provides, an image
But over here they
with custom focused behaviors.
Another example that we
with is the concept
Once again the App Store
that this button had to reflect
of an app.
Whether you're buying the app,
whether the app is being
they did all these by
And that's the common theme we
Reuse TVMLKit as much
for the parts that
So templates.
If you've used TVMLKit it
when you inject it into
up on the screen.
TV mark-up language is
all with unique names.
And when it enters the framework
This is the central registry
and is able to translate
that the rest of the
The TVInterfaceFactory
to generate user interfaces
and place them currently
And this is how TVML
So let's look at what happens
When it comes to extension
as adding your own mark-up in
It goes through the
it enters the element
but when it hits the
because we do not know
about your user interfaces,
When you've given us the user
will put it on the screen
So now that you have an idea
let's look at things in detail.
There are three steps
about when you want
and the very first thing
Mark-up in TVML is
And you have an idea of what
like on the screen.
You have to translate that
of resembles what
on the screen in mark-up itself.
In our example, we wanted a
This banner had an animated
to be able to control the
within TVML.
Therefore, this element,
myBanner has a property
Additionally, we
but because there
for additional functionality,
we could just use
and this is a form of a button.
So now that you have an idea
of what your user interface is
to tell the framework about it.
And this is as simple
as registering your unique
Registration has to be done once
startup so that we're fully
that we have to take care of.
It's as simple as telling the
to associate a TVViewElement
and your custom, element name.
The TVViewElement is the base
to translate your mark-up
of the framework understands.
Along with TVViewElement,
there are two other
TVImageElement deals
and TVTextElement has special
Now that we have registered the
the third step that involves
but still we try to
with only just two steps.
The very first thing
to setup an interface
to the TVInterfaceCreating
This particular object
that vends your user
and there are some call
to implement from the
declaration that
of UI you want to return.
The next step is when we call
into your interface
configure your user
As I stressed before, reuse
because we have done a
that our elements are
and feel good onto tvOS.
So let's take a look
of what this interface
Over here I have a
that conforms to
Because we are only
for the better we are going to
existingView call back method.
Once this class has been set
to register an instance of it
Looking at makeView in detail,
we can see that TVMLKit
and a optional existingView.
So in the case of the
to inspect the element
We're particularly interested
and when we find
we create an instance
Because the myBanner has an
inspect this using the element
that the call back
and then assign it
We also know that we have
and because this is a
as asking the TVInterfaceFactory
and returning the view
Finally of course,
In the case of default
you have to return nil.
Now we've talked
what about view controllers?
TVMLKit has view controllers
of a shelf lockups that
that expands vertically.
So by using the TVMLKit
to return view controllers
for your own view controllers.
The usage is similar to
we still furnish
but an existingViewController
and we expect an
to be returned.
Now you're thinking, Aha!
Collection of views.
Collection of views has
so this is how I can
Remember this example?
The App Store theme specifically
to have a unique cell.
Of unique custom layouts
everything else, as you can see,
The titles go up
on whether the focus is
So, new in tvOS 10,
to specify your own custom
This allows you to have
and most importantly
when the cell comes into focus.
To do this there are two
The very first thing is to use
that allows you to give us
when we ask for it for
And when we build the user
we would use makeView to
configure the cell
We would provide you the custom
queued from the collection
parameter itself.
So I'd like to invite Parry on
of how this works, Parry.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jeremy.
Hi, my name is Parry and
to use custom cells in TVMLKit.
Now custom cells
if you want to use TVMLKit
and grids, but you want
to showcase your content
and focus mechanism.
So I'm going to show
that I am working
And then later on, I'm going
to make appear better.
So let's get to it.
So I'm going to switch
and I have here Xcode project
that I'm working on
Now let me talk about
It's an app that lets users
So the application
and the associated XML files are
and let me go over them
So here's one of the pages
to showcase user's photo albums.
Now you can see it's a stacked
with a background
to showcase the albums and each
by a lockup.
Now each one of these
from the album that
Other than some custom styling
to make this lockup
I have not customized
So it's kind of out
So let's run this real quick
and see what it looks
And for that I'm going to
So there's the app, that's
that I talked about.
So you see the nice
and the shelf at the bottom.
And you know, I have to say just
out of the box it
It's functional and the
of difference.
But I think it can
So, consider this, how about
from the album, to
What if we chose multiple
from that album, and use that to
Now I'm going to just
How about we create a
when the album is not
out into a nice grid when
That will be cool.
But more than that, it'll give
of what the album is about.
Because the user gets to see
Now this is a really
for having custom
So let me show you how to do it.
So I'm going to switch
and the first thing I want
to do is create a mark-up
It's kind of a translation of
of your user interface
that TVMLKit can understand.
So I have that here right
it's again a stacked
but instead of lockups,
that I have created
That's the cell that
I'm calling it flyout because
And as mentioned
I want multiple photos
I have multiple image
Now there's one important
is that for all custom cells,
with three styles, and
and a new style we've added into
Now TVMLKit uses
to give your cells a nice
And it uses TV focus
to know how much
to grow when it gets focused.
It uses this information
between shelves, and also
when the cell underneath
So now that we have the
We know we have to add this
so let's do that real quick.
So for that I'm going to
and in the method application
I'm going to quickly
that I wrote earlier,
So using this I've just
using TVElementFactory
Now TVMLKit also wants me to
by extending it, so that I can
So let's do that
So, that's all the configuration
now let's have a look at the
starting off with the
Now for custom cells you
First, the
this is required to map
to the collectionViewCellClass
And second, makeView,
to configure your cell
So let's quickly fill in these
that I've written before.
So there goes the
with the collectionViewCellClass
And similarly, the
that collectionViewCell
Now an important
that the existing view
because TVMLKit just dequeued it
from the collection view
So it's always going to be
Now before I jump into the
let's have a look at the
So that's the
that I'm using to
And as you can see, it
UICollectionViewCell, in
with TVMLKit, it's
I can use it in a native
The important point to note
of image views that it uses
And these image views are the
in our extended interface
from the TV view element.
So let's head back to
and add that code.
So that's the configuration,
but the important
I am trading over all the
and extracting the
and simply reusing TVMLKit to
Now out of the box,
really good because what
of remote images, it gives
to fit the bounds so that the
And it also gives
in case I reuse those
So reusing these TVMLKit views,
and other infrastructure
I highly encourage it.
So, with that we've configured
in TVMLKit knows
There's only one thing remaining
to the stacked document
and replace all the
that I have just added.
So I'm going to head back there,
and add my FlyoutCell.
Now there were three albums,
there are three FlyoutCells
each FlyoutCell has,
And when you add these cells,
as well, that's required,
So now that we've added
and see what it looks like now.
So I'm going to switch
and there's the flyout cell.
[ Applause ]
And you can immediately tell
then just having one
so much more immersive.
And notice that the cell
all the spacing is right,
it moves up and down as the
It just feels like it
although you added it.
So there you have it,
to implement, and it lets
to your application, by
but by also showcasing your
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Parry.
I think Parry spend more
than actually configuring
So before we continue, I'd
of what we've seen today.
The very first thing when it
to define a custom mark-up that
Register it with a
about it and are
into TV view elements.
Provide an extended
so that you can vend this user
building the UI on the screen.
And most importantly, use the
and attributes to configure your
it on the screen.
So that's all there is
to extending templates,
And we are all really excited
to see what you can
But before we continue, there
that we want you to know.
Your user interface is
within the document in TVML.
And this document can
Take for example a
as results, in a
As you search this shelf will
and the contents will change,
that's what a document
Now, when we build the user,
when document updates happen,
extended interface creator,
at the update type
and figure out what's changed.
For example, the children might
you don't really want
because that's not a nice
Instead, reuse cells, reuse
In our initial example
we weren't really
in the TVMLKit ecosystem, we
Let's see if we can change this.
It's as simple as
in this case we look at the
of the call back
out if this view is a
in this case a MyBanner view.
If it's not, we instantiate
Now because we have a TVMLKit
we have to do the right thing as
to the extended, by passing it
the existing view parameter.
Now in this particular example,
because MyBanner is
that is totally fine to
we don't really look
But if your view hierarchy
For performance reasons, we
at the update type and
That's the first line that you
Now, new in tvOS
of light and dark appearance.
If you have a custom view that
you can listen to trait
out if you're in light or dark.
We have a session,
that absolutely explains
and I highly encourage
In the case that you are
and you reuse our components,
We highly encourage you to
from the element update type.
This gives you an idea
in the light or dark appearance,
and this reuses the
and it's the only
to update your views for
Because they are TVMLKit
to reuse them.
And more importantly,
into the TVInterfaceFactory
If you have a native app
or rather you have your
and you have a TVMLKit based
with the framework itself.
This is as simple as defining
once again registering
And where we built
for a particular
return your view controller
Another way to use TVMLKit with
is by hosting the
that we provide, as
You've already learned how
to create a TV application
and I'd like to highlight that
to specify a window,
Choose the view controller
in navigation controller with.
Once you have a TV
take its navigation
An alternative to this is to
and in this particular
to specify the window parameter.
Once JavaScript starts up and
TVMLKit will do the right thing
and bring your window
And with that, I'd like to hand
to talk to you about how you can
through extending
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Jeremy.
Hi, I'm Christopher,
So we just saw how you can
in TVMLKit to use
implement your own
and collection view cells.
You can also extend the
which is powered
to implement your own app
in JavaScript or
There are three main
into the JavaScript context
of your TVML application,
First, you can simply load
at run time.
Second, you can use native
with the JavaScript context in
like invoke functions into
and forth between environments.
Third, you can take
and you can actually
to make them accessible to your
conventions in JavaScriptCore.
Let's go into detail
of these methods starting
When your TVML application
the first thing that's going
to fetch a JavaScript file
that contains the
where control will be
for your TVML application.
Startup has to wait until this
and evaluated before
If you have a large application,
up the code into separate
This is a common pattern
by allowing you to load
at any point in the
Your JavaScript libraries are
and functions that get shared
Let's take a look at the
that TVMLKit JS provides.
Generally you'd want to call
but you can actually
The function takes an
and a completion call
When your completion call back
to use the variables
that were defined
But there are a few
When you call evaluate
to execute the code,
in your JavaScript files.
So don't call evaluate scripts
Also, be careful if you
on other scripts, that you
Evaluate scripts fetches
in parallel, and then
If any of the scripts
none of the scripts
so always check the
to your completion
that your library
And finally, I'd just
that even though TVMLKit
your TVML application
So you may find some
that will be helpful to you
especially if they rely
like a global window object
Just keep that in mind.
But you don't have to limit
in your TVML applications,
into the JavaScript
From here you can do things
down into JavaScript
between JavaScript and native.
In TVML, your JavaScript context
in a class called the
JavaScript executes on a
to schedule your
In the simplest form, all you
on this TVApplicationController,
and pass in a block
When your block executes,
to the JS context, from
as JavaScript code, you can
and you can get and
into JavaScript using
Just make sure that you
or use it anywhere
Since your JavaScript is all
you also want to be careful
that you don't perform any
evaluating this block,
as you may deadlock
For more information on
please see the 2013 WWDC
Let's take a look at an
into JavaScript code from
Here we're looking
for our TVML app's app delegate.
We've implemented a stub here
for the UIApplication
to handle custom URL schemes.
If we wanted to pass this
all we have to do is
to evaluate a block in
When this block executes,
to the JSContext, from here we
on the JavaScript
We can take native values
as JavaScript properties
as a function argument.
Here, we're invoking the
that was defined in JavaScript
of the URL from the
call back.
Just like that we've
into our TVMLKit application
and exposed application
Next, let's talk about bridging.
So we just saw how super easy
and use them in JavaScript,
numbers, and arrays
for you by JavaScriptCore.
If you want to use your
to do is follow a few
and JavaScriptCore can actually
Let's take a look.
So there are three
First, you have to
that extends JSExport,
which comes from JavaScriptCore.
Second, we're going to define
and extending this
to expose our native classes.
And third, we're going to take
or the class itself that we want
on the TV application
to prepare the JSContext
over to JavaScript
Let's take a look at an
about creating a wrapper
to expose something like in
to JavaScript.
We start off by defining
here's where we'd specify
that we wanted JavaScriptCore
Here we'll just leave it
that we've extended JSExport
and defined a protocol called
Next, we will create a class
that extends NSObject and
Once again I've left the details
where you'd define your
that you wanted JavaScript
And finally, we implement the
method to evaluate app
This gets called before
and allows us to expose our
control gets handed
That's really all
We've now defined
we've gone through the
to our TVML application's
So in this session we've seen
functionality to enhance
You can extend templates
for your own views and
You can actually host TVMLKit
or use your own native view
You can even extend the
to bridge native classes, type
and load additional libraries.
I hope we've shown
to build app specific
in your TVMLKit apps
TVMLKit is a really simple
with high quality results
I encourage you to
and TVML catalog sample
on how to extend
Please also check out the
for programming guides, sample
Also, check out these other
at WWDC 2016, especially
for TVMLKit Part 1,
of building an app
Thank you, and enjoy