[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
Welcome to Session 230.
I'm Sirisha, an engineer
by my colleagues,
And we are excited to introduce
CallKit.
A lot of you here have
You have changed the
and have made the world smaller.
And you want your app to be
and receive calls on
CallKit is a framework
to elevate your third
to a first party experience.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So while a lot of you
for the next 40 minutes
and I have created a brand
So Speakerbox is a
and receive voice calls on
So before we take a look, let
So Jane has been
and her concerned parents
to make sure she's doing okay.
But because she's international
to make calls to her.
So let's see how an incoming
So this is Jane's locked screen.
And at first, she gets
And before she could
she gets an incoming
Jane can't discern
between this incoming
and the incoming phone
because that's just what
Just a notification.
And if Jane wants to
she has to slide on
and then that gets
and then she can begin speaking.
And this is Jane's
and the experience
She gets an incoming
Did you miss that
That's right.
It was just a banner
So wouldn't it be nice if
to Jane looked more like this?
This is Jane's locked
And she gets an incoming
Notice the full screen
[ Applause ]
And Jane can just
and start talking to her mom.
And from the unlock
Native UI with answer
and your custom ringtone
[ Applause ]
And wouldn't it be nice if
with other calls on the systems?
Perhaps at the telephony
or maybe another VoIP call?
And even have VoIP calls get
and even get assigned
And get started from
and even get do not disturb
That is CallKit.
[ Applause ]
All right.
So today we're going to go over
and incoming call flow, and
with some more details
So let's get started.
All right.
So over here, we have all our
Siri, CarPlay, and
And over here, we have all
These are two separate
Calls made on Speakerbox
and then our services.
In iOS 10, we have
in all our system services.
So now calls made on
to our system UI via CallKit.
So if Speakerbox wants
it needs to adopt CallKit.
So now calls made on
to our system via CallKit
and then system can
to the rest of our services.
So let's talk a little
So here we have Speakerbox
It talks to its network
and we're going to link CallKit.
So there are two primary classes
The first is the CXProvider.
So the provider is the class
to let the system about any
out of band notifications
The second class is
The CXCallController is the
to let the system know
So let's take a deeper look
at these two classes
So the provider, like I
that we use to let the
of band notifications.
That is these are
but actually external
an incoming call
Contrasts this with
The CXCallController is the
to let the system
from within the app itself.
That is these are
and like internal events,
By using the CallController,
with other calls on the system.
Say, for example, there's
and the user wants to
from Speakerbox's UI.
By using the controller,
about the start call action
and then the system can
to hold its call so as to let
So let's take a look at
So the provider is
out of band notifications.
Like, for example, an incoming
or maybe an outgoing
Or that outgoing call
Whereas the controller is
from the system like
to start an outgoing call or the
from Speakerbox or maybe ending
So when the provider
to the system it uses
And when the system
about any user interactions,
to let Speakerbox know.
And the controller communicates
to the system user actions
to let the system to know
So that was a lot
So let's take a look all of
So here we have Speakerbox
that incoming call from Mom.
The incoming call
and then Speakerbox
and using the provider
And then the system can then
to all our services
And if Jane wants to answer
the answer action
Our system can then tell
to the CXAnswerCallAction
and then Speakerbox can answer
And if Jane now wants
from within the app's own UI,
the end action comes
The controller bundles it
and that comes to the system
the system sends that back up to
and then Speakerbox can
All right.
Now let's take a look all of
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Sirisha.
So now that you've heard
I'd like to show
in an existing VoIP
which Sirisha mentioned.
I'll first show you how to adopt
So I'll first open up the
Now before I dive into
let me just show
about how the app is structured
so you have a frame
So we have two main classes
The SpeakerboxCallManager class
in the app and has
such as starting a
And our other primary
This is our model class which
in the app and has
as some call back blocks
about the life cycle events
So like Sirisha mentioned,
when adopting CallKit is
to create a CXProvider
So I'll do that by
called ProviderDelegate.
So into this new file,
that we've already
through what this is doing.
So in our initializer
to the SpeakerboxCallManager
This allows the ProviderDelegate
of calls and references them
Next, we have -- we create
and we pass it -- something
which we see here.
The provider configuration
into more detail later in the
to configure to the
about how it should behave.
Now back in our initializer, we
of our provider and
we request authorization
So great. So now we have our
but we need to create
So I'll declare a property
and I'll instantiate that in
launching with options method.
Cool. So now we have
How does the app respond
So if I scroll down, we can see
that the app currently
about an incoming call
And if we look at what
we can see that it looks
from our push notification
about the incoming call
which is an identifier
And then we call the
and we can see here that this is
where the app hosts the
to show the user
But when using CallKit
on a local notification
We can, instead, use the
incoming call UI and we want
so much richer of an experience.
So to do that, I'll go back
and I'm going to
which will allow us to call
I'll call that report
I'll start by creating
which contains metadata to
And then we'll call the
on our provider and this is the
about that incoming call.
Now, in the completion block,
and if there wasn't, we create
and configure it and we add that
We'll go into more detail
about why there could be an
to say, there's certain
in which the device
to accept an incoming call.
Okay. So now that we
on our ProviderDelegate, I'll
and just replace this code that
with a call to our helper.
So great. So now
to report an incoming
about from a push
and the system is showing the
call UI.
Well what happens when the
and answers the incoming call?
When that happens,
our ProviderDelegate will
that we need to implement.
And that is the
method.
Let me walk through
So we start by getting
of our Speakerbox call class
of the call that
Next, we call the answer
and this is some code that
and this talks to our
to actually answer that call.
And now we do it here in our
And last, we call
In CallKit, every action
if it was successful or
in processing in that.
And we can actually see
if we were unable to find a
we call the failed
to indicate that to the system.
So this method handles
about when the user
For that, we have a similar
ProviderPerformEndCallAction.
And this is very similar.
It looks up a call
It talks to our network using
It signals that that
to the system by
And it removes the call from
So we're almost done
but there's one other
when handling that
And that is our call's audio.
So when using CallKit, you will
audio session directly.
Instead you will only
and the system will actually
session for you at
So let me show you
Back in our
I'll insert a call to
audio session.
And this does like it says,
it configures the
but does not activate it.
Instead our audio session will
and after that happens,
we'll receive a delegate
didActivate audioSession.
And this is the point where
call's audio.
Now the last step is to stop
in the PerformEndCallAction
Okay. So that's all
to handle an incoming
And now I've got on my device
and let's build and run
So for the purpose of this demo,
I'll just simulate an
at the bottom.
And now when I press this,
we'll see our call using
full screen Native
And I can just accept that call
and our ProviderDelegate
PerformAnswerCallAction method.
It fulfills that and then
to Jane I can just end the call
fulfills that as well.
So that's a demo of handling
And I'll now pass
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Stuart.
So let's take a look at
So first, we reported
to the system via the report
Then we handled an
by implementing the delegate
call action.
Then once we've actually
that action by calling
So CallKit can do more
Here a list of all our other
As you can see, there's holds,
So now let's spend a few seconds
So say Speakerbox can
Right here, in this example,
there's already an active
and then there's an
Now if the user wants
and the answer incoming waiting
the system will send
A CXTransaction is nothing
of one or more actions.
In this case, it's a list
And once Speakerbox has handled
of these actions, it
of them individually so
to transition the UI.
All right.
Now I'll hand this
through an outgoing call flow.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Sirisha.
So let's check back
She talked to her mom yesterday
but today she's feeling a little
in with the home front.
So let's see what it takes
So the first thing that happens
and taps to call her mom back is
with a start call intent.
Now some of you may have already
session where we introduced
like to find out
you can always watch
In a nutshell though,
that represents a
is wrapped up in
and then passed back to our app.
So our app has received
and now we've constructed
on the information
We'll take that action
and request it via
The CallController will
through to the system and if
to our app via the
Then finally our app
and use the necessary
to make that outgoing call.
So now let's take a
of the outgoing call
So we've just begun performing
So the call is in
From here, we'll finish
and fulfill the action to move
Then when the remote
we'll notify the provider that
And then finally,
that the call has connected
that the two parties can
So now I'd like to
back up to give us another demo.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Nick.
So now I'd like to give
of adopting CallKit
This time how to use it to
I'll open up the Speakerbox
Now back in our app
we can see that Speakerbox
with a URL to start a new call.
But when using CallKit,
the process of dialing an
but when the user starts a call
recents tab, or a
the app will be launched with
to us via an NSUser activity.
So the first step in
to implement the application
And taking a look at
we look at our NSUser
of the startCallHandle property.
This is some code we've
at the NSUser activity, get the
which is a string
which represents the
Now once we have our handle,
the process of starting
to the URL handler above.
We just call the start call
So now let's look at what
So we can see in the
that we start a call by
of our model class,
and then we call the
which talks to our network
And finally we add this
But now this is not yet using
about our intention
And we need to do that.
So I'm going to remove this
to add parts of it back later.
The first step of adopting
to import the framework.
And then I need that second
the CXCallController class.
And now that I have that,
I need to create a
with the handle that
Then I create a CXTransaction
and finally I call
on our callController to
Now just to reiterate a point
you maybe wondering why we need
from the system when it seems
like everything that's
within our own app.
And the reason for that
to begin an outgoing call,
there may already be a call
For instance, if the user is
or even a call from
If that happens, the
that call before
So that's why we need to
to let it know about
So now, once the system receives
and improves our start call
that back to our app via
So I need to implement
on our ProviderDelegate class.
This time it's the provider
And let's fill this
So we start same
of creating a Speakerbox
and configuring it
which we're going to dial.
Then we configure our audio
when answering a call
we need to configure a few
And there's a lot
so let's walk through it.
We set two call back
The
and hasConnctedDidChange.
These are asynchronous call back
when the call progresses
to connecting and
And in these call back blocks,
we report to the system
And it allows the system
and reflect it in the UI.
So with that set, we can now
method on our call.
And this again, talks
and it starts it outgoing.
We fulfill the action to
and add the call to
Okay. So this handles starting
about when the user wants to
from within our own --
So for that, we need to go back
to our Speakerbox
and look at the end method.
And we can see here that just
like the start call
this is not yet using CallKit.
So I need to replace
I'll just drag this in and we
to call action and it
and then requests
from the callController.
But this time, we don't need
in our ProviderDelegate
we already implemented
So that's all the code that we
and I'll now build and
And give you another demo.
So I've built and updated
but to show you an
like to go back to the phone
And we can now see the
on the contact card and I just
And when we do, our
It will receive that intent
and it will start a call
It will request a transaction
by the system and fed
which will then fulfill
And here we go.
We just saw that happen.
The call is now active.
So now once the call is
we can see something new.
For the first time, the green
shown for our app.
Previously this was
and FaceTime calls
we'll be sent right
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Then when I'm done
and this will request an end
which our ProviderDelegate
So that's all demo for handling
I'll pass it back to
over a few other API details.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Stuart.
So first let's take a quick
The first thing that happened is
intent, created a start call
and then requested
Then the start call
ProviderDelegate,
And then finally, Speakerbox
to connecting and then
So, now that we've seen a few
of the details of the
out our usage of CallKit.
And in particular, we'll take a
and configuration to
in the native UI.
We'll take a look at how
and system restrictions and
at how CallKit plays a role in
So as with other APIs like
CallKit requires permission
And because of this,
that your app should do when it
authorization status.
This may have changed since the
If the user went into settings
and maybe enabled or
Then from here, if you discover
that your app's authorization
yet been determined, you
for your app.
And what this does is it tells
to the user to request
And this is done on behalf of
on behalf of your app,
to include an informative usage
And lastly while
you should always be sure
to any authorization status
so that you can always show the
So now let's talk about
So the provider configuration
to customize its in
in the Native and Call UI.
Some of the things that can
localized name to
This also includes
such as whether your app
And this even includes things
like specifying your own masked
in one of the buttons
And when tapped, this will take
Just a note though
for this app icon
in a future seed [phonetic].
So we've taken a look at what
when executing actions
when we run into a problem?
Well take a look at the
We've just started performing
Let's say that in the process
of performing that,
Maybe we don't have
with our network server,
so we can't actually
Well in this case, we should
And the reason this is important
that something went wrong.
And then the system
inform the user via things
And along with these action
So each action on the
out associated with it.
And these time outs are
that actions initiated
in a performance and
So because of this, your
to perform those actions
However, if an action
your app will be notified via
method at which point it
So based on the current
certain system restrictions
And we'll take a look at an
One of the reasons
your app's incoming call
the user has disabled your app
Or maybe the remote caller
in the user's blocked list.
Or perhaps the user has enabled
to see any incoming calls
Well for all of these cases,
you app will be notified via
For example,
the reportNewIncomingCall
in its completion handler.
And as you can see here,
that's returned.
Sees that the error code is
and then handles
So now let's take a look
So with CallKit your app
with its call's audio.
And one of the biggest
that its audio session will
on the system on par with
And what this means
on the system will not be able
to interrupt your
And in addition to
of certain audio routing
which means it can decide where
like the user's current
or currently connected
Let's take a look at an incoming
We know that, at some point,
during an incoming call our
action and then fulfill
Well after receiving the answer
to configure our audio session.
And that's because we know
that the call will
Then when we fulfill
the system will automatically
for our app at a
and then let our app know
that this has happened via
provider delegate call back.
And this is an indication
to start media for the call.
So that was just a quick look at
to help us complete our
So now we invite
in your existing VoIP apps
from the ground up
With CallKit you'll
into the system's
and once you've adopted CallKit
with native calling services.
But most importantly,
with CallKit your app will
across the system whether
incoming alerts on the locked
favorites, and contacts,
CarPlay, and Bluetooth.
For more information you can
at developer.apple.com
where we'll also have the
that we've been referencing
We've got a lot of great
So be sure to check out more
networking, and audio.
Thank you all so
and we'll see you in the labs.
[ Applause ]