[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
And thanks for checking
My name is, Dave Browning.
And here with me today
And we're going to be,
we're both engineers
And we're going to be
about some best practices
when building your
So, what are we going
Well, first I'm going to
at Apple use CloudKit.
We'll talk about the work
in order to provide a seamless
And by that I mean, allowing
in their applications
Next, Nihar is going to come
when using the CKOperation API.
And the configurability
and flexibility you can
Then he's going to
to consider when data modeling.
What you're going to
How you're going to store it.
How you're going to
And then he'll talk
which we've always
in CloudKit applications.
He's going to cover the
that you'll encounter
and how to consider
on your application's use case.
So, a quick reminder, we here
or built many applications
And so you can be confident
because we've scaled it to
I also want to do
about the conceptual model.
So, the highest level, we have
This is usually a one to one
So, the photos application
the notes application,
Inside of the container
This is where you can store
So, an example of
or the news app in iOS.
They're built on CloudKit.
They use a public database
that kind of stuff
Next there's the
This is where you store data
That user can see their data
but no other users can see it.
And then new this year
If you want to learn more about
and check out the video
on What's New in CloudKit.
And they do a deep dive
Inside of the database
And there's a default zone, and
where if you throw records
that's where they'll end up.
But, you can choose in
to create 1 or more
And you can store
And then when content is shared
that shows up as a shared
which you can think of
to the custom zone and the
And then of course if multiple
in multiple custom zones
up potentially seeing
in the shared database.
And now what I'm going to focus
in a custom and shared zones
that we're talking
Finally at the lowest
This is your key value structure
And a record always
So, a quick reminder on the
at the high level, you focus
and not worried about
We do that for you.
Your users get what we like to
That means, if they're signed
you do not need to prompt them
or any of the stuff that can
to using your application.
If they're signed into
you immediately have a uniquely
And you can start storing
And then finally, what the
that same data, your users can
of their devices when
All right.
So, let's talk about the
when we're building our
And so what happens is, you have
in this example let's
So, Notes is built on CloudKit.
They create a note on
that's stored over to the cloud.
And then when they open up
maybe on a second
it feels like that data was
And it's already
And if they make
it feels like it's just
So, that's sort of the use
at providing for our users.
So, the way to think
the servers are the
your devices have a local
And then CloudKit, the API is
All right.
So, how does this actually work?
Well, basically when
the work flow we recommend is
that you fetch changes
Especially the first
because you don't know if
that the user wrote
All right.
So, you talked to the server.
You fetched down any data
And then you insure that you're
By subscribing to future
the server, to send
to your applications
And then of course
you'll want to fetch
down the new changes
from the users other device.
All right.
So, let's dig into these
so subscribing to changes.
The way this work is, when
for the first time, and we'll
but when it's launched
you create a subscription
here is the set of data I
And then when that data
When your application
on another device the
for the user on the server.
But, your app doesn't know that,
because it's launching
So, you need to make
So, you'll do the same thing
that you did before
Now that you're subscribing
and CloudKit is sending
you want to listen for
So, let's walk through
The user writes a new note.
The application stores
The servers says, ah ha, there's
They wanted to know
It says it came from the iPhone.
So, I don't need
But, the user also had an iPad.
So, it looks up the proper Apple
Talks to APNS on your
to send a push to the iPad.
So, you don't have to deal
with sending pushes
So, then finally your
What does it do next?
Well, as we said, now it goes
and fetches the new
So, it talks to CloudKit,
updates its local cache, and
bam, they see the same stuff
All right.
So, let's look at
Let's walk through the code,
to make all of this happen.
So, first we'll talk about
So, remember what I said before.
This is one of those
to do the first time
So, you'll notice we have
of our code that says, have we
The fact that we've already
because if we've already
to keep doing it
You save yourself
You save the user
All right.
So, if we haven't
let's look in the
So, new this year in iOS 10,
there's an API called
This allows you to
across an entire
in a private database,
So, in this example let's focus
So, you can give a
which allows you
And we'll talk about
But, in this case
with a shared database let's
Next you need tell CloudKit what
when this subscription triggers.
And so let's dig into the
So, the first one that we
in most cases is a
And the way to do that in our
You can set the notification
info object.
And if you set the property,
to true, and only that property,
the back end will send a
for this subscription.
And the key to this is
to prompt the user
So, we've had people
we have this subscription,
You guys have seen it, allow
And a lot of people
You don't get pushed and
If you do it this
to be alerting the
So, you don't need to
And then finally you can listen
for these notifications
RegisterForRemoteNotifications.
So, if you do want to send a UI
or banner, or make a sound,
of these 3 properties.
And that will tell CloudKit to
because you will be alerting
for user acceptance
And then of course you
in the same way as before.
So, a little bit of fine print.
If you read the APNS
that pushes can be
on the conditions of the device.
So, that means if a subscription
to your user's device, there
bad network, etcetera where
But the coalescing piece
at least one of those.
So, what that means is, you
as a way to tell your
because if 5 pushes were sent
you're going to miss
Instead, think of push
that something changed.
One or more things.
And that's why we need
to figure out what those were.
And the good news is the
to ask for only what
So, you don't have to pull down
All right.
Let's jump back into our code.
Remember we're creating
And in this case we've set
by doing
to true.
Now, we need to take
and ask the CloudKit client
And you're probably
if you've used CloudKit.
But, the way you do
And in this example, we do a
And we tell it about the
And this is the one
With CloudKit because the
to the server over the network,
of time, everything
So, that means all of
completion blocks.
They get called once
And so in this case, we
completion block.
And the first thing
of your completion blocks,
I know we say this all the
And Nihar is going
in a bit more detail about this.
But, in this case, let's just
then we know that the
Now we can locally cache the
so that we don't
because of that check
Quick note, and Nihar is
CKOperations inherit from
in Swift 3, and so
to set this quality
And the default is utility.
And he'll talk about some
in mind when setting this.
And then finally, the way
to actually finally take this
to send it back, is to add it
And again because we're doing
in this case, we add it
to the shared database's
And the client will now go off
Okay. So, we're subscribed
So, now the next step
since CloudKit will
when data is changed
So, you want to make sure
that in Xcode you've
And you want to check the
And potentially background
to do this while your
Once you've done that, there's
that you might be familiar with,
which is applicationDidReceive
fetchCompletionHandler.
This method gets passed
And CloudKit provides
if you can get a CKNotification
So, if you can, remember
for other reasons.
But if it's coming from
you'll be able to
And now we can check
So, the reason this is important
to end up having a
for the private database,
and maybe for other things.
So, this is how you
which subscription
So, in this case let's say
Now we can go off and
And we'll talk about
And when that's done, we
that was passed into
Okay. So, now we are
And let's say some time later
So, what do we do?
Remember what we said.
You need to fetch new changes.
And so let's look at
of sort of how this works.
So, we got to push
And we said, okay, that's
There are sort of 2
The first one is, you
for which zones changed
Remember we talked about
because there may be
up that you don't
because someone shared
And you pass along a
that tells the server
And we'll dig into
Step 2 is, now with the no
and say, okay, please
where changed inside of
And again you have change
where in history your
All right.
So, let's talk about
in a bit more detail.
So, imagine your
the iPhone we were
they're using your application,
and they send some
Those changes are accepted,
that point in history.
It does that with the
And in this case for simplicity
That device sends down
that are accepted, goes to
Sometime later user runs
Let's say that iPad we
And the first thing
remember on app launch
for any changes that
So, it goes and says, I would
like to fetch the
The server says,
Here's what exists.
And at the end of that it says,
you are now at server
So device 2 has now marked
Now let's say device 2 then
Somewhere along the way
Device 1 fetches
And at the end of that
you're now at change token E.
All right.
Device 2 makes another
Device 1 gets a push,
it's now at change token I.
Now you'll notice that device
And that's because when you're
change tokens back.
You don't get those until
So, let's say device
or they restart their
Your app launches up.
You go and fetch changes.
The server will send you
from that device, because
that locally cached or
All right.
So, don't be surprised if
This allows you to confirm
And now at the end of
out a change token, I.
And you notice that both devices
They have same server
So, that's sort of an
Okay. So, let's look at
for fetching these changes.
So, in this case we're going
So, a new API, iOS 10 is
And again you pass in
that we just talked about.
And the first time you ever
and it will tell the server
And it will give you everything
Next, in previous
at the end of this operation
to see if the server said that
Now, we'll talk about
But, if that was set to
on the client's side to
But, what we've done is,
on these operations
And it defaults to true.
And what it does is, it tells
that on your behalf so that
So, if after running
if the client sees that
it will automatically enqueue
And of course call your
so that you don't have to
Next, you want to implement
recordZoneWithIDChangeBlock.
And this is where you will
that changed in the
So, you'll want to collect
about what to do with
Next, there is,
This tells you about the zones
that no longer exist
And allows you to clean up
in those zones from before.
And you'll see this
where something was
because that zone no longer
And then new is, a
So, let's dig into this.
So, remember before we had
down in the server.
We had device 2 had
And then sometime way later,
device 3 for this
And remember the first
go talk to the server
And because fetchAllChanges
it's asking for everything.
But, there might be a lot of
Right. And the server might
to send all of this back
So, we're to chunk it up.
So, it's going to send
The CloudKit client will see
that there's more
So, it needs to go back
and issue another
But, before it does that, it's
and tell you that you're
And this allows you to sort
as it's making its operations.
So, you update your local change
of the stuff you've
So, let's say this client,
there's more stuff
Let's go back and get it.
See some new data.
At the end of that calls
see if there's new data, goes
But, this time there's an error.
In your error handling, it's
up calling fetchChanges again.
But, instead of starting
because you have a
your local change
So, when you call your next
you only need F through I.
You don't need the old stuff
So, that's why it's important
to implement the
And you just cache the
like you normally do.
And then finally we have
which in this case is,
fetchDatabaseChanges
Again, the first thing
Again, Nihar will
And then you'll get
which in that last example
would have been the
Cache that just like
And so now we've
that changed in that database.
Now we need to go fetch
That was step 2 in
And we do that via new API,
CKFetchRecordZone
And it allows you to pass
So, you don't have to worry
for all the different
You call one, pass in all
And we won't dig into the code,
but it looks very
You're going to have
where you're dealing with
And you'll be getting
All right.
So, quick recap on
So, you subscribed to changes
to receive pushes when
on another device.
You've listened to those
And when you receive one, you've
and fetched exactly
And by doing this, your
that seamless experience
across all of their devices.
All right.
So, now Nihar's going
into some more specific
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Dave.
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for coming out today.
My name is, Nihar Sharma.
And I'm an engineer
And today I'm very
with you some CloudKit
that we've learned here at
that you can take advantage
Let's take a look at what
First, I'd like to talk about
Dave touched on this briefly.
I'd like to go into a little bit
How you can take
Next, I'd like to talk
which is the workhorse of our
Then we'll dig into a couple of
when designing the
that will help you
of the CloudKit API
And finally, we've told you
error handling is to
And I'd like to reiterate
And talk to you about a few
and how your application
So, let's get started.
First up, automatic
Now, you might be familiar
where on first launch
of private information
even before the user has
Well, we think in CloudKit
to increase the chances of
without requiring any
The way we do this is via
As a reminder, this user
for every user that when
that is logged into
In this manner it is unique
And it offers you a stable
that is stable across
OS upgrades, etcetera.
So, you can save this
and start building a profile
And when you notice
with your apps a lot more, then
to enrich their profiles.
The way you access
for the current user is
CompletionHandler
So, that was automatic
Now, let's talk about
As a recap, there
in which the CloudKit framework
One is via convenience
which work on one
And the other is via those
So, in this manner, every
that we expose, that
has a CKOperation counterpart.
And that works on a
So, for example, we have
on CKDatabase to fetch
And we have its corresponding
that takes an array
and fetches them in a batch.
Now, there's certain advantages
that you get over
I'd like to walk through
So, first and foremost,
CKOperation is a
What this means is that,
of the NSOperation API
You can do things like,
between your CKOperations.
You can assign the
to let the system know how
to you, or even manage queue
on your own NSOperation queues.
And you even get
that have already
So, I'd like you
and read up the documentation
to take full advantage
A great reference for this is
that we gave at WWDC last year.
So, now since we're talking
there are a few more things
And I'd like to touch upon 3
First, is the configurability
Next is, how it lets you
for the system, and
And last, I'd like to talk
which is something new
to be able to do in iOS 9.3.
So, first up, a quick recap
on just what you can
Operations let you have
or not you wish network
to go out over cellular.
You can also specify keys for
from the server if you want
to download just partial records
which the community's
You can even limit
that a particular
And finally, long running
progress updates
to drive certain UI elements.
Now, let's talk about
The number 1 resource
on the system are
Now, every convenience
into at least 1 network
So, when you use the CKOperation
to minimize the number of
to send your changes
So, for instance, if you want
and you use a
the system will take
to optimize a request needed
So, now in this manner
for the system resources,
but it also helps you optimize
as developers.
Additionally, by default
network activity into
What we mean by this is that,
you let the system
for your request
For more information I
out the discretionary property
The way we expose this to you on
of service properties.
So, by default, CKOperations
of service utility.
Any QOS, which is utility
to this discretionary behavior.
So, if you notice that your
longer time to execute than
because the system does not
for your request to go out yet.
Now, additionally there
that you should keep in mind.
When opting into
network failures will be
And along with that, by default
for every single request
So, that was resource
Now, let's talk about
On our platforms, there are
application may exit.
For instance, you might be
and be evicted, or a user
Now, you might have certain
happened, which were
and you really want to just
Regardless of whether
or you might have a
at a lower priority that
or not your app sticks around.
So, to serve this purpose in iOS
of CloudKit long-lived
What these operations
once you mark them long-lived,
that operation on your
or not your app sticks around.
We will cache any
for that operation, and
to be able to replay those
So, let's take a look at
to be able to do this.
Well, on CKOperation it's
You have an isLongLived flag.
So, you create a
Once you've set this
into a long-lived operation.
Along with that you
which is a system
that uniquely identifies
And we will take a look
at why that's important
So, here's the general
of how you run a
You initialize an operation
You just set the
along with your arguments
and you run the operation.
Now, when you wish to
that long-lived operation
from the CKContainer class
You will set the callbacks
if you're interested
And you would run that
Let's take a look at an example.
Let's say we wish
fetchRecordsOperation.
So, we set up the operation
like we did normally
But, we remember to set
And we save the operation ID
so that we'd remember what
We set up the callbacks, and
Now, when you wish to resume it,
you can use the
with ID API available
to fetch that operation.
And since you know what
and from your cache,
and set the appropriate
You do not need to set the
of the other operation
that you might have previously,
and you've resumed
Now, CloudKit will then replay
back for that operation.
And either catch you
that the operation has made
or give you the entirety of
And what this also means is that
That's important sign.
And normally this happens
of that operation is called.
You must note that your apps
to resume any long-lived
that they might have enqueued.
So, that was all
Now, let's switch gears and
There's 3 main tips that
The first one is around
How you can use them and how
CloudKit API more effectively.
The second one is
to avoid a certain class of
in your CloudKit apps.
And lastly I'd like to talk
which are a new type of
in this release to
So, let's talk about
Let's take an example of
Now, the first thing
on a server this app is
where you store a user's
that they've taken on one of
Now, let's say when the
while you're fetching changes
you wish to display
of all the user's
Something like this,
Then it seems like an awful
to be able to download
that entire high resolution
to load this page.
So, what can you do here?
Well, it's pretty
You can think about adding a
which represents the
And what this allows you to
of CKOperation and the
that we talked about,
to fetch partial records.
You can now fetch just the key
that your user's interested in.
You can even set the
to limit just the
that you're showing
So, in this manner, you can
to be able to present a
You fetch only what is
And the desired keys
on the new CKFetchRecordZone
as well as
both of which fetch items
Now, as a reminder, these
on the web via CloudKit JS.
So, by using them,
to have a more dynamic
because they're not waiting
that are downloading data
Next, let's talk
As a quick reminder,
Well, they're CloudKit's
to point records
So, for instance, if
Record A and record B, we
initializing it with record B.
We've created a CKReference.
Now, let's say we wish to add
which can contain
So, how would we go
about modeling this
Well, in a simple manner,
that this might be a good
Storing the record ID's, the
that are part of
on the album record
This is what that
Now, let's take a look at what
for your user try to add albums,
try to add photographs
So, let's say we have an
that does not have
Now, remember that
to have multiple devices.
They all fetch this
See that it has no photos.
They're happy with it.
Now they have photos.
They each have photos that they
So, now they in-queue that
Let's say our iPhone
And now the server knows
the references to one
But, now when the other
to make their updates, they're
version of the server record.
So, in this case, both of those
CK error serverRecordChanged.
Now, I invite you to take a look
from WWDC '14 for more details
on how you can handle
But, let's see if we
where we can avoid it entirely.
Well, in this case we know
to have frequent rights on it.
So, instead if we model our
back pointer by storing the
that is part of that album,
we completely eliminate
that we had on our album record.
So, in this case whenever a
you just set a reference
that it's a part of and
But, by doing this you've
contention that you
And now you might wonder, well,
which is part of my
Well, you can use
Here's a query that
to fetch all photo records
It's pretty straight forward.
All you need to do is equate
that you have on
Next let's talk about
On CKRecord this year,
of reference called
that will help you
that better supports
What we'd like to
if your app supports sharing,
to set up a hierarchical
Recognize the unit of
up the parent references
Let's take a look at an
Our photo and album
of using a parent reference.
An album is clearly a
So, all we need to do is
on the photo record to
and save that photo record.
Now, let's say that we've used
and we end up with a
And now a user comes
to share this entire album.
Well, all you would need
create a CKShare with that album
And in one fail swoop you will
that you set up using
Now, CloudKit also supports
So, in this case, if a
to share photo C, for example.
You could have created a
And in this case, only the photo
up via parent references
And that was data modeling.
Let's talk about error handling.
Now, there are a few
and your application
in a few main different ways.
And let's take a
So, let's say we
where your device comes along
and you chose a
and tries to talk to the server.
There are 2 main things that
It could either say that, I
please don't try it
that everything was
but right now is
Come back a little
Now, we need your apps to
in very different ways.
And let's take a
The first kind of error,
you really can't do much.
There are a couple
which indicate a fatal error.
For example, internalError,
invalidArguments, or
In this case, we want you
to your user in your
that something went wrong,
However, the other
where the server wants you
and time, we will tell
that the server wishes
Here are a couple of error
of time embedded in them.
ZoneBusy, serviceUnavailable,
When you receive any of these
for the CKError RetryAfterKey
in the errors users
You should wait for
and reinitialize
with the same arguments,
Here's all the code you need for
for that period of
by the CKErrorRetryAfterValue.
And reinitialize the
Now, what happens in some cases
when your operations
on the device before even
There are 2 main cases that
where CloudKit may be
The first one is when
Well, in this case,
that you monitor network
like you would for any
If you're using a quality
or above, such that a
automatically retried for you,
you will see this error code
So, once you're monitoring
which you can do via the
for example, in system
you can then let the
these changes are not going
But, we recommend that you let
with your app while
You should save these changes
And when your reachability API
online, then you enqueue
to save those records
The other main state
to use the private
and the user is not logged
In this case we will
code CKErrorNotAuthenticatedTo.
And what we recommend
on first launch always
to the CKAccount
When it fires use
with CompletionHandler API
to research the account
And let them know that
because they don't have an
So, in summary, let's take a
We saw how to subscribe
to efficiently stay up
We saw the advantages of using
which we recommend all
We saw a couple of tips on
to completely avoid a
or to use the CloudKit
And finally, we saw how to
And how to differentiate
And what the server
with certain error code
Now, we had a related
If you could not check it
and look at it online.
More information
Thank you and have a great day.
[ Applause ]