[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everyone,
[ Applause ]
Thank you for attending this
I'm an internationalization
and today with my
we're going to talk about
So let's get started.
At Apple we support over 40
and every language has its
in particular, we are going to
to left languages
which are Arabic and Hebrew.
So this language has
in building your apps and
of the writing direction.
So why are we talking about
With over 400 million
this really is a growing market.
So just last year, we
in the UAE these are images
Dubai and just few weeks ago,
in Arabic for the first time.
This is really, really exciting,
As a developer, you have growth
and designing word ready apps
for your customers
So in this session we're mainly
to left languages, but if you
about designing word ready
Inclusive App Design,
on the human interface
and Internationalization Best
about internationalization.
Last year, on iOS 9 we extended
to fully support languages
And just after that, we
and Arabic localizations
This year I'm happy to say
on redesigning macOS
So now, I would like to
the agenda to see what we
So first, Joaquim is going
of the APIs we introduced last
about what's new in iOS
and how you can evaluate
He will finish up with
I am going to talk about what's
in text support and how can you
correctly in your applications.
And with that, I'm going
to talk about iOS, Joaquim.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Alright, thank you
Thank you all for coming.
So, my name is Joaquim,
by talking about iOS.
So as Sara mentioned, last year
to left UISupport on iOS 9
When your users run their apps
in these languages they
to the nature of
UIKit does a lot of the work
and views do the correct
in a right to left context.
Managing the layout between
auto layout.
And this can either
such as UIStack view new in iOS
which lets you easily model
of easy to use horizontal
and vertical groups
And the nice thing
that it manages auto
And in particular, for right
to left languages it manages
and what these are, are
that change automatically to
in a right to left context.
Having said that, it's
because these languages are
to left, this doesn't mean
in an aspect of your app should
direction of these languages.
There are nuances and some
when designing for
So one example up above is
to playback such as rewind and
timeline scrubbers, these
across layout direction.
Another example is
this can either refer
that don't have a specific
to them, things like left
which should obviously stay
in the same position
And also the example above
so things that have a physical
or geographical correspondence
north, east and west don't
On iOS we have semantic content
and in turn, determine and
of individual views
This exposes an enum it's
like I said before, and
that I just mentioned,
one for spatial UI, we have
cases as well, in
which is the default value.
And this is probably where most
So, if you want to look
and if you're also new to right
I highly recommend you check
New UIKit Ssupport
It goes into all of these
and also talks about some of
some of the API we added in
So that's a recap of what
for layout, and with that I'd
So images for right to left are
to fall into one of
The first one is universal
where most of your images will
or icons, and they don't need
for any language or
So they just stay the same, this
as regular UIImage or
and Interface Builder.
The second category is images
that do have the direction
So whether this is
of navigation arrows such as the
or the detail disclosure
on UITableView cells,
a simplified representation
these should be mirrored
And simply flipping the image
for right to left, so in this
and now bullets are
On iOS you can do this
LeftLlayoutDirection, we
and the object returned
in the UIImage view, does the
if it's running in a
Lastly, the third
that do have the direction
they are relatively complex
such that simply flipping
incorrect result
So in this case I have
but instead of bullets
and when I flip the image
in the correct place,
and they should actually
in this example for
So really what I need here is
one for each layout direction.
So I can fine-tune my
and now it's displaying
but now I have two
And up until now the way
to display the correct one
at runtime is really
You would use our semantic
for your layout direction and
from your bundle at runtime.
On iOS 10 we're changing
and we're starting with the
for right to left
And with it we're
that will let you do all three
of these things using
or image names in
Introducing, brand new,
in Xcode 8 for your
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, what does this mean?
So your image assets, in Xcode,
and a new property that you
and the values that you
that I mentioned in
So an image can either
you can specify also
for one layout direction
for the other, either from
to left or vice versa.
Or you can simply specify
in your asset catalogs,
Now these are image assets and
with the technology for other
such as different
across different platforms.
So really this is the same
to do is either set an
or load it using
And with that, I'd love
Alright so, so I have
and let me just run it once
It's called Flags and in
of course it's a
So, this is pretty
it's a lot of fun in groups,
and what you can see
So I've got here the
and I have a Reveal
does anybody know what
I know it's Friday,
Yeah, alright, I heard,
I'm hearing France a
Okay, so thank you.
We also have two arrows,
for the next question
And this is all done using
and this is a vertical
Anybody know what this one is?
Oh, wow, okay, awesome,
Sweet, yeah, that's my
you get the idea, right?
So, I'm thinking of adding right
Now I don't speak a word of
to be written and read in
to see how my app would
Xcode allows me to
to left environment
So all I have to do is go to
and edit the scheme
So this drops down
I have Options tab
And over here I have an
So this lists my
which are just English
but I could also pick a right
What this is going to do
in my development language which
to make the UI think
in a right to left environment.
So I can just do that,
Yep. So let me start
So already we're seeing
the navigation bar is
it's showing the Back
And my UI largely
except you might
that the arrows are now pointing
at each other which,
They're actually in the
on the left, which is
But the images themselves
so I need to do that.
Now all I have to do in Xcode
so I'm going to go ahead
And you'll notice that I
one for the back arrow,
And I'm going to go
and select this new
of it being a fixed image,
that mirrors for the
I'm going to go do the same
just so you can see that,
left to right mirrors
And now let me just
and see how it looks like.
Cool, let's start the game.
Alright, that's all I had to do
to now completely
This is without an
of code dedicated
Auto layout, stack views and
lifting for you at runtime.
And by the way, I forgot to
by a page controller that
for going forward and
to worry about that either.
So that's the demo on image
Cool. So that's a brief
in the new direction support.
Now you can also do all of this
if your images are not
and say you're fetching
that you know has a
and you want display on your UI.
So this is for images
you can associate these
in UIKit.
We also have the
that lets you specify that
of another and that
for adding to an image asset.
It's called imageWith
and it's probably simpler if
So here it is and all I have
in this particular example I'm
from the remote source,
And my right to left image
but horizontally flipped and
on UIImage.
Then just register each image,
one for each layout direction
for left to right
And then really you might
that is similar to this, you
with a trait collection
And this probably doesn't
because once again, it's the
directionality property
So that's directional images,
and also watchOS and macOS.
We have a new trait which
as you saw before, this is a
and because this is a new trait,
in mind when it comes to
on iOS with this new concept.
So let's say just as a very
subclass and I'm doing
on layout sub views,
by this very simple blue box.
This is informed by semantic
should be left to
and you can use our
Now if this is unspecified,
semantic content attribute can
and this can either be
which has a trait collection,
or the app's general user
Now really, your UIView should
about whether or not it should
to left, that's it, right.
And this can get pretty
So I'm happy to say that
that by using this new
it's a computed property
LayoutDirection and it takes all
and tells you immediately
yourself out in left to
If you're not using UIKit or
for your drawing, say you have
or a SpriteKit view, but
of these view controller
You can with this new
that gives you the same, that
to a semantic content attribute.
And that's a brief look
so we saw brand new directional
with Interface Builder
with no extra lines
for right to left support.
You can do the same
that are not directly
and as a result we
imageFlippedForRightToLeft
We also just took a look at
on UIView for determining layout
in addition to a class method
that lets you achieve the
So that's iOS, and now I'd
like to move swiftly
So watchOS 2.1 added
as selectable system languages.
And what this means
that watchKit is now
So all watchKit elements
when running in Arabic
We have an API that's
that lets you fine-tune
or interface object instances.
And it's important to note
it's natural that it
a lot of the design
in iOS do apply on the watch.
So, the idea of pushing and
in their direction, these
and you should keep this
that reflects this as well.
Any horizontal layout that
or has an ordering like showing
and then a label, you
And, something very particular
is the idea and concept of time
and in particular
And this is going back to
if you have any radial
and anti-clockwise UI
across layout directions, just
in mind in addition to the
So how do you do
So like I said before,
all interface objects now do
in right to left,
your sliders and your switches.
In addition to that,
and alignment also
So this means that the direction
and their alignment and also
in watchKit relative to
So in the example, above
with a horizontal
with left alignment
And a vertical group at the
When I run this app in Hebrew,
so note the ordering
at the horizontal
We have semantic content
with the same cases
about to help manage
interface objects or groups.
And seeing this in action
as any other property that you
If you're not using
say you're using
they're new in watchOS 3,
you could still evaluate
if you have a semantic
So here I just got the
on interface device and once
if it's left to right
And that's a brief look at
So once again it's the same
All watchKit elements do the
with no extra work needed
that you have should
Keeping in mind of course,
that I mentioned and you can
to help determine the
And with that, I'd like to
to talk to you about macOS and
thank you very much, I hope you
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
So let's talk about macOS.
Just like the other
the concepts are exactly
So if you are using
you will get the
when you're running your app
So now I would like to walk
from our own system to show
So let's start with what we
So we call these
because the layout follow the
in instead of your
But this will make more sense
so let's take a look,
So I'm running my system in
and as you can see here,
from the right edge
Also, the elements inside the
And this concept also
So by design we decided to
consistent across
if your app is localized or not.
So if you are doing
and you're doing your own custom
that into consideration
if you don't support Arabic
Next, app level controls.
So app level controls here,
your layout direction
So for example, NSTableView,
from the activity monitor app,
and as you can see the table
automatically when I'm running
Another example,
and from the finder app
where the collection view flow
I will give you one
NSScrollView and the
so we also switch the position
of the scroll bar
And this also will
with the content of
And keep in mind if you are
so scroll in there works
So WebKit will look at the
and evaluate its HTML
on that value it will
So for example here, I'm running
in Apple.com in English.
So looking at the content of
the dir attribute here
so we position the scroll
If I take the exact
but this time I am in
so looking at the content.
So here my content is in Arabic,
looking at the dir attributes
to left, so we switch the
So these are just examples
and AppKit controls,
like to talk to you about API.
So we just saw in
that WebKit's controls work
from AppKit.
So with that we are
in WebKit called
As I mentioned, the default
of your webpage, but you can
for example your scrollers
to follow the system
of the content of your webpage.
So you can override it to use
Next, let's talk
As a quick recap, if you use
don't have to do anything,
everything will just
Now you might have a specific
to layout your views
So in that case we
that you use StackViews
So grid views are new to macOS,
and both these tools are really
up auto layouts constraints
And they also use leading
which will flip your
when you're running in a
If you are not using StackViews
If you're not familiar with
from previous years and there is
What's New in Auto
Finally, if you're
in base approach
of flipping the text
In addition to that, we
that will let you get and
of your views.
So for example here,
that has two values,
So I want my slider
across all my localizations,
because it makes sense
on the left side and
on the right side.
So here it will make total sense
of my slider to be
So as I mentioned, we
that will let you do that.
The default value is set
to NSApp.userInterfaceLayout
but you can override it
on what you want to
Now let's talk about images.
As we just saw in
we introduced directional
So assets catalogs
and they work exactly the same
to go through details here.
But again, sometimes you
in your application bundle
from a remote location,
So we also have an API in
that and register
So let's go through an
just see how it works.
So as I mentioned, sometimes you
and you want to register them.
So first what you need to
to right image by
And once you have that you need
to set this layout
So same thing for your
but this time you will
So once you have both images, so
to left image representation
and that by using
So with that, once you have both
the right image for
either if you're running
to right localization or a
Finally, we have new
for common AppKit controls.
For an accessory for example, it
and auto layout attributes
And for NSButton, it
the checkbox position, and the
for free.
So with that, I would
to summarize what we
Alright. Cool, so I got
and I created a scoreboard
when we are playing
So here I have a simple,
in my view controller, I
and I already setup my
And inside my table view cell
and a [inaudible]
So here I'm using
out the elements inside my table
to worry about setting
because text view just
And here at the bottom,
where I update my highest
So pretty simple.
So what I'm going to do now,
to left environment
and see how it looks like.
Great. So I'm going to
to my application language
to left pseudo language
I'm going to build
And it's building, great.
So as you can see here without
just by using storyboard,
auto layouts, it just works.
So that's it, so now that my app
what I'm going to do, I want
I'm going to run
in my system language instead
So this will just run
because my system
Now I'm going to
So why I'm doing this, so I just
of international
So here, so my app looks
and now I want to join the game.
So I'm going to add
I'm going to click here, add
for fun, I want to write my
So I'm going to go ahead
to use Arabic instead
Alright, so I type my
And I'm also really good at
to win this game, so I'm
So I'm just going to
So, alright, see
So just by updating my name, so
because it jumps
and now my label just reads "!
has the highest score 12, Sara."
That doesn't make any sense.
So in the next section I
to solve this kind of
by directional text correctly.
So let's go back to slides.
So we just saw in the demo
in Arabic, it broke the
So now let's see how we can
So rendering text in
really important.
It doesn't matter if
of that specific language,
even if you are supporting
your users can still
in any other language.
And when it comes to text, it's
that text alignment and
different concepts.
So for example here, I have
it's right aligned, it's
because you might need
so it won't break
But if I take the same example
but I'm forcing the writing
to left, that will break
As you can see here the
in the correct position.
So let's talk a little
Lateral alignment is
so if you don't override
so we'll get the right
So let's talk about
because it's a little
So here I'm just going to give
of the text engine by algorithm.
But if you want to
by the algorithm please check
out the full specification
But let's start with the basics.
So there are three types
So they can be either
for example scripts
with Latin, Chinese or Japanese.
They can be strong right to left
like Arabic, Hebrew, Farsi or
that they don't have a
and we call these neutral
For example spaces.
So how the text engine decides
of a specific paragraph?
So the text engine just look
at the first strong Unicode
And if it's a strong
my paragraph would
If it's strong left to right,
to right directionality.
So let's walk through an example
So if I take my label
%@ has the highest color.
So I have no idea at runtime
because my user can write
or input anything,
So let's take the
where my %@ will be
So here the first character
so it's a strong left to right.
So the directionality of my
so it renders correctly.
Now if my variable is
So the first strong character
which give the directionality
of my whole paragraph
So that's why the, my
so this is wrong.
So the right behavior here will
to see something like that,
I want it to be on the
of my paragraph will be rendered
So wouldn't it be great
that will take my
and give it its own
without affecting the
And that's possible
So Isolates are the latest
that were introduced
and that our text engine
So as I mentioned, Isolates will
and have the directionality
and that's without affecting
And I'm happy to
to insert these characters
because if you use
we do that for you
So localizedStringWithFormat
and it will do the
So now, I would like to
and fix the issue we introduce
of code, so let's do that.
Alright, so cool.
So now I'm going to go back
and this is where
So just to save some time
to use localized standard string
with format instead
So I'm going to go ahead here
and uncomment the line that is
I'm going to run my app again,
Right, so as you can see
So my name now is on the
I can read it correctly.
So let's see if it works
So see here if I update
And with Arabic names as well,
and that's Isolates
So let's go back to slides.
[ Applause ]
Alright so let's summarize.
So in this session we introduced
So it's easier now for you
for both your left to right and
We have new APIs for you
And auto layout is your best
out your views and support
And we also improved
by supporting Isolates
So with all these improvements,
as a developer, to go ahead
For more information, please
to find our session there and
And those are related sessions
if you didn't watch
please check them
And have a wonderful
of WWDC, thank you so much.