[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good Morning.
My name is David Duncan.
And along with Kurt Revis
about making your apps adaptive.
So, in the first part,
that Interface Builder has
on how you can do adaptively.
But in this part, we're
about techniques that you can
as well as code that
to build your own experiences
So, let's look at
The first thing we're
about is just some basics on
to refresh everyone's memory.
In addition, we're going to talk
in UIKit in the Tools
with Interface Builder and so
And finally, Kurt's going
about how you can go
to build your experiences.
And so with that,
So, sizes.
If we go ahead and
and their orientations and
that's pretty
of things.
I don't think anyone wants
figure out what their layouts
So let's see if we
to simplify what all
Well, that's still
And I don't want you to read
that because there's a
And it's really hard to read.
So let's see if we can
and color and make it simpler.
And it's not really helping.
So, what else can we do?
Well, when we thought about this
in UIKit we thought what
that we can divide this space
up to create good
And as you might have guessed
about are size classes.
We split the grid
up into the compact
compact height and
And what we decided
in the compact space, you have
where you try and make
But in the regular
to do more advanced things,
with that space that really
And so that take
that when you see a regular size
to make a really great
with that space, going
in a compact space.
So, let's take a look at
for you based on size class.
Most views and controls
So, you take a look
It's the same whether you're
That nav bar is also
in compact or regular.
But what things do change?
Well, here's a presentation.
It looks like it's a
It's on a iPhone 6s Plus.
But, if we rotate
in compact, we see a form sheet.
And so one thing you see
if you do a form
in regular size class, if you
we don't have enough
And so we change that to a
Now, the thing in UIKit
that does most complicated
on size classes and
is UISplitViewController.
Again, we're looking
at a compact width experience
And you see that, as you might
you just got a navigation
where we push and pop things.
But again, if we rotate
we bring in the sidebar.
And we think that on an iPhone
in regular width that having
that side bar is a better
Even though we only have
Similarly on iPad, the 9.7
you can see that we keep that
to easily switch
But what do we do when
Remember, on an iPad,
But we've decided that on iPad
that is much larger, much more
and so forth, and you
so that you can still
However, we allow you
so you can still easily
And so those are some things
to give you the best experience
and the actual amount
And in order to take
let's look at some
to make the most out
So, we're going to speak to some
And in the first part, you saw
to building adaptive
Being able to easily make
in gamut and other traits.
But, Xcode also provides
And Asset Catalogs are great,
not just for organizing your
and how they should be used.
And of course, UIKit
that make building
We've been talking about
There are many sessions
you should go review those.
And of course, there's
on New Things in Auto Layout.
And trait collections
in the first half as well.
But other things
which allows your application
that users want to use.
Layout Guides are a great way
to pass Auto Layout
And we're going to discuss
that UIKit provides by default.
And finally, UIAppearance
to declaratively specify how
controls and views to look.
So let's go ahead and
Asset catalogs allow you to
on the trait environment
And here's a small
So we've got our picture
And we have 1, 2 and 3x
So that whether you're on an
you can get the best
for the resolution
But another advantage of it is
that Asset Catalogs lets you
And what that means is is that
to an iPhone 6s, which is
to pay the space penalty
and 3x images as well.
Similarly, we'll also trim
and a few other things.
So, use the Asset Catalogs
and you can make the best
and carry the least
when you actually
Other things that Asset Catalogs
that you can attach to your
And the first one we're going
So let's bring baby
And let's say that we
where sometimes we actually want
to crop this image
And if we just naively pick
we'd miss most of her face.
We really do want that square
Now, what are you going to do?
Well, you're going to bring in
out how far are you away
But, instead of having to put
with assets, you can do that
And UIImage will vend
to you whenever you need them.
And similarly, of course, you
But being able to put them
in the Asset Catalog
to have a giant table
with metadata.
Similarly, let's say that you
for a table view or what have
to resize to adapt to whatever
Well, you can create a nine-part
and store those in your
And then, when that image
it resizes nicely
around large images
that you're working with.
And so, that's for
Let's talk about other
to make for your
We love Dynamic Type.
It gives our users the
and especially for our users
with vision, they can
that allow them to
And so this year, we've
to adopt Dynamic Type
And we've done this in two ways.
The first, we made it part
So you don't have to listen
It's just right there for
to take advantage
But we figured you
that for regular text
text fields and text views.
So we've made those
All you have to do is assign
that you want and set the
for the content size category.
All your labels, your text
they'll automatically adapt to
and you don't have
[ Applause ]
So of course, if
be certain to test
in all the Dynamic Type sizes.
As I mentioned, there's
The Accessibility Inspector
to your application and allow
without having to go back
And if you're displaying these
you'll want to review
in Collection View" session,
because there's some really
and behavior enhancements
that you can take advantage
And so, let's talk
And UIView provides
a Margin Guide the
And we'll go through
Both of these start
Whatever content you
The Layout Margins
by a property UIView that
which defines insets
And so, how do we then
Well, that's just a rec
And that Layout Margin
provides auto layout
to generate your
Simple. So, what's the
in relation to this?
The Readable Content Guide
with information on
so that it has a nice,
If you're on one of the
you can layout text from side
of being turning their
So, the first thing we want
to calculate is what is the
And then, of course,
to flow outside of the margins.
So we bring in that
as part of our calculation.
And we combine these two
to finally form the
another layout guide
that you can lay
Now, the Readable
on the dynamic text size.
So, what happens
Well, we increase
and the ideal width increases.
And as you can see, because the
inside of the layout margins,
the guide doesn't necessarily
And then you can
and get a nice readable length
of text that's inside
And so with that, let's
UIAppearance, if you haven't
for you to specify what your
And what does that mean?
Well, that means that
when you see a new tab bar,
You say, for all of my tab bars,
the appearance should have the
Really simple.
And that any time
unselected items
But it's also contextual.
And that means that
on trait collections or based on
And what does that look like?
Let's take a look.
So, here we have our
And as is the style, we want
at the top when we're in
And we're going to have
that image just replace
However, when we're in
we're going to have a
And the image is not going
to the navigation bar.
So we want it to use
So let's do the default
We create a TraitCollection
We grab the navigation
for that TraitCollection.
And we say we don't want
to use any background
And that will cause the
to using its default appearance.
Similarly, when we do
we create a trait collection
and assign an empty image, which
to construct no background
Now, you might note
for trait collection, that
We're actually going to be
so be on the lookout for that.
And so with that,
up the best practices section
where we reviewed
to organize your images.
Dynamic Type to adapt to the
Layout Guides to help you
that are easily adaptable to
And finally, Appearance
to get your application looking
And so with that, I'll
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, David.
So, if you remember from
Part 1" you'll remember the
The system is going to do most
of the work, so you
Now, I'm going to talk today
So, if you want to go beyond
here's how to do it.
And the operative word
This isn't required.
However, if you don't -- even
of this, you might learn
to work more effectively
So I'll talk about how
I'll tell you how to design your
of device orientation and size.
I'll talk about how you
and change between
as your app changes size.
And then I'll talk about
to make it quicker and
And I'll do this in
We'll build a real app here.
So, I'll call my app My
And fortunately, it's
We've only got three things that
Three items.
Each one has a title.
Here they're just A, B and C.
And then there's a longer
that goes with each one.
So even though this
I'm going to use
in your much more
So this is the model of my app.
This is the data inside of it.
But how should my app look
What's the design?
Well, when I'm thinking
I need to consider all
But that's far too much to do
That would be far too much work.
So let's try to simplify this.
I think in my app I can do
I'll call the first
And I'll arrange these
and C vertically in the stack.
My other design will be "Wide."
So I'll arrange these
Now, I think no matter what
for my app I can use one
of these two designs
So now the question
of device orientation and size,
how do I choose what
I need to define
And again, this is
I think I'm going to
than the height, I'll
Otherwise, I'll use
Now, I can run through
and see how it works.
I can do this on paper before
at all.
So for instance, this iPhone
than the height, we'll
Now, I can continue that
and with an iPad, full screen,
and go through all the
and make sure they make sense.
So I'll reiterate
When I'm designing my
I thought through
I came up with designs to
the whole range.
And then I defined rules
So when I'm defining
there's many ways I can do it.
This is what makes
But you'll note that I
if the size exactly
I could have seen is
therefore it's an iPad and
I don't want to do that because
to handle.
And those sizes will
So instead, I defined a
that would tell me
And there's many
The first one, and most obvious,
Then we've done most
All you have to do is check
Also, your app will act like
because you're using
All the Xcode tooling
You'll get a lot of
But, you can also
For instance, I could
or height to a threshold value.
Or I could compare two values
Or I could combine these.
The point is that I came up with
to figure out what
So another thing
about your designs is even
you might be, say, on one side
So don't make your designs
on the device are, or
if you're multitasking,
I'll need to find
I'll need to use those rules
And then last, I'll apply
So change the views of
Now, where should
If I make a new template in
it gives me this template
And it says do any
So that's where I
Unfortunately, it's
The reason you don't
because views get
The first time something
in your view controller,
And that's very early.
So we know at that
in a superview yet.
Layout wont' be valid yet.
So you really can't
or any parent size
It's just too early.
So for one-time only things
viewDidLoad, you only want
to be the same across
A better place for
in a view controller's
And we'll view that because
at that time the view
Layout of all those
Sizes are valid.
My view size is valid.
Traits are valid.
Everything's good.
And also, this is a good time
of my view controller.
So this is where I should
controller views and
Now, it's important
Because this is a very hot path.
This is called very often.
Often, for reasons
So, do as little work as you
Ideally you would find
since the last time it was
as you can to update
So change only the
that you absolutely
And then finally, be careful
If you invalidate layout
they might in turn
And soon you're finding that
and invalidating layout and
So to find out more about
out about layout loops,
in Auto Layout" session
So, here's my two designs.
We'll go back to this.
How am I actually going
Well, I think I can
for each item, A, B, and C.
And then I'll us a UIStackView
to arrange these things
UIStackView will do
I don't have to think too hard.
So here's some code.
My simple example view
of UIVIewController.
And I made a storyboard
It's got a stack view in it
and it's already got
Now, I am going to,
in my viewWillLayoutSubviews
First step, get the size,
Second, apply my rules.
So if the width is
or equal to the height, I will
And then finally I'll
So, if I'm using
my stack view's access
Otherwise it should be vertical.
That's all I have to do.
So you'll note that here
And I'm also taking
that StackView is smart.
If I'm setting the access to
it's not going to do
So let's see this in action.
Here's my app on an
We've got that vertical layout.
And now if I rotate
we'll see that the app
And also I got this
So I'll go back to portrait
There we are.
We rotated.
So, I showed this to David,
because I was especially
that StackView gave me
I didn't expect that.
And he said, "Well,
That's pretty amazing.
But can you make it better?
Could you make it pop?"
And if you're an app developer,
from one of your clients.
So I said, "Sure, I
I can make my app a
and I'll make it pop here.
So I'll do this by,
I'll make the items
And then when I'm done, I'll
shrink back to normal.
Now, this isn't something
that you do in your app.
Not this particular
But the point is where
and where I'm exactly
So, I'm doing this code
to size with coordinator.
And I'm doing this because it
size change or a rotation.
And I'm giving this
up animations alongside
and to happen afterwards.
Now, why don't I put all
That's because this isn't
through when your app launches.
There's other reasons, but
So I'll use the coordinator
to animate alongside
And all I have to do in this
that I want to be animated.
It'll go alongside the rotation
with the same curve
And I'm going to set that stack
up of a factor of 1.4.
So a little bit bigger.
Then when I'm done, I get to set
up my own animation
Here I'm picking .5.
And we'll go back to normal.
We'll set the affine
So back to normal.
So here we go.
Here's the same app just with
It'll rotate.
And it popped towards
If we rotate again, it
So there we go.
I got to add that pop effect.
I got to make it a
But I didn't have to
It remained the same.
So I just added it on top.
So the last thing I'd like to
And this is a way that you can
that can be reused
This way you can build you app
of these different
to rewrite everything.
We'll do this by using
Each piece will typically
And that's because
of useful stuff all together.
For instance, you get
not just a single view,
and all their constraints
You get to make connections
So you might perform a segue
or present something, find
and so on.
And also, it's a place
to the rest of your app.
So you might have a connection
that represents network
Now, the view controllers
to perform different roles.
You might have a
And it might contain multiple
Now, you're probably used
to writing contained
and then putting them in
For example a navigation
or split view controller or a
But you can write your own
And this lets you really
You can do a lot of
So I'll show how to do this.
Here's my designs again.
And in my case, I think I can
controller that I'll call
And inside of that I'll have
one for each one
Now, thinking about it, I think
to my design.
So if I don't have much
to show just a preview
I don't have room for the
So, when I click on one of
tap on one of these items,
I will present another
that shows the full text.
Then when I tap on
we'll dismiss it, it'll go away.
So I'll do this by having my
will have three small
I'll define this later.
When we present one, when we
and present a new large
Now, if my app is big enough,
I'd like to just show the large
here directly in that container.
So my container will
of another class
And when the app size
we'll change the view
between one of these two states.
So I'll show the code here.
We're going to work our way
up from the contained view
So we'll start with
for these contained
And it's pretty simple.
We've just got a simple
You'll note that I
to be
And I also set the storyboard
This way I can find these
and instantiate them later.
For the
it's bigger.
It's got that extra text in it.
The same idea.
I set my custom class to
And I set the identifier.
So here's the code for the
We'll start with this.
And I know that every time I
to tap it to show the large one.
So in my viewDidLoad, this is
I'm going to set up my
and add it to my view.
Later, when that thing is
We'll go on and find our main
that LargeElementViewController
identifier largeElement.
Finally, all we have to
In the
it's a little more
to know are we being
If it's being presented,
If it's not, we don't.
So I'll put this code
I'm doing that because I
isBeingPresented to find out
So if it is, then I add
the same way as before.
When that's tapped, all
So now let's get on to the
And I'm going to add
to make this easier
We'll call this the
And the design object
up all the information that
I'll make it an immutable
So I can write a function
and after it's been
Nobody can change it.
And then finally, I'll
So I can see is my design
than what I'm currently
So let's actually
I've got just a simple
It's going to have two
The first one is the axis.
I'm reusing this
so it's either vertical
Then I'm going to
for whether I'm using the small
of the view controllers inside.
I call that elementKind.
Finally, I've got a read-only
called elementIdentifier.
And this just tells me
to make those view
Finally, I'll implement the
This is just function
And I just compare the
to see if they're the same.
So finally, let's get up into
and actually do this stuff.
You'll remember it's going
to have three child
It's going to use
and decide what design to use.
And then finally we'll update.
Every layout will
and change things if we need to.
So here we go.
The
I've got an array
for three optional
And they start out as nil.
Because when this thing
nothing is going to
I'll also keep track
that I'm currently displaying.
And also that's optional
because nothing has
So, in my
this should look
I'm going to get my size.
I'm going to call a function
on the size, return
And if that design is different
than what I'm currently
I'm going to apply
So change my UI to match.
So you'll note this
that I talked about earlier.
And really, no matter
you can probably follow
You'll have different
Your decideDesign
and applyDesign methods
But you'll probably be following
So let's fill in these
decideDesign will first
And we've already been over
For the elementKind I'm going
So I'm going to choose
than a threshold, choose
Otherwise use the large ones.
And here I'm just
This is just an example
This isn't a value you should
It's just an example.
Finally, I'm going to wrap up
in a design object
To apply a design, I need
So I need to find out
So again, for the
that directly to the stack view.
It's smart.
It won't do anything
For the elementKind,
If we have old element
and the element kind is
to destroy the old ones
So here's how we'll do that.
We'll iterate through
And I'm using this
because it lets me get
at that index simultaneously
And finally, if we've got an
then I need to remove it.
I'll call this function
Go to my storyboard, create
using the identifier
And then finally call
that new child view controller.
And then save it in the array
So, last slide of code.
Thank you for sticking with me.
These are some things
to be a well-behaved
So it's important to do these
When we're adding a
we first call
This adds that view controller
as to self's list
Then we need to add that
to the view hierarchy.
We do this by using
addArrangedSubviews method.
And UIKit doesn't
And in fact, can't do it for
where it's going to go
Only you can tell us that.
Finally, once that's done,
you tell that view
to a new parent view
To remove the old one, we
just in the opposite order.
So we tell it it will move
to a new parent view
Remove its view from
And then finally, remove
of child view controllers.
So here we are.
I'll actually show
Here we are on the
We've got lots of room.
We're using that
and we're using the
Now, if I slide over another app
and pin it, my app's
I switched to that
But I'm using those
still.
In fact, they're the same
that we were looking at earlier.
Now, if I make that
you'll note that we switch
So we're still vertical.
We are using that
I can now tap on one of
present the large one.
If I tap again, we'll
So there's my app.
You'll note that we
We really decided exactly what
I handled designs of
I implemented each design.
We changed between
as the app changed size,
and also used reusable
So my app is an example of this.
Your app can do all
So now we've been
We've shown you what
We've shown you some of
that UIKit provides in this
And we've been through
So, we've really barely
There's a lot more to go.
So, check out our
Also, if you didn't see
There was a great talk
that talked about typography.
New stuff in Collection
that David mentioned earlier.
And then also the last two
about adaptive apps
And we really didn't duplicate
So, please review that stuff.
There's a lot of great
So thank you.
Have a fantastic Friday.
[ Applause ]