[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
Welcome to Building
You are here because you care
about building the
for users of your fitness apps.
Some of them are fanatical.
They're spending hours
and they expect responsive,
that provide accurate data
and integrate seamlessly
My name is Dash.
I'm an engineer on Apple's
and I'll be joined up
by my colleague Jorge.
Today, we're going to show you
that your users will love.
Working out is an important
It can help you sleep,
and clear your mind.
Many of you have worked hard
that inspire users to track
and reach for new
With Apple Watch,
within the moment heart
and activity detection,
in an experience delivered
Today, we're going to
to build great workout
We'll start by introducing
a new game changing capability
Then, we'll walk
of a workout from
Along the way, we'll show
contribute to the
Next, we'll discuss some
for workouts in iOS 10.
And finally, we'll review
So let's get started.
At the core of every workout
that the user can
So we start with
This API is simple to use
and provides automatic
When a workout session
the sensors on Apple Watch
of the session to accurately
This will also enable
to the user's activity rings.
For example, during a workout,
activity will use the workout
to the user's exercise ring.
During a workout session,
your app will be displayed
their device.
Users will love having
to your app while they're
Finally, we're really excited
in watchOS 3 can now be set
Let's talk more about
[ Applause ]
Background running will
of your workout app.
Your app will be
from the sensors
For example, you'll be able
to receive continuous
when your app isn't
You'll also be able to provide
at any time during
You can send the
to let them know their
This will also allow
up to date data whenever
at their wrist.
Enabling background
just add workout-processing
in your extensions Info.plist.
Of course, to maintain high
it's critical that you
to only do what's necessary.
If your app uses excessive
watchOS may decide
We recommend that
to measure your app's
You can use the CPU
or the time profiler
watchOS 3 will also
with a backtrace whenever your
Now that you're set up
let's walk through the steps
There are three steps
First, you need to
to access data in HealthKit.
Second, you'll create a
representing the type of workout
And third, you'll create
and start a workout
workout configuration.
Let's go through
All workout apps will want
to write workouts to HealthKit.
This will enable workouts
up in the user's health
Depending on the specifics of
to request authorization
distance, and a heart rate.
If you'd like more information
we recommend you take a
Getting the Most
Workout sessions are created
with a workoutConfiguration
The workoutConfiguration
type, such as running
and the location type,
You will use the
to create a workoutSession,
simply pass it to the start
Let's try this out with a demo.
For just today, let's pretend we
Our latest project is
for watchOS 3 that's designed
It's called SpeedySloth.
I've an Xcode project here
that already has the UI
Let's take a look together.
So this is the first
when they open our app.
It has two pickers,
which can be walking,
And another for location type,
which can be outdoor,
When I press the Start
Let's fix that together.
The view that you
by a class called configuration
I've a method right here
that's called whenever the
I'll fill it in now.
I'm creating a
and I'm setting the
to be the currently
from that first picker.
Then I'm setting
to be the currently
from that second picker.
I'm passing the
to a new interface
WorkoutInterface Controller.
WorkoutInterface
for managing the UI
It will also be responsible
and stopping the
Let's take a look at
So, I'm in the awake method of
and I know that we'll receive
as a context object
Let's use it to start
First, I'm unwrapping the
that it's a valid
Then I'm using it to create a
to the initializer
I'm setting the delegate of
so we'll receive
like state changes and errors.
Then I'm saving the current date
We'll use this later on, when
to HealthKit.
Next, I'm passing
to the start method
Let's try it out.
So here we are at configuration
I'm going to leave it at
to press the Start button again.
So this just opened
So I've a feeling, that our
correctly, but to be
at the clock face on the device.
You'll see at the top,
that there's a green
This indicates that
on this watch has an
The user can tap this at any
with the active session.
So it looks like our session
Let's review what we just did.
We used information
to create a workoutConfiguration
Then we used that configuration
And we started the
to the start method
Now that we have an
we want to start collecting
to the user during the workout.
To talk to you more about
I'd like to invite up
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Dash.
Good morning.
My name is Jorge.
I'm a software engineer
So, my colleague Dash just
and start a workout session.
Now, we are going to continue
by discussing how
and control the state of your
We are going to be
and control those different
from the moment you
and until you decide to end it.
Let's take a look at all
First, we are going to be
retrieving sample information
to incorporate those
Next, we are going to
Events can be generated by
from your user interface.
We're going to be discussing
in detail later.
Once you started
you're in a running state.
At any point, you
and then resume the
And later, you will
to end your workout session.
So let's take a look
at all these steps a
First, we said we wanted
The way you do this is by
for each of the data tabs
That could be, maybe,
or it could be active
When you do this, you also will
to receive new event, new
That will allow you to keep
such as maybe the total
or total accumulated
With that, you will be able
You will also be able
the most recent heart
You could also notify users
whenever they reach the
or whenever they burn
in their rowing workout.
So let's now take a
Since we are going to be
the first thing that
to create a predicate
We are going to start by using
You do not want samples that the
to count against your totals.
Next, you're going to
from the local device.
That means the current watch.
You want to avoid, for
that are being saved on
of a sync operation
Finally, you're going to
into the final predicate you're
Next, you have to set
to process samples
You will normally accumulate
and maybe display some
Now, we are ready to create
You're going to be using the
in, the predicate we just built,
and set up your initial
as the handle we defined before.
You will also set
so you get new samples arriving
to HealthKit during
Finally, you're going to execute
We also mention that you would
of certain reached goals.
For example, whenever
or the first 100
The way you will normally do
to alert the user
When you do that, we recommend
that you update your
so you reflect what
It is very likely when
they will raise their wrist
what this haptic was about.
The way to play a haptic
in WatchKit interface device.
Now let's talk about events.
Events are timestamps
to highlight certain
For example, you can use
to highlight the point where
Some events are going to be
and saved later into
Others are going to be created
New in watchOS 3, we have
in workout session delegate
to send events to
So let's now take a look at
that we have in watchOS 3.
Laps and markers are two new
These are events that you
to store in your workout.
This will represent
for displaying your workouts
There is a difference
Laps represent events that
in equal distance portion.
For example, if you're in a
in a track, you would create
completes a round.
Markers, on the other side,
can be arbitrary
They don't have to be tied to
They could represent,
the moment your user
or maybe that time where
Now let's talk about pausing
During a workout session,
to momentarily stop
For example, they are on a run,
to buy a bottle of water.
In this case, you will have
for your user to let you
When this happens, you can
to pause your workout.
This will allow HealthKit
and space in the database.
Of course, when this happens,
that arrives to your
You don't want to
to your totals while
HealthKit will respond
by generating pause
that you will get using the
It's important to know that
no new events will be
until you resume your session.
New in watchOS 3, the
and resume your workout
pause workoutSession and
Events that you will receive
which you may already know
Now let's talk about
This is new in watchOS 3.
The motion pause and
Your watch, during a running
that the user stopped moving.
That means they are
And we will be able to
running again.
When you receive these events,
into your workout, the
when the user manually paused.
However, you do not need to
Note that this is
for the running activity type.
So let's go back into our
and see how we can
of the concepts we
So I'm going to be
So to recap what we saw before,
which already started our
on the screen that calories
We are not accumulating
So let's go into our workout
So going back to our workout
I'm going to be looking
when decision changes it state.
This is workoutSession
Here I have switch statement
What I'm interested in right
Whenever we came from a
that the application
So if you are in the running
I'm going to be calling
startAccumulating Data.
So let's take a look
What we want to do is to update
on the screen, one
and another one for
So basically we are going to be
of those two data types.
The way you start the query
the presentation.
We first are going
to be building a predicate
Next, we are going to
In this case, I already have
that will grab those
and update my user interface.
Now, I'm ready to
set up the updateHandler
And finally, what I want to do
Because a query executed
we want to stop it
So let's now go and run
Switch to the simulator.
Okay. Here we are.
So we are going to be
a running outdoor workout.
There it is.
When we start, we can see
that we see some numbers
This is because the watch's
fake samples for you whenever
Great. So if you take
we see there are
but they are currently
We already discussed how you can
for your app, so
and see how we can do that.
So here I have the didTapPause
but it's hooked up to the
so I'm going to be
First I'm going to be checking
and I'm going to be
If it's running, I'm going to
If it's paused, I'm
Good. As a result of this,
your workout session will change
to the delegate callback,
whenever your workout session
you're going to see here that
so we're going to be
In this case I already
pauseAccumulatingData,
that will basically stop
as they arrive into the
Similarly, we need to resume
so whenever our session
we're going to receive
The other button that we have
on the screen was
In this case, what
to do is create a markerEvent.
We just create the workout event
with a marker type
We're going to be saving
for later saving
And finally, I have a step
on the user interface.
This event just happened.
Also note that we already have
event that is a callback from
In this case, we also want
by HealthKit into the
So let's now run our
Give it a second
Okay. Here it is.
I'm going to choose
And give it a few seconds
so we can have some
You can see at the top of
that there is an active workout.
Whenever I hit the Pause
and you can see that the
for calories and meters.
I can probably resume
It goes into active state, and
You can also tap on
which it basically displays
It is very likely that an actual
for your user.
Great. So let's now switch
So let's recap what we saw.
We just saw how you can
to get information
and update your workout totals.
Then we implemented
in your workout application,
to create an event
Next step will be ending
To talk about that, I'm going
to invite my colleague
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello again.
Ending and saving a
With a few steps, workouts saved
from your app will
with the activity
Let's take a look at
Workouts saved to HealthKit
up in the activity
Starting in iOS 10,
this includes workouts
This means that a user can do a
when their watch
and they'll still get
[ Applause ]
Workouts saved with
to contribute to
Users will love getting credit
in their activity day.
Let's walk through the steps
so that it shows up in
There are three steps
First, you end the
Second, you save the
And third, you add related
such as energy burned
Let's go through
To end the workout
on your healthStore, and pass
This will reset the devices
When HealthKit finishes
your workout session delegate
in its state change method.
When you see that the
it's time to save the workout.
You'll create an HKWorkout
The information that
with will be displayed in the
Make sure to use the same
on your workout configuration.
Set a startDate and an
and include an array
This array can include events
and markers or laps as
The totalEnergyBurned
that represents the sum
of all energy burned
Likewise, the totalDistance
that represents all
workout session.
Finally, don't forget
Set a value for the
to indicate the location
You can save this workout
by passing it to the save
When you see that it's
it's time to add
Let's talk more about
When you add samples
HealthKit creates an association
and the workout itself.
Apps will be able to query
that are associated
This will be useful if you
across your workout timeline.
Adding energy samples to
if you want the user
in their activity move ring.
Activity will use these
to compute credit for that ring.
Finally, make sure that the
on your workout sample
of all these associated samples.
To add samples to your
of HK samples to the add samples
to workout method
Let's update SpeedySloth
and saving the workout.
So when we were last in the
to collect data to
And also how to control the
You may have noticed
of the Workout Interface
that there's this button
When I tap it, it
So we'll fix that now.
I'm back in Workout
and I have a method
Let's fill it in.
First, I'm saving the current
We'll use this in just a second
when we create that
Next, I'm calling the end
and passing along
When HealthKit finishes
we can expect a callback
I'll go back to this
So Jorge showed us earlier,
how to handle the
Now we want to handle
We want to do two things when
First, we want to
This method is already
over the array of open queries
Next, we want to
Let's implement that now.
I'm creating a workout sample
and I'm using the
from our workout configuration.
Then I'm setting the start
that we saved earlier on.
I'm including the
that Jorge showed us how
to build during the
I'm using the quantities
and totalDistance
from our data queries
And finally, I'm including
I'm setting the indoor workout
on the location type of
I'm passing this workout
on my healthStore, which
When I see that it's
I'm going to call
which is a function right down
I want to add two
one for totalEnergyBurned,
For totalEnergyBurned, I'm
and I'm using the quantityType
Then I'm passing the same
that I used on my
This means that there will be
that spans the entire
If you'd like to, you can create
samples, just make sure that
that you set on the
I'm doing the same thing
I'm using the quantity type
HealthKit has three
I'm using WalkingRunning because
walking and running distance.
If you're building a
you'd want to use
and we've also just added
wheelchair distance,
for wheelchair based workouts.
I'm using the same total
on the workout sample, and I'm
and end date.
So again, this is one
that spans the duration
I'm adding these two samples
in an array to the add samples
to workout method
When I see that they've
I know that all my data for this
Now I want to display
I'm doing this by passing
to a new interface
SummaryInterface Controller.
SummaryInterface Controller
to display an HKWorkout to
I'm going to run the app again,
and we'll see how
Let's do outdoor run again.
I'll press Start.
And we'll wait a few moments
Okay I'm going to press
because we have some data.
Our workout session was ended
and our sample was
Here's the summary
that workout sample to us now.
To make sure that it did indeed
let's take a look at the Health
Here I am in the Workouts
I'm going to tap Show
of all of our workouts.
At the top you can see a workout
that was just completed
That's our workout.
I'm going to tap it to see
So you can see that this
It had an almost
and there's our start
This is all the information
You can even see the
that says it's not
At the bottom, you can
that we associated
We have almost two calories
Good job everyone.
And we have a 100th of a mile.
So looks like everything did
Let's review what we just did.
We ended our workout session by
And then we waited
in our state change
When we saw that the
we created a workout sample
Then, we created two samples
one for totalEnergyBurned,
Remember associating that energy
so that the user will get
So we've just built an entire
It's that simple.
[ Applause ]
Now every app on WatchOS comes
with a parent application
So we've added some new API's
in iOS 10 specifically
To talk to you more
like to invite Jorge back up.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Dash.
So you've been developing great
So workout apps are not
Starting on iOS 10,
we are providing some
to implement new functionality
We mentioned that every
with a parent iPhone app.
You can use that
to build great experiences
You might already be using
between the two applications.
This is an effective way
of implementing features while
and the application is running.
Now we have background running,
so your application can
That allows you to implement
However, in order
you need to have your
So, starting with iOS 10,
where you can start a
That is, your watch will
without the user having to
So, let's take a look
On your iPhone application, you
and a location, and
workoutConfiguration object.
Once you have that, you send
to the watch application.
If the watch application
it will be launched for you.
Now, the workout application
and start a workout session.
In order for this to work,
you need to have the workout
mentioned earlier in
So let's now take a
You may be familiar
because we saw it earlier
This is what you do
to start a workout
You first create a
and then use that to create a
In this case, we want to
The first part, creating
will be executed on
Creating a workoutSession
and start date will be
For this to work, you need
between the two applications,
at the iPhone application code.
First, you need to check
if you have an activated
and if you have a watch
Once you do that, you're ready
to create your
Next, in order to pass
to your watch application,
in the new in iOS
with workoutConfiguration,
which is a new method
This will grab your
over to your watch app.
So let's now look at the
What you want to do is grab
to create a session
For that, you will implement
which is a new function,
of WatchKit ExtensionDelegate.
By implementing this function,
you will grab your
and are ready to start it.
So, let's now go back into
and see how we can
from your iPhone.
So, let's take a look
I'm going to create
And here I have the
of our SpeedySloth application.
So I'm going to launch it,
and you see that the user
to what we did on the watch.
We have a user interface
to select an Activity
And then we have a Start button
that is currently
So let's take a look at our code
and see how we can actually
So I'm going to be
for the iPhone application
and I have configuration view
that handles that
In the didTapStart button,
we're going to be
First, we're going
to be creating our
with the selected activity
This is the exact same code
Next, we are going
to be grabbing our
for our storyboard.
This is the UI that we're going
to show while the
We are going to set the property
in order to pass the
And finally, we are going to be
So let's take a look at
and see what it is doing.
On the viewDidLoad method,
that we do is to
This is basically grabbing
and make sure it's initialized.
Then, we are going to be calling
The startWatchApp function
that we have a valid
and then this is the same code
We first check that the
activated and that we have
Finally, we are going to be
with workoutConfiguration.
Great. So now we have to go
to make sure that we grab that
So, we are going to be
into the ExtensionDelegate
and using the same code to
When we do that, we want to
in a context object and pass to
This is the same user interface
that we were showing
on the watch.
One other thing that we want
to Workout InterfaceController,
let me see -- whenever I said
changes state.
We're going to be calling
This is something that we
in our code, which is basically
of the session, and send in
to the iPhone application.
So, let's now run our code
and take a look.
There it is.
So we are going to be selecting
When I press the Start button,
you see the workout
If you go back to
you see that the app launch,
Going back to the iPhone app,
in running state,
I can probably pause
and you see that we updated
And we can probably end
of the workout also
[ Applause ]
So to recap, we just saw
in your iPhone application,
in a workout state, and at
intervention needed
So, let's now talk about some
to follow whenever you are
The first is that we
that your watch application is
reach -- sorry, whenever
from your iPhone.
This is, for example,
to start a running workout
and go for a run, leave
In that situation, we do not
So, the first thing
to keep your workout
even when you lose
Another interesting
is that you can use
because HealthKit is able to
when you don't have
Also, we said that your
from either their iPhone
I would advise if you
on which device they want
Other advice involves
historic workouts.
If you do this, display
not only your own app.
We want you to show
by other applications too.
If you're doing so, don't forget
You do not want to keep
that were removed from
So, to finalize today, there are
to take from this presentation.
First, we learned about
which is a great way of
constantly, and having your
Second, you learned
to your activity rings by
either on your watch, or
And finally, third, we learned
from either your
So we would like you to
take a look at your code, and
to implement some great
For more information, you
where you can see videos
We have some related sessions.
One from HealthKit and another
If you missed them, you can
And here are also
from previous years
This is all for today.
Thank you very much.
Enjoy the rest of your day.
[ Applause ]