[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Wow. Good afternoon,
Good afternoon and welcome.
You want to create great apps.
And having a great layout is
Auto Layout makes it easier
targeting different
adaptations as well as layout
Today we are going to talk
and this session is broken
First is going to be with me.
My name is Jason Yao.
I'm an Interface
I'm going to tell you
Second, Jesse Donaldson from
in Cocoa, and then
from UIKit will tell you
With these tools and techniques,
you will save yourself
when you apply them
So, let's get started shall we?
The first topic I want to
that I'm calling incrementally
incrementally adopting
What do I mean by this?
Well, when you are laying
of Interface Builder,
to constrain everything at once.
You can do it incrementally
simplify your setups, as well as
But before I show you how to do
at an example to
So it all starts by taking
onto Interface Builder Canvas.
You give it a size and position.
You compile it and run.
And you're going to get that
Then you go head and rotate
that it's fitting the same
that needs to be done.
So what's going on here?
What's going on is we're
and to the left with
In fact, what we're doing is
constraints during compile time
in -- with the Auto
If you needed more
what you would need to do is
and add your own constraints.
And the question is could there
perhaps a way without
to get simple resize behavior?
There can be.
New to Xcode 8 is the ability in
to specify autoresizing
that do not have constraints.
What that means is that you
by specifying autoresizing
For those of you who remember
might recognize this UI.
[ Applause ]
This is the Springs &amp; Struts UI.
You can pin things
as decide whether it's going to
And these views are
to your constraint views.
In fact, what we are
to take those autoresizing
to translate them
But we are going
into constraints at runtime.
And there is a key
We're generating them at
because it's going to be more
to you, giving you
to do anything programmatic to
who are pro-Auto
you might recognize this flag.
On the view, we are
translatesAutoresizingMask
What about for the views
to inside of Interface Builder?
They're going to be
You click on the view.
You are going to see
that are affecting that view.
Autoresizing masks are
and translatesAutoresizingMask
So, putting all of this together
we can incrementally adopt
with autoresizing masks to so
and then add constraints for
And that gives you
When you are ready to add
that you want to
start from the parent,
This allows you to adopt
and is great for new
to be building to get that --
but it's also great
where you've been
Well, now you can
existing behavior.
I'd like to show you a
So, let's take a
So, I've got Xcode 8 open
I am going to build
I've got my views
into the View Controller,
and they are fitting
And so, let's take a look
like in landscape by going to
and switching it to landscape.
Clicking over here, you
So, let's go ahead and
And we want this to be
Instead of adding constraints,
to this yet, I can go
And of course we've got the
over here, and all I need to
and pin to the other edge.
Now, I want to work
I'm going to go to the moon,
to the top and to the
As for the cloud, I'm going to
of the pin for -- to the left.
And then for the label, I want
and proportionally precision.
So, I'll get rid of
make it width resizable, and
animation showing me the
And then we'll just pin
and make it height
Now when we take a look at
to landscape, and it's
Let's try two-thirds
It's almost there, but
What's going on there?
What's going on is
at the label it's
It's using autoresizing mask,
and it's proportionally
Autoresizing masks do not take
into account the content
I can fix this up by
but for this particular case UI
I'm just going to go into
and then switch it
over to a minimum font size.
That way it's fitting into
So, now when we go back
it's looking pretty good,
Next, we are going to deal
with the temperature
I want a more sophisticated
So, I'm going to
What I could do is I'm
I want to constrain the
So, I'm going to hold down
drag out a connection
It brings up the constraint
and add multiple
So, I want to center it
and hit add constraints.
Similarly, I want
Control drag to the
and we want to horizontally
as add a baseline constraint.
And then do the same to the sun.
Control drag, hold down
and this time center vertically.
Now, my views have the
And we just need to
so that they are in position.
And so we are going to go to the
for the selected views
Next, I want to make the
So, I'm going to click on that
and just increase
And you might notice that
because everything is already
to automatically
We do more automatic update
So, next, we want to
and this is a sunny day.
So, we're going to go ahead
From the object library, I'm
out that image view,
and then set as image, as
In this case, we probably want
Now, we want to make sure
that this thing is
And we could add
and pin them to each side.
But for this simple resize
to add constraints because we
and just use autoresizing
making it width and
Last but not least, let's go
of my document outline.
So, it's in the back.
And then we're going to clear
because this is a
and we now can see
And then we'll test it out.
So, it's looking good --
It's looking good in landscape,
two-thirds split
as well as iPhone 6s Plus.
And so that is how you can
[ Applause ]
The next topic I want to talk
about is a little
And it is about mixing design
There are situations where
of thing where you are
of Interface Builder and
but you do not know all the
to views until runtime,
on information like time of day
that only the run
There are three tools and three
through for dealing with
The first is the use of
In this situation, I've got an
and center it in my device both
also a little bit inside
I also want the image to
However, I don't know what
to be, not until runtime.
And so, in order to assimilate
so I can see the Interface
and add a 4 by 3 aspect ratio,
approximately what I think
as a place order constraint.
Therefore, it would be
When I actually get the image
in runtime, I'll go ahead
and create the real aspect ratio
For the second example,
custom control.
Your custom control is going
like US -- UIView or NSview.
It's going to provide its own
to manage its own content.
It may want to even
It could provide that size
by specifying its
Interface Builder is
and so it doesn't know what your
to be, but you can simulate
by giving it reasonable
size placeholder.
Therefore, you could
to look like in your layout.
Just remember for your custom
to do this, that you do need
to provide its real
and you can do this
by overriding the intrinsic
on your custom control.
The final example is the
and I'm leaving it for last
because it should also be the
when you have exhausted
for both placeholder
and intrinsic content
And so, we're giving
to tune the ambiguity warning
What that means is that for
and center it on
but that's all I know.
I don't know what horizontal
or what size it's going to be.
In fact Interface Builder
because it's warning me that it
to be able to position it.
It's ambiguous.
I know that I'm going to be
on at runtime when I have all
so I can go ahead and remove
from my work space by going
and switching it from verifying
for position or never verifying
to myself I will add those
that the view holds its size
These are the tools
with designer runtime
when you've exhausted
of constraining everything you
Well, what we've seen is how to
and how to play well with
and we're ready for the
I'd like to invite up my
to talk about what's
Over to you, Jesse.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
Today I'm going to tell
a new layout container that
So maintenance on constraints
when you have something
of checkboxes, and we've
to make it easier to
And it's great anytime you need
to spread some items
But there's some kinds of layout
to achieve like this,
You can build this with stacks,
to help you align the content
across both the rows
So that's why we've
It makes it easy
into an explicitly defined
of alignment for you
So let's have a closer look.
I took this UI from our
and I've added these
to help you see how it
NSGridView uses a couple of
and NSGridColumn, to
and by default they're sized
You can also specify an explicit
These also let you add
if you need some extra space
and if you have some UI
that doesn't apply the
then they can be
NSGridView uses a
to represent the
and the job of a cell is
for a particular content view.
Cells also let you control
if the cell has a bunch
And if you have some
to span the boundaries between
as you might be familiar with
So, I've built a smaller
that still has all the
and I want to go through
and show you how it's built.
So we intend to provide
for NSGridView, but until
to be working with the code.
What I've done here is
for all the controls that
and then whenever you specify
it will take care of
of the grid if needed.
This makes it really easy
at run time and then
into an existing view hierarchy.
There's a few different ways
I think this is the easiest one.
All you need to do
of the content views
And let's get to a
First, you don't have to
It'll take care of however many
for the content that
Second, the code that you end
up with is roughly
at least highly correlated with
This makes it much easier
to come back later and find
So, if we just run this,
That's not too bad just for
but it doesn't match the
The most striking
that the UI is very spread out.
There are all these
And this occurs because the
to the edges of the window.
Now when I did that,
to make the window the
but what actually happened was
that the grid was
If you've used Auto Layout
you may have encountered
with text fields
And we're going to resolve
by adjusting the content hugging
So, the other controls in this
content hugging from
but until we raise the content
then it's possible
to actually pull the content
from the rows and columns.
Once we raise it, instead
of the windows are pulled
So, the next thing I'd like
They're clearly laid
but they really need to be
up against the controls
And this is easy to change
by just adjusting the
The x and y placement properties
cells, and the grid view itself.
The idea is that if the
on the cell itself, then
and column will be used or from
This makes it very easy to
and then have it affect
So, in this case, we can
from the grid view and just set
and we'll see both of the labels
The next thing I'd like to look
at here is the baseline
The text of the labels
with the text in the controls.
And it's subtle in the
by adjusting the row alignment.
Row alignment is inherited
and for this particular design,
it's fine to just
in the grid align by baseline.
And so, we can set the value
and it will affect everything.
And if you look carefully,
you'll see the text
Now, one thing to keep in
that you may have
in your row that
And then you may also specify
So, in that kind of a case,
to satisfy all the requests.
And so, it's important
that the row alignment
over the placement.
The way it works is that
of aligned content views
and then we'll place
from the first cell.
So, the next piece I'd like to
The design has a little
and below the pop-up button,
in our layout by adding
So, the first thing we need
We could actually
that we got the column before
but this way is a
Instead, we ask the
that contains this
and then from the
This is better because if
and changes the configuration of
or something like that, this
If you fill your code with a
then as soon as someone adds
and review all of
which of the indices
And in any case, once we
and set the padding
that we get a little
above and below the pop-up.
We need a little space over
and we can achieve
So, I want to take a moment here
between padding and spacing.
We haven't really talked
The padding values are
and they are just for adding
where you need it in your grid.
The spacing values are available
and they apply to the spaces
between all the rows
So, if we take a copy of the
of the padding, then
The UI is still properly
but we lose the visual
between the different
If instead we keep the
out all the spacing,
We still have our
but the UI is very
And of course if you remove
where the whole thing is
So, an important thing
that the padding properties
You won't have any padding in
But you almost always want some
and so the spacing on the grid
If your use case requires
out immediately next to each
to the grid view and set those
The last piece that's really out
and it's an interesting
to span the boundary between
But we can do that
like I mentioned in
There are a few methods
we can just tell the row to
And when you do this, it has the
of the top leading cell to
So with this code in effect
and now this content view is
as if they were the same one.
And in fact, you can see it's
placement from that
We don't really want it to
but we don't want to have
This checkbox is actually
on the boundary between
So, because the columns
this isn't something that
for you out of the box.
But it does leave you room
And that starts by setting a
When you set these
it has the effect of causing the
that aspect of the layout.
And what that buys us is
that the grid view won't
that might conflict
So, once that's done, we can
from the checkbox's center x
of the checkbox above it.
And then once we
we could actually
like you normally would
But in this case,
in the custom placement
If you do that, then
to maintain any custom
and it will do things
and deactivate the
or not the cell is visible.
So, with this code into place,
into position, and the
the design.
We're finished.
Some pieces of the grid
bit complicated, but the whole
that if you needed
from basic constraints
In fact, there's not a lot
to expand this to the
from the voiceover preferences.
So, to summarize,
if your application has
that you need to manage.
And a great way to start
of your content views
into a grid and see
At that point, you can
of your grid until you've
that you're looking for.
I hope you find it useful.
Next, I'd like to bring out
who's going to talk to you
about some new debugging
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; It doesn't happen often,
and then that turns
and it can be hard to debug.
And that's a layout
When you encounter a
you're usually beginning
and it might be something
You tap the button to
and the button responds,
So, you're running on
in the debugging navigator, and
memory's increasing, and
and you just see a bunch
And what's happening is that
of views that are running
and again in a tight loop.
The run loop's never turning.
Any messages that are
to autorelease objects,
So that's why the
And what's driving this is
And what I mean by that is one
of the [inaudible] views during
that is causing a more
to get a setNeedsLayout so
it goes right back to
and what you want to know
because that's going to
that setNeedsLayout
and what you're going
This information is actually
So, that's why we're introducing
to help with these
This is a launch argument
It's the UIView
or NSViewLayoutFeedbackLoop
depending on whether
And you give it a value.
I've used 100 here.
You can use any value, but we'll
Now when you've got this
the layout feedback loop
subviews for every
and if any of them run
within the same turn
it will then allow
for a little bit while
Then it will throw --
that information into the logs.
It dumps it to the
or the com.apple.UIKit
depending on whether
in both cases the
If you want to know more about
and categories, come to the
at Knob Hill on the unified
Alternatively, you can set a
an exception break point.
And you can print the
or it's also nice to
and maybe introspect what's
So, I said info dump,
So we're going to go
of real live layout feedback
with the layout feedback
Now we're going to look at
and hopefully a walkthrough
of two different logs
We're going to look at a layout
by an upstream setNeedsLayout.
This is actually independent
that was caused by ambiguous
which is very special
So for the first example with
here's a graph of the view tree
where the feedback
And a lot of view in that
running layout.
Often you're lucky and
and ones like this your
But it turned out that ten
They were innocent victims
that was happening higher
So, what was going on was
during its layout, was changing
Now when a views bounds change,
it gets an implicit
because it will need
to re position its views
But also if that view that's
if its superview is
the superview will also
so that layout subviews
on what the layout is.
So when the layout pass gets
it goes back to the top,
because that top view
which resets the bounds
And the feedback loop is powered
over the bounds of the
As you can imagine, there's
So, there's a lot of
So brace yourself.
This is what the log looks like,
which is where I
when you look at
The first thing that's called
that -- of the layout
So, in this loop there
than this view that's
Following that is a recursive
under that top-level view.
And next to some of the views
in that description,
For instance, the -- you
to the top-level view.
In this case it's 23.
Those numbers, the ones with
that are actually
and the numbers are in ordering.
Of course, it's a cycle,
But we do it so that the last
so it gives you an idea of
So, that's a 23, but there
and there is three up here,
So, what happened?
Well, let's go look at the
which is the views
And in this section,
because there is one loop
that lays out in
We have ten views
followed by another two views,
followed by those
And so, those where the
And when you see this situation,
that lay out more than once in
of the other ones that
So, as I said early on,
in where is the top-level view
So, following this
about the actual --
what's actually happening
So, we're going to scroll
of the log to a section
to the top-level view.
So, it's down there, and you
Now, there can be more
You know, usually
This was a pretty refractory
They're pretty similar.
So, I'm only going to
At the top of the backtrace
for the feedback loop debugger,
that in frame five, you see
set bounds.
And if you remember from
the DropShadowView was the
So, the only way that set bounds
of the DropShadowView could
on the TransitionView would be
because the TransitionView
So, that view in frame seven
the TransitionView.
It's something else.
But we don't have that
I didn't have symbols
So there, they are
Furthermore, it could be a view.
We're lucky here because it's
receiving set bounds,
but it could be a view
But hopefully between the
and the information from
in the details you're
And so, what we are interested
for the DropShadowView.
So, we scroll back up,
and we find where that
So, this is under some
And we see that in fact
to bounds changes and
change are repeating
And two of those changes
on the TransitionView, which is
But one of them is coming from
of a particular view controller
of the TransitionView.
So, we've located our problem,
for the programmer to
to achieve their ends that don't
of a superview during layout.
All right, so now we're taking
to example two, which
of feedback loop entirely.
For those of you who have
to do anything very
into the problem of
And ambiguous layout is
Usually you get maybe a
And you're like where did my
the layout is what you want
the device or something and
But sometimes you're
and during the update
that precede layout, you
And if that ambiguity
then variable changes
and each time it'll
And so you get this cycle.
Now an ambiguous layout as
to something that's really
that gets you scratching your
So, that's why when
we call it out at
So they're already
And so, it says ambiguous
And then when you look at
you see ambiguous layout all
it's pretty suspicious.
I'm going to digress
because I have abbreviated
to make them fit
And -- but there's an
that you might not recognize
that is actually
And that's the tAMIC.
You see that right there were
So tAMIC stands for
into Constraints, and now
[ Laughter ]
At any rate, so were pretty sure
that ambiguous layout
And we could go look
for the setNeedsLayout is
But I'm not going
All that's in there is internal
And it's not helpful to us.
So, in this case, we need
and the details here are
with variable changes that
And one thing you
about ambiguous layout
So, you might just be missing
But a bunch of views
because they're all kind
So, you may have a lot of these,
and once that's fixed up,
a whole lot of the rest will
So you look at this.
You see that the min x variable
and minus 160, which is
And because it's ambiguous
that are affecting the layout,
which you can then
and get some idea
I'm going to go over now
because it can be intimidating
And drawing pictures is the
I like to start with a graph of
that are in -- that are
And fortunately for
the views were all
so I could label them for you.
And the next thing I drew
of what the constraints were.
So the constraints
and trailing padding for the
And there was a centering
between the container
And then the action view had
positioning it within
kind of positioning
Something's definitely funky
And finally there's an alignment
between the representation
But there's nothing that
this whole view hierarchy needs
So, that's how we
and the layout feedback loop.
So that's layout
It's a launch argument.
You won't need to use often.
But when you do, it should
And to recap, we saw the --
how you can incrementally
and Interface Builder.
In AppKit, there's NSGridView
If you'd like to see that
in Apple Bug Reporter.
Finally, we have the
debugging threshold.
More information on the Dub-Dub
of the afternoon, and
[ Applause ]