[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Good afternoon everyone.
Welcome to the session
I'm Umer. I'm an engineer
Our agenda will consist of
and how it came about.
Taking a look at an app
to enhance the patient-provider
Working through the CareKit
to create an app here.
Then a demo of an app that uses
And then lastly what's
and the developer
to take it to the next level.
So before I talk
let's see where it came from.
Many of you might be
It's a framework that
that enables providers
to create a study
on a large-scale using iPhones.
So if you're interested, I
at the session from
What's New in ResearchKit,
and Yuen Xiou [phonetic].
And the ResearchKit
hosted by John Roll [phonetic],
In the past year with
of requests on study
to be able to see the data
that they were providing
This led us to brainstorm
While brainstorming these
for care, expanding beyond the
And therefore from ResearchKit
CareKit.
So CareKit is an open source
to build apps that
to take an active
Now CareKit is great for
So a great example for a chronic
Where medication
Also doing assessments like
to see your progress and
that actually improve
Just stuff that you need
a support group or
And then another good
of the most critical parts
post-surgery.
So let's focus on this use case,
and walk through the current
and provider experience.
So currently, if you leave the
you're given a sheet of
This has everything you need
This sheet of paper has some
with many that change over time.
The compliance to these
And they typically
These plans are not dynamic,
and therefore they don't change
And ultimately the
to the hospital to be retreated.
Our goal with CareKit
and take something like
and turn it into what
Now this is a Care Card
to see their entire
One that is interactive,
and it provides a great sense
So in the development of
that there's so much
because now we're on an iPhone.
And that let us create
with the patient
The Symptom and Measurement
which records subjective
The insides dashboard, that
in a way that enables
and gaps in their care.
And the connect module
and sharing the data with a
So let's see how
to enhance the patient-provider
Texas Medical Center was one of
They've taken these modules
to create a unique
So let's take a look at
At first, you are greeted with
to create an account or log in.
Our patient, John Appleseed,
and is set up to use the app.
So John wakes up and
that he needs to weigh himself.
He enters the app
and then he weighs
and the value is
And the CareKit app will
using HealthKit.
This is very easy
because CareKit provides
with HealthKit.
After recording his weight,
to see what he needs
what's on his to-do list today.
So the Care Card and the Symptom
and Measurement Tracker
is populating its
from the ERM Health System
So John doesn't recall
of his activities,
So he can tap into that cell,
and he can read the
And then John completes
and takes his first
He now taps into
to see what assessments he
In his Symptom and Measurement
that he has some surgical
of what could be an infection.
So first he records
using the scale assessment.
And then he decides to take
and upload it to the app.
And he can do that
and Measurement Tracker,
and this data is
Lastly, he performs a
As he is walking around
the sensors on the iPhone are
And once he has completed
the data is transmitted
So John decides to take a look
to see his data for
He can see the tips and
This provides a way for him to
and user-friendly way.
And then he also navigates
to be able to compare his
Meanwhile, he is still worried
that he reported earlier
So he decides to send a
He taps to compose a
to email his provider,
In his message, he does not need
to upload the infection
because it's already been
through the infection
So then later in the day,
from his care team
And he can go back into
that the provider
And that's how Texas Medical
module, and created an app that
with the patient-provider
[ Applause ]
Thanks. Let's take a
of creating an app
Here are the four
that we've already looked at.
Accompanied by two back-end
and the Document Exporter.
Now we'll go into each one of
on the Care Plan Store.
The Care Plan Store consists
So let's begin by defining
then creating an activity
exploring the relationship
and then bringing
So if you look at
we can visualize what an
Let's focus on the ibuprofen.
Where Ibuprofen 200
And the circles underneath
And then activities and
to create the Care Plan Store.
So here's an activity.
Let's go ahead and
You'll first give an identifier,
which we've used
This helps uniquely
in the Care Plan Store.
Then a group identifier to
of certain activities that you
later on.
The title is Ibuprofen.
The text is 200 mg.
Now these properties
So be sure they properly
The tint color, which can be
Apart from the tint
there are many other
that are available in CareKit
and we'll discuss
Now the two properties
on are type and schedule.
So the type determines
which front-end module
So for example, we
which belong on the Care Card.
And we have assessments,
and Measurement Tracker.
So because we're creating
it belongs in the Care Card.
Therefore, the activity
Next, I want to focus
The schedule determines
and when this activity
So there are three
to specify the days
You can use a daily
or you can create your
And then you can
to indicate how many times per
Now this sounds a
but it's really not.
So let's simplify it.
Let's go ahead and define a
Well here's a weekly schedule.
And we'll say we want the
on Monday, Wednesday,
And then we can use a frequency
twice on Wednesday, and
And then combined together
for this activity.
And now we have a complete
to the Care Plan Store.
So before we look
to create the Care Plan Store
let's just discuss what an
So an event is an object
that a developer never
In fact, it's created
by the Care Plan Store.
So to understand how these
to the schedule object
A schedule object
on the frequency you specify.
So for example, here, we
Therefore, we've got four
And then we have two
so you've got two for June 22nd.
And then it'll keep
So the way you can stop the
is by specifying an end date.
Once you specify an end
the Care Plan Store will
So even though a developer
it provides a lot of
From an event object you can
You can see what state it is
which means the user
It could be completed
The results object contains
As things such as
and any other information you
And then there's also a
that this event came out of.
So activities generate
and combined together they
a Care Plan Store.
So let's take a look
So now to create
it's very straight forward.
You just define a variable,
which I have here
of type OCKCarePlanStore.
Then you have to define a
Which in this case
to documents directory.
And then you just initialize
and you have a Care
So now, let's go ahead and
that we just created.
First you will create
So you have a start
as the beginning of this year.
And then using a weekly
for occurrences on each day to
So for example, our
So zero on Sunday, four on
And then so on and so forth.
So once you have that
and initialize the
You give it the identifier,
All the other parameters
There's two here that we
which is instructions
So these are shown
on the detailed [inaudible]
For example, when John
he could see additional
So we'll have additional
with an image, and we'll
when we look at the Care Card.
And then to add this activity
we just call the add method
created, and then use
for any error checking
That's how you create
and that's how you
Let's see how we can use
onto the Care Card now.
Creating the Care Plan Store
and adding an activity
Showing it on the Care Card
and straightforward.
I'm going to show you the
Emphasize the type property
So because you set intervention,
the Care PlanS tore
to show it on the Care Card.
And then to actually
you just initialize the
with a carePlanStore object.
You embed it inside a
The reason this is necessary is
because we provide some
with calendar navigation as
onto the navigation stack.
And then you just present
into a tab bar controller.
And with these three
you get what we have
[ Applause ]
So as you can see here, we have
with some other ones
And then let's look at the
to understand what
So the header view shows you
You can slide left and right
You can select a specific date
The heart completion here
and updated based
in the Care Plan Store.
So the heart and the fill
You can specify a
that might suit your
And then the fill
to match the custom image.
And we'll see an
that has this customization
Now below the header
This shows all the interventions
to complete for that day.
So any time you add
from the Care Plan Store, this
with no additional work
So here's ibuprofen
And if you tap on the
into the detail view which
as well as an image
so that the user does not
that they might be taking.
Now let's take a look at
So this one here asks the user
So while this is something
by just tapping into the cell,
it can also be updated
on the Apple Watch.
So that brings me
is how can we update
Well there's different ways.
One of which, like we
such as medication tracking
where they can report they've
They can be marked completed
after the user has
Such as an active
Or it can be updated
from device sensors
and the iPhone using HealthKit.
So that's the Care Card.
It's an interactive
that uses the Care Plan Store to
and provide the user
on their day-to-day health.
So just like the Care
and Measurement Tracker also
to record a subjective and
So the process of adding an
to how we did in the
So let's say that we have
to create for your lower back.
The code here is nearly
so we'll assume that
to the Care Plan Store.
Now let's take a look at how
to actually show
Just like the Care Card, you
with your controller with
There's a delegate
but I'll get to that shortly.
And then embed it into
And then again, just present it
So if we dissect this UI,
the header view contains
as the Care Card where
and right to change weeks.
We select specific days to
As you're working on the
the ring -- there will be a ring
And once you've completed them,
to know that you have no more
The color for the ring and the
to suit your app.
Underneath here, you will have
to be completed for the day.
Now there can be a
so let's take a look
Here we have a pain survey.
For this you can use the
to present a beautifully
They can be an active task.
So you could launch
or create a custom active
such as the range of motion one.
It can be self-reported.
So you can present a view
in the Texas Medical Center
to take a photo of the
And then it could be any data
from a HealthKit or
So in the Texas Medical
John jumped onto
and it automatically updated
So that's where the
In order to present the
you have to implement the
which provides a callback
for the developer whenever the
In this call back, you're
that they want to launch.
And then you can determine
to present appropriately
Once you've presented
let's say a pain survey,
and use the data from that
then you create a result object,
an optional unit strength, and
for all the -- any additional
And then you just update the
the result object, the state
and then use the completion
And all that combined gives you
and Measurement Tracker.
[ Applause ]
The Insights Dashboard can use
to generate messages and charts.
And this allows the user to
that they're actually
So for us to make this easy
we've created what we
You can plug and play those
And these also can include
And they can also be charts
that we introduced in CareKit,
So for example the charts
from ResearchKit can
into our chart object.
So let's take a look at the
This is a medication
Message items help motivate
by surfacing valuable
This message item is using
to calculate the adherence for
These messages can also be
and then passed into
So let's look at the code on how
Here you can specify start
So I've used the beginning
and the end of last
as a start and end date.
Then we can call the
on the Care Plan Store,
to enumerate on, the dates
and to, and then in the handler
in the store for that activity.
And then we can enumerate
to check their state
if they've been completed or
So let's say we calculated
and we want to go ahead
Here you will want to take the
and turn it into a
So that it's easier
and actually gain
And then you just create --
initialize a message item with
like to show, a color,
For example, this one's a tip.
Next we have a group bar
to present multi-series
For example, in this
and ibuprofen mapped together
in a way that allows
and gaps in their care.
So here I've defined a
It's of type OCK insight ttem.
A barChartItem consists
In the one we just saw
and an ibuprofen series.
So in order to create
we will define a pain series
by initializing a bar
And an array of numeric
of string values,
Now the number of items
in the array are not
So your chart can show
or any number of data points.
The array of numeric values is
on the chart.
And the array of string values
Oftentimes these
For example, in the
the numeric values determine
but they don't represent
For example, the 1-5-4 and so on
and so forth can
to mean one tablet, five
Therefore, the value
that their medication is
50 percent, and 40 percent.
So now that we have the
we're going to go ahead and
Give it a title, a
And we've got two arrays for
that show up to the
And then you can specify
like to show.
This could be one, two, or ten.
Now there are two
which is the scale.
The minimum scale range and
If you don't specify these, we
on the data you've given us.
But if you do, then be mindful
so that the data
For example, if you have data
to ten, and you specify a
then all the points that are
to the user.
And it will make the
So we have a message
And we have a chart item.
Let's go ahead and create
You initialize the
with an array of
Give it an optional
A title and a subtitle.
And then you just present it,
[ Applause ]
And that's how you
So the next one is Connect.
Connect allows you to
with your care team and
So to make this easy as well,
we've created what we
And there are two types here.
We've got a care team contact,
or any other care team member.
And then we have a
which could be a close
So if we look at
these show up grouped
Here we have the care
And then down below we have
So let's look at the code
To create a physician
PhysicianContact of
And then you just initialize the
which is careTeam, the name,
to this contact, the tint color,
and message number, which
for formatting purposes.
The email address is just a
to be shown if there's
to specify what the physician
or the care team
Once you've created
you just initialize the connect
of all the contacts, and
But there's also a delegate
which we'll get to
And before we can present
in a navigation controller,
and detail views for
So you will get a Connect
with the Connect
Now if we focus in on the
Dr. Paul Cashman.
If we tap into the cell, it will
where you get a contact
In this contact card, you see
up top here, which shows you
Text message him, or
And then down below is
and send your reports with him.
Now this is where the
The connect delegate
with this contact.
So for example, when the
this method is called.
And then you are given
from which you can determine
to generate and then you can
Now this part is
To create the report
So let's see what we can
So to make the connect
to make it easy to share
we've created the
which works hand-in-hand
The document exporter
from the Care Plan Store.
And even other sources to create
And just like everything
to make this easy, we've created
You've got headers and footers.
We've got texts and paragraphs,
And then combining
you can create a rich
[ Applause ]
So as we can see in this
of the patient, a user friendly
and now the same chart
at in their Insights
by their provider, so that
and gaps in their care.
I know there's a
out all the subjective
for these patients
So let's take a look at
We have a
which is just text content.
This text content can also come
from the Care Plan Store
Then we have a document
which basically accepts the same
in the Insights Dashboard.
So there's no need
or new chart generation here.
Then we have a table here which
And an array of arrays, in
of the data you want to show.
For example, a weekly
or a weekly data of
Then once you have all the
to use in the document, you
Give it a title.
And then give it an array
And then turning
into a PDF is really
You just call the
Use the NSData that's returned
and write it to a file URL.
So now when the user taps the
and generate the PDF using
created, present it
so they know what they're about
on the share button and then
to share this PDF with others
And that's how the Document
with the Connect Module
[ Applause ]
So all these modules
and form the CareKit framework.
So Patient PAL recently
care experience using CareKit.
And I want to show you how
to match their user experience
and they've created
to help their patients
So their Care Card
with a custom image
Their app is focused on
to perform certain
For example, if you focus on
the pink one down
on the remaining
But before it can be
we have to perform
In this exercise task,
of the exercise along with a
to make sure they're performing
What's even nicer is
to record yourself while
so that the care provider
When you tap the
it shows it embedded
And once you feel like you've
you can tap Get Started
And then there's an
through each set and each rep.
Once you've completed
you can see under Care
to reflect the change.
And now you've got a completion
for that little circle
So by default, we
we provide detailed views for
but you can implement
to provide your own as well.
So one other thing that
that when the user taps on
for example the hamstring
and bring up a view controller
that lets you send
So there's the two
And then the third one,
go ahead and let's
And now the app will go ahead
to come back in and perform this
So CareKit provides a lot of
so that you can tailor
And these are some of the ones.
So that brings me
or slides What's
Currently, CareKit allows you
Next, we want to focus
between these apps and
and then also transmitting
to the care team app or portal.
This sort of infrastructure
in the Texas Medical Center app
What we would like is, as you're
and linking them to your cloud,
that you can contribute
And other people who are using
benefit from it.
CareKit is open source.
It will become what
[ Applause ]
So please contribute.
You can find the
It's
on github.com/carekit-apple/
So here's how you can help
Your role involves checking
out the issues section
You can create a new issue or
then develop the feature.
Feel free to reach out
with any questions you have
And then work with us through
And this usually involves
and the Apple engineers.
And that's kind of where
Once you have facilitated with
of the feature, we'll
and enhance the feature even
We'll localize it for all the
And then we'll do QA testing
We might ask for your help
And then once the feature's
and merge it into the framework.
With CareKit we are
of us can work together
to create this new
You can find more
It includes links to our website
as well as information on
if you have any technical
or if you have a
that you would like to share.
Be sure to check out
that can help you
And thanks for coming
[ Applause ]