[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, my name is Daphne Larose.
I'm a software engineer
Welcome to my talk.
Thanks to those of you
I know it's kind
So, I wanted to start
that we commonly
The first thing that comes
about you, are converter apps.
Makes sense, convert
But I wonder though,
that also use measurements but
I don't know, but when I think
it's interesting, right, because
We just don't normally think
and they can pop up in
one of those ways being when
that are common for whatever
So, let's say I'm in
that is calculating
and I expect the measurement to
but they show up
It's like, hmm.
It makes for kind of a jarring,
And so in this talk, we're going
of APIs that helps you ensure
that this never happens
So, if we think again about
other apps that we
I had mentioned converter
But another example
So, today we're talking about
It's called Jammin' in
because z's are cool, and
So, the premise of the game is
to dance from level to level.
I have some pretty set
One, I need this
Like, the most fun a
Two, tons of emoji,
Three, it needs to be
I want it everywhere.
So, when we think
that this game would
every round would be
and within this jam session,
of time that it takes our player
the distance that
the number of dance
and maybe even, like, the rate
But let's think about the things
Notice anything?
They're all measureable.
They're quantifiable
And so, if we were stop
whip out a computer,
how would we represent this?
Well, we could represent
That's true.
Easy. The problem with that
some context when we do that.
And so let's look at an example.
So we have our little player.
I told you, lots of
And our little player has
and they've moonwalked
Now, if we stored this distance
but what does five
It brings up this
But if we say five feet,
This actually makes sense.
It now has context
And so now, let's talk
or the API that Foundation
to accurately represent
So, you have a new struct.
It's called Measurement, and
and we'll get into what a
Contains a unit as well as
So, what's cool about this is
to represent a measurement
And so if we go back
let's say in the game we
of distance traveled, but
of the distance that the
How would we do this
Well, now we can
as a measurement of five feet.
We could also represent
as a measurement of,
And so now, you can actually
with them.
You can add them together
which is a measurement
You can multiply them
the value that you expect.
You could also divide them,
and get a similar
So if we go back to
what are some things that we
Well, first off, every unit
Units can have a dimension, and
for the dimension length.
It could use, like, feet
Units could also be
so one foot could be equivalent
And so now we have APIs
to actually represent
Now, if you're paying close
that every unit has a symbol,
and so in this API we're
We don't necessarily
or the equivalents because not
to another one, and not
But at the very least,
so we're representing that here.
But if we go back
of a dimension, what
What does that actually mean?
Well, dimensions are categories
with different kinds of units.
So, when we think of
length can be represented
feet, miles, what have you.
Dimensions also always have
to the length example, the
You can also perform
within a single dimension.
So you can convert
meters to miles, et cetera.
So now we have API to represent
that dimension subclass is Unit,
which means that it inherently
We have a converter property,
and I'll go into what a unit
but essentially it defines
and from its base unit.
We have an initializer,
and a converter instance,
every dimension has a base unit.
So now we have a class property
that will return
The important thing to
is that every instance
in and of itself a unit.
Now, with this new API
the cool thing is that
to you some 170-plus units that
You don't even have to
You can just use them, like,
And most of these
with the International System
that you're already used to
Now let's look at an example.
We have the dimension of
of units that are class
this dimension.
And so, if we go back
instances of a dimension
what happens is any time you
getting back an instance
The difference between each
their symbols are different,
that define their
So, just an overview of all of
to you, all the different
Remember I told you there's like
play with them to
But we have some pretty cool
like area, mass,
But also, some kind of
and electric current, but sounds
So, let's go back to
and our distance
So, this is code
Now, we're going to
out because we're
So, we're leaving
but now we're defining
of six, but instead of
we're passing in kilometers.
Now, this is where things
because we're now
and distanceToGo
and one's in kilometers.
What does this mean
Is it in terms of feet?
It is in terms of kilometers?
Will this stage just
I don't know.
But, phew, no, it won't.
Actually what happened is
of the base unit,
And so what's cool about this is
of this implicitly for you.
You don't have to
You could just use the
with regular scalar values
and you get the results
So, now let's say, and
to track the player at certain
of the demo we're just printing
to do something funkier,
add more functionality
But the key here is
to compare these
So Measurement has support for
to be able to do this.
And so if we were to
we would get what we expect,
because Measurement was
that distanceTraveled is
So, let's talk more
because we haven't really
As previously mentioned,
in terms of their base unit.
There are methods that
and from the base unit
about that a little bit more
The important thing, though,
that conversion can only happen
So, when you think of
you can convert kilometers
to convert kilometers
Conceptually that doesn't
And so, in this case, with
to do that, it would
or it would be a
So, remember I had
like 170 plus units
Chances are, you won't need to
but if you do, that's the
about defining them,
You can actually just use them,
the units that are already
but if you are creating a
about how the converter
And so, the cool thing is
that Measurement can
for you implicitly even
It just auto-magically works.
So, let's talk about
We're making some custom
We have a jamz unit here,
to calculate total time
of this unit called jamz.
Seconds is a little
But if you see here, we have
What is that?
We haven't really
So let's go back to talking
about conversions
So again, to and
UnitConverter is a root class
that describe this conversion.
So baseUnitValue(fromValue),
UnitConverterLinear
and defines them linearly.
So, for all the math people
of A X plus B, where
and B is the constant.
So, if we go back
we see here that this
a scalar value of
that one jamz unit is equivalent
in our linear function, we have
would be.
So, if a jam session was
then if we wanted to
it would be four times 30
and you could do the reverse.
120 divided by 30 to
Yeah. So let's say I wanted
for length, for example,
to calculate distance traveled
I wanted to do something a
like hopz.
So, here, same concept.
One hopz is equivalent
and so we're defining the
and same with some
that I would create for this.
So, you start to get the idea.
So, if you recall
about the jam session,
that I had named was the number
Unfortunately, the
of units does not
that recognizes dance movements.
I'm not entirely sure
that we are defining here today.
And so, we have UnitDanceMove
with a base unit of
And so you see here that one
to another wackyArmMovement,
another way to think about how
many of the base unit make
So, here's one-to-ones so
Let's say we wanted to
It's like, approximately
like four wackyArmMovements,
cabbagePatch is like
Sure. And of course, no dance
without jazzHands, which is
I think it's pretty accurate,
And so now, let's go back and
that I had outlined earlier.
So distance traveled, this
which will be in terms of this
jamTime will be in
and dance moves will be
So our player will be roboting
And so the dance rate
of meters per second,
none of the other measurements
so how are we going
Well, we can take stepsTaken
We can also take the jamTime
and now we can actually
in terms of meters per second.
And so the cool thing here
of code we were actually able
to completely define
So, now we know how to actually
as model objects,
But I told you, though,
that I want this game
Now to do that we actually have
That's where things
So, if we have our player, and
for only five feet, they danced
Hard core.
If we wanted to represent this
across the world,
Well, in Canada, we could
as it was previously written,
If we were to try to represent
we'd actually have to
In Arabic, we'd have
and change the number
that our right-to-left
So, all of this is more
to add manually to my app.
And then finally, in the
What are those?
What are those things?"
So, then, not only do I have to
of my calculations, but I also
for formatting, which is
to add to my app.
So, what's the solution here?
You let Foundation do
We have a new formatter
It formatters both measurements
so you don't have to
So let's take a look at it.
Its subclass is Formatter.
If you're familiar with any
of our other formatters,
It has the unitOptions property,
about unitOptions in a second.
It also has unitStyle.
So, again, if you're familiar
with the other formatter,
It has a locale that's setable.
Now, chances are, you're
to the current locale
which is what this locale
but if you needed to set
It also takes a custom
So, let's say you wanted your
to be represented in terms
you can provide a
to do that for you.
It also has methods that take
in both a Measurement
So let's talk a little bit
The cool thing is
by default the formatter formats
of your user's locale.
So, you don't even
It also takes into account
So, you know, if you're
of road distance verses in terms
to want to use different units
So I'll take a look
that MeasurementFormatter
One is provided unit, and
where we want to pass in a
but our locale is the U.S. Now
for road distance for
because that's what's
But if you set provided
that whatever unit you
that actually gets formatted.
There's also an action
So, this is great in
So, if your, you know, your
and you're really concerned
then instead of putting
which would take up a
you can actually have it
Another is temperature
So let's say you
that represents 90
but you don't want
to actually show.
You can set this to get the
So, let's play around
We have our formatter here,
and we have our original
in five kilometers,
player danced.
And now we want to get a
You'll see that the result is
about this is that in
not only did we get the
but we didn't have to do
just out-of-the-box
it knew exactly what to do.
Now let's say that we give it
And Measurement,
that has no conception, no idea
but we create this hopz
to the formatter, and
to do the conversion
We don't have to do anything.
Now let's say though, you know,
and we actually want
so we'll set provided unit.
We'll give it a measurement
And now the result will
Now this case is a
because not only are we
but we're also providing
within a custom dimension,
And so at this point, it's
what will MeasurementFormatter
Oh, well, it'll do
which is pretty awesome.
So, now, I'm going to hand
of the Foundation
to show how measurements
and formatted in the High
Thanks [applause].
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Daphne.
So, my name is Peter Hosey.
I am also an engineer
and like Daphne said, this
where we're showing a list
As you tap on each one,
about the level, the
You see some important
about playing the level,
And you even see your statistics
of how well you've
You see things like
how many wacky arm
You see how far you've danced.
You see how fast you've danced.
But these values are
They lack dimension.
So we don't know,
Now you could implement an
You could start small by just
of each of these numbers.
You could maybe build out
have a unit conversion system
that will understand
and translate the unit
and that's a lot
Like Daphne said, let Foundation
We now have Measurement
and MeasurementFormatter
so let's use them in our game.
So we're going to start by
that Daphne showed you,
We've got a couple of length
and we have our four
that do not come
Now that we've got our custom
into our model, which
which has our basic
and includes the
which are just numbers.
So let's change them
So, now we have a measurement
of length, and a
and as we change the properties,
so much we change
So, now it's possible to create
and we want to do that in
which is a controller for this
Our List ViewController
which returns a JSON list of
containing all of
And particularly includes
as just numbers.
So, we want to create
around these numbers,
so now this a number
This is a number of Hopz.
This is a number of hopzPerJamz.
Now that this information is in
as measurements in our
and that's the only
in the List ViewController.
Now we can go over to the
which is what shows this
for every one of these levels,
and we can use our
So, we already have
This is a NumberFormatter, and
to six digits with zeros,
but we want to build
We want to make this
So we're going to add
and I'll explain
Now that we've created them,
we go to the same place we're
formatter, which is in
This is inherited
and here we're overwriting it.
We configure the
with our minimum integer
to configure our
to use our provided unit,
which you can't tell
And use our NumberFormatter
so that we continue
And I mentioned we created
so let's configure
This one we want to use the
so we're not going to
but we're still going to set
And now if I run that, oops, oh.
So, I've configured
Now I need to actually use the
So we're already
and we say sting
Well that worked fine
but now it's a measurement.
So now we need to talk to
Now, it's a simple
Otherwise, it's exactly
Works the same for
The other two we're creating
and you can imagine how
for your localization effort.
Here too we want
So, we'll use our other
again, the same thing.
We do string from, in this
and this returns a string,
So now we can run the app.
And now we see our
So this is a start, but,
we're still not really
which is our goal to start with.
We need to show these
So we could do some
but MeasurementFormatter
So, we're going to create one
and as we have the custom
we're also going to
MeasurementFormatter.
As we create it, same
except we don't' actually
because MeasurementFormatter
automatically to the unit
that the player expects
Now, this is where it's going
so bear with me a moment.
We're currently talking
asking it for one string,
and passing it directly
So what we're going to do
to the customUnitsMeasurement
get its string for
Then we talk to the
and get its string
And then we'll use a
to put these two things
that we will pass to the label,
and we do it also
And that's all we have to do.
In order to show both our
that the player expects
their real world distance.
[ Applause ]
But we don't need to stop there,
because remember the goal
over the world in every country.
So miles is great in
we're in the United States.
We see miles.
But we want to make sure
So I'm going to make use of
of your scheme, so I'm going
I'm going to duplicate
and when it duplicates
It's going to ask me for a
to give my scheme a
And now, having named my scheme,
I'm going to make one simple
Options tab, Application Region.
I'm going to our testing into an
And now, I'm going to
and with no code
with no configuration
just changing the scheme, we
this shows kilometers.
That's all you have to
with our new Measurement
and MeasurementFormatter
Thank you [applause].
Thank you, Daphne.
&gt;&gt; Thanks so much, Peter.
So, obviously this game
I'm, like, super
Let's wrap up real quick though.
So, we just saw throughout
and in the demo how Measurements
that we can use in our apps,
We also saw that it's
and they require very little
And the best part
of this very powerful
without having to specify
just right out of the box.
So, now you don't actually have
to suddenly become a
change all the logic
to be able to support this.
You could just use it as-is.
If you'd like more information,
These sessions are
but if you're super
I would recommend
and thank you so much.
[ Applause ]