[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, welcome to
My name's Corbin Dunn, and
with my colleague Jeff.
We're both AppKit
So let's jump right into it.
What are we going
We have a whole bunch
We're going to talk about
drag and drop and how
container view controls,
using some system appearances,
and some other cool
Tons of stuff which
with a quick demo
that we see in this screen shot.
How it's alive in new features
or existing features
And all these technologies, most
on Mac OS 10.10 or
to 10.12 we will specifically
And this demo app we
It's not quite available
and it will be associated
So let's jump right
about creating a modern
and what you can do there.
So modern look means a modern
such as shown in
One thing you want to be
content view.
The full size content view
to extend underneath
that I'm highlighting
And that means that full size
automatically blurred by the
without you having
Using a full size content
It's just a window style mask.
You can use the
on it to include it.
Or if you're using Interface
check box, full size
So if you're using the full
to offset your content
For instance, let's say
that we want underneath
We might want to put like
If we put that label
under that titlebar/toolbar
a dynamic height that would
to not have a hard
because hard coding
So what we have is we have the
on NSWindow.
This is a key value observable,
which you can use to find
out whenever the
in turquoise changes.
So you can go and place your
titlebar/toolbar based on that.
But we also encourage you
And if you're using auto
contentLayoutGuide which
For instance, inside of your
might be overriding
and you want to create
You grab the window's
tick the top anchor for it,
and you create a constraint
to that text field's top
And if you do that, that text
that titlebar/toolbar area
without you having
It's very simple to do.
Next for a modern app
to use a streamlined toolbar.
So here's a screen shot
The things to notice here is
or, sorry, it's got
and you would have an icon there
if the app actually had
If I go to using a streamlined
the toolbar is pushed
and the window buttons,
are directly in line with
To do this it's really simple.
And all you have to do is set
to .hidden, and that
the toolbar will be pushed up,
When do you want to do this?
You probably want to do this
of like shoebox applications,
system preferences, things
of like one window applications
So what other things
Well, you might want
that titlebar/toolbar area with
For instance, you might want
to have an accessory view
the titlebar, and by
to automatically be blurred
without you having
The size to be automatically
as the window is resized without
So how do you do this?
It's really simple.
We have a view controller
called NSTitlebar
set the view to that
In addition, it exposes
So the layout attribute could be
this accessory is going to be on
And notice the text appeared
we're using the proper
in content layout guide
In addition to the bottom, the
to leading or trailing.
And this means you get a
up in your titlebar area
or something else that
New to macOs 10.12 is the
and trailing as opposed
which were published before.
We prefer you to use
because it allows your
when you're using a right
So, for instance, if I'm just
to left mode you can see
that that accessory view
to the other side without
Next we, the system,
may actually be adding our
to your window.
For instance, we might be using
where we aggregate
into one sort of virtual window.
So how do we do tab windows, and
You don't really
If you order a window front what
that are similar to that window.
And by similar I mean we look
for the tabbing identifier
If it has the same tabbing
to aggregate those windows
The windows themselves are all
it might be in a hidden tab.
But we actually hide them
If you're using NSDocument,
such as the plus button inside
without you having
But if you aren't using
responder chain method
to create a new document or a
For more information check out
to see more details on this.
For more information
the accessory view controllers
with full screen, I highly
from 2015 on improving the
Next let's talk a little
So what is core animation?
Well, it's a graphics
of the work on the
So everything can be
We can do very fast
And the base component
How we actually create
and your views using
So this is an example
like a background
and then a front layer
So you want to compose your
to create the final look.
Let's take a look at some of
or CALayer that allow
of what you see on screen.
Speaking of contents, CALayer
The contents property can be
that actually represents
for that layer's contents.
But you could also set
such as the background
the border width,
There are more properties you
to see the other things that are
So these are some of
to actually set how
And we're going to talk a little
But what you should be doing
backed view.
So you're going to be using
which I'll show in a
and that will implicitly
And that means that you can
draw method.
But if you're using layers we'll
methods, updateLayer
And in just a second I'm going
and when you'll want
So what do we actually recommend
or when should you use core
Well, we recommend that
content view.
And when you layer back one
will automatically get
without you have
for every individual child view.
We recommend that
and you not use CALayers
because that takes care of some
such as when a layer is
We'll do some more setup
Turning on layer
On the content view of your
to true and code.
Or, of course, you can just go
and check the checkbox
on a top most view.
So an important property
on layer backed views is the
You want to set this
which is not the
What this means is you
as a developer whenever you
or the view to change you
This is slightly
in the way normal
where they might actually
across changing a frame origin.
So it's something you need
and it's better for performance
So how do you actually get
So let's say your view is dirty.
You mark SetNeedsDisplay.
And what we do is we
what do you do for
What's your answer
And here we fork.
If you say yes
for wantsUpdateLayer then we're
If you say no we're
So this is a complete fork.
It's an either/or.
Then you may be wondering, well,
when should I use
This gets back to what I was
and NSLayer properties.
So if you can represent your
by setting CALayer properties
to use updateLayer.
It's going to be more efficient.
So if you can set
layer background color,
If you can't, then that's
to override draw or drawRect
and actually do your manual
The thing about doing
which implements drawRect
backing score which you
And so if you have a lot of
in particular for memory.
Let's take a quick look at an
and how you would use it.
So first of all you'll
say that you want to get
by responding with a true.
And then you're going to get
where you can actually
So we access the view's
and the self.layer
or whatever other
and you set it at this time.
So that was talking about modern
for the titlebar/toolbar.
Let's talk about drag and drop
So modern drag and drop,
what you should be doing is
in this video right here.
Drag flocking is where each
independently and flock
And when you let go of the mouse
to where their original
To use drag flocking you
beginDraggingSession,
of the actual items that you
It's very simple to do.
For more complex
or collection view we
for you to adopt these.
So for table view you should
delegate method.
tableView pasteboardWriter
where it can provide an
item for every item in a table
As opposed to the older
to a pasteboard where you
in one go to the pasteboard.
Similarly, collection view
that look very similar to that.
And for collection view
pasteboardWriter
as opposed to the other version.
So with drag flocking new to
for drag file promises.
This may be a reason why you
up until this point.
And you can use NSFile
and NSFile PromiseProvider
and writing of file promises.
Take a look at the talk,
for more information and
So let's take a look
And let's say you
And let's say it has a
So you have this button.
And what you want to happen
on that button down and up it
You will do some action
But you also want to be aware
and if you actually drag the
So how to get both those
modern way that works well
Well, first of all let's
and how you'll track
And this window has a method
with a timeout mode handler.
And the handler is
We prefer that you use this
on NSApplication which was
With the older method you
With the newer method you
to do your work.
Taking a look at a
in that button we subclass
The first thing we're going
to do inside this mouseDown
We want to track
for the drag and
If the user did a click,
then we're going to just be
and we're going to say,
for super because that way
like an NS button.
But here's the extra part.
Let's say you click and
and drag inside this
out if you went far enough, if
to pass off to the window
And so what that means is when
of the window the window and
over dragging the
You should not be dragging
by calling set frame again
If you pass off to the system
if your application hangs,
to be moveable even if your
In addition, other
such as space switching,
down when you move to
window snapping,
Any other new system
with window movement
without you having
So we encourage you to
by calling performDrag.
So that was talking
a little bit about
Let's talk about container
to handle those properly.
So container view controls we
table view at this point.
And you do that by using the
40, or inside of an interface
up directly in interface
And why you want to do it is
on that video new features
which only exists in the
To do the swipe to
There's a table view
on a particular edge, the left
leading or trailing edge.
And you can return an
or a zero or more row actions.
In the NSTableView
to create a string value for
and a handler to actually
when the user clicks on the
to actually invoke it.
Next let's talk about ScrollView
So for using all these
about let's say that we
or let's say we take the window
titlebar appears transparent
which makes the titlebar
Applications like Messages
to allow the contents
So here we can see
That ScrollView on the side is
the titlebar/toolbar area
and would automatically
But this presents a dilemma.
How do you get that ScrollView
so that you don't have to add
or anything really weird?
And it's very convenient
ScrollView has a method or a
that allows you to drop the
In fact, we can do
so we have a property
ContentInsets.
And if you set that to
to do is ScrollView
to track the contentLayoutRect
and automatically set
to be the appropriate
But you as a developer may
of the content insets.
You might want to drop
and add some other
like a search field
And an example of where we do
down a little bit and adds
That's how we accomplish
in our system applications.
Next let's talk about
You should be using auto layout,
and you should be using
Which means that all your nymphs
of multiple copies
and different localizations.
You shouldn't use fixed
You want to use controls to have
of hard coding sizes.
Prefer to use StackView.
Use leading and trailing
All these things are right
for creating a properly
But let's take a look at some of
In particular let's look
Layout and Mirror section.
So the text direction
It has natural, left to
Natural means that the actual
at the string value that
like a text field, look
And if that string is a right
to left string then
in the direction right to left.
If it's a left to right string
Or you can manually control
to right or right to left.
The next property is the
which is key to layout.
And it has either left to
System controls such as table
and may do things
like automatically
when it's set to right to left.
The default here is
But the interesting thing
because it's a little confusing.
So if mirroring is set
that userInterface
the last property we just
from left to right to right
to left localization
And it will also flip other
like the cell image
So the button's image is on
and put it on the right
But one property that we won't
If you have it set
or natural those don't
so we won't flip them.
So then you might
when do I actually not
Well, you might want to
when you want a control that has
like a play button,
a fast forward button
And then these are all
so how do you actually
So in code you actually have
for the user interface
If it's set to left to right
to say, hey button, I want
when it's in a left
And I want that image to
in a right to left localization.
You have to manually do this.
But to make it a
in 10.12 we added a
and an init method which allows
a target and an action and
happen for you.
So that's it for
I'm going to bring up Jeff
storyboards and some
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, thanks, Corbin.
We got an absolute ton of
so I'm going to dive right
So here's our app.
We've been looking at
And we're trying to
And we've decided that we want
to adopt this really
This is kind of characteristic
And we're nothing
with our little demo app here.
But look at this, this
We have an entirely different
we need all our control
segmented controls,
And all of our text
from dark text to light text.
Which seems like an awful lot of
in one line of code
All we've got to do is create
assign it to the window,
and it's automatically
You can think of an appearance
and artwork that we use
of our standard system controls
and also all of our
These are things like
And for that reason
that you use these
Not only do you fit in better
but you'll continue to fit in if
or if you change your
So let's take a closer look.
Here we've got a panel.
It's got tons of nice labels,
And all we have to do is
and we see a pretty
Our control artwork has changed,
of course, inverted
We can actually take
and apply this cool
You may have noticed a slide
that we applied is
That doesn't mean that you're
but it does mean that
in a vibrant context.
And to get this appearance
of your controls as a subview
And you'll automatically
blurring and also
for everything on top.
Now, you might be thinking
but my designer has this
that they want for
and so I'm not going
I think that I'm not planning
or vice versa so I'm
Well, let's have some
Let's check in with
and we're going to
in the middle here
And let's see what
On the left we again
But on the right
with Increase contrast
And although we haven't
this transformation is
as the transformation
You can see that the window
lighter, our text is
and all of our controls have
bold outline.
It makes it really pop
Now, when you provide a
really second guess that.
We can't adjust for
And so if you don't supply
secondary label color, you
to people who need settings
to get the most out
Now I hinted a moment ago at
We're not going to go into
but I would refer
in 2014 that's Adopting
of the new UI of OS X Yosemite.
And that's appearances.
It's a real simple way to theme
harmonious with the overall
Next up storyboards.
Storyboards are a
to design not only the
and the views that comprise
but also visually
between those components.
In this case when I say
in terms of controllers,
and view controllers.
And we connect them together
those are the arrows up
And segues abstract away
of putting these
Those are things like adding
creating popovers,
Now, one thing that we need to
when we have separable
you can see I've got
and you can see the
all these new little components
that every piece of UI
that it wants to
And we can't necessarily
from one scene to another.
Of course, if we did that
components anymore, and then
of this whole thing.
But sometimes this
on doesn't really live conically
in down in our leaf node.
Sometimes it might
up on the window
So how do we propagate
up from the top level
Well, we have a couple of
and fast rules but
that we think are good
For one, dependencies should
If you're wondering, if you
for this just follow the
If nothing else this gives you a
flow in your application,
and that makes it a lot
Next try to reduce the
about your UI structure that
Now, you just got done designing
And if you hardcode
that structure is put together
to make a change to your
and forth.
You've got to change your
and now you're fighting
Let's not do that.
Let's have our code focus
on designing our interface
And one technique that we
to use protocol conformances
to work really generically
So here's an example.
Let's say we have
it's up on our window
and we want to automatically
to anything in our view
So in our didSet we're
and call this propagate method.
And we've got this protocol
that we've defined off screen
And this just says I
with a photoController.
And so if we look at a
that it conforms to
the property.
And then we also automatically
to all of its children.
But what about things like
things that are kind
These probably don't exist
when you're setting
And we need to be able
on demand before they
And that's exactly what the
This is called on the
or window controller at the time
And in this case instead of
or segue identifier forcibly
that we expect it to be
of specific setup, here we're
We're checking out what
and then setting the
And what this does is
from focusing really strictly
We're saying I have
and anything that's presented
that knowledge automatically
It's really handy.
More about actions.
It's really frequent
to handle an action that's
in the same scene that
And this is exemplified
in their own little scene
from your UI.
And luckily we have a
for handling this case, and
If you're coming from
where maybe you don't use
so heavily, that is that little
of every storyboard scene.
That's a proxy for
And so if you hook up
to that proxy it will
up the responder chain when
But what if there's no
that handles your method?
Or what if in the case of zoom
in it's not always
For example, we might be
and so we don't want our zoom
We should be able to look
And that's what UI
So let's take a look
that would inspect UI
if a control is actionable.
The first thing that we're
for the target for an
And what that does is it
responder chain and
that implements that action.
Or it might not find any action,
or it might not find
The first case we want to look
at for the results
that implements the
validations protocol.
And this just means you
if a control is valid.
And so if you're on the
and you have a control that
implement this method.
And controls like NSMenuItem
and toolbar item will
against that method.
So we can ask that method.
And then, of course, we also
that just handles the method
at all which clearly means
that we're not prepared
And there's just some techniques
So now we've been talking
of design time facets
Let's look at some more
that really help you make
And the first of those
NSUserActivity is this
of what your app is doing
what is it editing, etcetera.
And this is the object
to move those activities
It kind of takes your whole
I won't have time to go into the
but I do want to
of an object this really is.
You construct it
and that is a unique identifier
that describes the
And this is also a key that you
to declare I'm a
up this activity
And then you just fill in
to describe your activity,
and also some user info.
Basically just the most basic
to jump back into that
We want to keep this
because it's often
and we definitely want our
We also get an opportunity
to add the absolute
about our context right before
or at some point before
And this is called at some
as needing to be saved.
And we'll call this
so you can fill in
Now, how do we decide
current activity?
Because, of course, we need
to certainly determine what
Well, you can manually manage
and resign current
That means that you're
to follow your user around
out what they clicked
out what they're doing.
AppKit can make this a
to attach activities
for automatic management.
For an example of this let's say
which looks a lot
And we have two activities
into our responder chain.
We've got a higher level
that we're looking at,
that we have here, and then
activity for the specific event
that we want to view
And by attaching these to the
that event and make it
that activity becomes
in the responder chain
And it becomes current
Now, you may not have
or the NSUserActivity
maybe you don't have
or you just haven't
that Handoff is especially
and your specific needs.
But activities are
New in Sierra we
and Siri uses the
to provide context to commands.
So, for example, if you
at some date, Siri is
to mean your current activity.
And it will actually
and embed it inside
so that you can pick
So we see activities as
for describing this
It's not just for Handoff.
Now, for full information
about the Handoff API I
from 2014, Adopting
That covers a lot more
like continuation streams
of data between devices.
The next feature, resume,
which we sometimes
It's one of the best
that when you quit
and then relaunch it, it
left it.
In fact, that happens if
or even reboot your machine.
Everything just comes back
Now, clearly to accomplish
of the UI state that builds up
when the app relaunches.
But clearly we don't want to
It doesn't really belong there.
So a state restoration API gives
that UI state separately,
to restore that state
but before your UI
You enable it on a
It's pretty simple.
You just say isRestorable
And then you may provide
that just handles the act
from the encoded data.
And good news if
NSDocument handles
Now, what kind of state
Well, we might choose
that we have active in our app.
We might also want to save
what's selected, what
How do we do that?
Well, if you've used
really simple.
The first method
with coder.
You implement this on
and then it's just
but for your controllers
Another important call is
And this just says
for encodeFestorableState
And we'll schedule to
that state again
And then finally
It's exactly like you'd expect.
It's a lot like a
All you have to do is call
that you've encoded before,
on that information
Now, that's pretty easy,
but we can actually
All you have to do is
restorableState KeyPaths.
Of course, we're
because that's the
but then we also append
And these are the
to have automatically
and restored by the system.
These properties need to be KVC,
that's key value
because we access them by
to be observable so that we
or state when they change.
And that's state restoration.
The third and final technology
documents in the cloud.
So once upon a time
in the cloud you actually
and create a container.
But these days with iCloud Drive
and now especially
and Documents it's
that your app is working with
Now, this is important because
of documents might be
And this means that you might
that aren't actually
So how do we handle this?
That seems pretty scary.
Luckily, first off if you're
everything for you so
But if not you need to make sure
that you're using
If you register yourself
with the file coordination
that your document is not
which is a good thing.
And then next if you
to coordination your IO on
that we schedule
after the entire file
And that's documents
Now, there are a
that we didn't have time
to give an honorable mention to.
The first is asset
than having loose
And they can also
like wide gamut and
Accessibility, extremely
Cocoa puts really powerful
within an arm's reach
And it's extremely
that you learn to use voice
of these accessible
that your app is
You would never ship an app with
so don't ship an app that
to accessibility.
Sandboxing and also XPC
but somewhat related
in that they help you isolate
and from other processes.
Sandboxing is, of course,
but it's appropriate
And XPC services can help
into separate processes.
This is really great
code that's handling
or doing some kind
We all like to think that our
we also wear seatbelts in our
that it's there if
So we have covered an
in a very short amount of time.
So I want to rewind
that we all remember what
And we started off by looking
with our modern view and window
great animation performance.
Then we talked about drag
making sure that you get the
effect, modern drag
Then we covered container views
and making sure that we
Then we walked into system
and also a couple of
that really make
and really take advantage of it.
Here's the permalink
You should find related
download for our demo
as it becomes available.
All of our related
I hope you were able
If not, then you
out the videos online.
And that's a wrap.
Thank you for attending.
[ Applause ]