[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everybody.
Thank you for coming out
and spending your
Hopefully you had a
And I'm excited for our talk
to discuss something
Fundamentally, everybody is here
because you love
and you probably want those
Now, the good news is, we want
to offer your app at the
so that you get more engagement.
And we're going to spend the
about different ways
We promote apps in
throughout the operating system
Siri app suggestions are
when they swipe left from home,
as well as when they
Even after entering a
from inside other
Handoff is another way we
your apps, as well.
As you start an activity from
we try to anticipate what
that app's icon in the bottom
In certain situations, where
to do is play a form of media,
to the lock screen
So say after you plug in a
to your car or your
that you usually use
the system will learn that, and
but that app's content.
And we're going to talk today
about how you can build a great
As you're using the
say reading a news article,
that are contextual to the
So for example, if
and you decide that you want to
or you want to read it at home
of watching a WWDC presentation,
And Siri will understand
"Remind me about this."
It will have the context of
And this will work in any app
that we're going to
This is particularly exciting
that when customers
they'll be de-blinked right
New in iOS 10 is the promotion
of locations throughout
when we think the customer has
to go somewhere, to
that they've been
We'll be talking later today
about how you can get your app's
Multitasking as well
where we will promote locations
interested in.
You can get your app, your
at the prime real estate
New in iOS 10 as
of your app's contact
within the native contact app.
So you notice here, there's
in WhatsApp.
And we'll talk later today
about how you can get your
So, to learn when to promote
to learn about your
Now, the good news is that a few
of the value that I
In addition to having your
you'll also get deeper Siri
with the contextual reminders.
So what we're going to do
about these APIs and
through proper adoption of
up getting more engagement
to promotion throughout the OS.
First, we're going to talk about
NSUserActivity is the kind
of the operating system.
It helps us understand what the
at on screen.
And schema.org is somewhat
Next, we're going to talk
and new APIs around apps
So if you're an app like
that offers many different
if you're an app like Uber
this will be very
Then we'll talk about
around media apps suggestions.
I showed you earlier an example
that will happen, say
in their headphones,
about how you can get
and center in that interface.
And then, we'll try to overview
about all the different things
To kick things off with
I'd love to invite
Sofiane?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Daniel.
Good afternoon everyone.
My name is Sofiane.
And I'm really excited to
about some of the features
Now, we just heard Daniel
to promote the content in your
Now let's talk about
that you can adopt
Throughout this presentation,
Some that you may be already
or Spotlight Search, and some
in iOS 10, like location
Now all of the features
have something in common.
And it's a single API
First, some background.
NSUserActivity was introduced
which is the amazing
to start an activity on a
where you left off on another.
Last year in iOS
to promote content directly
from NSUserActivity inside
Now, this year in iOS 10, we
so it can capture locations
and promote them in many
Even inside other apps.
NSUserActivity now also
so Siri can now help you get
to the place you're
Also new in iOS 10,
NSUserActivity enables
to be promoted straight
as an alternate communication
Now, I know what you
"That's cool," hopefully.
"But how does this work?"
Well, let me tell you,
and we have a lot of great
So let's dive right in.
We're going to talk about
These APIs allow you
to seamlessly integrate
NSUserActivity for native apps,
We'll focus on the
NSUserActivity is a
to capture application state
in a way that can
So for instance, here we're
which is a local search app,
we created an NSUserActivity
that we need to recreate
So for instance, when I trigger
we follow the same pattern
And again, when I actually
Now, in this particular case,
In iOS 10, NSUserActivity
about certain concepts
or communication interactions.
We'll talk about this in a
to take a closer
So here we create an activity
to recreate the state later,
For instance, the
Then we inform the system
that this represents
and we decide whether it will
available temporarily
for location suggestions.
Or added to the on
or added to the Spotlight on
in Spotlight Search results.
Now there are a few related
specifically on adoption
for Handoff and App Search.
Really recommend that you
They provide a lot
Alright, now let's dig
So, I'm going to show you how
So here we're extenuating an
And providing it with
That's the string
It's the same string that you
Now we recommend to use a
here to keep the strings unique.
Next, our activity needs
to use a title that describes
at here.
So here we're looking
And something to keep in mind
of your user activities.
This is how, for instance,
in Spotlight Search results.
So you want to make
that is descriptive
Next, we're enabling Handoff,
since the content we're
And then we're setting
on the userInfo property,
that we need to recreate
when the activity is restored.
Now in that case,
of that location we were
when the activity is being
when it's handed off to another
that ID from the server
as the user would expect.
Now to fully describe
and for richer search results,
you can use this
in iOS 9 called CSSearchableItem
It provides a common language
to describe your content better.
Now, if you have a website
that you're looking
can provide the web URL so
for instance, handed
where your app is not installed,
it will be appropriately
in Safari instead,
And finally, we call
indicating to the system
that this represents
This is what the user is
Now, what happens when your
When your activity is being
Or handed off to another device?
Your application is
and a UIApplication
called continueUserActivity
The first thing we need to do
and make sure that it
That case matches the one
that we were just
And then we can use the
to start restoring the state.
Earlier, we had put the
So typically here, we would
from the server and
and display the right controller
So with minimal code here,
from three great features;
and contextual Siri reminders.
Now, we'll talk about some of
Before, let me ask you this.
Have you ever been in a
and you're trying to find
So you start in Yelp and
Then you want to
so that they can meet you there.
So you switch to
"Hey guys, I found this place."
But then you realize you don't
of that place, so you
you copy the address, then
You paste it in there, and
Except you're not,
you're also going to
So you're going to
and there's probably more
And you get the idea.
It's not a great experience.
So in iOS 10, we're trying
to make this experience
You still start at a same point.
You're looking at a location,
say a restaurant,
And by adopting NSUserActivity,
that same location in many
the system.
When you switch away
the multitasking UI
and offers this nice proactive
offering to get directions
to the place you
If you go to Messages,
You can start writing
" and the QuickType UI
that location directly into
that you're providing.
Same thing with Maps.
Maps promotes these locations
Not only in the Maps app,
but also in the new
as well as in CarPlay which is
Imagine that.
Look at your app, get in
that's it, you're done.
You can be on your way.
These locations can even be
So what we're looking at here
through NSUserActivity
as the user engages with
Again, it also provides
so you can now be looking
to get you directions
to the place you're looking at.
So all of these features with
And all of these features
is that they all indicate
where the suggestion is
in that case from Yelp.
Now imagine if this
Wouldn't that be great?
Well, this is possible now.
NSUserActivity now allows you
that are viewed inside
We're introducing new
and CoreSpotlight, allowing
with all of these places
In terms of code, we're going
and we're going to
that we had defined earlier,
We don't have to create
So, for apps using
as setting your MKMapItem to
defined as NSUserActivity.
And that's pretty much it.
This also has the
of populating the
for you automatically
so if you want to adopt App
to specify that you
and these locations
Now there's another way which is
and for those of you who are
you can use CSSearchableItem
and describe the location.
Now, let's break this
First thing we're doing
of the location, which
And that's required for all
of the UIs we just
Next, we're specifying the text
and that's required for
such as the keyboard,
Next, we're specifying the
That's optional,
that your users are
to the place you
Latitude and longitude is the
that you can use if you
Next, we're setting the phone
to get access to Siri
"Call this place," for instance.
And finally, we're indicating
that this content supports
This way, the results will be
In Spotlight Search results UI,
with the right quick action
or get directions, for instance.
That's how you get
It's that easy.
Now, your app is going
of these different places.
We think this is going
to provide a much richer
but also outside your app.
Now, your brand can be further
Not within the confinement
Let's move on to
IOS 10 DP integrates
from a contact card.
So what we're looking at
where the WhatsApp handle was
When I go ahead and tap on the
to send a message, I'm
of contact I'd like to use.
And if I do so, this choice can
as a default mean
So your app can be promoted
for messaging for
That's also supported by
with a new intense framework,
which is the same
to get deep Siri integration.
There were two great talks about
I really recommend that
So here we're looking
sending a text message,
to work on how this works.
So the first thing we do is
which is a new object we're
This contains information
For instance, which
So for instance, sending a text
as well as some other
the sender, and some
like whether the communication
Next, you call the Donate
This way the system will
and promote your app directly
Now, when users interact
through the contact card,
Create an INInteraction
trying to do.
And wrap it up inside
which your app is
Now let's see how this
The first thing here,
we're creating the
And something to note is
to the user's address book,
you can specify what contact
with here.
And this way the system will
out the right contact
Next, we're creating intent.
And here we're using
since we're sending
Now there are three
to you for sending
making audio, and video calls.
Now it's important
to also make sure you specify
of handling in your info plist
to that pretty much the same
what we talked about earlier.
Next, we'll provide the
And here we're using WhatsApp.
And this is particularly
with multiple protocols.
So for instance, if you
which deals with both
you'll want to make sure you
Next, we create an INInteraction
of the information
And some metadata
like directionality
Now since here we're
we're using the outgoing
and that's the only
for donations of interactions.
And finally, we donate this
This way it will be --
the system will be able
to augment the contacts you're
Now again, like I said, when
from a contact card, we
and use the same UI
to launch your app.
The first thing we're doing
and interaction from
and then we can start
with the intended recipients.
And that's how you get
Now, your app can be promoted
which is the most natural
So we did it.
We checked everything
But we're not done.
We have some more to talk about.
So let's talk about some
in mind while working
The first thing is to be lazy.
Okay, now we're talking.
So, imagine you're working in a
to adopt Handoff so
to start writing an email on
where they left off on
on the go for instance.
So here what we're doing
that is called every
on the keyboard.
And every single
and update the userinfo
Now that can be costly
So instead what you should do is
indicating to the system
And then this way, the system
at an opportune time to update
For instance, right before the
to another device.
Now here, this is
and we're implementing the
method, and this
to update the userinfo
This way we can do it only once
and we're way more
Next, make sure you
to the current activity.
So what we're doing here is
doing a bunch of things to it,
So that's good.
Except after that, we're not
and exiting the function.
And therefore, the
because it goes out of scope.
An activity release
because it doesn't exist.
So instead what you should
to the current activity.
If you're dealing with
that conforms to a UI responder,
can also use the User
User Activity Property,
And this has the great effect
of having UIKit manage the
So you don't have to call
UIKit does it for you
for instance are linked
Next, transfer a small payload.
So make sure that you keep
in your userinfo dictionary,
to recreate the states,
And remember that these user
over the air, by Bluetooth, so
as lightweight as possible.
So for instance, imagine you're
with large photos
So what we're doing here is
serializing them as
in the userinfo dictionary,
which could be very
which is not efficient.
Instead what you can do is try
to that content you're working
this way when you're
you can maybe fetch
or obtain it through
Now if you really have to
you can use continuation
and these are specifically
There's a ton of
in the developer documentation.
Okay, one more.
Make sure you keep your activity
And that's to avoid collisions.
But it's also important
that they represent the
or the current user actions.
So instead of having a
that I reuse everywhere
it's good to have multiple
different parts of my app.
So for instance, one when
one when I'm searching
and what you'll notice
that I'm using a reverse DNS
that there's no collision
that might have been
Alright, time for a demo now.
So we're going to use
which is a sample we're
on the Developer Library.
And we'll see how we
to promote locations.
We'll also briefly touch on
Let's get writing.
Alright, so I'm going to launch
and I have my device
and Xcode here right behind.
So I'm going to give you a
to get an idea of what it does.
So here we have a
This is an app that
and uses core location to get
as MapKit to fetch places
So I'm going to look
and I get a richer page
like the name, phone
as well as a map of this place.
Now we're going to work
and implement location
so that this same
in many different places.
But before this, let's do that.
I'm going to time myself.
How about that?
See how long it takes to do so.
Now, I'll start the
Alright, so I'm going
And this is my location view
that I use to display the
the richer results
And this is the method
that I call every time a map
So I'm going to go ahead and
And this is where I'm
So as you can see, I am creating
with an activity type that is
I'm doing.
In this case, I'm also using
which makes sure that my
And I already defined
in my info plist earlier.
Next, we're setting the
And again, here I'm
because that's what's going
to be the public face
Next, I'm setting Handoff, App
because the content we're
And the more important
which is where I'm setting my
Now again, this has
of populating the
So that's what I'm
I'm just completing
that this content supports
This way it will have
in the Spotlight Search results.
Okay now, remember
That's what I'm doing here.
So, setting needsSave to
This way, the userActivity
when I need to update
And finally, I'm using the
by UR Responder in
and setting the activity to it
so that I keep a
and that UIKit manages
Next, I'm going to
this User Activity
updateUser ActivityState.
And this is where I'm going to
with the content that I
which returns the
the relevant information,
that I need to recreate
Okay, let's go ahead,
Okay, so safe to say
Okay, I didn't break
So I'm going to go ahead
and now as you can see,
at the bottom to get
that I was just looking at.
It's very easy.
Super handy.
Same thing when I go to Maps.
I see that same location
even showing my application
[Applause] thank you.
[ Applause ]
Alright, let's zoom back out.
Same thing when I go to
like "Let's meet at-- ."
You see that I have the same
suggested directly inside the
so I can just tap on it and
and the address get inserted.
[ Applause ]
But, it even works
So here I'm getting a text
phone number is, and it's
from my NSUserActivity so
and insert the phone
That's really cool.
[ Applause ]
Now let's go check on timing.
Three minutes, forty.
So that's not bad.
All of these location
provided by my app
Well, I cheated a little bit.
I had some sample codes
It's not a tremendous
So messages, QuickType,
all of that, a single API.
Alright, so we had worked
indexing this content.
So I'm going to go
and restore it in
Then I'm going to go ahead
Pizza. And sure enough, I
But when I go ahead and tap
but my app doesn't
It doesn't restore
to the user as they
It doesn't show the rich
I'm going to go back
and this is because I
UIApplicationDelegate methods.
So I'm going to go to my
that part, and what
I'm implementing the continue
UIApplicationDelegate, checking
This is the one that we
And then calling this method
which looks at the userInfo
as the user would expect.
I'm going to build
and see that one more time.
So, I'll go back to
and now we're doing the right
as the user would expect.
So that's a quick tour of how
for location suggestions,
Alright, let's switch back.
[ Applause ]
So again, this sample
on the Developer Library.
It actually does a couple
And it helps you test your
So it's a great tool to keep by
on the Location Suggestions
Okay, so we just saw how easy
and promote your content in many
And we'll take a look at how
of these benefits, specifically
Now when we design these
suggestion features.
We wanted them to
with websites you
And so for this, for instance,
which mirrors the same content
in the Yelp app, when you
you get the same,
to get directions to this place.
And that's because
which is the technology
A little bit of background,
schema.org is open web markup
to semantically annotate
with rich, structured, metadata.
So there are many
of representations
And schema.org is also intended
to provide a rich search
both inside iOS, but also
So these schemas
in a tree-like structure.
So for instance,
like restaurants inherits
from more generic ones
Let's take a look at
So, it inherits from multiple
inherits from all
defining each of these.
And for instance, the name
in the Thing schema would
of the restaurant in that case.
Same with the address
in the Local Business schema.
And things that are more
such as whether it accepts
directly inside the
So here's an example of
On the left, we're seeing the
at earlier.
And on the right, content
in a way that can be
Creating things like
the name of the restaurant,
rating, website, and more.
It can even do more.
Let's look at a simple example.
Here is a very simple
describing content
Now, let's look at how
with the addition of
As you can see, we
to the actual content
or the actual structure
We've just provided
describing the content in a
It includes simple
but also more complex structured
which is itself another
If you prefer, you can
in line with microdata.
So that's what we're doing here.
We're changing the
of our initial document
with inline microdata markups.
So Safari in iOS 10, it strikes
and promotes them much
like a native app would
That also gives you some of
about earlier for
So these are some of the
Anything with a PostalAddress,
or a telephone property, and the
that we were working with
You have all of these
or specify the ones that you
Alright, so we talked about
Use NSUserActivity,
that users view inside
throughout the system,
Also for communication apps.
And also of course for all
Use schema.org for your website,
for location suggestion,
through NSUserActivity.
Alright, now let's move
on to how your apps can
suggestions like we
So here we're going to talk
about two different
One through the keyboard, and
Let's start with Number 1.
So, if your app deals with
you can benefit from location
through the QuickType UI.
Now here we're looking
which is ride sharing app for
And as the user enters a text
as a location text field, we're
from Yelp, directly inside Uber.
Now this includes locations
in NSUserActivities by
Upcoming locations
Locations that you may have
So if you receive text message
And even, recent places
with using Siri.
So for instance, if
if you ask Siri to show
and then interact with a
in there as part of
So, we're introducing
So your app can inform the
text fields are expecting.
And in this case, we were
Now based on this hint,
to make the right
if there's any available
But if there's no proactive
it still provides a
in terms of auto correction.
Because autocorrect
is now able to know what
So, we added a new property
in UITextInputTraits
which allows you
So here, we're working with
to UITextInputTraits, and
And we're indicating that
street address.
There's a bunch of text content
ranging from describing
and a bunch of others.
There's a full list
in the Developer Library.
But let's take a closer
So these two are both
but they have different
So you want to use the one
that represents your
with the right level
So for instance, a navigation
full street address so that it
to their destination, whereas a
care about the state and city
because that might just be
And as you can see here, based
that we specified, we're getting
inside the QuickType bar.
In one case, the full street
just San Francisco, California.
And that's how easy
to get suggestions
Now let's look at how your
from these nice direction
Like Daniel said
third party routing apps
accelerating users
when we think there is an intent
So we're leveraging an existing
which was introduced in iOS 6,
and lets your routing
and then handle all
iOS will learn over time what a
based on various factors, such
And then suggest it
in the Multitasking
So, to do so, you want to make
to receive directions requests.
And that's easily
through the capabilities panel.
In iOS 10, we're
which is specifically
Next, you want to
where your app is
So if your app is a local
you can specify that your app
And finally, you
that you take the appropriate
within MKDirectionsRequest.
And that is that your app should
or populate the UI in a
for the user to get directions.
In terms of code,
of how you can adopt
MKDirectionsRequest
So when your app is launched,
First thing we're
that the URL we're
valid MKDirectionsRequest.
An MKDirectionsRequest offers
to your URL for that.
Next, we're extenuating an
from the contents of that URL
about the origin
that the user is
And next and new in iOS 10,
especially for those of you
who already adopt
is that you can now be
that don't have geo-coordinates.
And in this case,
that address dictionary you
geocode AddressDictionary, which
with the right latitude
which will help you
to the intended location.
And that's pretty much it.
That's how your routing app
in this prime real estate
Now with that, I'd like to
about media app suggestions.
Thank you.
&gt;&gt; That was awesome.
Alright. Now, let's talk
So, if you're an app that
like a podcast app or a
that plays video, you'll
iOS today, promotes the app
to use based on your behavior.
And we promote that app in
that I showed you earlier.
We in particular, offer those
and in the Today View.
If the act of the suggestion
like for example when you plug
or even arriving at a certain
we may further elevate that.
So, let's see what
This is what the promotion
If say, I always or
after plugging in headphones.
Notice, in the upper
the podcast app a suggestion.
In certain situations
of that will be elevated
And so what you're seeing is,
for Handoff, is now being
that we think I'm likely to
of those triggers I mentioned.
Now, this is a pretty good
as it could be because at the
to do now is you have to
in the right direction in
that we're predicting, we
With a pretty simple API,
you can build a far better
This is what it looks
This is what I just showed you.
And this is what it
We're getting it?
This is what it looks
Far, far better.
Not only can the customer engage
to unlock their device, but you
and center, in front
Now, this might be quite
but this particular interface
conversion if you look
And so, if you're interested
in getting your users
which presumably you are,
So how do we do this?
I'm going to walk
The adoption is pretty simple.
It all boils down to a class
So let's imagine you've got
of different properties.
You know, a title, an artist,
to do is you want to get this
of the device when the system
to engage with it.
Well, you're going
by doing is importing Media
as conformant as to a
And then you're going to want
to implement a method called
It's pretty simple.
First, you want to
through whatever means you have.
Now, you'll obviously
especially if you're
for it not working.
In which case, you're
that call back handler
and the system will understand,
Next, you're going to want to
on the Lock Screen
This is a method that I
to show you what's behind it.
The first thing that you
onto the infoCenter object,
and then if you do
that this media item
that to the Lock
If you have a default image that
for you to get your
Then you're going to
to the nowPlayingInfo
and most importantly, you're
on the infoCenter,
that I showed you
So you want to do this
If for whatever reason you don't
in preparing playback.
Again, if the phone's
This is another opportunity
Now note, you don't
to start playback at this point.
You plugged in your
for the customer to
But you want to get
load into Stream, and so forth.
And that's it.
So again, today, iOS promotes
If they follow a particular
we elevate them to
Through pretty simple adoption
you can get a much better
to promote your brand
and whatever gorgeous
Alright, so let's summarize
We spoke about a few simple APIs
that helped you deeply
into the operating system.
We spoke about NSUserActivity,
of the operating system.
It helps us understand
is currently staring at.
Then we spoke about schema.org,
similar to NSUserActivities
We spoke about a new use
as a brand new UIKit API, to
when to elevate locations.
Then we spoke about MPContent,
Which is particularly
And hopefully it's been
that these APIs are easy
There's some more
as well as some great
that you should check out,
There's a lot of related
A lot of related work around our
as well as some previous
around Handoff and
Lastly, I wanted to close by
that we are going to continue
And what we need from you,
about the capabilities
in the most detailed
Because fundamentally the
the more we'll understand
And so, you saw today, a
where there was varying levels
that you could annotate an
I'd encourage you as much
as explicit as you
not only to support the features
but also to put your application
in a good place,
Thank you all for coming today.
I hope you had a great
Bye, bye.
[ Applause ]