[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. My name is Ellis
for public transit
Our goal here at Apple is always
to create the best possible
We believe that design
about how something
Great experiences are
In this talk, I'd like to
to transit in Apple Maps.
But first, I'd like to start
by giving you an
Transit launched in September
and Mac OS X, El Capitan.
As of today, it is available
as well as over 300
We use transit schedule data
Here's a bit of a fun fact.
To date, we've mapped more
Next, I'd like to
of the four key features
The first is a beautiful
Roads and other driving-related
out while transit
and transfer stations
The second feature
for each station showing each
The third is detailed point
with a guided navigation
Finally, we show
and even modify our recommended
to planned service changes
Our goal is to provide
in each city we support.
So how do we do that?
We start with agency schedule
We collect additional data
through original research
Then we add in a layer
and delight our customers.
Our goal is that at every
to match the instruction we're
in the real world around them.
Gathering these details
But as Steve Jobs once
It's worth waiting
Here are some examples
that we collect ourselves.
Station entrances and exits.
Station footprints or
Agency signage.
And the real world
by which I mean the path
and ferries actually
This example shows a
We've individually surveys
for location but also type.
Stairs, escalator,
Here is that same entrance
You can also see the
This is really helpful in
and out of train stations.
Stations have different names
From the outside, the entrance
But from the inside, there's
We show that number
so that you can be
in the correct direction.
We try to match agency signage
in terms of the signage itself,
where and in what order.
Again, you see that
Finally, something that
that the transit lines shown
on the map follow
Many iconic transit maps such as
schematic, not representative of
However, with a digital map on
that your location position as
up with the line you're
This builds confidence
in the directions the
After we've gathered all
we go even deeper
Our belief is that every city
and we try to understand
and respect this culture
at our customers.
In the next few slides,
I'm going to dive
Boarding instructions vary
For example, in London
Whereas in New York
You don't take the
or the A Line in New York.
That's not a local convention.
Sometimes the line name matters,
but sometimes only the
Here in the Bay Area, for
Sometimes the local convention
sometimes it's assumed.
In Mexico City, we specify
We capture these subtleties
because that allows
to match what we're telling them
Here is a different example.
In New York, the MTA
in alphabetical order.
Instead, they list
A and C are blue,
You see the same ordering
Trams and street cars are
but different cities
to one or the other.
For example, in Toronto,
to board the 510 Spadina Tram,
Everyone calls it the
so that's what we
In Berlin, on the other
And that is reflected
Here's another example.
In San Francisco, you
Whereas in London or Toronto,
eastbound, and westbound.
But in New York, you
Again, you see this
One final example.
In Rio, the bus rapid transit
In many ways, they are
and commuter rail systems.
We raise the prominence of
on our map to reflect
That's the blue and orange lines
that you see in this
Here is how we build
We start with agency data for
to add additional curated data.
For example, station
as we've previously seen.
Then we customize the experience
to respect the unique
Finally, this is all
to bring delight
Now, I'd like to give
Let's say you just flew into San
and you'd like directions
First, you can see our
As I mentioned, transit lines
are dimmed.
Now, we're going to
for Powell Street Station.
Powell Street is serviced
and you can see the upcoming
as the upcoming Muni departures.
Now, at the top I noticed
When I tap on details,
I see that Muni has some
and we are communicating
to our customers.
You can zoom out to see
of the Bay Area.
Or you can zoom in
The information density
that we show changes
Now, some people may want
So, for example,
if a bus route is available.
In our product, you can select
like to use for your journey.
Here is a competing bus route.
Now, we didn't recommend
But it's an option
So let's go back to our
that in greater detail.
The route planner tells you when
and gives a summary
Tapping on this, I get
A detailed list of
I can expand the list
Now, when I select start,
with detailed instructions.
Since I'm already
it just tells me
Tells me to exit at Powell, and
Here you can see we're
exit with an exit code, E3,
Finally, I arrive
That concludes the presentation.
For more information,
or e mail
Thanks for listening.