[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; So hi, everybody.
[ Applause ]
I'm Melissa, I'm one of
and this literally the first
to break a leg before I go out
that a month ago and
without a cast [laughter].
So if I'm limping around
[ Applause ]
So one of the best
on core data is actually
up on stage here every year
and interesting stuff
this year we have a lot of it,
we hope you're going to love it.
So I'm going to talk about a
some changes in the core
I'm going to talk about some
of core data stack configuration
And we're going to talk a
to integrate more neatly and
of the improvements we've made
in the area of Xcode
And that's a lot so, on with
Query generations is a
but before I sort
about query generations
about faults a little bit.
Core data uses faults a lot,
Manage objects can be faults,
their relationships
and if you're using
then the array you get back
from NSManagedObjectContext
is going to be a very
So that being said,
Well, up here on the
of an object graph, I've got
State, California,
Santa Clara and San Francisco.
And some cities in Santa
And some of this is a piece
of like a tourist guide a
in and navigate through
in a city you're planning
But just based on what we
this isn't a full object
of an object graph, sub graph.
Because we know that the
and those states
and those counties
And you know, beyond
that the United States is
And even in a guidebook I'm only
at one set of data at a time.
If I'm planning a trip to
about Oregon or Washington,
I don't even really care
I need to be able to
to those destinations
and change my mind later about
But for the immediate short
and planning my trip to Santa
And that not caring
in memory a fault, it's an
and retrieve data
if I decide I want to use it.
So say I find out my
and her wedding's in
you know plan a trip to Seattle.
So at this point I'm going to
and come down, I want
and core data will automatically
for Washington even
when I first loaded
And you know, I can navigate
And that's what a fault is,
or lazy loading, these
for the same kind of
to help minimize the
in memory at any given point.
Why do we use faults?
Well performance, performance,
performance, and
The best most performing
that doesn't do any
You don't load objects over
You don't spend any
on objects that you don't need.
You don't want to have those
up your heaps high water mark
if your user's never
But there is kind of
and it's sort of this.
Here we have that object
we've got a lot of faults.
And I'm navigating down my
and I want to fire
But in the meantime, an external
from the web and for whatever
Well, what happens?
I have a fault that's
and retrieve information
but there's no information
I said, I talked a lot about
but in this case, you
well did I actually need
Oops.
In core data right
by using the
property on
If you set that then
that you're trying to fire a
it will mark the fault as
of its properties with nils.
This is mostly what
but sometimes it
because your UI doesn't
with you know, a nil identifier.
The other alternative is
use relationship keypads
of the objects you think
That moves you into
with your user trying
predict what they're going
users are unpredictable,
The other alternative,
there's always a third
starting with using
on the manage object context
in the database before
Write lots of try catch,
around all your fault firing
and frankly that's not
you'd really rather be
for your users to use,
to your application,
But let's step back
about your user interacting
The user view and the
about seeing the
freshest, snappiest data.
How do we know this?
Let's think about gas
Most of you are familiar
in a car at some point.
Gas pumps have a display that
or how many liters you've
And that display has
and I'd like a show of hands
of reading that field,
as they put gas in their car.
That's about what I expected,
the human brain wants data
in intervals that
So the user doesn't really
they just need it
reasonably, quickly updated.
And a user who's saving
this is why core data
they want to make a bunch
to have those edits saved
in the database and have
You pick the merge
because you know your
So what if we could take
What if we could provide a way
of data in the database?
What if we could give you
update changes
And what if we could
so that you would
[ Applause ]
And now I can talk
Query generations are a way
of giving your manage object
transaction on data
All reads into that manage
to see the same view of data
and you'll never see could
And the important part is
that's always been
How do they work?
Well, I've got a
in it, id 1, name fred.
And because these are
down because I need all the real
In a traditional database
you have one file, it has one
Using query generations though,
that becomes the
of data in your database.
And processes come along,
it can be an importer, it can
something modifies the database.
A new generation is created.
And, more data is
And at this point, the user
creates manage object
And that context now
in the database it
So as other processes or
and modify the database
more generations are created,
that context still
Second context comes up, loads
and saves and in saving it
and tracks that it's now
in this case 6, in the database.
And at this point if we
even though the object
that fault may have been
it's still visible to the
in the database under
And at this point the user can
delete some objects, change some
And when they save that context
policy to merge all of those
in the database and
In the same way that context 1.
[ Applause ]
In the same way that context 1
when it was pinned
Context 2 can do whatever it
turn them back into
and it will still see
in generation 6 in the database.
So basically it's full
at the manage object
We've talked a lot
are essentially right
and now we've made them
So allows you to immediately
by context level,
like preventive prefetching
you know, everybody wins.
Basics. An individual context
wants, it can decide that it
that you're used to
We call unpinned, see top
You can also specify
to whatever generation is
when data is first
Or you can specify
to a specific generation
if you have another context
Nested contacts are going
to inherit their
they're implicitly unpinned
through the, the
plus whatever pending changes
around unsaved.
Updates are kind of important,
the user doesn't
eventually they don't want to
Generations are updated when
to update by setting a
They're updated on
if you call mergeChanges,
at that point since you've
you know it should be looking
in the database,
as a result of calling reset.
Thing to note though is that,
registered objects
when you update the generation,
and it's easy for us to let
to let you undo it if we
If you want to refresh the data
or refreshAllObjects, but it
that data actually gets updated.
If you want to use query
to be using and SQL store and
Although if you try and
and you haven't met those
of fail gracefully and just
How did we do it?
Well, there's an now opaque
to track a query generation.
This will tell the
and what store it
The query generation token
you can use to retrieve
that a context should
ManagedObjectContext, we
there's a property,
that will tell you what query
It'll be nil if the
And you can set a query
either the current token
the result of calling
on another manage
A generation won't include
to the store coordinator after
If you load data into a
add a store to the
you will not see results
But it does not prevent
from the coordinator, although
if you try and load data into a
of the stores that it was
And now I'm going to talk
well we always talk
This is the current state
and it's manage object
You use perform and
with it, do schedule
on the managed object
There is a third model,
which is to use the
which allows you to
but that's deprecated
out that that's really
in any threading situation.
The persistent store
and has the same API
And the coordinator will
in from individual managed
with whatever request you've
perform and performAndWait
And at this point I'd like to
we have added, for those of
and using manual retain
around perform, block and wait.
This means that you're now
for extending the lifespan
in the blocks you've
to use those objects
It's easy to remember to
for example an execute fetch.
It's a little bit less
that you also need to
that may be being returned.
This doesn't only affect people
and we have a link time check
until you recompile
But let's talk about concurrency
Or, as it exists in the
Context 1 tries to do
to the persistent store, so
Which, because its sterilizing
And at this point context 2,
which may be your UIContext
to message the coordinator.
But because the coordinator is
as the request from context 1 is
and whatever work is necessary
And it's only when that
of execution returns that
on the coordinator and
down to the store.
And this means that context 2
on whatever work it is
And eventually it will return
but in the meantime
you know been a little bit slow.
New stuff, the SQL store now has
of handling multiple
Specifically it can now
and a single writer, size of
from platform to platform.
We've adopted it and
to change it in a couple slides.
So how does this work now?
Well context 1 dispatches
and well no lock is taken.
Context 2, which may still be
the coordinator and both
down to the persistent
Persistent store then does
out what messages
and those are sent
And it's only at that
and this is the standard
SQLite does whatever it needs
right it's a bunch of SQL,
ends at that point returns.
So you can see at this point
really decreased the scope of
And why do you care?
This is going to make your
you can fault and
a main UI while background
on a separate context.
And the immediate fallout
from this is it really
architecture, a fairly
has been that people will have
loading data for
And another, a main UIContext
And they end up having
because the UI needs
and they need the
to be as small as possible.
And the only way to get
to lock the entire stack, was
And that introduced an issue
okay there's a manage object
but it's coming from an entirely
coordinator and I need
That's no longer an issue there,
to the same persistent store
in parallel and you can
and as a huge bonus this means
which is really going to
It's going to divide
we've only got one
It's on by default, it's for SQL
if all coordinated stores
on a persistent store
You can configure the size
of the connection pool
ConnectionPoolMax
to specify the maximum
If you want serial
the old behavior,
We do reserve the right
to one million and that's
to use a more reasonable number.
It should be transparent to
your UIs will possibly get
The big thing we noticed
on, was a whole bunch of
out a couple hundred, couple
And you should do it because man
A few of you.
[ Applause ]
A few of you may notice,
If you had a context, context
and wait and context 2 that also
originally context 2 would
until context 1's block had
So for the like .1% of you
your timing's going to
to decrease the bandwidth
the rearchitect.
The rest of you, you'll
and interesting and
And at this point I'm
Scott up on stage and
about a bunch of other stuff.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Melissa.
Good morning, let's talk
starting with adding
To add a persistent
you need four pieces
to do most operations
New this year, core data has
NSPersistentStoreDescription
of the data needed
and also includes convenience
like whether the store
the timeout that the coordinator
and mapping options which are
And a new option, for adding
this new type works
on the persistent
that takes a trail
for the store description and an
if the operation failed.
If you're adding a store
the conditional in a
like posting a notification or
after the store has
This way your app's model setup
which is especially useful
since a migration
Remember, if iOS notices that
for a while after launch,
This can prevent a migration
it's not a problem anymore
if you're adding a
So that's persistent
there's a lot more involved
To represent a core data stack
plus the boiler plate to
New this year, core data
that encapsulates
of the boiler plate called
not only does it [laughter].
[ Applause ]
I realized a lot of you have
maybe but [laughter] this one
configuration it
a list of store descriptions,
to load store descriptions
that haven't already been
This means that the
to setup core data goes
to just a couple of lines.
[ Applause ]
So there's a lot of
let's take a look
The container guarantees that
so the getters for things like
will always return new
The container's initializer
that you pass into
there's also another initializer
that takes an explicit
By default, new containers
in the list, it's an
and a file name based on
And it's stored in a directory
on the container, and
by default will return
on the platform that you're on.
So it will use the application
your container document
and your containers
If you want to set your own
in this persistent container
sorry the defaulted
We think container's really
but they also provide
for common operations.
Containers have a main queue
context that you can
There's also a factory method
that are ready to use
you'll probably want to
for performing background tasks
which is called
So instead of having to setup a
up and then a queue a
in the background you can just
Using performBackgroundTask
on code concision using it
to reduce the number of
to do your work, and also can
to ensure that your
even under heavy load.
Speaking of common
the NSManagedObjectContext has
automatically merges
It's a Boolean and
to true the context will
save the change the
This works for [laughter].
[ Applause ]
This is really handy, it
when the parent saves its
for top level context when a
It works especially well
which Melissa talked
So your UIs can be maintenance
to the latest generation and
your faults will be safe
and fetch results controllers
up to date [laughter].
Alright. Let's talk
Core data has adopted generics
in both ObjC and Swift.
There is a new protocol
and it is adopted by all of the
to see back from the fetch
or all the entity subclasses.
Object IDs, NSDictionary
NSFetchRequest is now
of the results which
by protocol conformance and
on NSManagedObjectContext
of fetch request all the
[Background noise] Finally,
who adopt the parameterization
of the fetch request
Speaking of
if you're using UICollection
UICollection view,
to adopt the new data
if you're using core data.
All you need is an
to get the request off the main
that you're not returning
For more information about
check out Steve and
what's new in UICollection view.
If you're a Mac developer I
The fetch results controller
[ Applause ]
Okay, so let's talk about some
starting with getting
Oops this, there we go.
For this you need the
and a managed object context.
Creating a fetch request also
as well as a type
to take advantage
And finally, there is
which has all three
a context parameter,
These operations are all
through improvements we've made
The entity description is now
[ Applause ]
Don't worry this gets
The class also has
for creating new fetch
[ Applause ]
And finally, you can
object using just the
[ Applause ]
There's one more thing
about which is performing
I mentioned earlier that
parameterized in Swift but ObjC
generics, so we've
like semantics to
So you can just call
from inside a block
and it will return
[ Applause ]
All this new API for model
of things much easier
that you're not really looking
of your subclasses, but
this should be the last year you
Because Xcode 8 can now generate
[ Applause ]
You can configure code
and Xcode will write
to your project's derived data
so it doesn't pollute
with code you didn't write.
You don't want to
since the code is
when you change your model
like add your own instance
to the subclass, then
to only generate a
and then you can own
In Swift all you need to do
to use this feature
that your entities belong to
as your code, but
to know a bit more
The most important file in,
to know about in ObjC is the
Each model has its own header
to get access to all of that
If we zoom in for a look at
for entities configured
Xcode creates two headers that
from generating classes
One declares the class interface
and the other declares
This is mostly important
because if you're
then Xcode will not
and the model's header will
Categories can't be declared
so the generated code
in your project that's
This is a file that you
in your project then your
So let's take a quick break
at what all this new
I have Xcode 8 open
to create a new Xcode project.
And use iOSes master
We've updated the templates
So if we, save this somewhere
then we can see that,
we're using a persistent
up the master view controller
with the container's
If we go to the master
we can see where it
that we're already using
that are generated by core data.
And we're not using KVC anymore
on the manage object and if
to the generated file.
If we come back and we look
at how the fetch results
there we are.
We can see that raising the
on the event subclass
and there's no extra
when we create the fetch
which is really tiny,
is passed through from
This means that elsewhere,
prepare for segue, there we go.
When we get an object from the
comes back with the right type.
So that's all great we
And, but I don't want this
in the master view controller
So let's add a title attribute
And we want it to
Alright so we've
and if we go back here
and we can delete
And take advantage of
to get a new property that
[ Applause ]
And again if we command
all of the code has
[ Applause ]
One of the best hidden
if you're using manually
or even KVC, if you change
you can wind up with
because your project
to actually making the calls
because the key path
Automatically subclass
of all of this.
So let's automatic
as some working examples
Last, let's talk about
The SQLite library that comes
with the operating
that you won't find
The first of which is
SQLite on Apple platforms does
and multi-threading bugs
sometimes because they usually
with a single thread
To make these issues
and reproduce the system
variable that enables
when they fire you'll see
and they're both using
SQLite has always supported
through a configuration that
but that function needs
to be called before the
which may have already happened.
SQLite configurability is great
but we're running
that has built-in
so there's now another
that chimes SQLite
Finally, I want to talk
All databases are represented
and file operations
when they're in multiple files.
The result of this is that
inherently unsafe.
Unix file APIs to
This is really important
of concrete examples of
Let's say I notice two database
my code wants to do some clean
between deleting the database
and the journal something
That database doesn't have
so it can't make
so it starts reporting
which affects your app.
Unless you can guarantee
or it will ever try to
it's not safe to
Let's say I have a
and something is using it,
and the database finally gets
When it gets open
that connection creates a
now you have two connections
that are using different
it's not long before they wind
These examples may seem
over a billion devices out there
with every possible operation
something will happen to
and they'll be very upset when
Hard links are especially bad,
don't use hard links
So, new this year the
with the operating system takes
and database connections
after an illegal operation
On its own the system solve
in most cases the damages
So to help you identify
and debug these issues we've
variable that causes
as they detect an illegal
their files.
If you're curious for more ways
that your database
SQLite has an instructional
on their website called how
to corrupt a SQLite
Luckily these problems
If you're using SQLite
that there's only one piece of
and that code needs to go
so files can't be
If you're using core
there's API in the
that is always safe to
whether they're open or not.
There's replacePersistentStore
with the contents of another.
And there's also
which safely deletes
and leaves an empty
Alright, that's it for what's
To recap, we have a new
which gives you a stable view of
We use support connection
and a persistent
which allows multiple
as a single writer, allowing
at the same time that you're
Setting up core data
and then using it is also
that works especially
This is all supported by great
and we also have new
that should make debugging
For more information,
out the developer website,
If you want to know more,
as well as what's new in Cocoa.
Thanks for coming.
[ Applause ]