[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everybody.
Welcome to our session
on Expanded Subscriptions
My name is Daniel Miao and
on iTunes Connect.
So, we're going to
by doing a quick review of
And then we're going to
of how we're enhancing auto
specifically in iTunes
So, we've received a
around how we can
to better fit your businesses.
So, we're very excited because
through new features that
over your pricing.
Help you to retain
And give you and your
for managing your subscriptions.
So, let's start with
What is an in-app purchase.
Well, an in-app purchase
or service that your customer
Now contrast with your customer
store and receiving all
Now, there are many ways
But, generally in-app
to give your customers
to get an understanding of your
add-ons to that offering.
Also, if you have a
in-app purchases are
And there are a number of in-app
We have consumables,
non-renewable subscriptions, and
Today we also have
But, free subscriptions will
So, for those of you who have
you can continue using them.
But, you will not be
So, let's go through
First, we have consumables.
Consumable is an in-app purchase
that your customers
Here we have an example
on the app store,
It's a great game.
And the way Fallout
to give you the opportunity
You use real money
Add them to your inventory.
And once you've used them
and you purchase more.
Next we have non-consumables.
The non-consumables
that your customer buys
In this example we
This is an interactive
When you purchase this
in the series with the download.
If you enjoy this book you're
from inside of the app either
Once you've unlocked these
Next we have non-renewable
A non-renewable subscription
and available for
In this case we have Quizlet,
And this app comes with many
But, if you'd like more features
Plus service.
You subscribe to Quizlet Plus
And after that year if you'd
like to continue using the
for an additional year.
And finally we have
And auto-renewable is
It's a subscription
and it's renewed automatically
Here we have HBO Now, which
HBO Now offers a subscription,
a monthly subscription
So, you purchase this
for $14.99 and each month
and you're charged $14.99.
And if at some point you want
you go into you manuals
in your account settings and
Okay. So, it says here a few
of the different types
Now, let's move into
that are coming specifically
Let's start by talking
So, those of you who have
that up until last week you
for any new subscriptions
to your auto-renewables
This is the same for
for other in-app purchase types.
But, beginning this week,
from any customers that haven't
[ Applause ]
The best part about
to wait a whole year
For those of you who
you'll start receiving
for any customers that have been
for a year or more beginning
[ Applause ]
All right.
Next let's talk about
Today if you want to create an
app has to belong inside a
Well, we've seen a lot of
around auto-renewables
And we've seen these businesses
to customers that the
Additionally many of you have
up auto-renewables to
So, we're very happy
if your app makes sense
categories will no
[ Applause ]
So, those are some
that are coming to
Now, let's talk about some
We'll start with how the
be evolving.
Here we have a subscription
on your customer's device
into the app store, go into
into manage subscriptions.
These are all the subscriptions,
that your customer's
If we take a look at one of
of metadata here that you're
We have an app icon.
We have an app name.
And incidentally you can
in iTunes Connect for
You might want to override this
if possibly your app name
In which case it'll be truncated
or if your service name doesn't
Next we have the name of
that this subscription is in.
This will show up if you have
And finally we have the name
as well as the duration.
Now, if your customer
of these subscription,
and they'll see this view.
Here we see the customer's
with renewal options
These renewal options are
in the same subscription group
In a subscription group
of subscriptions that
Now, as your customer moves
between subscriptions they
subscription per group.
So, for example, if they went
from the full course
to the entree only,
into effect full
Next, if your customers
in a group regularly, that will
That means that as long
within this group you'll
that year that you need
from this customer.
As part of this feature
to be adding the
upgrade, and downgrade paths.
And upgraded goes into
So, in this case if
if we've designated entree only
the switch to full course
selects it.
If the customer downgrades,
into effect at the end of the
Okay. So, we've talked a
Now, let's take a
of one of these groups.
For those of you who are
you make recognize the
Beginning this fall
to families as groups.
Here we have an example
that has three subscriptions
A one week, a one month,
Today we have a restriction
than one of the same
So, in this case that means you
than one, one year
But, we will be removing this
I mean this restriction
So, that will allow you
We call these subscription
Here you'll see an example that
a gold level, and
Each of these levels has two
of six subscriptions
You'll also notice on the
This is how you decide
and what is considered
For example, if your customer
to platinum, that would
and platinum would go
If they went from gold to silver
into effect at the end of
Period. And those are
So, I'd like to invite Jenn
of such subscription
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. I'm Jennifer Makower.
I'm an engineer on the
I'm going to walk you
for subscriptions
and subscription groups
We're going to be working
which provides recipe and
for various meal plan types.
Now, currently we have
We have a dinner meal plan type
and we have a breakfast
And both of those serve as
So, we're coming out with
which is going to be
It's going to be for
So, let's take a look in
Here we go.
Okay. So, I'm going to click
next to in-app purchase
and select auto-renewable
So, here's where
up with my subscription name.
And when I create a new
in a moment to select either
or create a new one.
So, we'll start with the
This is going to be
So, our first subscription's
about different sandwich types.
So, I'll type in sandwiches.
And here's where I'll
Now, once I create my
it can't be edited later on.
So, I need to make sure
So, we're making
of our sandwich subscription.
And then I'll click
So, here's where I'm going
to create our new subscription
And I'll type in
And then click on create.
So, what we have here is our
And I'll come back to this
through what's on this page.
But, what I want to focus
on right now is subscription
So, I'm going to go to the
on lunch plans, which
to our subscription group page.
So, here at the top you can
subscription that
Below that we have
reference name.
And below that we have our
And we can add additional
to localize for additional
As well we can go here
to override the app
So, in this case my app name
and Shopping lists, which is
up on the account
So, that would get truncated.
So, I'm going to
and just use the short version
and then go to the top of
So, what I'd like to
to arrange multiple
to create an upgrade
So, I'm going to move over
which has a number of
And what we can do here is
so that they're in an order of
So, first is our full course,
which will be our
So, I'm going to pull that
and move it to the top.
And I'm going to take both
We have a one week
And within one ranking
this can have differences
The main idea here is
between these two subscriptions.
It's neither an upgrade
And then I'll take omelets only
which is our lowest
And then I'll click
So, as Daniel explained,
within this group are
So, a customer would
of these subscriptions
If your intention is to
subscriptions, they would need
So, now this is arranged in
So, full course subscriptions
of service.
Muffins and omelets, movies
and omelets are my mid-range
And omelets only is my
And you can actually
of subscriptions as you want.
We just say three for now.
But, you can see the numbering
on the side here
And that is about
I'll give it back to Daniel.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jenn.
All right.
Now, let's move into how we'll
price changes with
Will start with territory
Today when you price an
you choose one price tier
Behind the scenes, this price
in individual territories
Now, we at Apple today manage
When there are currency
prices for you.
Now, this has always
But, you asked us
So, beginning this fall, you'll
[ Applause ]
The way this will work is,
instead of choosing a single
with a base currency
This base price will come from
And as you move though the work
for each territory
on the current exchange
that you plan the price change.
After we generate these
and you can edit the
Maybe you want to change the
And you can do this for one
for multiple countries.
Once you set up these
this price change
at whatever start
Next let's talk about
in the context of price changes.
So, one of the biggest
with customer attention when we
price of subscription.
When we increase the price all
which is all the customers,
that the price has increased and
From here they have to go
go into their account settings
and re-enable the
Well, beginning this fall,
we're introducing a
With this new process when a
or a price increase they
and an enhanced email.
From either the push
or the email they can simply
into an app store page
where they can review the
This gives your customers many
in a more direct and
Now, no matter how good the, no
if we increase the price
that we can lose customers,
which is why we've added the
for existing customers while
[ Applause ]
Let's take a look at
Let's say we're launching
We'd like to set our
So, we set that up.
And once this in-app
we'll have our early
for both new subscriptions
Now, after some time has passed,
we're ready to launch
So, we get our marketing
We do a big push.
And we like to set our
But, when we set
we like to keep our
because they've been loyal.
They've been sticking with us.
So, when this new price
we'll have our launch
for both new subscriptions
And we'll have our early
for their renewals.
Now, some more time passes and
up to a new target price
This new price is 360 yen.
But, this time when we want,
into effect, we'd also like
up to 360.
So, we set that in
And once this goes into
of customers both launch
And we have early adopters
Now, notice here that the
prices increased.
So, they do get a
Finally we've reached the
that we're ready to simplify our
And we'd like to bring our
We go into iTunes Connect.
We edit that price change.
And once we hit save, our
This change happens immediately,
that we plan for the future.
Now, we have everybody paying
until we plan more
Okay. I'd like to invite Jenn
of iTunes Connect and
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So to go back into
What we've decided to do
with the three phrase approach.
So, when we launch a
out with an initial price to
And we're going to keep
for a certain amount of time,
then on our second
to raise the price a little,
but only do that in a
And then lastly we're going
that we want to sell our
So, let's get started
So, I want to go
And dessert and entree
that we're going
So, I need to go in and set
So, this again is our
And I can click into the
So, again this is our new
We have the reference
We have a subscription
We have the price
And I'll come back to
up our initial pricing.
Again we have our
And I can add additional
to market this for
And then our app store,
The screen shot should show
presents itself within
And we can put in some
notes there to help extra
So, I'm going to go click on set
to set up our initial pricing.
So, my base currency
And that can be set
within your user profile.
And I'm going select
for this subscription
And then click on
So, these are the prices
on current exchange rates.
If one of these territories,
I have some additional licensing
and I need to raise the price
for that one particular
and select this and move it
And if I forget which
that had been calculated
and it will remind me.
So, I'm going to scroll
and go click on done.
And then click on okay.
So, once this subscription
that will be our price
So, I'm going to click on
And then go back to our
to our appetizer on
So, in this case we've
We have some initial
And I want to raise
for our next phase of marketing.
So, I'm going to click
So, as I said in this case we're
but only in a few
So, I'm going to pick the
Italy, Spain, and France.
And then click on next.
The price, the date for this
And again, my base
And I'm going to make the
And then click on next.
So, again these are the
based on my base
And I can see here what
You know, we originally selected
And the new price will be $1.99.
And then I'll click
And here's where we're
with our existing subscribers.
In this case we're going to
at the price that they
And this change will be for
on starting from the date
So, I'm going to click on done.
And that change will go
That's the date that I selected.
And click okay.
And, so then we we'll have
for this subscription.
And I can change this price
that it goes into effect.
So, I'm going to go click on
And then go back to our
to our entree only subscription.
Now in this case we've gone
of marketing and we're
to our target price
to sell the subscription
So, I'm going to click on
in the price schedule.
And now in this case I'm going
to apply this to
So, I click this
and click next at
Again our date for our marketing
So, I'll select that date.
And the price change will be
Again, select next.
And once again we have
And I can see that the last
on March 18th.
And our new price is
So, I've clicked
Now in this case for our
the last price change, I want to
after that point up
But, we're still going to keep
renewing at that original
So, this change I only want
to affect just the existing
that last price change.
So, in this case I'm going
to existing subscribers.
And I've applied it
But, I can go and select
that this would apply
And I can see here, it
$1.99 subscribers
And that is what I want to do.
So, I'm going to click on next.
And it's important to note that
into effect it cannot
And once it does go into effect,
that will have their price
that their price has changed.
And they will need to consent
to that higher price before
So, that is what we want to do.
So, I'm going to go ahead and
and then click done,
So, once this price change
you won't be able to
But, we can edit it
that it goes into effect.
So, I'm going to select save
to our subscription group page.
And for our last task
at our full course subscription.
So, now in this case we have hit
And it's time to move those
so we can simplify the
So, I want us to take a
I want to click on the
And I can see that
for new subscribers is $4.99.
And I can even see
for the first year
And if they stay
or more I can see what my
So, I'm going to click on done.
But, what I want to do is raise
So, I'm going to click
And here I can see that these
So, we want to move them up.
So, I'm going to click on
And here I can see
And that the current is $4.99.
So, I'm going to click
That will apply it
And again, if I need to I can
to apply this to if I
So, here it says 99 cent
That will simplify a pricing
So, I'm going to go
Now in this case, the
effect immediately.
So, as soon as I
It cannot be edited or changed.
So, they will, and when
when it's time for them to renew
You know, the consent request
for this subscription
automatically renew.
And that is what we want to do.
So, I'm going to go ahead
and select the check box
And then click on okay.
And now we have one price
So, once I click save
and it will not be
And that is territory pricing.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hey, thanks again, Jenn.
All right.
So, we talked about a
So, a quick recap of
We talked about increased
You'll be receiving 85%
that haven't subscribed
We're expanding to
for auto-renewable
We're giving you the
upgraded, and downgrade paths.
We're allowing you to
We're streamlining
And we're giving you the
for existing customers while
If you'd like more information,
a bunch of great resources here.
We also have a number
We have the using StoreKit
with Swift 3 session that
This is a great session
to integrate your
with all the things we talked
to check for seats and
with in-app purchases.
There's also the What's New
with iTunes Connect session
Be sure to check that out.
There's all kinds of new
around iTunes Connect.
That's this Friday at 1:40.
Thanks for joining us and enjoy
[ Applause ]