[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and welcome.
I'm Lindsay Verity,
by my colleagues Casey
We're here to introduce
to help people discover
If you've developed an app for
effort and passion goes into
and wonderful apps
Just like this year's
You also know that putting
and discoverability
as crucial to its success.
And that's what we're here
But before we do that,
let's review all the ways a user
in the App Store.
There's featured app collections
that showcase the best apps
and seasonal or cultural events.
Categories where
and explore apps
Top Charts, which list the
or most downloaded apps and
free, and top-grossing.
And whilst editorial
to get a quick burst of
by users with over a
in the U.S. App Store, the most
for your app as if it shows up
Now the best way to
and the likelihood a user
in App Store Search, is
for your product page.
And show your app name,
and keywords are highly
This should be the prime
to support your app's
Last week, we announced Search
to control the visibility
in App Store search results.
Search Ads can help develop
and increase usage
Almost two-thirds of all
from searches on the App Store.
The App Store is the place where
for an app to download,
to invest in the
When a user searches
a single sponsored ad
of the search results.
The sponsored listing will
and ad icon next to
The app may be in one of
optimized to what
for that search query and user.
Because user experience
relevance is the main factor
be showed for search query.
If your app is not relevant to
it will not appear in
of how much you may
Let me give you an example.
You have a pizza delivery app
because you think those
engrossed to actually
Well, your app most likely will
for those searches because
Now relevance will be determined
of your App Store metadata.
So as I mentioned earlier,
in thoughtfully crafting
and metadata with the most
improve your organic presence,
it will also improve
for sponsored ads as well.
We also take users'
as a signal for its relevance.
If users don't respond to an ad,
Pricing is a Cost Per Tap model.
So you only pay when a
and you decide the maximum
to pay for a tap.
The actual cost of
of a Second Price Auction,
meaning the price
on what your nearest
to show their ad up
This means you'll never pay more
or more than you need to.
And whether your ad will
of your app's relevance to the
of your bid comparative
to others bidding
And as I said earlier, apps
that aren't relevant won't
With App Store Search being the
of app downloads, our goal
to give all developers
to reach more customers through
in relevant search results.
Whether you have a
have marketing expertise
I now invite Casey
about the features
into the product
&gt;&gt; We've worked hard to make
for all developers.
But we really thought a lot
for smaller developers
and as simple as possible.
So that way you can get back
which is creating great apps.
Search Ads was designed
so that you can get
in a matter of minutes.
And there are only a
to tell us before you can
And that is, your
and your payment information.
And that's it.
So let's talk about
You tell us the app that
and Search Ads will
for you using the
that you've already provided
So there's actually nothing for
that your App Store information
of your app.
Now because we know so much
we can then take that ad and
that are coming through
We do this with our default
and we absolutely
We really think that
Next you'll define your budget.
Your budget can include
You'll also tell us the maximum
to pay for a tap on your ad.
Eric will talk about how to best
on in the presentation.
Finally, you add your
We support all of the currencies
and except all major
And that's it.
Your ad is now eligible
in App Store Search results.
That's pretty simple.
Now we realize there are some of
when it comes to
and you may want more
Now whether that be choosing
that you want your ad to show
for those keywords, or
about a particular
to reach with your ad.
Well, you can do all that.
Let's talk about keywords first.
Now because we know so much
we can provide a list of
so that you don't have to think
Furthermore, you can add
and we'll give you a list of
For all of our keywords,
we offer what we call a relative
And this just give
of how important a particular
but also the relative
We have two match
There's Broad match, which
as well as its relative variance
that include that keyword.
And then there's Exact
that specific phrase as
like common misspellings
If you want to learn
you should come talk to us
in our lab session tomorrow
about how these work
Now you can keep
And you could set a default bid
or you can apply individual
and that would be if you
that keyword based on
or just how important that
There are also additional
to you if appropriate
Now our default setting is
that have already
That way your budget can focus
However, if your campaign
you can target existing users as
If you want to further refine
to target by things like gender,
So a very simple way to use
that you have an app that
Well, you could target
and that way you wouldn't
that your app doesn't service.
Or perhaps there's an
that you know is your
Let's say males, ages 18 to 34.
Well, you could create
that would allow you to closely
then, for that audience.
Now we obviously want you
on investment in Search Ads.
But we want that to be a very
So we designed an
and reporting UI that will allow
of what's happening,
down into the details
Now the best place to
of performance is
on the campaign overview
And this is where we've trended
in one very easy to digest page.
From here, you could hop
And you'll see we've
to optimize those keywords
because we've placed
in the exact same place
If you have bulk sets of
which would be the keywords
to show against, you can upload
as well.
Then there's the
And this is a very powerful tab.
You could learn the actual
to an impression, tap,
So all the search queries
that your ad's been
So anything from that Search
about earlier will be
And you'd also see search
from your own Broad
So really it's just a great
Now these management screens
with performance
But we've also built a
that allows you to parse
and keywords by things
location, device, and more.
You can download all of
and we also offer
campaign creation,
Once you've acquired a customer,
we offer a robust
to give you advance insights,
to understand the keywords
that are delivering the most
That way you can
to optimize your bidding
And now I'd like to invite Eric
to show you just how
and optimize a Search
in our simple, yet powerful UI.
&gt;&gt; I'm going to share
and manage a successful search
First, I search for my app
My app is LightRight, a new
in unique filters that aren't
Search Ads has found my app
which it will use to make my
Straight away I can see it has
for me, and I can
The first thing I need
and put in my budget.
My budget is $3,000.
I also have the option to
I want to pace out my budget
so I'll set it to $50.
Now I need to create
So I can organize my
or audience targeting
I'm going to call mine
Because Search Ads knows
it has defaulted my ads
on both the iPad and the iPhone.
I have the option to
but I want to reach as
so I'll leave it as is.
If appropriate, I can also
and stop on specific dates.
The default setting is to
I can also choose to have my
of the week or times of the day.
But for my LightRight App, I'd
as the App Store, 24/7.
Importantly, I need to set my
To work out how I should
I take what I know an average
and decide how much
on acquiring each new customer.
I can afford to spend
Given that searchers in the
downloaders, I'm going to assume
of the people who tap on my ad
Doing the math, that means I
of $2.50 per tap or $1.
So I'll set my starting
I have the option to
acquisition goal.
Search Ads will use this
but it's not a guarantee.
If I set it too low, I
that may lead to downloads.
For now, I'm not
until I have some
Now I'm moving into defining
Search Match is on by default,
on because as Casey mentioned,
Search Match will
to relevant user searches.
If I want to keep things simple,
to do all of the work for me.
Because as I have time and
with search campaigns, I'm going
to see what keywords are
All of these look good, so I'm
I can also see that some
such as picture editor
I'll want to keep a
I also have a few keywords that
As Casey mentioned,
then it's considered an
of the words are broad match.
So LightRight is an exact
in light conditions
I have the option to
But I plan to leave
Advanced targeting
to refine the audience
for my particular app.
The first default setting is
who have not downloaded my app.
Other options, such as
also open to me.
But in my case, LightRight is a
on acquiring new users.
So I'll go with the
If appropriate, I could
to a specific gender or age.
For example, if your app is
then you may target female
But for my LightRight
and genders would be excited
so I'll skip the
Device location can be a
if your app only serves a
For example, a food delivery
around San Francisco might
Now that I've set up my initial
into the future and
My average cost per tap at
And my average cost per
below my $2.50 target.
My average conversion rate
At a high level, these
But I notice my impressions,
and conversions have flattened
and are starting
Given that my CPT and CPA
there may be opportunity for
Let's drill down into
to see what's happening.
To get there, I click
and then on Search Term.
The Search Term view is where I
terms that match to my ad
and their performance.
I can see here that
to some really relevant terms
that are increasing
Color edit search term is
from my app at a
I want to see if I can
if I raise my max CPT bid.
So I'm going to add it
I'm going to up my
Color search term,
is driving very few
It's a broad match to
So I'm going to add it as a
as people searching color are
to my app.
Let's add color as a
To learn and manage
of the keywords I specifically
over to the Manage Keyword tab.
I see that app for lighting
and the CPA at $5.17 is a
I'm going to pause the app
I like the picture
as that is performing
So I'm going to use
to get recommendations for
So let's type in picture editor.
The photo editor
That should drive relevant
I'll add it to my
And it will show up at
The reporting view is a great
about your campaigns
In my case, we're looking
of device class and impressions.
It seems that 80 percent
for my app from an iPhone.
Therefore, I should consider
for iPhone so that I can
to get more impressions
Now I'm driving users to my
That's great.
But knowing the true value
of these downloads will help
on my campaign investment.
Because Search Ads, the App
to develop my app are all
It's easy to know which of
by Search Ads.
The Search Ads attribution
downloads to my campaign, but
to a specific bidded keyword
It's a turnkey solution that
and track meaningful
and their value to me over time.
This information will help
and other targeting parameters
And I can use those insights
to optimize my campaign
The best part about the
is to instrument.
You just need the ad -- the I
and then add these lines of
Here's the response object
that contains campaign
download date, and click date.
While the API allows
and segment your users, rest
or transmit any personal
to any third parties.
We accomplish this by enabling
and response on device
customer relationship
to prevent information look
up by turning limited
Now that you're armed with these
to set up and manage your
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Eric.
You're going to love
to discover your amazing apps.
What could be better than the
up at the top of relevant
that millions of users are
And connecting those users
Setting up your Search Ad
We create the ads for you.
We match it to relevant
and there's an intuitive
and reporting UI
to quickly view your results.
You're in control of how
And you have the option to
refine your targeting, and
for advanced insights.
We've talked about a
But there are a few things
to get prepared for Search Ads.
Firstly, optimize
and ensure it is
and accurate reflection
Understand the value
and how much you can
This will help you determine
And lastly, implement
in your app.
You'll love the rich
To learn more, you can
and here you will also find
for our [inaudible] commenced.
Thank you so much for listening