[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to Session 303.
I'm Todd Fernandez.
And I'm very pleased to be
to give you an update on what's
Now, before we begin,
that I am still a
after attending my college
And I'm not going to
but if it had been
I would have received
Now, despite being a little
to see you all here in the hall,
out to all of you watching the
as well as you future viewers
at some indefinite period
Hello, future viewers.
But speaking of the
no, not that kind of time,
although I do love
I want to talk about
Now, many of you here in the
like a quiet time for
As we toil behind the scenes
that we're going to
and then ship in
But it turns out
that schools actually want
to use those features
fall releases.
They want to configure
of all those new
for use during the
But in order to do that,
they need to have already
and software even earlier.
And in order to do that, they
of the new hardware, software,
Which brings us to iOS 9.3.
It's really strange how
of jumped right out at us.
But the schedule isn't
what about the features?
There are a ton of new
in our spring software
But the true stars of the
Manager, Shared iPad,
Let's first talk a little bit
which provides a
to access Apple's device
Those services include
and teachers, as well as
between them, configuring how
for remote management, and
and creating the curriculum
And fortunately, one of the
of the school districts
which piloted these features
that Apple School Manager will
of time, allowing them to
and our student accounts
exactly what we intended.
Now let's turn to Shared iPad.
Shared iPad allows the majority
and around the world
to provide their students
and enable them to use the
Shared iPad can be configured so
in by simply tapping
and entering a four-digit
Student data is stored in
to a specific iPad when
Again, it's great to see that
for getting these Shared iPads
that Shared iPad will allow our
of shared devices
into a personalized learning
Again, nailed it.
All right.
Finally, Classroom.
Classroom empowers
and their students
rather than managing technology
of key capabilities at
in the classroom.
Teachers can easily open an app
or a selected group of student
to the Classroom Apple TV, or
who may be off task even
with a different group of
And I was very fortunate
to visit Mr. Garcia's
and it was truly inspiring
that his students were
with his support
And after his experience
that Classroom has been an
the school day to enhance the
going on his classroom.
Classroom helps him to keep
for their work while also
in their assignments.
Now while it's extremely
of response to the features we
to hear some great feedback
including from some very
who have raved about the blazing
of Classroom's features.
Now, these spring 2016 changes
with an extremely
and high quality
which schools need
to deliver not only
and most advanced
but also the best device
We've demonstrated this
in providing a great experience
to schools bringing Apple
But we need all of our
to tool providers, to all of you
to see your app used by
around the world to
that that great experience
of our joint customers
But I do want to
up because although we don't
we are definitely not done yet.
So today I'm going to cover
across the entire device
So let's go ahead
I'll cover a few changes to
into some detail
like Apple School Manager,
of course, Shared iPad.
So first I want to cover a few
For Enterprise customers we
programs, the Device
for configuring how your devices
as well as the volume purchase
and books and distributing them
However, we've also
of new device management
in the spring and
about later in this session.
And we'll try to highlight those
to Enterprise customers, though
for education also are
Turning to education,
about Apple School
As I mentioned, it allows the
the devices, and the content the
that improved performance
With respect to getting
there are two options: You can
to your student information
out all the student,
and relationship information;
that information
Once Apple School Manager
it creates managed Apple IDs
as well as creating classes
between which teachers have
What are those managed
Well, they're used both
as administer accounts
and accommodate tiered
so that different administers
for managing your school's
The student accounts have a
They're required to
but they can be used for
And in Apple School Manager
options for Managed Apple ID
from the full-strength iCloud
or six-digit pass code.
Managed Apple IDs are
in that some services are
so that students using a Managed
from our stores.
There are also services such
which can be enabled
if the school decides they
All right.
For you NDM vendors
just as with the Device
and the volume purchase
to access this roster
from Apple School Manager and
to all the student and
as well as the classes.
In terms of the transition
from the Apple deployment
to Apple School Manager,
that they do not need
It will continue to work.
But your NDM solution needs to
and be checking to see if their
Manager type and
which will actually be
to the roster service
On a parallel track,
with the Device Enrollment
that you now support
that information in the header.
And you'll receive the
now available via that API.
I also wanted to pass
that my team has learned
in adopting this API
The first is really a
that we think your customers
If they have been using
they've undoubtedly connected it
and group information so
representation for each user.
Once you connect up to
in Apple School Manager,
to be getting a second
in the form of the
And we recommend that you
to provide some matching
so that you can automatically
into one representation of
And because that matching won't
we think you also should allow
to be able to tell you this
as this Managed Apple ID.
One special note about
by CSV uploads is that the
in the CSV template becomes
in the API results
That source system identifier
like a student ID; it's not
So that field can
and is not guaranteed
And you need to be
The final practice I wanted
out that there is no delta
to do a full enumeration to get
Since the student information
once per day between it
there's no need to automatically
than that frequency.
And in fact, if you give
to request a sync, you're going
that they're not overwhelming
Turning from people to devices,
to configure the Device
for your school's devices,
including finding
configuring the details
and then assigning devices
when they're enrolled they'll
And finally content.
Apple School Manager
to the Volume Purchase
and books, and it
to iTunes U Course Manager.
And I also wanted to mention
that we recently
which now supports integration
to pull managed course
Now let's talk about some of
to getting your devices
Last year I talked
in iOS 9 called enrollment
And just a recap this allows
in the Device Enrollment
that I want to you wait
until I'm done configuring
to use the device.
That setting comes down to
in their DEP settings.
It then sends a token
to the MDM server,
that I'm ready to be configured.
The MDM server can then
install as many configuration
that device up to
it then sends a device
to the device, which then
and allows the student or the
This enables the
that that device is not used
Now that we have Shared iPad,
in that there's a new
At that point the Shared iPad
to the MDM server.
But in contrast to
about that's device-specific,
this token update reports
for the user who signed in.
That enables the MDM server to
as it needs to configure
with any per-user
into a bit more later.
One crucial difference between
and the device-specific
that unlike the prior one
until the MDM server is
from completing sign in
A few security best practices.
Those of you who have
that we removed support for MD5
We've also deprecated DES,
So the message here is that your
or AES as soon as
to be using the most
and it's time to move
Next, a few details about
one of the other features of
In iOS 9.3.2 we now allow you
to skip the new True Tone
on hardware which
And new in macOS Sierra, we
but in fact you might
to configure them during setup.
So you can skip the Siri or
Now, this is another
I think I've done this now,
for you MDM vendors to
which allows tools
to obtain information
such as the DEP enrollment
to fetch the anchor certs.
Profile Manager has supported
and Apple Configurator 2 takes
to simply enter the host
and Configurator does the rest.
Now let's talk about
Of course, this brings
to iPad in the classroom.
A few details about
And then I want to talk a
of how it preserves user data.
As I mentioned earlier,
Shared iPad requires a
Once a student signs in
she is also signed into her
as well as her iTunes
which I'll talk about
It's also used for
Now, since there isn't
into a Shared iPad,
and install them using device
to VPP managed distribution
MDM vendors hopefully have all
but you'll need to use
to support device assignments.
All app types are
to [inaudible] apps
Although in order to distribute
the developer of that app must
and C's in iTunes Connect
Now let's talk a little bit
about the underlying
As I mentioned, the student
that's where the truth is.
But once they've signed into
their data is downloaded
However, that cache
if additional students need
to be accommodated
Each student can only
But if they generate a lot
and they sign out before all
of that data has successfully
Shared iPad will continue to
in screen or even if
The key to all this
of your apps are
That primarily means that you're
and settings in the Cloud.
We've got a whole session right
to make your app education
and I encourage you
Now, just kind of animation
Student enters her pass code.
Shared iPad gets her
to the Home screen, excuse me.
Downloads her data.
See, she's working on her
to sign out, to go
or to go home for the day.
Even back at the login screen
Maybe she was working
But even if another
and begins downloading his data,
the previous student's
until it's all safely
But the next student can
right away.
So what do you MDM vendors need
Again, hopefully all of
but for those of you who
there's a new setting in the
to supervision that tells
You also will want to use
that I talked about earlier
to set some key options
And I'm going to go
about both user quota and
So what is the user quota?
Well, it's the maximum
which will be cached
Let's say six.
iOS will then automatically
should be allocated
taking into account
as well as books and apps
As users log in, their
and cached on the Shared iPad.
But in this case with a quota of
one of the user data
And we will purge the
who doesn't have any
to upload to the Cloud.
Some guidelines on how to choose
to try to get it close to
who will actually use the
which will typically
of class periods
Because if you have too few,
students will have their
than necessary.
And if you choose a number
to allocate space that's not
Lock screen grace period.
So let's imagine we
And this option gives
to choose the right
for their students and data
And I think it's easier to
than for me to talk about it.
Again, let's imagine we
The teacher asks the students
So the screen locks.
Let's imagine she
and after 30 seconds Mia
and she gets right back
to enter her pass code.
Now let's imagine the
and Mia swipes after
She will be prompted to
So, again, this offers an
to choose that right balance.
Another detail for
iOS as part of Shared iPad now
to the device channel
to send MDM commands
macOS has had a user
And this is very similar
but with some differences
In fact, if your MDM solution
over the user channel to Macs,
to iOS devices previously,
But with iOS devices 9.3
and later they will now
There's a subset of
which are able to be
which I'll cover in a moment.
One important difference
and macOS is that no user
before delivering those per-user
So you should never send
over user channel, and
that no credentials are
That includes the new
that we introduced in iOS 9.3.
As I mentioned, all
including that new Google OAuth
on the user channel, as
Home screen layout and Safari
to the domains payload that
The existing restrictions
on the user channel, including
that was added in iOS 9.3.
One important detail about
at first seem confusing
from how they have
if a restriction's payload is
and the user channel, they
to compute an effective
with the most restrictive
This prevents a student
from installing another
without that setting and
from that restriction.
The reason this isn't really any
multiple profiles have
if delivered all
And with that, I'd like to
and give you a demo of
of the other education features
David, take it away.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Todd.
It's great to be here demoing
Let's take a look at
between a couple classes
To start we'll look
Now, you can see the
We have some recent
and then a class list that
from to log in.
When I want to log into this
from the list, which is
of students to choose from.
If this isn't my class, I can
select a separate class, again,
of students we can choose from.
Now, if I'm not in any class
in using any Managed
to the same organization
But to demonstrate Shared
to our recent users.
Here we have Ava, a
a third-grader, who
in their classes yesterday.
The second grade class
So let's log in as Ava.
Now, when we log in and log
out our video sync
So I'll show you here.
After she enters
they'll authenticate against
on the device, the iPad will
on her personalized Home screen
that the school has
Now, while the video catches up,
let's talk about how this
The school configured
for second and third-graders.
They chose the apps
in those grades would use and
for each of the students
that they would see every
within that organization.
So for Ava, as a second-grader,
they've chosen these
You can see iBooks
because those are the most-used
In fact, Ava's been
across a variety
And you can see that all
to this iPad from iCloud.
Now, we can create more notes on
and be available on other iPads.
Today her class was
Of course, it's a great topic.
So let's help her
to commemorate this session.
In fact, let's take
All right, everybody,
&gt;&gt; WWDC.
&gt;&gt; Woo-hoo.
Perfect. Now she'll
Unfortunately, it's time for her
Now, when Ava logs out
which applications are saving
to be synced afterwards
or when another user is
So when we land back at
in as another user, that
in the background.
For example, if we had been
up to this point instead
it would be given another
Now a third grade
and Liam is back at this device.
So we'll log in as him.
Again, after we enter his
the iPad gets ready,
or his personalized Home screen.
For the third-graders the
of the same application
But they've also included a
including the ones from iWork
because the third-graders
throughout the year.
And they've also included
so that the students
for those presentations.
So if you look at the dock,
you'll see that Liam also
but he now has Maps and Safari
because the third-graders
and history of the great
Now, Liam needs to put together
for a presentation
And though Ava just used
Liam does not see
In fact, it looks like Liam has
So let's help him
We'll create a new note.
And Liam's found
that he'll be able
So let's add one of those now.
Oh, beautiful.
California state flag.
That's a great flag and a
But unfortunately, class
so Liam needs to log out.
Thankfully, when he logs out,
he knows that his data is being
when he gets home and wants to
Every day throughout the entire
the same iPads to work on their
and it's synced and available
across multiple devices
For Ava and Liam, that means
on their projects wherever
Thank you.
Back to you, Todd.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you very much, David.
Just a brief recap.
So David showed how you
on Shared iPad's log in screen,
of building up a list
in with their Managed
They had actually signed
and demonstrated that Ava
and Liam only see
in Notes and over other app.
And in fact, the school can
of apps and Home screen layout
for different groups
Well, that concludes our
Let's continue with
We got a few changes to
And let's get right to it.
So there's a great new feature
that allows MDM servers
to programmatically link Managed
to their Volume Purchase
so that no invitation process
that this account is coming
that wants to distribute
This, of course, does
or Apple School Manager
from the same organization.
But as I mentioned earlier,
to download any new
to Apple School Manager,
For you MDM vendors,
that the school has different
that appear to be from
There is a dedicated error
So you can try to
and just catch the failure and
"Hey, your tokens don't
that before we can
Of course, to give this
you'll have to adopt
which is already
And this is going
for distributing iBooks
which we'll talk about next.
So how can you get iBooks Store
VPP books can only
and cannot be distributed
So the way it will work is
that once you've
to your Managed Apple IDs,
into Shared iPad will
in their iBook Bookshelf,
and they can simply
to get those bits.
The good news is that the second
to use that book on
to immediately download because
on the device and are only
and bandwidth of
In contrast, non-iBook
or iBooks author documents or
and managed just like
Finally, a few important
to how Enterprise apps
with universal provisioning
that were introduced
to be somewhat confusing.
These universal provisioning
app to run even if that
on the provisioning profile
For this to work, it requires
of that app signer, as well
by Apple that that specific
remains valid.
So, again, when installing one
than MDM, the user must
However, if the device
those apps are implicitly
that they trusted
when enrolling in MDM.
However, the second piece
that Apple must consider
to continue to run requires
to be online occasionally to
Even MDM installed apps
periodic validation.
But an MDM server can
"Go validate all of
This is a really key
such as an electronic flight
that will be offline
on a regular schedule.
The MDM server can tell the
to be offline, "Go ahead and
that they continue to run."
And in fact, for
and this is what we've done in
that you just go ahead
and automatically validate
when fetching the
that are not validated, and that
the time.
That concludes our
And now let's move
in device management
in an ongoing basis to
And to take us through
like to invite Shubham Kedia
Shubham?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Todd.
Good morning, everyone.
I'm thrilled to be
through some great new
to both iOS and macOS this year.
So let's start with iOS 9.3
where we added some brand
to go alongside Shared iPad.
The settings command was
to now specify the
that can have local
We saw Todd talk
You can now also toggle
We added some commands that
as well, such as the user list
to get the list of all users
and even get information
or not they're logged
or not they have data that's
as well as information
and how much space they've used.
There are new commands
and delete users as well.
9.3 also introduced MDM Lost
Now, these aren't
these work across all
So you can rest assured that
you can remotely enable MDM
and phone number
to get the device's location.
For devices like Shared iPads
where you don't have an Apple
MDM Activation Lock is also a
Now, before I move
out these icons that
These represent commands,
or configuration
to either Shared
that you'll see throughout
9.3 also introduced some
that you allow to configure
you want.
The education payload is used
to configure both the
as well as Classroom app.
Notifications allows you
to configure exactly the
like for all applications.
You can preapprove or deny
that aren't even installed
like sounds and badges.
The Home screen layout
in his demo earlier can be used
to configure exactly
and folders you'd like
The lock screen message
to specify a custom
on the lock screen and the
The exchange and mail payloads
You can now choose whether
of Mail Drop when sending
The domains payload has been
to now specify exactly
for which Safari will offer to
For you Enterprise
we've updated the
with some great new
and the restrictions payload
You can now restrict
iCloud Photo Library,
You can also choose whether
to be monitored by teachers
You can disable modification
which you may have set using
as well as -- and you also
and hide specific apps.
Again, we saw David use
I'd like to talk a
about the education payload.
It's extremely important
because not only does it
and classes you see in the
but it's also how Classroom
and student devices should
In this payload you'll specify
and even be able
for these students and teachers.
You'll do so by specifying URLs.
And it's important that
When you update these photos,
Only one such payload can
and it's important
and teacher devices
So all these payloads that I've
be applied at the device
of the users on a Shared iPad.
But there are five
over the user channel per user.
These include all of
including the new Google
Home screen layout, the domains
for Safari auto fill domains, as
with the ability to
Next let's talk about iOS 9.3.2.
Here we updated the settings
or disable app analytics,
as well as set the lock
Of course, we also updated
and SecurityInfo queries
to return the correct
One thing to note here is
that the security info query
lock grace period and pass code
The enforced value might be more
from your MDM server since it
while users are logged in.
Now, one of the great uses
for standardized testing.
And we've had two great
in past releases:
and Autonomous Single App mode.
These continue to work the
on supervised devices.
However, now with a new
to your app, you
and also disable five system
for your assessment app.
These include things like
keyboard shortcuts, predictive
And for the first time the
ability to enable this mode on
Of course, we do
on unmanaged unsupervised
where you can simply reboot
9.3.2 also added a
to prevent users from disabling
or enabling diagnostic
which you may have set via MDM.
Now let's talk about iOS 10.
In iOS 10 we updated the
and the LDAP payloads
for communication service rules.
We saw earlier this week the
in iOS 10.
And what this key allows you
to do is specify a default
when making audio calls to
The lock screen message
with new key names as well.
Of course, it remains
for administers creating
but we like MDM vendors to
as the old ones have
The VPN payload now has support
for IKEv2, as well
to specify a timeout for IPSec.
PPTP has also been removed
and existing payloads
The Wi-Fi payload saw
You can specify if you want to
and Cisco fast lane
And for those of you who know
Finally, the restrictions
to prevent users from
Now, this is extremely
since Classroom relies
to connect its student
So here are some restrictions
that were introduced before
And we talked last year about
like to deprecate these and
on unsupervised devices.
Now, that future iOS
but we promise we are going
So please note that these
on unsupervised devices.
Next let's talk about macOS.
Earlier this year we
to install software updates
on Macs enrolled in the
This is going to be
when macOS Sierra is
to install it on
in Device Enrollment Program in
New in macOS Sierra we also
profile payload to
and added some new updates
We brought some keys
such as Apple Music,
and iCloud Photo Library,
that are specific to the
Find My Mac, and sharing to
It's been my pleasure
of these great features
And with that, I'd like
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Great job.
Thanks. All right.
Thank you very much, Shubham.
Let's turn to our final
And of course, the most exciting
We talked a little
and it offers some amazing
carefully curated
for teachers in the classroom.
But instead of hearing
you can read the
I'd like to ask Shruti Gupta to
Shruti?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Todd.
I am so excited to show you one
What you see here
that is running Classroom on it.
And there are a bunch
that are configure
And all my students are
When the class begins, the
to the iPads and then students
For this demo the students are
in since you've already
in process during David's demo.
Now, let's assume that I'm
and today we'll be learning
And for that I found a really
to share with all my students.
So I'm going to tap on
and select the healthy
And it's navigating;
on all student devices.
Okay. Looks like one
But if you look at
you can see that Classroom app
Safari, indicating that all
yeah?
And if you tap on the screens,
up pretty much on
And I guess some are already
Kids, pay attention
[ Laughter ]
&gt;&gt; So for the next
to divide the students
So I'm going to tap on Class
add a bunch of students
and give the group a
Now when I launch
into activities specific
let's say I want Green's group
to make a list of
I will open Notes app for them
so they can start
Okay? And while students
I want to see how they're doing.
So I'm going to go back
and observe their screen.
And it seems that Edison is not
Let's take a closer look.
I'm going to tap on
and clearly she is not
So I'm going to go back.
Now I can either lock her screen
to get her attention back in the
into Notes app by sliding
on the Notes so she
Once the class ends, I can bring
out all the students iPads
And all the students
Thank you.
Back to Todd.
&gt;&gt; Thank you very much, Shruti.
It was great of you
in this amazing stress
with the most iOS devices
Thank you very much.
So what did we see?
We saw Shruti use
on all the student iPads,
in addition to the
that Classroom creates
into an app to focus
view the students' screens to
and redirect as needed,
if they get off track.
So a few brief notes
that we make available to
for the Device Enrollment
and Volume Purchase Program,
to test their implementation of
especially handling
that may be very
to simulate any other way with
The simulators have been
of the new features
And as always, they're
on the Developer portal.
And I strongly encourage you to
That brings us to the
Just a few summary slides
to cover the key points
If you're a school
and use Apple School Manager
and content in your school.
Everyone can use the DEP
in their remote management
or you can also use
or to combine the two using
enrollment feature that
to Configurator and complete
on the DEP settings without
If you're a school and
use Shared iPad with Managed
and everyone can use VPP managed
to devices or users
to allow your users to use
For MDM developers, please add
including the programmatic
for use with VPP, as well
that Shubham talked
in iOS 10 and macOS Sierra.
Updated documentation
And please, again, do test with
Last but not least,
we want you to get your
by storing your app's data
And you can simulate
by testing using your app
And the session immediately
about best practices will
about what you need to do
Speaking of which, this is the
Again, right here
There's some great
on our website both for
and for Enterprise at
I encourage you to check it out.
And finally, there are
direct links to documentations,
at our WWDC 2016
for Session 303.
And with that, I will thank
and hope you have a
Thank you very much.