[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, good afternoon.
Good afternoon, and welcome to
I'm Dave Van Tassell,
Engineering Manager
I'm excited to spend some times
about what we've been up
Now iTunes Connect covers the
from uploading the metadata,
releasing your app onto the
to see how well you're
And so, today we're
of these different
We're going to start with
to in-app purchases and
about iTunes Connect for iOS,
our mobile companion
We're also going to
and what's new with
And then something
which is screenshot
and this is about the
about uploading images and
We want to talk a little
what you have to do in iTunes
and submit your iMessage apps.
And then we're going to finish
So let's get started.
We're going to talk
and the first area we're going
Now when we talk
what we're talking about are
and the biggest change we made
up to all categories.
[ Applause ]
So no longer is it
that can use autorenewables.
Everybody's eligible
Now we're also introducing
so that you can price your
in each territory.
Instead of selecting one price
you can select individual
And to go along with that, we're
of available price
to over 200 different
and this should really let
in the right country
and your subscribers.
Another new feature we're adding
to the subscriptions is
Now this is for your
When you raise the price of a
if you want them to also
or you can let them keep
so when they renew,
to pay their existing price.
And the last change we're making
with you for over a year.
When they renew,
of the proceeds, and
So you no longer have to
Anyone who's already
to your in-app purchase for
with their next subscription
you will receive 85
[ Applause ]
This is a good one.
Now there's actually so much
to subscriptions we've
that are dedicated just to this.
The first is a more
to actually program a
check your receipt,
It's a great session.
The second one is more about
and how to set up all this new
To change the price in
and preserve your price, so
If you didn't get a
then I highly recommend
And those are the changes
Now this next change
to all in-app purchases,
and this is in-app
[ Applause ]
In-app purchase promo
in iTunes Connect right next to
for your app versions.
So you go to the features
you have where you can
for your app version.
And then down below,
up in-app purchase promo codes.
The first thing you
which in-app purchase you
I'm going to do Dream
I just need the one right now.
And so we go through
It's how many promo
So we can select in here.
I think right now I need 25.
That ought to do it.
And that's it.
Now I'm ready to
I can download them as a text
and people can download my
Now this feature, as well
to subscriptions, will be
And those are our changes
Now the next thing
about is iTunes Connect for iOS.
And to do that, I'm
on state to tell you more.
Mike?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Dave.
Good afternoon, everyone.
My name is Mike Amirault, and I
to talk to you about
Before I begin, how many of you
out there have downloaded
All right.
Quite a few.
We'll try to get the rest of you
to download it before
For those of you who
let me give you a brief
iTunes Connect for iOS is
to the iTunes Connect website.
It allows you on-the-go access
ratings and reviews
the ability to reject a
for the store, and
so you can be immediately
of any changes to your apps.
It is available for
Let's talk about what's new.
In the past year, we
for the mobile app, but
like to highlight for you today.
First, new push notifications,
and third, full access
within the mobile app.
Let's look at each of these.
New push notifications,
of push notifications
First, if your app contracts
if you get a message
you can now get a push
with the issue immediately.
And lastly, and this has been
you can get a push notification
when your app has finished
[ Applause ]
I know. It's the little things.
So let's talk about
What does that mean?
Some of you work on apps
In the past, this was
in the world to do.
You would have to have
and you would have to
in order to see all your apps.
With multiprovider support,
and you can have it associated
with all the providers
I'd like to show you how
When you log in, we'll
to the last one that
If you want to change it,
in the bottom right, and then
This will show you all
with your account.
Simply pick the one you want,
for just that provider.
Now push notifications
So you can turn them on
or turn them off for others.
It's completely up to you
So that's multiprovider support,
of you that work with
Resolution Center, this was the
in the past year, full
within the mobile app.
Let me show you what
Anywhere within the mobile
of your apps, either in recents,
any of your apps that have
will be displayed
Let's tap into one of those.
So you can see at the top
of the view it gives you a
of active issues you have and
Let's tap on that header.
Here you can see the
and you can get a
of all the replies
If you tap on the reply
you have the option here
on through email to another
or you can reply directly
to the App Review team.
When App Review responds, you
so you can deal with
So that's the Resolution
It's just one of the three --
Now let's talk about
Now there's one feature
of this list for most
the ability to see exactly
in gross sales and proceeds
I am happy to say that
in our next release, and I would
So this is the Sales and
when you sign in today.
On the left side, you'll
for each line item, and on
and green rectangles,
between the current
and the previous period.
Much like the stocks app,
and green rectangles, you
So let's tap on it, and now
for each of these line items.
If we tap on it again, now we're
As we tap through
the graph at the bottom
to represent the dimension
Let's look at top products.
Here we're showing the
for your top products.
This will allow you to easily
most popular apps are
you can tap the red or
between sales, proceeds,
Let's look at a specific app.
When you're looking
you can get the daily
Here we're showing the
If we tap on the view line,
proceeds, sales, and updates.
Let's look at sales.
Then we hit back.
So now we're displaying
on a per day basis.
So that's our new sales
It will be available
and we know you've been
so it'll be available today.
[ Applause ]
Now since we're going to be
I'd like to take this
for you my favorite
and that's the ability
to release your app
So what I'm going to do
on the current version
to release the new version
So we're going to do that now.
First off, you want
Mine's very easy to find because
And you can see we
One is currently
We don't want to be
And our second one is
So let's look at
And you can see we
We can either release this
We don't want to reject
So we're going to tap
and it will give us
because we don't want you
or release your binary.
And we're going to
And there it is.
The app is now ready for sale.
[ Applause ]
So the app is now
and it'll be available
and I'm now going to hand
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks, Mike.
That's what's coming up
with enhanced notification
Resolution Center built
as well as the just released
So I'm going to talk about
to believe that it's
since this has become
in iTunes Connect Toolbox.
And to talk more about what
I'm going to invite
David?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks, Dave.
I'm David Hopkins, and I'm going
about what's new
For those of you who
it's available as a
It's free.
There's no integration
and it has customer
So let's talk about
Why are analytics important?
First, analytics
Are customers finding my app?
Are customers downloading
Are they using my app?
How stable is my app?
These are some of the questions
that App Analytics
Next, App Analytics reveals
Perhaps you have a large
and you didn't realize
that customers were
Well, that's an opportunity
and localize your
And App Analytics can help you
Next, App Analytics helps
There's been a lot of great
design and build great apps.
But we believe that building
when you release
It's important to continue
and App Analytics can
to make great decisions
So let's talk about the types of
First, we provide
This is data about how many
on the App Store, how many
your app.
Next, we provide sales data.
This is data about how much
in your app, how many users
and how much -- and how many
in your app.
And finally, there's usage data.
This is data about how
your app, what your
and how stable your app is.
So with this data, we're able
from the time that
with App Store data
with customers with usage data.
But today, we're primarily
on updates to App Store data.
And App Store data starts
Every time a customer views your
this registers a
So, for example, we have
and this is our product page.
Customer views this.
This would count as
If a customer goes on to
They purchase our app.
This would count as an app unit.
So app units help you track
that you have in any
So this helps you understand
You're able to see
that your product
You're able to see the
But it doesn't tell the whole
because it doesn't tell
in the App Store that
And so, to help you
we're introducing a new
[ Applause ]
So impressions are going to
that customers have viewed
So we talked about one way
That's your product page.
But let's talk about other ways
that customers view your
First, there's search.
A customer searches for
and our app Trip Guide shows
This will count as an
If you're taking advantage
and your app shows up in
this will also count
If your app shows up
or in our top charts or
that will register
So this is the new
Let's take a look at what this
This is the App List.
This the entry point to
From here, you can see a
and Apple TV apps
starting with your impressions
to see how many customers
on the App Store, app units
to tell you how many
sales to tell you how much
or on your app, sessions to tell
have opened your app, and
of how stable your app is.
We show you the value for
as the percentage change
to help you understand whether
So we can see our
It's in the first row here.
And we can see that
we had around 300,000
This is a 17 percent increase
If we want to find out more
you can click into that number,
and it'll take you
So the metrics view allows
of more information about
You can see this data
and you can also slice this
if you want to see something --
drill down to something
perhaps how many impression you
In addition to providing
we're also providing unique
So if you select
down to just the unique
So if I were to view
on the App Store three times
that would count as
but one unique impression.
So if I select that, now I'm
for impressions.
This helps us better understand
who are viewing our
at any given time period.
With this, we can start
to the number of new users we
to understand our App
how well our App Store presence
So I'll walk you through that.
You can select compare to
Now you're viewing app units
on the same graph, but
to view this data as a ratio.
So if you change from single
now you can view this as
and we can see that
it takes about ten
And so, we can start to --
and our description to our
to see what effect that has on
So that's the impression feature
to look at your App
And we're excited to announce
that all this is available
[ Applause ]
So let's talk about what's
We've given you impressions to
of customers that are viewing
but the next question we want
to help you answer is how
And we do this today
And so, let's talk about what
for customers to find
The first source is
So we talked about
with searching on the App Store.
We've searched for guides.
That's one way that
Similarly, if we were to find
in the top charts, in featured,
these are all ways that
by browsing the App Store.
So that's one source for
But we recognize that
that customers are finding your
And so, the first source
about outside of the
So websites are tracked any
from a website in Mobile
to the App Store page.
This counts as a
So we have our app Trip Guide
on our website,
This would be a situation
and the website is
So that's one source
where customers can find your
The other source that
about for customers to
of the App Store are other apps.
So for example, we tweeted
and we included a link
We're trying to promote our
Someone follows that link.
That would be an
where the source was another
Similarly, if customers are
if you're taking advantage
in iOS 10 and customers are
these are other examples
of where the source
for customers to find your app.
And the apps here would
Okay. So those are the
for how customers
Let's take a look at how we plan
to visualize this
First, if you've been
you're probably familiar
This is the list of
From here, you're able to see
which websites are driving
and not only are you able to
that came from these websites,
that across your app units
to understand how many new
You're able to see the sales
to understand how much money
who came from each website.
And you're able to see sessions
from customers who
So we talked about the Twitter
Well, if a customer also is
from Twitter.com in
up under your top websites.
All right.
So that's the list
Let's talk about how we plan
to visualize the list
This is the App List.
From here, you're able to view
to traffic for customers
So we talked -- again,
the Twitter mobile app.
It'll show up here.
Messages, if that's a source
this will show up here as well.
So as you start to
across many different
which channels are the
to compare them not just across
of the measures that
on App Analytics today.
[ Applause ]
So that's the new app sources
Next we're going to
to visualize the three sources
that I talked to
And the first way is
With the Source Overview, we're
into each of these three sources
which of these three
to the most customers
So you can see customers
from browsing the App
from an app refer,
from a web refer,
And you can see a percentage
Right now, we're
but you can also look at
So again, you can
You can look at your sessions
and understand how
that came from each source.
And so, we talked before about
and how you're able to look at
Well, you could also look at
across each of these sources.
So let's do that.
When we left off in the
in the App Store
If we want to view this rate
we can select view by.
And you can see in there we have
We could look at territory
to understand how our App
on each territory.
But for right now, we're
And so, if we select
to see our App Store
of the three sources
and better understand
which source is converting
So that's the new sources
to visualize it in the product.
We're excited to say that this
[ Applause ]
That's what's new
and a little bit
I'm going to hand it
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks, David.
That's what's new
So let's talk about
And to talk about this,
to take a step back and think
So you can have up to
of your devices that give
into what's going on in your app
when they're browsing
And since we give
for each device size, when
that's going to give
As you start to include
that number increases to 30,
and this is before you've even
And we support up to
on iTunes Connect and the
up to 840 different
And we haven't even
With Apple Watch, that
to 980 screenshots,
There's a lot of power in this
because you can actually
for the right device and
But you don't always
and that's what screenshot
and how we can simplify
of screenshots per
[ Applause ]
Yeah, we can clap for this one.
So let's see what this is going
So we're going to start
and the first thing
at the top we just have the
And now the [inaudible] will
screenshots, the 5-1/2 inch.
So we drag those on in.
They fill in.
We have our app preview first,
followed by our five
And if we want to see our other
We can open it up,
that automatically we've begun
to share those screenshots I
down to these smaller sizes.
In fact, if we zoom in,
on the screenshot where
And if we want to change
for these other sizes,
of iTunes Connect
Now let's look into this.
This Media Manager is going
about all those screenshots
across different languages
So you can see at the top we
and they've been shared down
In fact, if we change
for the 5-1/2 inch, it's
that have been shared.
But not every app looks
on the 5-1/2 inch iPhone as
So you may want to
that are more specific
In order to do that,
for our 4.7 inch.
We're going to stop sharing
and that's going to clear
We simply drag in the
and now these screenshots
with those that are smaller.
We're going to find the
from which we can
Now if we want to localize our
we can do the same thing
So let's pick German.
When we look at our German
we're going to see that the
came from my default
in this case my US English.
And the 4.7 are copied from
If I want to upload
I can come here to my
and this is actually
of my screenshots for German.
We're going to favor your
over all else.
So now we can drag in my
and they're going to fill in
but everything down below.
And since my German app
on these different
uncheck the sharing
They get cleared out, and I
And that's it.
And that's how we use
There's two different
We start with iPhone and iPad
across all the different
as the different
But there are some device types
Apple Watch, Apple
You can still use
but in this case, all
across are the localizations.
What if you do want to still
Well, the best way to do that
This is a command line
that lets you upload
all your app previews, as well
You can set your
You can include metadata
your leaderboards, and
And if you want more
you can go to the Resources and
or last year we had a great
out of iTunes Connect, where
to Transporter XML Feed.
So what is screenshot
Quite simply, create only
that you need and share those
And this will be
Now I want to talk
This is a great new
so you can really interact
with the people using
And we wanted to touch
on iTunes Connect to get these
We tried to make it as simple
to what you're already doing.
So the first thing is,
is if you're creating a
then we have a new category
with some more subcategories,
And the second thing is we
for your iMessage apps.
So you can show what it'll be
of messages, and
on the App Store
Now how does this work
iMessage apps behave
in that we have different
so you can show how it works
as across localizations.
And this works the same way
Now if you want to know more
we have two great
If you didn't get a
I encourage you to
And that's what it
to use your iMessage
Now the last thing
about today are the
And those of you who
of "What's New on
know that often we take this
about do they have any
to maybe get your app through
or perhaps some common stumbling
And this year, we're going to
for a couple of reasons.
The first is that App Review
and we've worked really
[ Applause ]
And the second is that
to hopefully make it easier
to the questions, and you
much faster.
So the biggest change in
in which they're worded.
You could call it
Instead of a list of things,
we've really tried to give you
and what are the best ways
to get your app ready
In fact, we've also
for when you're ready to submit
on things you can be thinking
to go when I submit to App
to go on the App Store?
Does your app require a
If that's the case,
that on iTunes Connect before
These guidelines are
so you can understand them,
In fact, how many people
App Guidelines?
So that's not enough.
Those at home can't see this.
It takes about 20 to
and read the guidelines and
The great thing about
in English is it's much
to be human readable in Spanish
And so, we've localized in
to ten different languages.
We've also combined our macOS
You only have one place
to what is appropriate
And lastly, I want to talk
about the organization
We want to try to make
to find answers to questions
and getting it through App
from more of a feature-based
And so, we broke this
And in fact, it kind
of the changes with
We've created a comic book and
into five different
So let's talk about
The first is safety, and
of the people using your app,
for kids, if it's safe for kids.
And also, are the
to be using your
to themselves or to the device?
It's that kind of safety.
The next area is performance.
What kind of hardware
How is it running?
Then we can talk about business.
Is your app appropriate
How does it work
Do you have a alternate
You want to understand what kind
of business models are
You can check with the
Let me talk with design
for the App Store?
Simple, refined,
And last, everybody's
A couple of people
This is where we can talk
intellectual property,
If you want to know when do I
and more information about
And these are our different
Again, instead of reading
out that you need a privacy
or you need a privacy
why don't you instead
out what are the rules
In order to help
to the questions
And those are our
So what's new in iTunes Connect?
Well, we've got the
with subscriptions
We have updates to
with a Resolution
and just released changes
We also talked about the
to App Analytics
Screenshot simplification
to create just the screenshots
and sizes that work for you.
We talked about what
to get your iMessage apps
through iTunes Connects and the
If you have any more questions,
from our sessions URL here
We talked about these
I'm putting them here so
And with that, I hope you've
and a great week, and
Thanks a lot.
[ Applause ]