[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, good morning.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to What's
Signing your apps
We understand this.
And what you need to know is,
in Xcode 8 we've made it really
In fact, it's automatic.
And on the other hand,
over what Xcode does and
you now have that as an option.
And Xcode won't modify
[ Applause ]
Signing identifies you to users.
And they know that when they
and it hasn't been
Signing also prevents
When you register your bundle
another developer team can't
Signing also allows
like iCloud internet payments.
We're going to go over
We're going to start
about the fundamentals
What do you need in
After that, we'll talk
that we've made involving
with signing certificates.
Today, you have to do things
Or revoke and recreate
And that's a thing of the past.
Yeah [applause] you're
And after that, we're
to some new workflows that makes
And we'll finish by talking
with setting up your projects.
Let's talk about
Now when Xcode builds
behind the scenes it uses
Now if you're new, you don't
Xcode does this for
And if you're experienced, you
How does it work?
Well, we use this codesign tool.
And what codesign does is,
and applies a code seal.
And this allows the
that have been made after
So if someone messes with your
Codesign also applies a code
So it can be identified.
And people know where
There are three things that you
The first thing is a
Signing certificates establish
Provisioning profiles
and they grant permissions.
And entitlements declare
Like iCloud or Wallet.
So certificates.
These are issued by Apple.
And this is important because
back to Apple so it
And certificates
You have development
which are for build and run.
And you have distribution
Which are used
for authentication
Or, if these are
it's for distribution to users.
And all signing certificates
This private key has
if you want to sign your apps.
And the private key for
when the certificate
And so it's very important
And it's worth noting here
that Apple never has a
You can't go to the developer
Now the good news
for your development
to worry about this anymore.
And we'll talk more
Provisioning profiles
And in contrast to
about your identity
the profiles are
Profiles allow access to
There's a list of
And at install time, the
of identifiers to check
And if it is, you
Profiles also allow
There's a white list of
And if you want to
it has to be in that list.
Now once again, if you're new,
you don't need to
Xcode handles this for you.
And if you're experienced,
you might be wondering
when you add an entitlement
It's because of that white list.
Speaking of entitlements,
entitlements declare
And fundamentally an
with an associated value.
Like a string or a bowl.
And these are defined
So if your app uses one
and your app extension uses
And Xcode has a dedicated editor
called the Capabilities tab.
And the Capabilities tab will
in the configuration details.
So you don't have to visit
You can do it all
So those are the things you
Now what happens when Xcode
It needs to know which
and which provision and profile.
The way that works is,
And then it looks at the list
And it picks the newest one that
Xcode then looks at
And it picks the newest one
And these two things
The profile is embedded
And the certificate
to apply the code seal.
So that's a quick
of the fundamentals
Let's talk now about the
up new machines with
So who's seen this before?
Yeah. Your account
and Xcode offers to reset it.
So what happens when
Yeah, so what happens
of your current cert
And why is this?
Well, your development
of one signing certificate.
And if you have a single
The cert is created.
You have a private key that's
in your keychain
Now what happens if
Well, to build and sign
you need a signing
And you can either sync that
or Xcode and import the
Or you can create a new
But that first requires
And now you can build on the
on your first Mac anymore.
And it's easy to repeat this
between being able to build on
to build on another one.
And this is really
Well, the good news
you can now have multiple
So -- yeah [applause].
Each of your machines can have
and private key.
So you never have to sync
and you don't have
These changes apply just for
Your distribution certs
that you need to manage.
These are created both through
And these are created
And if you have an old copy
and you create one of these new
They're 100% backwards
So that's what we've changed
about signing certificates
I'd like to turn the stage
who's going to tell you
in Xcode 8 [applause].
&gt;&gt; Good morning everyone.
So Joshua's walked us
that are involved in
You need a signing certificate
that matches your device
But many of you also
Watch apps.
Or embedded frameworks
And each of those brings its
All this can add up to
where signing becomes
And fitting all the pieces
difficult sometimes.
So Xcode for many releases
to help make this easier.
In Xcode 7, the Fix Issue button
detected that something was
Now sometimes clicking on Fix
and you can return to
But a lot of the times it
Or you had to click
And in all cases, Xcode
about what the issue was.
What it did when you
And really, if Xcode knew
why did it need to interrupt
and make you click a button?
Interacting with signing
like you were talking
You couldn't see inside, but you
whenever you got frustrated.
So that didn't work
And in Xcode 8 we've gotten
But we've also done a lot more.
[ Applause ]
We fully redesigned how
There's a brand new
which is much faster and
On top of that, we
and a new user interface
So you can see and manage
in one place.
Then we took a look at
with you about signing issues.
A lot of the error messages
or communicative.
And so we've revised
So that you see much
and actionable information
And for those of you
about what Xcode
when it fixes a signing problem.
We've added new status
So you can always see exactly
So as Joshua mentioned
there are two new ways of
The first one is
Now automatic signing has
and it takes care of all of
You'll never need to create a
And Xcode will do it
So while you're developing
Xcode will keep your
For those of you who
over how your application
you can enable customized
In this mode, Xcode will
of your provisioning profiles.
And it will never change
So let's take a look
in a little bit more detail.
Starting with automatic signing.
When you create a new project,
automatic signing
But if you're an
or you're opening an existing
in the General tab in
All you have to do
And then tell Xcode
From that point on, Xcode will
and signing certificates
And it will even show you
that will be used when
So what sorts of things will
Well, it will create your
So if you're developing
it'll create an iOS
It will also create and update
And it does this
in the background while you're
So you can stay focused
But there are still
where Xcode 8 will prompt you.
In particular, when you connect
One that's not already
on your development team.
Xcode will ask you
Because we know device limits
to have full control over
And finally, if you're
on your behalf in
you can view the signing report
to see exactly what
So let me show you how this
So I'm going to show you
using a brand new iOS app.
I'll hit Next.
And I'll give this a name.
I'm not a great cook,
Now the first thing I'd
to in the new project assistant
When you create your project,
you can immediately choose the
like to use for signing.
And from that point on,
your project will
for automatic signing
So I'll just hit Next.
And I'll create this
So what did Xcode just do?
It created a brand new project,
and automatic signing
When I created the project,
it immediately generated
and a provisioning
I can zoom in on here
If I'd like to change
I can also do that there.
So that's how easy it is to
I can immediately build
I never had to click "Fix Issue"
or configure any
All I did was create a new
But let's make this a
As Joshua mentioned earlier,
to enable platform
like to use, like Cloud Kit.
So let's do that in
We'll go to the Capabilities
And here I see all
that my app can support.
And all I have to do is flip
I'd like to use Cloud Kit
So when I did that, Xcode made
It linked frameworks.
It modified my Entitlement's
But it also communicated
to download a new profile.
And now I can build
And I can immediately
Again, I never had to
or type in any entitlements
Now, I happen to know that
because I'm an Xcode engineer.
But most of you probably aren't.
So if you're curious about what
over to the Reports Navigator.
Where you'll see a brand new
Whenever Xcode resolves a
one of these reports
Let's take a look at
to see what it contains.
And I'll zoom in to
So here we can see Xcode
And I can see more information
that row and expanding it.
So Xcode's telling me my
support iCloud.
And immediately below that,
I can see that it created
So that's how easy it is to
on my behalf whenever
[ Applause ]
Now there are a few more
about automatic signing.
The first one is that it
Distribution is handled
which Joshua will describe
And it's limited to Xcode
These of course are profiles
and it keeps them up-to-date
as you're working
And as a result of these,
without ever having to worry
about your distribution signing
So your distribution certificate
and provisioning profile
by automatic signing.
So automatic signing.
It's been completely
It stays out of your way,
So you can focus on
which is developing your app.
Now let's take a look at
Customized signing.
As you'll recall, this is a
over how your app is signed.
You can enable customized
by unchecking the checkbox
And once you've done that,
Xcode will let you choose
for each of your
This is really handy if you have
Or you need different
and paid versions of your app.
Now you have the
And you can configure this
You don't have to visit the
So this is a really
for configuring your
But we wanted to take
Those of you who have manually
have probably run into
or runtime issues usually
And we wanted Xcode to give
about that before you
So we've added new
within the General tab.
And you can see this right
So it's easier to
Here I can see that my profile
that my app is using.
So I know exactly what
to resolve the problem.
In addition, I can
about my provisioning profile
by clicking the profile
And here I can see
Like when my profile
Which capabilities it supports.
And again, it's easy to
exactly what I need
Now customized signing
to manually created profiles.
These are profiles
on your team has created
And Xcode will never
And you can choose
So as I mentioned, if you want
for some build configurations,
for others, you're
Now this is a really cool thing.
Especially for those of
who have manually chosen
There's a new build setting
in Xcode 8 called
And what this does is it
by name.
Now the reason this is a
to Xcode 8, Xcode would
by their unique ID.
Whenever a new developer
or you added a new device,
you'd need to generate a
And when you did that,
So then you'd need to
Well, now in Xcode 8, since
all you need to do is
and Xcode will automatically
You don't need to update your
[ Applause ]
So let's take a look
at how customized signing
Okay. I'm going to show you
on called, Scrapbook.
And let me zoom in on that.
So Scrapbook is set up
I've chosen different
and paid versions of my app.
And it's really easy
that in the General tab.
This is all I had to do.
Just select different
And since I don't see
I already know I can
and everything will work.
But as in the earlier demo,
let's make this a
I'd like to use the Capabilities
and Push Notifications
Now if you've used the
with a manually specified
you might've noticed that it
signing settings.
Or make changes that
In Xcode 8, the Capabilities
in customized signing mode.
It'll make the local changes
such as updating your
But it won't touch
It'll just tell you what steps
in order to resolve
So let's take a look at that.
I'll click on Capabilities,
and Push Notifications.
Now Xcode is showing me
that it was able to complete.
And little error icons next
to complete on the
I can see more information
I'll zoom in on that.
And if you look at
you can see Xcode's telling
support iCloud and
That's kind of obvious
But it's really clear.
I can tell exactly what I need
Whereas in the past, if I
my app either wouldn't install
And finally, if I want
I can click the Profile
And Xcode will show me more
Like the capabilities that it
So again, it's easy to
to do to fix a problem.
So let's go fix this one.
As I mentioned earlier, in
Xcode won't modify
I need to visit the developer
So I'll open up the
on Certificates,
The first thing I need to
So I'll select App IDs.
And I'll choose the app ID I've
This shows me all the
I'll hit, Edit.
Scroll down and turn on iCloud.
Now this alert message that
that after I update my app ID,
I also need to download
of my provisioning profile.
So I'll just hit, Okay.
And then I'd like to enable
So I'll turn that on.
And again I'm reminded
So I'll click, Okay.
Scroll down and turn
And now I'm done.
The next step is
So I'm going to click
And you'll see the two scrapbook
as invalid.
That's because I've made
But I haven't regenerated
So they're out of date.
Let's update the
I'll select it and click, Edit.
And I can scroll down
I'm not making changes
And I'll click on Generate.
And then download
Now the very last step is I
so that Xcode can use it.
I can do that just by clicking
So what just happened there?
I'll zoom in on that.
When I clicked on the
and immediately updated
So we can see the errors in
of my app have disappeared.
You might also have noticed
that I didn't make any
This is provisioning profile
the scenes.
Once I installed the new
Xcode just started
Now I can build and run
and everything will work.
I can use iCloud and Push.
But it looks like I still need
to update the premium
Does everybody want to see me do
Or we get the idea?
Okay. It's a little bit tedious.
If you were paying
you might have noticed
all those steps I just performed
that Xcode performed for
So that's customized signing.
A brand new mode in Xcode 8,
over how your app is signed.
Xcode won't interfere
or modify your profiles.
But I'd like to encourage
out automatic signing.
It's been completely
and it's provides a really
that I think you'll
Now I'd like to invite
up to show you some best
&gt;&gt; Thanks Itai [applause].
So we just saw the new
that makes it really easy
Now I'd like to talk
for managing signing
The first thing is,
Automatic is designed to make
And it works great
with individual developers,
So you should add all of the
to your development team.
You should use the Capabilities
So you can avoid visiting
to configure things
If you use customized signing,
You have a specific
that is linked to your account.
So if you set this to your
and someone else
they won't be able to build.
So you should leave that
Instead of visiting the
you should use the new UI
in the General tab
This allows you to see more
And it also correctly sets
so you can avoid churn
You should also use
in Customized Signing Mode to
And if you use development
of your project's configuration,
When you get back to your
in the target editor
When it comes to
Xcode has a dedicated
And it's based around
Archives contain a
And it's important to note
that you should use
If you sign your app with
you won't be able to
that you were trying to develop.
So this should be
And when it comes time
when you use the organizer,
Xcode will resign the app using
and provisioning profiles.
And if you clicked
to iTunes connect.
Or if you clicked Export,
that has been distribution
So that's the best practice
We've covered a few
We've talked about the new
that makes it really easy
We've talked about the
which takes a lot of the pain
And we talked about the new
So you can configure your
If that's what you desire.
If you want to learn
If you want to learn more
check out these sessions.
And with that, thank you.
[ Applause ]