[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to What's New in Swift.
Let's start out by
for the Swift 3 release.
Swift was released as an open
ago, and a big part of doing
out a bunch of sources
but to create a fully
that drives the evolution
Swift 3 is the first major
to be a product of that
about how that community has
the evolution process
that crafts the language going
about what that community
Another big aspect for this
to more people.
Today's software
and people are doing a
in different contexts,
for the server, they are
We want Swift to be available
about some great things that
And this is really the
since Swift was ported to Linux.
Now, looking inward at the
through some iterate
over the last two releases,
from developers who are using
from the Swift community
A big thing about Swift
to get those core fundamentals
so we can really build on
And last, and probably the most
to awesomize Swift
All right?
Swift is really intended to
of developers, and in their
amazing things.
That's what we intended
Now, this is a really
and the way we've been directing
to feedback from those
but also how we're
And so I want to
about how we've been
in the last year in our
Now, the big thing here is it's
at Apple; it's just we're
of different ways, whether
we have internal frameworks
Agents and Daemons,
of power the underlying
in the operating system.
And so if you can look, you
you can see things like the New
amount of Swift.
The Console app in Sierra
to the new logging initiatives,
Also with the Agents and
in picture feature in Sierra is
Now, looking to the Tools,
it's using Swift as well.
For example, the new
in Xcode 8 is 100
And the new beautiful
that's 100 percent
So we are really using Swift
And this is really focusing our
of problems, whether
such as memory usage, getting
and so forth, and
that Swift is the right
I want to talk about a
and that's the Dock.
And the Dock is interesting
The first reason is it's a
It's not just the bar at
It's actually a large amount
management experience.
So things like Mission
this is all what we
The second reason why Dock is
been a Swift adopter
It started adopting
So we have two releases
in how it was using Swift.
So a lot of changes happened
First, almost all of Mission
and the accessibility engine
Why did we do this?
We just didn't rewrite code just
The code had kind of grown
as features had been added and
But also some new functionality
and so it was the
you know, to do this rewrite.
Now, what does this look
So to give you an idea, Dock
with tens of thousands of
And between El Capitan and
in the project more
And this actually, because
this replaced a significant
of C and Objective-C code.
And the effects here
because there's some refactoring
and some new features being
about 15 percent less code
and Objective-C code in Swift,
and this is with new features
And the net result is this
smaller in Sierra than
Now, there's a lot you
I think the most important thing
on the Dock love using Swift.
They are not mandated to use it.
They volunteered.
They really just
And their experience
that they can more
that they want to write and
from Swift that gives
that the code they
Let's move on to
If you haven't already,
on the web is swift.org.
And there you can find a variety
to the project, such
to do the most awesome
and be a compiler hacker, you
and find ways to contribute.
And there's other ways.
You know, you can contribute
to take the Swift language?
Now, how we run the
It's meant to be
We want it to be a very
and free, and everyone
in driving the language forward.
And they can see the rationale
This is really important.
And so all changes to language,
who works at Apple or
who is writing apps and you have
to change Swift, it works
And I think this is
And it also means that non-Apple
you know, to commit
and all those repositories.
And so we really wanted
to drive Swift forward.
Third, and I think this
we have a very strong code
and we think it's very important
without feeling that they are
in an unprofessional manner, and
And last, the project is under a
This is really important,
in ways that Apple
This is one of the goals
We really want everyone to be
And there's strong
for the community as well.
So that's why we
Now, you can follow along
Trunk Development for
You can check out the sources.
You can build the compiler.
We also provide downloadable
that you can download from
in Xcode, or you can
And as other platforms
we will provide those
What's really awesome
in an Xcode 8 is we now have
with these downloadable
which is a really
with the language as it evolves.
Also, you no longer have to
to use one of these tool chains,
so this really creates a really
out the latest version of Swift.
Now, all the development
and it's not just one project.
It's actually a family
and you can find a description
but they can roughly
into these three
and its evolution
and a set of Core Libraries.
Let me talk about each.
Now, the Package
when Swift went Open Source.
It's still very early but
There's over 1,000
that use the Package Manager.
So what is this?
It's a cross-platform, Package
packages for Linux, for 0S 10.
The idea is that we want to
to build, a software
And we think this is really
to other contexts, like
It's designed for very
It's like easy to get
easy to articulate
It's just -- the idea is
And we think the Package Manager
and its long-term success
to delivering fantastic
of the Package Manager
Let's talk about
So what are these?
There's a lot of
in macOS, TD OS, and WatchOS.
A lot of these are like part
that we think should
for everyone to get work done.
And so the Core Libraries
implementations that aren't
of some of these core APIs on
that Swift will be ported to, so
like XE tests, so you
a subset of foundation that
and not really tied to Cocoa,
of libdispatch so you can use
Now, the work here is
It launched with
but there's a lot
So for foundation on Linux,
like manipulating URLs, dates,
And we expect this to mature
over time as the community
Now, let's talk about
Now, Chris will talk a lot
about specific changes
I want to talk about
that creates those changes.
This happens out on the
So let's say you have an idea
Like you think there's
and some problem there
of doing core development.
Maybe it was a good design
but it should be revisited.
Or maybe there's something
that would enable
of opportunities for developers.
Doesn't matter.
You start the idea
on a mailing list, kicking it
who have similar
you know, is this a good idea?
What are the pros and cons here?
And once there's
it gets turned into a proposal.
This is just essentially
written in markdown, which
right in a web browser
And here's an example of
and it gets submitted for
Now, you notice in the bottom
number, it says SE0046.
Each proposal is numbered,
you know, the actual
that created change in Swift.
Chris will refer to these
of the talk when he talks about
And these proposals are the way
to the language,
of why we're doing
what the specific change
and once the proposal
the rationale for accepting it.
So a formal review for
by accepting it into
and the review is really just
It's on the mailing list,
to the specific proposal
not just some abstract idea.
And after some period of
which is a small set of
to shepherd the project going
of the community, sees, you
and arbitrates a decision based
And they look at a
How does the current
So does it make sense?
So sometimes proposals are
the way it currently is, this
so go back and consider
Or this will just never
But also the proposals
sometimes with refinements.
And any time it's
a rationale is documented.
So everyone can look
of the language evolution and
and why it was proposed and why
And you can go and see all
to the Swift-evolution
And this is the process
a process driven by everyone.
And to talk more about
I'm going to hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ted.
Well, with everything
unfortunately I didn't have time
to prepare notes
But I printed out
and I thought I'd
Sound good?
[Laughter] Maybe not.
So what are we trying
We said before that we want
to make the core
And that isn't just
That's also the standard
of working with major
and also working with our tools.
And so we'll go through and talk
Now, our number one goal for
And that's a big goal.
That means we want to look at
in your applications
that when Swift 3 comes out,
that's the right
And this is actually
because this isn't just a
or do we use colons,
It's also about real key APIs
to get Swift 3 into that
with it forever and
out from underneath
Now, there's a number of
one of which is that we're
into the Swift-evolution
that Ted discussed before, so
in after Swift 3 really think
Now, I think the biggest aspect,
that affects the
on a daily basis is the APIs.
And so let's dive
and just get a quick
So APIs are an essential
about building its platform in
that you all work
on to make great applications.
And the naming rules, and
into that shape them in
And so with Swift 3, we looked
at what is the best way
Do we want full verbosity?
Do we want full terseness and
And what we found
that really matters is clarity.
And clarity at the point of use.
And so we've really optimized
for capturing the essential
without encoding lots of
Now, let's dive into a couple of
of the thought process
for what this means in practice.
So here are a couple
We will start with array
With Swift 3, this
The verb append, the
Contents of is something
of the parameter you pass in.
Now it's an argument
or gets used at the call site.
This makes it a lot more
Inserted index, this was
but that index didn't add
It was just repeating
that would be better
In foundation, let's
It has a file URL method or
at it, it's not clear
and so now it starts with
Another simple example is URL
it just drops the
because it's not necessary.
And so there's a ton of
that all kind of
and there's a lot more
up right after this at 10:00.
Now, let's talk about
and how they work in Swift.
Because again, that's a key
with look and how you
We've done a number of
so one we call import is member.
Here's a typical core
In Swift 2 it would come in as
Well, this works, but this isn't
with as Swift developers, and so
that allows the API author to
that wraps an attribute
as a method providing the
that you have seen in core
This is something you
Another is generics.
We introduced lightweight
and we used them to import
But a number of frameworks
at Apple adopted lightweight
for example, auto
With Swift 3 we are now able
to import the fully general
as generic types, which
and redundant coding of that
go away.
Let's talk --
[ Applause ]
Let's talk about constants.
A common pattern
of Cocoa APIs are
And we do this because
that we could find to encode an
but there are a lot of
These "enums," in quotes,
which then get imported
and they get used with
This is really unfortunate
one of which is it's
because you can pass
and it won't work.
It's also not great because
and it just doesn't feel
very good direction
With Swift 3 we solved this.
So now an API author can
to their type def and now
of this become strongly
So you'll find with
a commonly used one, that these
user defaults in this
with proper dot syntax.
And the great thing about this
[ Applause ]
So there are a ton
of improvements throughout
and other features that you
There are a number of
Let's dive into the
So with these changes
and looked at parameter labels.
And as a quick refresher, if you
you'd call it and
out of the three parameters.
Why is that?
Well, the answer is that we were
and design patterns and
with Cocoa and the Cocoa
But of course we've just
works in Swift, and so now we're
to all the parameters,
which makes the language a lot
[ Applause ]
Let's talk about generics.
So the Swift generic
is really beautiful
It allows you to capture the key
in a very concise
Unfortunately, though,
into more advanced use cases,
you start adding
and the generic constraints are
of the function in this
down the primary signature
and it makes it a lot
With Swift 3, we've extended
so now your signature is
to see it and the constraints
[ Applause ]
Let's talk about unused results.
So here's a simple function.
It just adds one to a
With Swift 2, you
about this code even though
Maybe you forgot to
Maybe you're just calling it
Right? So with Swift 3 you
It's safe.
This is great.
And this is also really good
for more complicated
So not all functions
in the functional sense.
Some of them actually
We live in the real world.
And so you may be wondering,
maybe I'm calling this
Well, that's okay, because you
which tells the compiler
to maintain your code that
that this returned something
and you explicitly don't
Now, not all functions
Some functions, which are
have a side effect as
and so the return value
that often you don't care about.
And so in those exceptional
you can actually use an
I know that this return
never produce a warning
which is a nice system.
So let's talk about the most
features that go away.
And you may be saying why
But we really want Swift
And Swift 3 is the sum
and many of the pieces were put
into Swift before we really knew
into and where we
And so what we did was we went
of the features in the language,
no matter when they
and asked a basic question.
If this feature were not already
And for some features,
and so we're taking them away.
And this is a great way,
because it simplifies the
Now, some of these I realize may
The great thing about
that we debated these
Each of these has a proposal
and if you really want to go
of emails on each of these,
to the mailing list archive
I think that pretty
of every perspective was
on these issues.
So now there are a bunch
to language as well, and I
of them, but we have things
We have type safe selector
We have new build
to power matching, a
and you can read them about
or in the extra release notes.
Now another aspect of the
about syntax, right?
And I think we all love,
the basic syntactic
I think it's one of the things
because it feels familiar and
But unfortunately,
in Swift were considered
of the syntactic
and so we went back,
and repainted everything
of your favorite color
of the weird corner cases,
if they are inconsistent with
it makes them even harder to
in the Swift because
And so we went back and
and we really want
so it's right for the long time.
So that's a brief overview
I want to dive a little
about the type system.
First of all, what
The type system in Swift works
to define how types work,
and the compiler
to prove your code is correct
as well as infer things that
because it's supposed
For example, what
Swift 3, we wanted to
make it more consistent,
to define away common types
into that were surprising
So let's talk about a
First is unsafe pointer, right?
So I don't know if you realize
in Swift 2 assign nil
You can test it directly
and you can actually
without having any idea
This is really inconsistent
and it makes unsafe
Well, with Swift 3, now
so you use optionals, just like
You get to use if let to safely
and you even get all the
optionals, which makes
more predictably.
Speaking of optionals,
of the language is
Implicitly unwrapped optionals
of the language, particularly
with two-phase initialization
that hasn't been
Now, here's an overly simplified
implicitly unwrapped
but this applies more
of different types of things.
Now, the basic way
that implicitly unwrapped
I think, was understandable
In the case of X, for
to force unwrap that implicitly
to do the addition,
In the case of Y, well,
and so if just kind
down through the code.
Well, this propagation was
It also was surprising because
us to scratch our heads about
Because you don't even know you
optional in many cases.
So here, I have an int and an
Does that implicitly
Do I get an array of any?
Do I get an array of optional?
What is going on?
Well, you never really
to compile your code and you
and this is not the effect
So implicitly unwrapped
as a concept, so we kept it,
to have a new, simpler model.
The model is now very local.
For any use of an
if the value can be used
That's the safe thing.
We don't want to be
where you don't expect it.
However, if the compiler
for type checking
So let's go through
Here, we have X, the
to do the addition,
This is the key aspect of what
optionals different
Why? Well, here the compiler
as an optional, and
of propagating the
maybe deep down through your
it turns into a strong optional,
about it and know
This also leads to more
with the array, because now, of
as a strong optional,
And if you actually
well, that's okay too.
You can explicitly
with the exclamation mark, and
about that, and your
So that's my quick tour of some
on with the type system.
Let's talk about the
The big news in the standard
collection indexing model.
And what does that mean?
Well, maybe you've
Maybe not.
There are a lot of great
The difference here
And previously in Swift 2, you'd
like Successor, to
In Swift 3, the model is
instead of the index
the collection moves
And why would we do this?
Well, there's a number of
First of all, we get to
A bunch of types just
Even better, common kinds of
You can now have an
up to the maximum element, which
which nobody expected.
We also think this is going
because we can get rid
with many common collections.
So we are pretty
Let's talk about numerics.
We have a new floating point
which help define
to write generic algorithms
of FloatingPoint types.
Even better, if you are a
and you understand IEEE
and not most people,
of great low level operations,
out of the whatever, some really
[Laughter] So I don't really
I think it's really
and people who do
I do understand things like
And in Swift 2 we always
and it really irritated me
because it was always the
to cast it, and it always
Well, now, despite all
in addition to all that IEEE
like Pi on all the
And Swift often has
And the other great
that if you have typed
here we're returning a CGFloat,
you can use CGFloat.Pi, but
compiler to infer that
It leads to a really
[ Applause ]
So as with the language,
of great improvements
Some of these can really effect
and really improve the
so I highly recommend sticking
which will dive into
So this was a quick tour of the
how Cocoa works in Swift, but
and the tools work together.
So to talk about that, I'd
Ewa?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Chris.
Good morning, everybody.
Let's talk about Tools, and
than what the tools can
As you can see, we've been
but let's talk about
We revamped the dictionary
and we also really focused
on optimizing the string hashing
and we see some really
in our micro benchmarks
that use strings
We also added stack promotion
for class instances array
from the heap, which is really
and we see some really
when our tests take
Also, as I already
on our string hashing
in a dramatic way in our tests
and suffixes of strings, like
Next, I want to talk to you
This is a feature we
but I want to just remind you
When you look at this diagram,
you can see a really
one file in, one file out.
With whole module optimization,
of compilation from one
And this is really great because
information to write new,
and to make your
So we think this
from our internal benchmarking,
on by default for
And existing projects will get
as it suggests, we think you
There's a big caveat,
As you look in this
that the compiler is
And as you would expect, your
To offset this cost, we have
and it's caching
to avoid reoptimization
So the result of all this is
that although the first time
it will take a longer
incremental compilations
Moving on to code size,
we did a lot of work
and we have some nice results.
DemoBots is a sample app that
at Apple.com, and
in its application binary
since Swift 2.2, so that's
Well, that's all I have
but there's lots more
So my favorite feature in
navigation of Swift code because
every day in development.
Let's take a look at an example.
So here's an example where we
and then just go Sort.
What do you think happens
and jump to a declaration?
In Xcode 7.1, you take
in a synthesized header
Like what is this?
It's an extension to
the sort here return self
and the only reference
So it doesn't make very much
So in Xcode 8, we're
and now you see there's
like you would expect and
to sorted in Xcode 8, now
So this really improves how
in Xcode and its readability.
It's much more logical.
Also, in the standard library,
we added groupings
For example, array is
And speaking of the standard
of new documentation for you.
And again, the protocols
so you can logically
in the synthesized interfaces.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
I think you're going to
Yeah. So how many people
Probably lots of people.
So, of course, we have the
but this year you get to choose.
You get to choose
[ Applause ]
If you're not quite
Swift 2.3 is just Swift 2.2 that
and we will be accepting
both with Swift 3 and 2.3,
that there are some very key
on Swift 3, like
and the new features as
Swift 2.3 is a really
to allow you the flexibility
to schedule time to
So please schedule it today.
Yeah. If you are
I have a little tip for you.
Here is a sample.
It's a little code snippet from
And when you run the
it will suggest you add an
because the core
with additional ability editing.
Now this code compiles both
but if you have a little
you could conditionally
with a pound FL statement here.
So that's just a little tip.
And when you are ready, when you
the migrator is there for you.
Just go to Edit, Convert
and you are taken through the
So it's easy.
Convert to Swift 3
So that's all I have
And just to recap,
about how Swift 3
down the fundamentals.
And we're doing all this
as Ted described, and you can
in the evolution process.
And you can see we've got
as well.
So there's lots more
There is just the beginning.
And we have lots of
I want to highlight one,
which is the Swift
It's in this room right
And have an awesome
Thank you.
[ Applause ]