[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Welcome. So, I'm Doug Gregor.
I'm here with my
to talk about design.
Because good design
And good API design helps
concise and beautiful in Swift.
And that's every bit as true
for a million other
for yourself inside
Because good design
So, we're going to be talking
about the Swift API
These are new guidelines we're
We're going to talk about
these guidelines.
Talk through some of them
to build great Swift APIs.
Now, then we're going to talk
Which is what we like
of these guidelines to all of
Swift Standard Library.
Cocoa and Cocoa Touch APIs.
Now, this Grand Renaming
to affect a lot of your code.
Pretty much all the
in Swift 2 is going to change
&gt;&gt; Whooh!
&gt;&gt; Yes!
[ Applause ]
So, we're going to talk through
And how to deal with it.
And starting thinking
Finally, we're going to talk
that we have for mapping
into beautiful Swift APIs.
That's a whole lot
The biggest question
about the guidelines is why?
Why, after two years of working
with Swift are we changing
with on a daily basis?
And the answer comes down to
Because every programing
distinctive character.
It has its own syntactic feel.
But it's more than the syntax.
It's also the kinds of tradeoffs
that that language
Does it skew toward
Do you care about some
or something that is
You take a look at Swift code,
And you can see Swift
about certain things here.
It uses trailing closures.
So the control flow works
with your libraries
It has optionals, so you have
to consider the possibility
You can't just ignore that
And so, when you're working
But it's not just the
It's really the APIs you
And these APIs have to meld with
So you get a consistent,
with beautiful Swift code.
Now, these are some Cocoa
And these APIs were
on the coding guidelines
You may have read these before.
I hope you have.
They espouse clarity
in the design of APIs.
And we've been applying these to
over more than a decade, all
and Cocoa Touch platforms.
And these wonderful APIs we use.
Now, these guidelines
for a different language
And so, when you bring all of
for Objective-C into
they seemed a little
They feel a bit not-Swifty.
What's that even mean?
Not Swifty?
You hear it a lot.
But in essence, this is why
as a platform that
of developers are using, is
Because we have experience
to understand what works
And so we set off to design the
to codify what it is
and help everyone build more
within this language
Now, in the lower
That's the Swift
that contains all of the
You'll see these proposal
Again, you can go
look up this proposal number
about that particular change
But for now, let's talk about
The main principles of the
clarity at the point of use.
Where your API shows up
And we love concise code.
But the clarity is the
It's more important
That said, concise code
Swift code does tend
We can feel it when we
And we see it in actual
that have been ported into
But that comes from using
Let's dive into these
and look at some APIs.
So, we're going to
So why focus on the use sites?
Well, for one, it's just
You're going to write
People will look at that
at the documentation for
But the vast majority of
the number of times it's seen,
of a whole lot of other code.
And when you're in that
of this extra rich
You have the local variables,
You have uses of related APIs.
And so the goal of
to stand up and say, "Hello!
I'm here and I have
The goal of your API is to fit
so that the end result
Now, when you're focusing on
to optimize for bad code.
It is absolutely true that
like A and B and C
And this code is
You can't fix this bad
All you can do is make other
So focus on proper use cases.
Focus on the beautiful code
Let's actually look at
And so we're going
that is removing an
We're going to start by
Sounds good.
But I've made my first mistake.
This is not a use case.
This is just a name
So, let's bring up a use case
Don't ask why.
He knows. So, remove item
Now, you'll notice that
in this use case
to what the argument is.
They're trying to
There's the word item
And then there's
which is some local
Of these two, the variable ted
of what the argument is.
It's in context.
As you're reading this call
that local variable is.
It means something.
It has a strong type.
So maybe the problem
that the word item isn't
Maybe we'd feel a little
if it were called removeObject.
Well, that's probably not right,
because we're probably using
So it's just actively wrong.
We could say, hmm,
Okay. Collections in Swift
But, it's not helping us any.
And moreover, if we
down different use cases,
it might actually
Here I want to remove
from a list of organic
That's misleading.
It's wrong.
Caffeine is not an element.
It's a compound made
So, our attempt at using
to describe the argument
to less clear use cases.
Okay. So maybe the problem
to get these innocuous sort
and we should be
Remove person ted from
It's a little awkward
I wouldn't say that.
I would just say, remove(ted).
But moreover, if I do this, if
for this generic API,
to be specific everywhere.
And now there's one conceptual
from a collection has
source base.
That makes it harder
It's harder to recognize
about the same thing
So, the Swift API Design
Omit needless words.
If a word is not
of the use site,
So we can just say, remove(ted)
It reads really nicely.
Now, one of the reasons this
that it has a strong static
that you don't write
interpret it in the wrong way.
And so the strong static
that the argument you passed
of the corresponding collection.
If you were to do
like for example, try to
of friends, you're going
from the compiler telling you
So, we've talked about
And we've eliminated a bunch
in the mind that what we're
That's not true.
We want clear code.
But, clear code has to hit
of spectrum of terseness
And if you think about what is
when you have extra information
And verbose code
Because what is your mind
through this verbose code?
It's trying to filter out
all the things you don't need
to find the actual
Now, the other end of the
If you have code
then you're missing critical
to understand that code.
A sign that this is happening,
that you've made
is when you're reading code
to the API documentation
because the APIs themselves
So we're looking for this
where you get clear
So all of the information you
and how they work is there in
This is actually a principle
So I'm going to put up
And in this bunch of code we
not needed in Swift.
That verbosity is all of these
These aren't adding
You can get a sense of
by reading the APIs.
And indeed, in Swift you
this way.
You would probably align
and let the static type
for you leading to
that you can still read
Now of course, types
And the types are there.
And if you need reassurance
if it'd help your
the answer is just an option
So let's look at another
about when a word
to help describe an argument.
We'll take this little API
at some particular point
And so we write out a use case.
Always start with the use case.
And think about the words
So in the first case we have
to this view argument that
Is child adding something?
Well, we know from
that sidebar is going to
But this word child
of this parameter
It's stating that this argument
It's establishing hierarchy.
That's really important
for understanding
Now, in the second argument, we
What's origin going to be?
Well, it's going
This API is going
And you can't provide anything
So this word, it's
It's just restating
in the strong static type
by the Swift language.
So take it away.
You don't need it.
And now notice what the
If we read it out, you add the
It reads grammatically.
All right?
This is one of the principles
of this particular API
that we really want the use
And we had this for our
from our list of friends.
Now, let's look at
So this is removing
If we look at, say, the
in a particular position.
Read it out.
Remove position of former
It's not right.
This isn't the collection
This is a collection of people.
To actually make this read
Let's read this out remove at
Notice how we've clarified the
in this first argument label
of the argument to the method.
This brings us to naming
So, in Swift, a function
of so-called base name,
of these APIs, as well as all
of the argument labels
And so these two related APIs,
of remove because they're in
that remove something
But their argument
because they do different
One removes an element
The other one removes
on its position in the sequence.
So slightly different
Now, you can overload
And if two APIs that share
But you should only do this
when the APIs have
So it's fine to overload
with no argument label
or a string to some text.
Because fundamentally these
They're just overloaded on
Now, when you're coming up with
you want that use case
And that includes the base
as the argument label.
So my first API here
Notice how that reads well.
Now, inside that API we
So it's a little bit of
But essentially it's withLabel.
And it describes the
to the actual operation
And so when you have one of
put it on the first
to describe the first argument.
You also use first
if you essentially can't
because it would be misleading
to have the first
And so here we have
And we say dismiss(true).
What is that?
I can't banish a Boolean
And so to make this
I need to put an
Dismiss the viewController.
And it's animated.
Animated is true.
And so this is extra
The first argument label breaks
and it's clear that what
view controller.
There are a couple of
about on Swift.org.
But essentially you still will
in some cases.
And these are cases where
to just have the argument
at the start index of friends.
That reads well.
We don't need a first argument
and so we leave it out.
Okay. Let's talk
about naming before we move on.
So, when you name a method, name
So, use English verbs, commands,
to tell the receiver
So here we might say, okay, we
Reverse it.
A viewController, present it.
Organic compounds, append to it.
Right? These are actions taken.
We name based on
Now, when we have methods whose
to return some value
Describe the thing
And so here we can ask for the
or the suffix of
Now, when you're
it's sometimes the case that
and a non-mutating form of
And here what we like to call --
we apply what we like
And so this follows
And essentially you
And so here we have
You're commanding X
Now, for the more
we use the "ed" rule.
So we ask for X reversed.
All right?
Where we're describing what the
And that corresponds
Now, when the "ed"
the "ing" rule generally does.
This is usually when we
So we have a document directory.
We can append a path
That's mutating.
We told it to append this.
Now we have the non-mutating
Give me the document directory
path component.
So these rules, and many, many
as part of the API Design
Highly recommend that
to apply them to your own APIs.
But of course, these guidelines,
they're not interesting
widely applied.
And this is why we set
Which is the application
to the Swift Standard
and Cocoa Touch APIs as well as
like Core Graphics,
They're used all the time to
to be beautiful in Swift.
I talked a little bit about the
So, this is a little screen shot
of a small Swift app called
for a couple years.
It's one of the sample
when it's being migrated
You can notice there's a whole
Basically every Swift file in
by the transition from
And if you're looking at some
and the right panes here,
of these Cocoa API
Okay? So, there's a
We'll talk about that.
But really what's interesting is
that these Cocoa APIs
for a very long time,
but now a given API has
Has one name that's
and one name that's
As a Swift programmer, most of
You can entirely work
Use your generated
everything will show
And that's all you'll deal with.
However, there are times
with the system where
Objective-C name.
For example, if you're
And so, here we actually need
to provide a selector
And we have this string literal.
What do we write here?
I don't know.
You can look at the
Maybe ask your Swift compiler
You can come up with the answer.
That's fine.
But, please don't do this.
Because this is a
between this string literal,
and the method above that
This is why in Swift 2.2
#selector is a very
It's an expression.
It takes in the name
and produces the Objective-C
You don't have to care what
The compiler will get it right.
And the great thing
is that Swift makes sure
Makes sure it's exposed
and computes the correct name.
And of course, this is
Works with code completion.
So it's a much nicer
That means you don't
about the Objective-C names.
In Swift 3 we've extended this
and setters of properties.
So we round out the set
of Objective-C method names
So this is very easy to use.
You just pass in the argument
to get the setter or
And then refer to an
And of course, the
that that property exists, that
and get the right
Now, selectors aren't
of stringly type thing
about Objective-C method names.
We also have Key Paths,
to get right when
as string literals
And so, in Swift 3 we're
[ Applause ]
#keyPath does exactly
You get to refer to a dotted
Compiler validates that these
properties, gets
And then produces the
down into the frameworks.
And so between #selector
you can essentially not worry
You just write everything
and you stay in that
You don't have to
Now, there are cases
about what the Objective-C
You may have a mixed project
that needs to refer to the
And names like this
for just don't feel right
So for these cases, you can
And in parentheses put the exact
And that will be reflected in
of the metadata and everything
over the Objective-C
of your Swift code actually
And of course, this @objc with
it works for methods,
Anything that can be exposed
you can control the name here.
So you get nice Objective-C
Okay. There's a lot of
The Swift language itself
about the Objective-C names,
and yet it gives you the
when you do care about
The tools are here to help you.
So the Swift 3 migrator is going
to the Swift 3 names
It's a lot of change.
But these tools will help
and get working with Swift 3.
Now, the Swift 3
But it can't migrate
Certainly can't migrate
and paste from stack overflow.
So, the Swift compiler's
The Swift compiler, it knows
of these APIs as well
So if you write or paste
it'll recognize the old API
with Fix-its to update your code
Additionally, we've put
when you're implementing
And so this is great when
You make some minor
of that delegate method
Now you'll get a warning with
so you can be sure that your
All right.
Now I'd like to turn things
who's going to talk
and Objective-C APIs into Swift.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So that's a lot about Swift.
But what if you're an
or are working with
All of your Objective-C
They always have been.
But as Doug explained,
for a different language.
They are increasingly starting
to feel a little bit
So today I'm going to show
of the situation and give
they deserve.
I'm going to start with
as they were imported
Here we have two methods;
and revertToContentsOfURL.
But these don't really express
that Doug outlined.
There's a lot of
We're not making effective use
first argument labels.
So I'm going to start with what
in the Swift 3 compiler.
Swift 3 has improvements to how
The Swift compiler will
and use grammatical
to infer first parameter labels.
The Swift compiler will
to eliminate redundant
The compiler can even
for common Objective-C idioms
Or option sets.
And also, there are
such as URL that
So when we import, we
To find out more about
What's New in Foundation
So, automatic inference
but fundamentally it's
The compiler, it
It doesn't know your intent.
And every now and then you
So we've extended NS Swift Name.
Now, NS Swift Name has
But in Swift 3 we support
A compound name is a base
So in this case, we
They're performing semantically
But they differ basically in
And so we import them with the
but we say we want it equal
or equal to this anchor.
Now, method names will get you
but this doesn't
Here I have some simple code
Gregorian calendar.
But if you look at this, this
especially
which is a plain
Plain string global variables,
that's not really
This is what we jokingly refer
And the fact that this
that kind of allows
And yes, I know this
and a developer would
But the fact that a user of this
and it's not a valid
that's an unnecessary
So, why is this API like this?
Well, we all know why
It came from Objective-C.
But the fact that this
that's an implementation detail.
And that implementation
And at Apple, we're
To figure out what's
let's see how this Objective-C
Our global variable comes in as
But other than the name
nothing really tells you
that this a very specific string
Now, we could try
and hint at our intent.
But a typedef, it's
It's a new name for an old type.
And so that doesn't really
So, how will this API
to design this fresh in Swift 3?
Well, we'd probably make a
to get some strong typing.
And these global
those would instead
So in Swift 3 we introduced
for this use case.
You can access this attribute
through NS Extensible
to tell the Swift compiler
to make a new wrapper
You can just add
And the importer will create
And any global variables of
automatically as static
Now, we chose a struct here
That is, other modules may
And if they do, they will also
on an extension of this struct.
Now, behind the scenes the Swift
to the underlying stored value,
meaning that there's no
or intermediaries involved.
So, let's focus on the use site.
Because good API design is
Before and after.
And because the type
we can even just say .gregorian.
[ Applause ]
I'll kick it off by
Also, in Swift 3 NSCalendar,
This is a little fix up.
So, we have method
What else do we have?
Well, we have an elephant.
That is, we have an
And we've been pretending
But it's always been there.
And it's C.
Now, with Objective-C, the APIs
so when we import them we
add a few types.
It's relatively straightforward.
But what about C?
I'm going to focus
Now, Core Graphics is a
by pretty much every
It is a powerful API.
But it looks and
Let's start with some code.
I have two functions here.
The first one transforms a --
takes a transform and rotates
And the second function
Now, neither of these
and the details don't matter.
But I just want to look
How does this feel?
Go ahead and take a moment.
So, if you notice, this
with global variables
And we don't really like
Or global variables, of course.
So, how could we
and make it look Swifty?
How can we make it feel Swifty?
Well, for that, we revisit
You can use NS Swift
to import globals
Let me start with
to show you what I mean.
Here at the top I have
Below that the generated
And underneath that
And we will be focusing
and improving the
So we add NS Swift Name and we
to tell the Swift compiler that
as the static property
And of course, the Swift use
nested property.
[ Applause ]
And of course, if the
users can even omit the CGColor.
Now Core Graphics has a lot
to create all different kinds
That's
as well
as CGAffineTransformMakeRotation
But in Swift we prefer
So we use TypeName.Init and
to tell the Swift compiler
that this should really
And we use argument
to clarify the roles
You can also import
Use the special argument
to tell the Swift
to plug the reference
And so now CGContextFillPath is
And of course, the
it just calls it like a method.
[ Applause ]
And the compiler will take
and plug it into the appropriate
by the special argument
We can get more complicated.
You can prefix a Swift name
to tell the compiler
as a computed property
Here ArtistGetName,
ArtistSetName are now just
for the computed
Let's focus in the use site
because good API design is
Before, we would use
to remember the former
and a different global
But now, our users can use the
In all cases, this is
That is, when the compiler
directly to the corresponding
without calling any wrappers
You can also use NS Swift
Remember earlier when we created
Well, you can use typeName.
-- well member name --
nest a type name in
So in this case we get
Now, we love the
We love it so much that we went
[ Laughter &amp; Applause ]
Don't clap for this.
And we applied it
in Core Graphics alone, 600.
Now you can clap.
[ Applause ]
That's a lot of bananas.
So, let's revisit
Before, our global variable,
which is painfully
And because the type
we can even omit the type name.
Our global functions
[ Applause ]
Actually, now that
I think this code
We don't need that
And so now this reads --
[ Applause ]
And so now this reads
We take a transform.
We translate it.
We rotate it.
And we translate it back.
Very straightforward.
Moving on.
CGColorCreateGenericRGB as
many different ways
these are now initializers
And of course --
and of course CGContextAddPath,
of the other crazy redundant
[ Applause ]
We hope you enjoy
So, to summarize, first we
Guidelines in Swift.
Good API design is always
Second, we looked at
This is also known as, "Oh, no!
Everything's different."
But don't panic.
It's okay.
The names are better.
The code is clearer.
And you have the
And last, we looked at
in the Swift compiler so
Great Renaming.
For more information, visit
at developer.apple.com and check
of the open source Swift
of the Swift evolution.
I also showed you Core Graphics.
But Grand Central Dispatch has
many of these same
So, Friday, check out
with Grand Central
Friday.
[ Applause ]