[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, and welcome to
I'm Dave Addey, and together
and Alex, I'd like to
of the Swift Programming
In the next 60 minutes you'll
to be able to read
to start writing it, too.
So let's start by taking a
of the language, and here's
I've written a constant,
it's called language,
And this colon in the middle,
this means is of type.
So language is of type string,
of Swift, using a string
Let's make a few more.
Let's have an integer
We'll that to 2014.
And a Boolean called isAwesome.
And we'll set that to true.
Now, you might notice that none
The language's name
nor is the year it
And two years on,
so that can probably
And this is the general
If something doesn't
we declare it as a constant.
Now, you might also
Constants and variables tend to
and types, such as String, Ints
Now, if we look at the
it's pretty obvious, actually,
an integer and a Boolean,
and where this is the case
We don't actually need
So you still get things
but you don't have to
So that's some constants.
What about variables?
Things do sometimes
So here's a variable
and it's for the
This has changed.
So let's bring it
Now, if I try to do
if I try to set isAwesome to
that it was an error,
So a common thing to want
to build strings
We could do this by
as shown here, but Swift
known as string interpolation,
And we can put strings and other
by wrapping them in parentheses
Here we're making the
We're not just limited
We can add other values as well,
such as integers here
And we could even add
We can add year +
that would work for
Now, strings in Swift are
They're just as happy
with dog, cows or with flags.
And the same also
and variables you create.
You can use pretty much
of your constants and variables.
Talking of [inaudible]
Swift does all the hard work
to be an individual character,
regardless of how your string
or how it appears on screen.
So here I have a
You might think that this
D, O, G, ?, !, dog face.
But you would be wrong.
There are five characters
This is a special character
mark, which is really,
really good for expressing
Now, if you don't believe me,
Every string has a
It gives us a collection of
and we can access the count
to see how many there are.
If we pass that to
we find out that we do,
But if you still don't
over each of those characters
and print each one of
and you can see we do,
D, O, G, ?!
and dog face.
Now, in addition to all of these
some built-in collections.
We have array and dictionary.
You might know dictionary
or map table from
And the easiest way
or a dictionary is
This is an array literal
on the outside and
Here we have an array of
Dictionaries look very similar.
Their keys and values are
Here we have a dictionary whose
and whose values are integers.
Now, you might notice from
that they're all the same
It wouldn't make sense to insert
to have an integer or
That would be just weird.
For names we always
and in Swift we can
We can say we want an array
as we get anything out of it,
we can do string
So this is how we write that.
This is how we write
a string with square
But as we saw earlier
from the right hand side
Swift works it out for us,
We actually don't need
It's clear we want
The same goes for
Here it's clear we want string
so Swift can infer
but everything is
Swift has all of the loops you
We have a while loop that checks
executing its body.
And a repeat-while loop,
which executes its body once
to see if it should continue.
And as we saw earlier, we have
to iterate over the
But that's not the only thing
We can use it to
Here we have a range that
and includes most of those
to print five entries
We write this as 1...5.
That is called a closed range
because it includes
However, sometimes it's useful
up to one less than
Here's an example of
I have an array of
to print the first five.
Now, because array
I actually want indices
So for that we can use the
..&lt; because it runs the one less
than the final number,
We can use a for-in
Here we're printing
of the names in our array.
And we can also use
Now, note here that we're
and the value, the name and
And this is an example of
which lets you combine those
and use them at the same time.
And we'll see another
And it makes for
when iterating over
So how would we modify
Well, here's my packing
I've declared it as a
but I've included the
Now, at WWDC 2014 I
and it was a nightmare, so I'm
So let's check that
in this array is
After 2014, if I put it on
We do this using a subscript,
writing an index inside square
and if we print this value,
I have indeed remembered
Socks and shoes will
for a week of the conference.
I'll need more things.
So let's append a new item.
Let's append some trousers
which we do using
But there's a problem here.
The conference is in America and
they call them pants,
to cause all kinds of confusion.
So let's change a
Let's change this
Again, we use a subscript
to change the item in index two.
Jeans are called the
so this shouldn't
Now, the conference
where it is always
so let's add a few more items.
Let's add some shorts, some
We can do this using the append
in a compatible array,
and they all get
That said, whilst the
it's in San Francisco, where
So maybe let's change those
with a hoodie and
We can do this by passing
And note that we're changing
this is still perfectly
So what about a dictionary?
Let's modify a dictionary.
Well, here I have my ages
I'd like to add somebody else
by adding a value for a key
a subscript.
Here I've added Justyn.
But thinking about it, it was
so this value is now incorrect.
I need to update it, which I
I just assign a different
and now my dictionary's correct.
What if I want to retrieve
What if I want to see if we have
or perhaps for Daniel?
Well, there might be a value in
but there might not, and we
and this is a great use case
for a Swift feature
If we tried this for Amy,
we might expect a
But if we tried it for Daryl,
There's no value here for Daryl.
Think of it like this.
There either is a value in the
that's for Amy, or there's
as in the case of Daryl.
So what we have here
which we write as
And the question mark means
but there might not.
Now, we can check to
by comparing it against nil.
Nil is just a special way,
a shorthand way of
If we try this for
we'd print the message.
Age not found.
If we try this for Amy,
so it doesn't equal nil and
Typically, however, we don't
We actually want to
and Swift has a really good
which we write as if let.
Now, this says here the
for Amy, let a new constant
And then we can use that
And note that we use it
It's not optional anymore.
The if statements checks
and gives us back
that we can do integer
So we've seen a few
Here's another that
There are two things to
Firstly, we don't
around the conditions so we can
And secondly, we do add
of the statement to make
of code are going to be run.
In addition to if, we also
and this is useful for
more powerful matches.
This switches over the
or a variable and matches
So, for example, we can have
where the value is
to print a simple happy
We can also match
Here matching any value that
And we can match more complex
which says that a temporary
value that we're
check if it will divide
use it to print a
for anyone who's
or some other significant age.
But there's a problem with
What would happen if we wanted
who was 41, or 97 or 56?
Well, they wouldn't
and that seems really
especially on their birthday.
Frankly, Swift helps
Swift makes sure that every
that you don't accidentally
of the cases that
And in this case we can
which catches every other case
and just says, Happy
Here's another switch statement.
This one takes a string value,
that indicates whether that
and we'll use both of these
out an appropriate message to
to log into a restricted area.
And to do this we can
at the same time using a tuple,
So this means we can
really interesting use cases,
some really interesting
We can have the case where
and the password is
to welcome back our
Now, in the case of a guest we
into the restricted area even
and so we can ignore
by writing an underscore,
and this means just match
For all other users we actually
name is.
We just care about the password.
So we can ignore the user
we've switched on
with the password's validity.
To do this we create a temporary
and we then use the ternary
that's the question
to say if it's valid,
otherwise, use this message.
So let's run that through
If we take our administrator,
they get a special administrator
If we try this for
even though their password is
you can't come in message.
If we try it for Bob,
he gets the welcome
But if his password is not
Now, there is one
about this switch statement,
and that's that it doesn't
And the reason it doesn't
It's already complete.
If we take a look at
this actually covers all
that we haven't already
and so the switch
without needing a default.
So those are some of the
I'd now like to hand over to my
to functions and
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thanks, Dave, as I was saying.
Let's get started by looking
at how you define a
You define a function
and you implement it
Here we've defined a simple
that prints a message
And you call this message
by writing its name,
followed by an empty
So let's add a parameter
that indicates whether the
You write the parameter's
and the parameter's
when you declare a
Here we've added a
which is of type Bool.
And when you call the function,
the parameter's name
for the argument you pass in.
Labeling your arguments
and makes the purpose or
In this case, if you left
someone reading your
that true just indicated whether
at all.
So you can shout a message,
to send the message to.
Let's add another parameter
to someone in particular.
So here we've added a
which is of type string,
and we've included
in our message using
And now when you call the
in the recipient's name.
Now, although the message
it doesn't read very
sendMessage recipient
When you call a function, you
In this case you'd like it to
to Morgan, which forms a
And you could do this
of the parameter, which
of the argument label, and this
better when you call it,
but it doesn't work so well
Inside the body you really
not a preposition, hey
But sometimes there
that works well both inside the
when you call the function.
In Swift you don't have
When a parameter's name
for the argument
you can explicitly provide
You write the explicit
of the parameter's name.
Here we've added to as an
in addition to the recipient
that you can use to when
sendMessage to Morgan, and you
the body of the function.
Let's add one more
which lets you provide a custom
Here we've added a message
Now when you call the function,
you can pass on your
Now, once again, this
but it doesn't read
sendMessage message
The message label isn't
of the first argument
from the base name of the
Here the argument label actually
In the cases like these, you
of the parameter's name.
And this means that you don't
when you call the function.
And now our function reads
sendMessage, See you
Now, it's not very often that
so we usually pass in
and in Swift you can actually
in the declaration
Whenever a parameter has a
you can provide that value as
by assigning a default
right after the type
and now when you call the
out the corresponding argument
And when you're deciding
to use an explicit argument
to provide default
remember that functions
but they're used repeatedly.
So the most important thing is
and concisely when it's called.
Now, to learn much
of things you should consider
when you're writing
check out the Swift
So we've looked at lots of
Let's take a look at some of
Let's say you want
that returns a first
that has a given prefix.
The function takes a string
and it returns the string
As you can see, you use an
of values your function
In this case a string.
So let's see how it works.
First use a for-in loop to
in the array and then you
given prefix.
You need to check whether the
strings.hasprefix method.
If it does, you're done and you
by writing it in a
But what do you return
if the array doesn't contain
Well, because this function was
the only option you have
in this case the empty string.
But this is not good Swift code.
However, as Dave showed
for representing values
So you just need to change the
to be an optional string
after string, and now
when the string isn't found.
And because the function
you can call it safely
Now, notice that Swift infers
so there's no need to
So we've looked at some of
and return values of various
integers, arrays and
Let's take a look at writing
Let's say you want to write a
of numbers based
Let's think about what
It's going to take in an array
in the array it's going to
that number in the
For example, if you wanted
to contain only the
you could test whether each
In this case, of
so it's included in
If a number isn't
the filtering function just
to test, and so on through
Now, let's look at writing
The function declaration
but what type do you put in for
As you saw a few moments
to include a number
in the filtered result is
not just a simple value,
and in Swift functions can take
So what does the type
Well, all function types in
The type of the function's
go inside of the parentheses,
and the function's return type.
So, for example, here's our
from earlier.
It has the type,
because it doesn't take
Here void just means it
And in Swift if your function
you don't need to write
And here's the firstString
Its signature is a
but its type follows
It takes a string,
and it returns an
So now that you've seen this
it's pretty clear how you need
to finish the declaration
The includeNumber
that takes an integer and
that type as Int in
So let's go ahead and write
You need to build up an
so here's a variable
It's been initialized to
And as you iterate through
pass into the function, you need
to check whether each
in the result array.
To do that you pass each number
and notice that inside
the includeNumber parameter
of the function it's passed
that you can call
that you do any other function.
So that's how you
that takes another
But how do you call one of
Well, first you're going
to pass into filterInts.
So here's an array of numbers
and a simple function
that indicates whether
As you can see, the type
of divisibleByTwo
of the includeNumber parameter.
So that means that we can pass
as an argument to filterInts.
You do this by simply
of the divisibleByTwo function
of only the even numbers.
Now, notice that you don't
when you pass in the
and that's because you're
Instead, it's called later
Also notice that we passed in
but you could have passed
for instance, if you just
without needing to create
The same is true for passing
It's not very likely that the
find much reuse.
And it would be pretty
to make a new function every
in a different filterInt
And if you look at the important
you can see that
at all is really just a
divisibleByTwo is just a
that you see highlighted.
And in Swift, just as you
or a literal array, you can
without a name called
and pass it around in your code.
The syntax for writing a closure
to a function declaration,
except that it doesn't
You write the entire body
of the curly braces and you
from its signature
as in use the parameter
of this closure,
Now, this is the most
to write a closure, but
Swift can infer a
from the context
For example, the function type
from the type of the
and this means you don't
And when the entire body
of the closure is a single
you don't need to write
So this is much cleaner syntax,
so short, even the number
And in cases like these Swift
names, so there's no need
to even write the parameter
These implicit arguments
and a number beginning at 0.
So $0 refers to the first
$1 the second, and so on.
And even though these
in any closure expression,
so doesn't make your
Now, you've seen that Swift
for writing closures,
but passing them directly inside
little punctuation heavy.
A closing curly brace right next
to a closing paren
However, when the closure is the
as it is in this case,
as a trailing closure right
And as you'll see later, if
to a function, you can drop
Now, trailing closures
when the closure contains
For example, here's a
that determines whether the sum
Trailing closure syntax ensures
with multiline functionality
Now, the filterInts function is
to do is filter integers,
to filter arrays of other
For example, say you
and you want a filtered array
that have less than a
You could do this by writing
like the one you see here,
and since you've already
let's see whether you can
Well, first, you'd obviously
and change all the
to numbers to refer to strings.
And next you need to change all
of the Int types
And because the behavior
of these two functions
for both integers and strings,
there's really nothing
They're essentially
And now you have this function
that filters an array
Now, if you want a
for other kinds of types, you
and over and over again
but this would obviously
So instead, you can write
with arrays of any kind of type.
This is called a
So let's look at
Writing one is not
than what you've seen already.
First you change the
So, for example, the function's
rather than filterInts
Next, and more importantly, you
that you see here with
but you don't know
So instead, what you really
The actual type is determined
Here we filled in
with a generic type
And so that you can
between type parameters and
like strings or integers,
up front inside of the
after the function's name.
And now you have a generic
with an array that
You call this kind of function
You don't need to specify the
to work with because
from the values you pass in.
Filtering is such
that the Swift standard library
with any kind of
It works in basically
as the filter function you just
so you call it using
names.filter, as you see here.
The Swift standard
of other methods that take
And another really useful
and it also works with any
Map returns a new array
of a plan enclosure
So here's an example that
of short names from above.
It passes a closure that
You can even chain
to perform multiple operations.
So, for example, you can
and the upper casing
By chaining these two
dot notation.
The filtering happens first,
on the filtered array,
which then finally returns
And this reads nicely even
when you're using the
So the combination of closures
as arguments makes it possible
powerful code in a concise
So we've looked at
and even a bit of
I'd like to invite Alex
about data types in Swift.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Brian.
You've seen how to use
Now let's take a look at how
to create some data
Let's start with structures.
You create one like this.
You write the struct
by the name of a structure.
Here, rectangle.
Then inside the curly braces
of the structure.
Properties use the same
for variables and constants.
Both properties here have
of the declaration, so
by just writing rectangle,
followed by a pair
And to access the properties,
You don't have to provide a
of the types declaration.
In fact, most of
More often, you write just the
when you create the instance.
So another property
of a rectangle besides its
You wouldn't want to
You'd have to update it every
What you want is a property
at the point you need
that using a computed property.
To make a computed property,
and its type, you write a
for computing and returning the
Even though it's computed
you still access it
There's more that you
You can have setters and
out information about those
of the Swift Programming
Just like you can define
you can also define methods.
They use the same syntax you've
And just like properties, you
when you need to call them.
You've seen this syntax a few
Let's look at what it does
It looks a little bit
because of the parenthesis,
but it's actually
So far we've been using a
member wise initializer
for you on structures.
Here's what it would
that initializer out explicitly.
You write the init keyword and
for the rectangle's properties.
Notice that there are two
There's a property and there's
to explicitly refer
So that's how you write
There's enough code in
that it could benefit from some
that in Swift is
An extension lets
to an existing type.
In Swift you can use extensions
Core functionality can go in
and additional functionality can
You're not limited to
If you need to, you can extend
such as foundation or
You saw earlier how you
which performs the
on data of different types.
You can also make
which contains data
The syntax looks very similar.
You still have the generic type
after the name.
This example attaches
of some kind of element.
This would be a useful data
to populate a table view that
You create a generic
like an instance
Here you can see if you
board games and primes
One is an array of strings
and the other is an
They have different
so they are different types.
You don't have to
Swift infers what
So that's structures.
Another data type
You write class before
about structures still applies.
Properties, methods,
So why would you want
One reason is that your code
of a class from several
and that's different than
for structures.
A structure acts
For example, in a game, if
and then give player2
you have two independent scores.
Changing player2's score
However, both players need to
when they log their high scores.
Since it's a class, that's
When player2 gets a new
to the file, both
If you're coming from another
you might be used to
and in Swift you don't
as often as you might think.
Anytime it makes sense to check
you usually want a value
For more information about how
there's a great talk
Another reason to use
to subclass an existing class.
For example, suppose
that gives you this
of core fish functionality.
You can subclass it
like a FlyingFish can
You indicate that this is a
Subclasses can also
to provide their
Like this ComplainingFish.
It swims like a normal fish, it
You write super.swim to call
This code doesn't compile yet.
When you override
you have to mark it
and now this code works.
Just like it's an error to
it's also an error
when you don't override
That means if you misspell a
to override, Swift tells you
about the error right
A segue can also
For example, fish that has an
ComplainingFish needs
with both a name
Inside the initializer
for the properties
and then you call super.init
to let the superclass
There's more you can
especially around classes.
You can read all about it
of the Swift Programming
You've seen how you
Now let's talk about
Continuing the game example,
suppose you have this
Since every player
there's a method to do that.
You have two kinds of players.
You have a HumanPlayer
by showing UI to the user.
And you have a ComputerPlayer
by finding the best legal move.
So the question then
in the base class
Well, there's no shared behavior
between human and
There isn't any shared
And in the surrounding code you
of the player base class.
So this method should
The only reasonable thing you
of fatal error to help
in the development process.
All the player class is doing
to be a player, that every
It's a sort of blueprint
In Swift you express this kind
of relationship using
Protocols specify requirements
They're like interfaces
that you might know
You make one using
And because it describes
to fulfill, you don't
Types conform to a protocol by
and you declare conformance
just like you do when
At this point you're
so these methods are
So you don't write override.
There's no real reason these
so let's make them structures.
And let's take a closer
It has a few other properties,
And if you make an instance of
You get a default
because the standard
from any type to a string.
But what if you wanted to
to print a nicer description?
The standard library also
CustomStringConvertible
which lets you provide a custom
that protocol looks like.
It has one requirement --
Any type that conforms
custom description.
Okay. So where should
description property.
Remember from earlier how you
extensions with core
in type declarations,
and additional functionality
Having a custom string
into the second category.
It's not core functionality, so
Here's how you extend a type
You write colon
in the first line.
And then you implement the
extension body.
Now when you call print,
string conversion.
There's a lot that you can
and extensions to organize your
For more information
on Protocol Oriented
That brings us to the last data
You use an enumeration when
that you know ahead of time.
Here's an enumeration
and right alignment for text.
When you use an enumeration,
you use dot notation
Here there are only two
if you write them on one line.
Because an enumeration has
it's very common to use one
for each enumeration case.
Writing alignment over and
and here it's not necessary.
The switch is considering
so the only possible
for are enumeration cases
That means you can omit
and write just .left.
Also, notice that there's
That's for the same
The switch already covers
so there's nothing left for
Omitting the default case
If you come back later and
but forget to update the switch,
until you add the missing code.
Now let's take a quick look
at two more things you
You can associate values
For example, the alignment can
and you can get that
out as part of the switch case.
You can also give each
from some other type, such
which lets you improve
by using enumerations
You've seen a lot of Swift this
to show you everything.
One last thing I'd like to
In Swift you can use an
You use throws to
that can throw an error.
You write defer before a block
whether or not there's an error,
and that execution happens
such as returning
Before calling code that
you mark it with try,
and throw errors
For all the details
take a look at the
in the Swift Programming
You can find a link to that
There are lots of other
out later this week or on video.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]