[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning and
Optimizing App Startup Time.
My name is Nick Kledzik,
and I are going to take
of how a process launches.
Now you may be wondering,
So we had our crack developing
and they determined there are
by listening to this talk.
The first, is app
that launches to slowly.
The second group, is app
in the first group [laughter].
And lastly, is anyone
about how the OS operates.
So this talk is going to
the first is more theory and
I'll be doing the
And in it I'll be walking
that happen, all
But in order for
and appreciate all
to give you a crash course
So first some Mach-O
Mach-O is a bunch of file types
for different run
So the first executable, that's
it's also the main binary
A dylib is a dynamic library,
you may know those
Our platform also has another
Now a bundle's a
that you cannot link against,
at run time by an
on a Mac OS for plug-ins.
Last, is the term image.
Image refers to any
And I'll be using
And lastly, the term
in our industry, but in this
with a special directory
to holds files needed
So let's dive right into
A Mach-O image is
by convention all segment names
Now, each segment is always
in this example the text
and LINKEDIT are each one page.
Now the page size is determined
the page size is 16K,
Now another way to look
So sections is something
But sections are really just
they don't have any of the
but they are non-overlapping.
Now, the most common segment
in fact almost every binary has
You can add custom ones but it
So what are these used for?
Well TEXT is at the
it contains the Mach header,
it contains any machine
as any read only constant
The DATA segment is rewrite,
the DATA segment contains
And lastly, is the LINKEDIT.
Now the LINKEDIT doesn't
of global variables, a
about your function of variables
You may have also heard of
Well suppose you build
and now you have
so what happens the next code
to build it for 32 bit devices?
When you rebuild, Xcode will
file, this one built
And then those two files are
called the Mach-O
And that has a header
and all the header has a
and what their offsets
And that header is
Now you may be wondering,
why are the segments
Why is the header a page sizes,
Well the reason everything
with our next topic
So what is virtual memory?
Some of you may know the
that every problem can be solved
by adding a level
So the problem with, that
is how do you manage
when you have all
So they added a little
Every process is a logical
to some physical page of RAM.
Now this mapping does not
you could have logical addresses
and you can have multiple
to the same physical RAM.
This offered lots of
So what can you do with VM?
Well first, if you
that does not map to any
that address in your
At that point the kernel stops
out what needs to happen.
The next thing is if
with different logical
mapping to the same
those two processes are now
You now have sharing
Another interesting feature
Rather than actually
into RAM you can tell the VM
the I want this slice
to this address range
So why would you do that?
Well rather than having
by having that mapping set up,
as you first access those
as if you had read it in memory,
that hasn't been accessed before
the kernel will read
And that gives you lazy
Now we can put all
and what I told you about
that the TEXT segment
or image can be mapped
it will be read lazily, and
between those processes.
What about the DATA segment?
The DATA segment is read, write,
so for that we have trick
it's kind of similar to
in the Apple file system.
What copy and write does is it
page between all the processes.
What happens when one process,
from the global variables
But as soon as one process
to its DATA page, the
The copy and write causes
of that page into
and redirect the
So that one process now has
Which brings us to clean
So that copy is considered
A dirty page is something
that contains process
A clean page is something
that the kernel could
such as rereading from disc.
So dirty pages are much more
And the last thing is the
on page boundaries.
By that I mean the permissions
readable, writable,
or any combination of those.
So let's put this all together,
I talked about the
something about virtual memory,
let's see how they
Now I'm going to skip
how the dyld operates and in a
you through this but for now,
I just want to show
between Mach-O and
So we have a dylib file here,
in memory we've mapped
So, in memory this dylib
The savings, why it's
So it turns out most global
So the static [inaudible]
that moves all the zero
and then takes up no disc space.
And instead, we use
to tell the VM the first
fill it with zero's.
So it requires no reading.
So the first thing dyld
at the Mach header, in
So it'll be looking at
when that happens,
there's no mapping to a physical
At that point the kernel
to a file, so it'll read
place it into physical
Now dyld can actually start
It reads through the Mach
there's some information
in the LINKEDIT segment
So again, dyld drops down what's
in the bottom box
Which again causes a page fault.
Kernel services it by reading
into another physical
Now dyld can expect a LINKEDIT.
Now in process, the
you need to make some
to make this dylib runable.
So, the same thing happens,
from the DATA page, but there's
dyld is actually going
it's actually going to
and at this point, a
And this page becomes dirty.
So what would have been
if I just malloced eight pages
into it I would have
But now I only have one page of
So what's going to happen
when the second process
So in the second process dyld
First it looks at
but this time the kernel says,
in RAM somewhere so it simply
that page no iO was done.
The same think with
Now we get to the DATA page,
to look to see if the DATA page,
the clean copy already still
and if it does it can reuse it,
And now in this process,
Now the last step is the
dyld is doing its operations.
So it can hint to the
that it doesn't really need
you can reclaim them when
So the result is now we have two
each one would have
or a total of 16 dirty pages,
but now we only have
and one clean, shared page.
Two other minor things
that how security effects dyld,
that have impacted dyld.
So one is ASLR, address
this is a decade or
where basically you
The second is code signing, it
to deal with code signing,
of code signing as, you
over the entire file, and then
Well, in order to
that means the entire file
So instead what actually
is every single page of your
individual cryptographic hash.
And all those hashes are
This allows each
that it hasn't been
by you at page in time.
Okay, so we finished the
to walk you from exec to main.
So what is exec?
Exec is a system call.
When you trap into the kernel,
to replace this process
The kernel wipes the entire
in that executable
Now for ASLR it maps it
The next thing it does is from
it marks that whole
ad by that I mean it's
not writeable, not executable.
The size of that region is at
and at least 4GB for
This catches any NULL
and also foresees more bits,
it catches any, pointer
Now, life was easy for
of Unix because all I
set the PC into it,
And then shared libraries
So who loads dylibs?
They quickly realize that they
and the kernel people didn't
so instead a helper
In our platform it's
On other Unix's you
So when the kernel's done
another Mach-O called
at another random address.
Sets the PC into dyld and
the process.
So now dyld's running in
to load all the dylibs
and get everything
So let's walk through
This is a whole bunch
of a timeline along
as we walk through these we'll
So first thing, is dyld has to
Well what are the
To find those it first reads the
that the kernel already mapped
of all the dependent libraries.
So it's got to parse that out.
Then it has to find each dylib.
And once it's found each dylib
of each file, it needs to make
validate it, find
register that code
And then it can actually
at each segment in that dylib.
Okay, so that's pretty simple.
Your app knows about
dyld then says oh this app
load the two of those,
Well, it gets more
and B.dylib themselves could
So dyld has to do the same
of those dylibs, and each
on something that's already
so it has to determine whether
and if not, it needs to load it.
So, this continues on and on.
And eventually it has
Now if you look at a
in our system, loads anywhere
so that's a lot of
Luckily most of those are OS
when building the
and pre-cache a lot of
to do to load these things.
So OS dylibs load
So now we've loaded all the
in their floating
and now we actually have
That's called fix-ups.
But one thing about
because of code signing we can't
So how does one dylib
if you can't change the
Well, we call back
and we add a lot
So our code-gen, is
It's positioned independent
meaning the code can be loaded
meaning things are,
What that means is to call
the co-gen actually creates
and that pointer points
The code loads that pointer
So all dyld is doing is
Now there's two main
and binding, so what's
So rebasing is if you have
to within your image, and any
the second is binding.
Binding is if you're pointing
And they each need to
so I'll go through the steps.
But first, if you're
dyld info with a bunch
You can run this on any binary
that dyld will have to be doing
So rebasing.
Well in the old age you could
for each dylib, and that
static linker and dyld work
it to that preferred load
and data that was supposed to
and dyld wouldn't have
But these days, with ASLR,
your dylib is loaded
It's slid to some other address,
and data are now still
So in order to fix those up,
which is how much has
of those interior pointers,
to basically add the
So rebasing means going
that are internal, and basically
So the concept is very
write, read, add, write.
But where are those
Where those pointers
are encoded in the
Now, at this point, all we've
so when we start doing rebasing,
we're actually causing
in all the DATA pages.
And then we causing copy and
So rebasing can sometimes be
But one trick we do is
and from the kernel's
it sees data faults
And when it sees that, the
which makes the iO less costly.
So next is binding,
that point outside your dylib.
They're actually bound by name,
in this case, malloc
that says this data pointer
So at run time, dyld needs to
of that symbol, which
looking through symbol tables.
Once it's found, that
in that data pointer.
So this is way more
than rebasing is.
But there's very little iO
because rebasing has done
Next, so ObjC has a
class DATA structure which
and a pointer to a super
Almost all those are fixed
But there's a few extra things
The first is ObjC
and you can request a class
So that means the ObjC run
of all names of which
So every time you load
its name needs to be
Next, in C++ you may have heard
of the fragile ivar
Fragile base class problem.
We don't have that problem
of the fix-ups we do is
of all the ivars
Next, in ObjC you
which change the
Sometimes those are in classes
on another dylib, that,
to be applied at this point.
And lastly, ObjC [inaudible] is
so we need unique selectors.
So now the work that we've
now we can do all
that can be basically
So now's our chance to
So in C++, you can
you can say [inaudible] equals
That arbitrary expression,
and it's run at this point now.
So the C++ compiler
for these arbitrary
In ObjC, there's something
Now the +load method is
that you don't use it.
We recommend you use
But if you have one,
So, now I have this big graph,
we have your main executable
this huge graph, we have
What order do we want them in?
Well, we run them bottom up.
And the reason is, when an
to call up some dylib
that dylibs already
So by running the initializers
up the app class
into something you depend on.
So once all initiliazers
now we actually finally get
So you survived this theory
on how processes
that dyld is a helper program,
it loads all dependent
fixing up all the DATA
and then jumps to main.
So now to put all this
I'd like to hand
who will be giving you
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Nick.
We've all had that experience
out of our pocket, press the
on an application
And then tap, and tap, and
because it's not responding.
When that happens to me,
and I want to delete the app.
I'm Louis Gerbarg I
we're going to discuss how to
so your users are delighted.
So first off, let's discuss
through in this part
We're going to discuss how fast
so that your users are going
How to measure that launch time.
Because it can be
The standard ways you measure
before your code can run.
We're going to go through a list
of the common reasons why your
through a list of, why,
the common reasons your
And finally, we're
a way to fix all the slow downs.
So I'm going to give
for the rest of my talk.
You need to do less
Now, I don't mean your app
I'm saying that your app has
to do less things
We want you to figure
of your launch behaviors
to initialize them
So, let's discuss the goals,
Well, the launch time for
But, a good, a good
is 400 milliseconds
Now, the reason for that is
on the phone to give
between the home screen
when you see it execute.
And those animations take
give you a chance to
Obviously that may be different,
in different context your app
that have to launch, they launch
And a phone and TV, and a
but 400 milliseconds
You can never take longer
If you take longer
the OS will kill your
through an infinite loop, and
Where you click an app, it
it doesn't respond, and
and that's usually
Finally, it's very
on your slowest supported
So those timers are
across all supported
So, if you hit 400 milliseconds
for testing right now, you're
you're probably not going
So let's do a recap of
What do we have to do to
map images, rebase
run image initializers,
If that sounds like
I'm exhausted just saying it.
And then after that, we have
you'll see that in
or in your Swift apps
That does some other things,
including running the
and loading your nibs.
And then finally
in your application delegate.
I'm mentioning these last
in those 400 milliseconds
But we're not going to
If you want a better view
there's a talk from 2012, iOS
I highly recommend you go
But that's the last we're going
So, let's move on, one more
warm versus cold launches.
So when you launch an app,
we talk about warm
And a warm launch is an app
in memory, either
and quit previously, and it's
in the kernel, or because
A cold launch is a launch
And a cold launch is generally
The reason a cold launch is more
when your user is launching an
or for the first
that's when you really
In order to measure
to reboot between measurements.
Having said that,
on improving your warm launches,
your cold launches will
You can do rapid development
but then every so often,
So, how do we measure
Well, we have a built in
you can access it through
DYLD Print Statistics.
And it's been available
but it prints out a lot
of internal debugging
particularly useful, it's
that you probably want.
And we're fixing that today.
So it's significantly
[ Applause ]
It's going to put out, a lot
for you that should
to improve your launch times.
And it will be available
So, one other thing I want
is that the debugger
on every single dylib load
from your app and load your
that can be very time consuming.
But dyld knows about that and
out from the numbers
So you don't have to worry
because dyld's going to give
than you'll observe by looking
That's expected and understood,
and it's everything's going
but I just wanted
So let's move on, to setting an
you just go to the
and you add it like this.
Once you do that you'll get the
console output logged.
And what does that look like?
Well this is what the
and we have a time bar
on the bottom representing
And let's add one more thing.
Let's add an indicator for
which this app I'm
So, if you look in, this is
that Nick discussed in order to
through them in order.
So dylib loading, the
about dylib loading and the
from it, is that embedded
So Nick said an average app
But OS dylibs are fast
we have ways of pre-calculating
But we don't have every
when we're building the OS.
We can't pre-calculate them
with your app, so we have to go
through a much slower
And the solution for
to use fewer dylibs
And I'm not saying you can't
of options here you can
You can use static
into both, into apps that way.
And you have an option to lazy
but dlopen causes some
and correctness issues,
in doing more work later
So, it's a viable option but
about it and, I would discourage
So, I have an app here that
And it's taking 240
but if I change it and merge
then it only takes 20
So I can still have dylibs, I
functionality between my
limiting them will
And I understand this is
between your development
and your application
Because the more dylibs that you
and re-link your app in and
cycles are.
So you absolutely can and should
to target a limited number, we
a good target's about
So now that we've fixed up
on to the next place where
Between 350 milliseconds
So as Nick mentioned, rebasing
and binding tends to be
but it's already done the iO.
So that iO is for both of
the timing's also comingled.
So if we go in and look at
up pointers in the DATA section.
So what we have to do, is
Nick showed you a
to see what pointers
up in the DATA, section,
And it shows what segments
so that will give you a good
For instance, if you see
in ObjC section, that's probably
that you have a bunch
So, one of the things you
to reduce the number
and ivars that you have.
So there are a number
that are encouraging
that maybe only have
And, those particular patterns
of your applications as you
So you should be
Now having 100 or 1,000
but we've seen apps with
And in those cases that can
to your launch time for
Another thing you can do is
of C++ virtual functions.
So virtual functions create
which are the same as ObjC
that they create structures
that have to be fixed up.
They're smaller than
than ObjC metadata but
for some applications.
You can use Swift structs.
So Swift tends to use less
for fix-ups of this sort.
And, Swift is more inlinable and
of that, so migrating to Swift
And one other thing,
about machine generated codes,
you may describe some
or some custom language
that generates other
And if those generated programs
they can become very expensive
because when you generate your
very large structures.
We've seen cases where,
and megabytes of data.
But the upside is you
because you can just
to use something
for instance offset
And that will be a big win.
So in this case, let's look
with my, with my load time.
And I have at least 10,000
so many it scrolled
And if I cut it down
I just cut my launch times, my
from 350 to 20 milliseconds.
So, now, everything but the
that 400 millisecond mark,
So for ObjC set up, well Nick
to do.
It had to do class
with the non-fragile ivars, it
and it has to do
And I'm not going to spend
and the reason I'm not is, we
up the rebasing and
All the reductions
to be the same thing
So we just get a little bit of
It's 8 milliseconds.
But we didn't do
And now finally, we're going
which are the big
So I'm going to go a little more
There are two types
explicit initializers,
As Nick said we recommend
which will cause the ObjC run
when the classes were
of when the file is loaded.
Or, in C/C++ there's an
onto functions which will
as initializers, so that's
that we just rather
We rather you replace them
So by call site initializers I
Or if you're in cross
Or if you're in C++
All these functions have
of functionality
of these blocks will be
and only that.
Dispatch once is very, very
After the first execution of
to a no op running past it, so
of using, explicit initializers.
So let's move on to
So inplicit initializers are
from C++ globals with
with non-trivial constructors.
And one option is
with call site initializers
There's certainly places
with non-global structures
that you will initialize.
Another option is that you don't
So in C++ there's initializers
And if you're objects are just
or the static linker will
for the DATA section, lay it
it doesn't have to be run, it
Finally, it can be
because they're implicit,
in the compiler
and if you do that it will give
generating one of these.
So it's good to add that to
Another option is just
And the reason is, Swift
and they'll be initialized,
to be initialized
But the way it does it, instead,
is instead of using
behind the scenes, uses
It uses one of those
So moving to Swift will
so I highly encourage
Finally, in your initializers
that will be a big performance
When dyld's running it's
we can do things like
because we're single threaded.
As soon as dlopens
the graph of how our
to run changes, we could
we have to turn on
to be a big performance mess.
You also can have
and undefined behaviors.
Also, please don't start
basically for the same reason.
You can set up a mute
and mute text even have like,
predefined static values
up with that run no code.
But actually starting a
potentially a big performance
So here we have some
with a non-trivial initializer.
&gt;&gt; I'm having trouble
Please try again in a moment.
&gt;&gt; Well, thank you Siri.
I'm having a, I have a
And I guess I had it in for
and okay, I'm down to
I have plenty of time
and do everything else,
So now that we've
let's talk about what we
this was really long
The first one is please
to measure your times, add it
to your performance
So you can track how your
so as you're actively doing
months later and have
You can improve your app launch
of dylibs you have, reducing the
and eliminating your
And you can improve in
because it just does
Finally, dlopen usage
it causes subtle
that are hard to diagnose.
For more information you can
There are several related
and again, there's the app
that goes into the other
that highly recommend you
Thank you for coming
[ Applause ]