[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
My name is Susumu Harada.
I'm an engineer on the
And I'm here today with
And we're really excited to
that will make it easier than
and fix accessibility
So, some of you may be
So let me quickly go
to make your app accessible
that you may encounter
So, accessibility
that everyone can enjoy
and the great apps
regardless of their abilities.
Now, some users may
with their vision
And some may experience
or cognitive and
So, to support this
we at Apple have worked
of assistive technologies
that help augment various users'
for people with visual
for people with motor
And we also made sure that these
across all of our
and iOS to watchOS and tvOS.
And while these assistive
enabling tools, the heart
of our users' experience are
So to better get a sense
with our assistive technologies
that you may run into, let's
So here I have a simple app that
And it just presents a user with
and four answer buttons
And the user can tap
and you get a feedback whether
It's pretty straightforward.
And it looks like its
But how might a user who is
So, obviously without any
be able to see the screen.
So, it's pretty useless.
But fortunately, they can
VoiceOver to have
on the screen read out to them.
And they can use various
and interact with different
So, if this app is
when the user touches on the
VoiceOver will read
Great. So what does the
like VoiceOver need
to present the interface
So, there are several key
But first it needs to know
where all the important
And for each of those elements
or their types such as what is a
And finally, it also needs
that uniquely identifies that
to the user in an
So with these key pieces
and other assistive technologies
to the user in a
And all the accessibility
by the app through
And we at Apple have
to build accessibility support
so that if you build your apps
of this accessibility
in for you automatically
And you don't have
But of course, your apps
custom controls.
And when they do, you
of this accessibility
And if you don't, you might end
So let's see what the impact
So, if I had implemented
at the top using complete custom
or OpenGL, so they don't have
by default.
So unless I explicitly
they might be completely
and other assistive
And with these four
if I used custom views
but forgot to indicate
as being a button,
and their users will
that they can press on these.
And finally, for the
if I implemented it using
and forgot to supply the
VoiceOver will have no idea
And the user will have no
So you can see how if you're
information the user
on assistive technology
So obviously it's very important
to make sure your app is
that it has a positive
But there's also
to making sure your
And that is a fully
with a fully accessible app you
for it using Xcode's
And for more information on
to check out UI Testing
from last year's WWDC.
Great. So, how can you make sure
that your app is
accessibility information?
Well, one method that
to use the actual assistive
and Switch control
Now, this is still
since you can mirror the
and also catch usability
that something is accessible.
But it does require that
to use these technologies.
And especially if your app
you might find it quite
to repeatedly deploy your
run through it using each of
and repeat the process
And all those platforms also
settings that the
such the Dynamic Type font size.
And you as a developer might
to go and switch back and forth
between changing the
going back to your app,
and repeating the process.
So, we've heard all
And today we're very excited
and more streamlined alternative
to auditing your apps using the
And in the new Accessibility
with just a single
it can automatically
for common accessibility issues.
It's super easy.
And it even suggests to you
And in the Interactive
easily, point at any
and get very detailed
about them.
And this works whether your
or on a connected device.
And we also offer a live
which lets you really easily go
and change an accessibility
and immediately see
without having to
And we're really
that this Accessibility
of our platforms.
This means that with a single
on your desktop you can audit
on macOS and iOS,
And you can do this simply
on the simulator or on a device
and choosing the respective
It's that easy.
And we hope that with this
than ever for you to test
across all of our platforms.
So, to give you a demo of
and the new accessibly
I'd like to hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. I'm Patty Hoa.
And I'm super excited to
about our new Accessibility
So, we've been working
to incorporate all
And so I can't wait to
So, to note, Accessibility
of the developer package.
That means you can
under the Open Developer
and launch the Accessibility
So here is a screenshot of
I want to bring your attention
On the left we have what
That allows you to inspect all
that we have, including
your desktop machine,
your TV and the simulators.
In the middle we have what we
Now, when you have this enabled,
then the tool can
under your finger
Or if you're in a simulator
under your mouse cursor.
Then on the right we
These are three major
And this is what I'll
of the session telling you
of these three features.
So what are these
First, we have Inspection.
The Inspection feature
and analyze the accessibility
Then we have the Audit
to find accessibility
And last we have the Settings
to quickly test how accessibly
So the first one I want to talk
So, ultimately your goal is
to make sure your app is
And to do that you need
Now, earlier Susumu
if you could actually run with
and audit your app that way.
Or you could also hire an
to do the evaluation
But today, I'm going to show
to get that solution.
And that is simply use our
And so, in our Audit tab we
And the best way to
about this feature is
So I have here on the
of the iOS version of the
in the simulator.
And so you could play a game.
We have equation.
We could pick one
Not that one.
This one. There.
So that's how you play the game.
Okay. So now I want to launch
So, I simply go to Xcode.
And on the top, under
we're going to launch the
So the first thing you
which device you
So in our Target Chooser, I'm
And then we'll click
And here's that Run Audit
So I'm going to go
In a split second we've
And here are the
You can now select that.
As you cycle through
you'll note that there's a
over the area where
And of course, if you're
like iPhone or iPad, this is
So, now if you want to
you will have to take your
and look on your iPad or iPhone.
So what we have here is
just give you a little
of that same element that
in the tools.
So you could keep your eye
All right.
So we have these issues.
So what's the next thing
Go fix it.
So let's pick one of
Element has no description.
And click on the disclosure
to get more information.
All right.
So element has no description.
What does that correspond
Do you know which
Well, if you went online,
about the accessibility API
on how to fix this issue.
But today I'm going to show you
Simply click on this
And the tool will tell
It says: Consider setting
So, at this point, if you
you would just go right into
But if you want more information
you could click on
which then will take you to --
eventually take you to
where you could find more
All right?
Since now I know which API
into the code and fix it up.
So, what I'm fixing
with the dots in there.
And the way it's implemented,
So now I'm simply going
to override the accessibility
And I'm going to return a string
And of course, you should
Okay? So now I have my
I'm going to save it,
Okay, let's go back to Addition.
And let's clear out
And rerun the Audit.
With that simple
we've just fixed up
Isn't that great?
[ Applause ]
All right.
So, note that this same powerful
by other teams of your
to do an assessment
And of course, then they will
So, to speed up the process
they can now just,
they could simply copy and
And of course, every good bug
So we have here this
If I click on that, you should
of your entire screen,
plus where the problem
So again, you could
and paste it into
And now you're ready
[ Applause ]
All right.
So what you've just seen is how
auto-detect problems
It could give you
And even speed up the process
As powerful and as
in helping you detect
similar to the compile
having no warning does not
any problem.
So that's why it's
of that manual auditing
And to show you why
let me give you an example.
So, suppose you have a button
and its function
Of course, the button comes
One thing we tend to
to create a new button
of these existing button
And of course, that
of that button gets transferred.
And we go and tweak
like the actions and the icons.
That's fine.
That's all good.
Except if you forget to
that could be a problem.
Especially in this case,
it's the accessibility
For assistive clients
the accessibility label
Because that's the only
about how this button functions.
So, if an assistive client
on this button, and you haven't
it still says Send Mail.
But they're going to
that they're sending a mail.
In fact, they've just
So that's not a great outcome.
And so for that, we're
through that manual
And that's why I want to
So let me give you some
and show you how that helps you
through the manual
So, suppose we have
that has eight dots in there.
In the Inspection tab on the top
And on the left side we have
or give you a summary of how
So in this case the eight-dot
And to the right there's
that allows you to
to the neighboring UI
from this button here.
Then below we have
that contains properties that's
So for example, we have
to Accessibility Label.
And returns the value 8.
And we have Trait.
In this case, it's a
And as this button
you'll look into the
that there's Activate
And so you could simply click
that this action works.
So that's a highlight
Let me go ahead and
All right.
So we're back here on our app.
And now we're going to go
So remember earlier I mentioned
Right now it's enabled, which
over the items in the simulator,
that element under the cursor.
And you can see that
So on the simulator in desktop,
on that item, it will turn
which then allows you
around without affecting
So right now we're
And you see a description
Now, I could click on the
And you'll see the highlight
Click again and we
And also you get a description.
This is the four-dot.
Note that we completely
The equation.
So simply doing this
of find issues along the way.
In this case we might have a
Let's keep going.
So, we're on the
And down to this
Except the description
IMG 0151. Hmm.
Doesn't sound right.
So, again, that may be
where you need to fix it up.
So, if you could simply use
navigate through all the
that all the description
then you're on the right track.
And of course, if you have
like these buttons,
to the Action Section and, in
on the Perform button
to verify the action works.
All right.
So what I've just shown you is
to help you along with your
Now the Inspection is also great
and analysis of the
An example of that is
accessibility hierarchy works,
especially on an OS X app
where the corresponding
to be more complex.
So to show you how this
and launch the OS X
All right?
So I have here the OS X
And let's do something a
multiplication.
And so then when you
&gt;&gt; Sorry, try again.
&gt;&gt; -- that, how about this?
&gt;&gt; Incorrect.
Try again.
&gt;&gt; -- 6. 18.
&gt;&gt; Correct.
&gt;&gt; Okay, so you play
And you know, this app works.
We have the same version
All right.
So the first thing you
that you're inspecting
So, we're going to go
because we're inspecting the
And in this case we
which app we want to inspect.
So I'm going to pick
And again, we could run Audit
And it found a bunch of issues.
I want to bring your attention
It says: "Potentially
So the way these answer
they were simply custom NSview.
That's drawing those
Now, by default, CA layers
Which means if you create them,
clients like VoiceOver is not
And so the tool is
that these are not accessible.
So to understand
it helps to know how the
So let's go to the Inspection.
And again, I'm going to
And so if I bring my
it's going to inspect
What I'm interested
in to inspect right now
And the reason is
who are the children
So, the way I could I look
under the hierarchy
And then here are all the
So, I'm on the equation.
You can see that red highlight.
On the image.
Some status text.
And a bunch of stuff in
So right now, those four crucial
exist as children of the window.
And so we know we need
But today I'm not going to
Instead, I'm going to refer you
to our sample code
It's something to download
This sample app contains
with different UI scenarios
and how you could add
So I encourage you to do that.
And once you fix it up, I expect
that those four answer choice
as children of this window.
So you could verify
So, what I've shown you
so far is how you can use
to help you do some of
And also how you could
to do some more debugging
of the accessibility
The next thing I want to
So, on every OS platform
many accessibility settings.
That comes built right in.
So for example, on the
under General Accessibility
many wonderful accessibility
And settings like Toggle.
So let's say if you want to
your app.
You could go in, adjust the font
Then go back to your app.
And then visually verify how a
Then you could go back
Readjust to something
Then see how a small
Now, you could see that this
if you have to constantly
between the Settings
And how do you know
which accessibility settings
Well, our tool will
So, here's our Settings tab.
Our Settings tab
of the most common
that we want you to test.
In addition, since it's
you no longer have to
between the Settings
[ Applause ]
And here's a demo to
So in the Settings tab, now
And immediately see the
And we could do the same
Adjust it.
And see it directly.
So, what you've just seen is
to make it easier for you.
So, today I've shown you
The first is the Audit
to autodetect accessibility
give you suggestions
And make it faster for you
Then we saw how great
to guide you through that
and allow you to do
of the accessibility
And last, you just saw
that will make it
to test how accessibility
your app.
And that is the quick look
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Great. Thank you Patti.
So we really look
of you try the new
And we hope that you now
of all abilities in mind when
And to help you do that,
we introduced you today the
that we hope will make it easier
diagnose and fix accessibility
And it integrates seamlessly
so that you can easily
whether it's running on a
And we're really excited
from macOS, iOS, to
So we hope that with this
and create wonderful
by all users of all abilities.
So you can find more information
with the video and the
And we'd love to
So we'd love to hear from you
about how we can better
And any issues you might
Inspector to audit your apps.
So you can send us
or bug reports, sorry,
bug reports at
And also participate
at forums.developer.apple.com.
And in case you missed
we highly encourage you to
of these great sessions,
in Accessibility" talk and the
And this evening we have
and Inclusive Design
in Buena Vista Park.
Not the real park, but the
So we'd love to see you there.
So thank you very much.
And enjoy the rest
[ Applause ]