[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
[ Applause ]
Good morning.
Thank you so much everybody.
My name is Matt Patenaude.
I'm a software engineer
And welcome to Session 408,
I am absolutely thrilled to be
to show this to you today,
and boy have we got
So with that in mind, we
So you've had 48 hours
so I'm sure a lot of you
But if some of you
to resist the temptation,
Swift Playgrounds is a really
that allows you to program
of Swift literally to
If you aren't that
we've got you covered.
We've built a great
that you can download
and we've designed it to
regardless of what level
And if nothing else, you can
dance moves out of it.
If you are a little
we've also given you some
like this shapes template,
with things like color and touch
that you couldn't
And if you're already used to
you can take any of
and once you update them for
on Swift Playgrounds
We think it's a really
and we know you're going
to do some really
And as such, we got
So we're going to break our talk
into three different
First, I'm going to ask my
on stage, and he's going to
including all of the great
that really make this a
After that, Jonathan's going
to show you how to build
for Swift Playgrounds, using
of our new document format.
And finally, Izzy's going
to show you some of
that you can do once you've had
around with this thing.
So without further ado, Max.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Matt.
Thanks Matt.
So we're going to start off by
of Swift Playgrounds,
of the different parts
So up at the left, the
we've got the source editor.
On the right, we've
Now the source editor is
of different sections.
So one type of section
and you'll see that we've
This can be interspersed
and this is the rich text
to help you learn
Underneath, we've got an
So here, this is where you'll
Along the bottom of the screen,
In the center of that,
and this depending on
On the left, we have the
and on the right we have the
One is to delete something.
The next is to insert
And the third is to
These buttons will help
without needing the keyboard.
Along the right side,
This is where you can see
in real time, and underneath
which will compile
Along the top left, we have
to your documents, the button to
that shows you all of
and pages inside
We have the two buttons for page
of that, the Tools menu, and the
But let's have a look
Inside of the Library menu,
Next to that, we have
that could be inside of your
And thirdly, we have file
that you can drag out of the
And in the Tools menu, this
about the app, a
with the document, two
about your document,
which takes movie of what you're
which will save a
And finally, the Reset Page
to the original state.
So here we are in the document
got a whole bunch of documents.
I'm going to open up the
that I've got here.
So I've only got one
Let rectangle equals value.
I want to draw some
because I think that'll be fun.
So I'm going to tap on Value,
up code completion
Got a whole bunch of
So I'm going to find a rectangle
and dragging to the left to
So there's a rectangle.
Tap on that.
It gets inserted
Now notice, there's
in the left side of the screen.
So that's a live issue
We're going to tap on that.
It tells me there's
I needed to add parens
So here we provide fix-its.
You can tap on the first one,
and then that will get
The orange circle goes away.
Now tap on my code, and we
It's a square, but.
Now notice when we move down,
we've now got Rectangle
So I'm going to tap on
and now it's going to list
and functions that I
Let's make this a
by changing the border's
So let's start out by
We get an equal operator.
Tap on that.
And we get a placeholder
Now notice the second item
in code completion
That means that we can insert
So I'm going to tap on that, and
Tapping on that brings
up a quick editor
There's a whole bunch
of Swift Playgrounds, and
So I'm going to change
and let's tap Run My Code.
And now it's going
It's not very visible,
to increase the border
Tap on Rectangle.
Tap on dot.
Tap on Border Width equals, and
which also brings
so we can punch in a number.
Going to punch in four.
Oops. And tap Run.
And now it's a bit more seeable.
Now I'm going to -- I want
that will draw a square
in the live view.
So I'm going to do a bit
and I want to hide
just to give me some
So I'm going to tap and hold
and it's going to split
Now drag to the right to
Let's tap at the
Now Swift Playgrounds also has a
to do programming with
So I'll tap the Keyboard
Notice the keys have
but more on that later.
Let's start by using the canvas
of the shapes playground to
So I'll type C-a-n.
Gives us a canvas object.
Type Shared to get
And now I'll type Drag.
Notice that Swift Playgrounds
drag handler from
So I'll tap on that, and we get
If I type Return, it'll
so we can do some coding.
Now I want it to create a
my finger.
So all I have to do is what I
So let's tap on the closing
and drag it down to encompass
One more thing I
I have to change the center
of the rectangle to
So let's add that
by setting the rectangle's
to the canvas shared
which I know is in array.
If I tap and hold on the H,
it gives me an array's
Now I can tap and hold on the
Now let's dismiss that,
and tap Run My Code,
Yeah.
[ Applause ]
Now I'll tap and hold on
Drag it to the left.
Dismiss the code.
Now I can draw everywhere.
Now, I like my little
so I'm going to send it to Matt.
So I'm going to tap
You just take a picture to
Now, a lot was going on here,
and there's a lot
to make a playground
So I'm going to bring
who's going to show us
of the playgrounds in
So, Jonathan.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Matt and Max.
So Swift Playgrounds on iPad
Playground documents that
and you can make
You can use AirDrop,
or other document providers
in either environment.
And don't forget to have fun.
But in addition
to the traditional
Swift Playgrounds for iPad
that takes advantage
Playground Books provide
to construct an interactive
that you want other
You want to show them something.
So in these next moments, I'd
of what's new, and then
these new things to good use.
So first off, Playground Books
into chapters, and a table
from this for easy navigation.
Playground Books provide a new
and this can be useful
to stage a full-screen
of a story that you're
You can see how our content
trying to demonstrate
And as you introduce concepts,
to link terms with their
of a finger, and all these terms
up to provide a reference
A Playground page full of Swift
to just jump into.
Sometimes you don't
from the finer point
So Playground Books
to focus the learner
You annotate your Swift
They become blanks that
This lets you reduce
especially at an early
to demonstrate a
And Playground Books
that you don't want
Hidden code blocks give you
and tear down code around some
It's a great way to hide
and then you can pull
and expose this setup magic
Playground Books lets you
that show up it the
You can specify or exclude
etcetera, customizing what
And with the new
you can configure the live
as the page is loaded.
It runs Swift code in a separate
of the code that is typed
This editor code on the left and
they talk to each other with
We're actually going to see how
through my demonstration and so
that you can take
It's a great way to do
building up with each successive
And if you've chosen to
and guide through the
you can analyze what was
that the learner can bring up
And if they succeed in their
with a success message.
And Playground Books will
of each page, and the learner
in the table of contents.
Use these Hint and
of your own motivational design.
You have access to a
that is kept with the document.
This lets you track preferences
of progress as the learner moves
And Playground Books
Every change made is kept
from the main document content.
And if the learner so chooses,
to the state it was when
The entire document
Every page will be pristine.
The key/value store
Assessments reset.
And they're ready
And last, but certainly not
you can see the documentation
We want to make sure that
so that you can work on your
workflows to make
Start with the examples
Dig into all that, and even
produced by our content
There you go.
So now I'd like to
that I have created to show
from an author's perspective.
So my audience for this
for you is someone
and even used Playgrounds
but now they're new to the
and they'd like to know
My goal with this
to build a living reference
always-on live view works
So let's get started.
What better way to
of Playground Books than
that demonstrates the new
We're very self-referential
All right.
So let's get started.
Now we have here the
I'm going to bring up my
to the Live View"
And you can see immediately
Notice that the code
on the editor has not even been
at all, yet we have
with the code I've written
for the always-on live view
face here.
I'd like you to meet Em.
My helper here is a
to recognize knock, knock jokes.
So we can see here on
our goal is to just play around.
I don't want to burden the
of how we're actually
over to the live view.
I just want you to
with this fun little
What we're going to
to send messages using this
These strings will be passed
and they'll advance the
that is running for Em
as the jokes continue.
So we'll start here.
We have a string already filled
out for us called
I'll just tap Run My Code, and
The code on the left
The special magic happened
and the string was
And we'll brush away the
So let's continue.
I'm going to say, "Boo."
And I'm using the
because I don't want
with the on-screen keyboard.
I will send this string
"Boo! Who?"
"Are you crying?"
Tap Run My Code.
[ Laughter ]
And Em has correctly
knock joke as a classic.
Let's try one more to see
I need to restart Em's
So I'm going to start by
I'll tap Run My Code to compile
over the wire to the other side.
"Who's there?"
UInt, which is Swift's
"UInt who?"
"UInterested in my
[ Laughter ]
That sounds like some
on this assessment here.
That's unfortunate.
But what we have here is a way
And when you're ready, you
where the magic dust
and you can see exactly how
This is all it takes
over to the live view process,
in a few minutes here.
But here, what we have
that progressively explores
from the author's perspective.
You can continue on to further
to send more complex
You can configure it
and punch line joke patterns.
You can even save these joke
to load them when you
after the next time you
So this Playground Book
with our session materials.
I encourage you to check
But right now, we're going
and see how this thing works
So Playground Books are a
towards teaching these
that we have on the iPad.
They're a folder with the
that is treated as a document
You edit these on your Mac with
You can use Xcode, your
Use your version control system,
build your own custom
if you need to, to be able
to produce content
And we're going to walk
assembled together.
The package contains
and Swift code assets
that make everything work.
And here's an overview
We're going to refer back to
of see how everything
At the very root of
you have a folder
and as you would guess, this is
where you put your
Moving inside, you will
if you've authored
Sources is where you put the
to have compiled and made
in your Playground Book.
You don't even have to import
Anything that's declared as
as soon as you open the page.
And then Resources holds the
Place your images, your
that you need to
and they'd be pulled
Note that these two folders
of this document
in them is made available to
If you choose to, you can
by putting a Sources and
or even individual pages.
You don't have to
across every other page.
It's up to you.
Customization there,
The next folder we're visiting
and as you would expect,
which are themselves folders
and each page is a folder
that you interact with when
in the app.
This first file we're going
to see here is called
It's a special configuration
up how the page will work.
If you open this file, it
We'll go through
Now, manifest files are property
and values that Swift Playground
with a document is
These manifest files
and the document level as
like the order of things
We're just going to focus
because it has the most
in the demonstration,
of these configuration
on the page.
The first key in the property
It sets the name at the top of
in the table of contents.
The next key, LiveViewMode,
when the page is first opened.
Usually, the live view is
in code or the learner
In this case, I want it to show
So by setting the string
by default, I get
PosterReference is a key that
up a file name in the
That file becomes a
up the live view area before
chance to run right
And as you can see here, as soon
to run, the poster
and we can see the live
The LiveViewEdgetoEdge
that determines whether
of the live view extends
of the viewport, and also
button, as you see here.
I wanted to that in my
If you set LiveViewEdgetoEdge
and you gave the live
this is what you'd see.
Note how it's inset
It's not covered up by
It's up to you which
depending on the
For instance, if you
that had full control
then setting LiveViewEdgetoEdge
to No would give
Playground logging mode controls
on the right side of every line
in the editor that
In my case, my live view does
that I need.
So I decided to set the
to the string value Off,
which turns off the
Now we've reached
of the Playground
This is where all
Let's take a look at this first
Now, all of you have interacted
Whether it's full screen
of the live view, as seen here,
whatever is in the editor
And when you tap the Run
and everything it
In my introduction page,
Contents.swift looks
At the top is Playground
to help describe
Your objectives, goals,
by the person going
to understand how they're
Those of you who've authored
recognize this.
It's the standard
And here, I have a few lines
up the page so that the real
but I don't want this
at least not on this page.
So I use these special magic
and end of a hidden code block.
Everything between these
It's executed along
but it is not visible
in Swift Playgrounds on iPad.
And the real work of the
with this statement, a
that was written above
Now I wanted to ensure that
down with this page
into this function parameter
that they wouldn't accidentally
So I'm using editable code
up with these special magic
and ending of an
and they can only
You can have as many of these
And the first time
only these areas can be
for what I need, and the
and they're just
And experienced Playground
placeholder syntax.
These angle brackets and
to show up in the editor.
The learner can tap on the
as they start typing,
with whatever they wanted.
This is a great way to give
to go in a certain spot.
So that's a good summary of what
a quick summary on
But now we're going
over to the right-hand
on in the always-on live view.
This introduction page has
This is what it looks like.
First we import
Now, those of you who've
familiar with XE Playground, the
to the page environment.
That's been renamed.
It's been new and improved.
It's called Playground Support,
and this is what you
So we ask, for the
and then we set the live
to be a fresh instance of this
Where did this
Well, it's part of
in the Sources directory at
This is the library of code
to share across all the pages.
Anything I put in here,
as it's marked as public.
Now, you could, if you want to,
write all of your live view code
There's nothing stopping
But then you have
to any other Playground
to share the same
Every page in my Playground
so I'm just using these
setup that make the
make the always-on
They're all sharing
and I just have to
across to any other page
Those of you who've authored
like you're looking at something
Isn't this how you would
if you were doing it from
Yes, it is, and you can
If you choose to, it runs
where all the code in the
That is really useful,
to the live view object.
You can take page.liveview,
and manipulate it
Call methods on it,
It's right there
But that means that the live
as the code in the
It will not start until the
It will stop as soon as
or starts typing
And it can't run if there's
that is currently being
So that is where the
and LiveView.swift comes in.
If this file -- if a file with
in your Playground Book page,
you automatically have
This file is executed as
and that makes it run
which is awesome, because that
Even if the code in the editor
The trade-off is that you
to an instance of
to it like you were
You have to use some sort
to send messages back and
to look into that next here.
Say we have this code
from Contents.swift,
of the code running
We want to send the
knock" to the other side.
So first thing we do is
We get access to
And when we ask for the
we don't cast it to
We cast it to this
PlaygroundRemoteLiveViewProxy.
The instance of this class
to hand things across the wire
And if this conditional
then that is your queue
in the main process that you
for this page.
Use this as that signal.
So assuming this all
We actually have a live view
We craft a message.
The message-sending mechanism
an enum that we'll kind of talk
But as you can probably guess
we're casting a string case with
"knock, knock," and then
and hand it over to the proxy,
calling the send
So the Contents.swift code
over to the live view proxy, and
that over to something
We need to wire up
so we can receive this message.
Somewhere in our
we've extended the
and we've said that
to the
protocol.
That means we must
that takes a PlaygroundValue.
This will be called, because
live view, because
to the page.liveview property.
That's what the live view
that this thing needs
Inside this message, we
and check to see
extracting any associated
I only care about strings right
if case let syntax, and then
the value of this enum is
And now, inside the if
Do something with it.
And in this case, we pass it off
to this function
that then advances Em's
So what if we want to
from the live view?
Say we set up something
and we get the string
How do we do that?
Well first, in the live view
that actually triggers the
to have a tap gesture
that will call us back
Once you tap on the face,
we craft the PlaygroundValue
with the associated literal
on self, passing this
Now, where did the
Well, by declaring
to this
protocol, it was
as a convenience, automatically.
Send is defined in
with a default implementation,
and because this class is
like this will just pass it
and it will make its way over
You tap on the face.
"Hello" is crafted, sent
and now then live view
that to something
Let's see how we could
There's a bit of set up we
code that you write
in Contents.swift will
as it reaches the
That's not what we
We're waiting for some sort of
at some later point in time,
so we need to first grab
and then tell it that
by setting the
property to true.
We asked for the live view
and now we need to have
as the delegate of that proxy
I'm just going to make
A class right in line.
Notice that it conforms
to the PlaygroundRemote
which means I have to implement
received method.
And that's it.
This will be called
with the Playground value that
if case let statement,
and inside we do
That defines the delegate.
Now we have to wire it up.
So we'll instantiate
to the proxy's delegate
and that completes the circle.
So now we have the
You tap on the face.
"Hello" is wrapped up
passed into the live view
to the delegate, that
and it receives the message, and
I want to quickly point out this
lot of options to statically
that we want to be able
between these two processes.
You can use these enum cases
in the last few slides.
Or you can define
into Playground values from
As an added bonus, the key
values too.
So the work done to get
of this model can be used both
and for saving statement.
So remember, Contents.swift
on the left-hand side.
It's what we call
And if you have a
in your Playground Book page,
in the separate always-on
in the process you
It's a different mechanism that
into our reference
to see how this thing works
so you can take advantage
Before we reach the
about authoring Playground
out one last detail
as an author of content.
When you play with your
and then you sync it back to
you'll notice at the top
up at the sibling
This is where all
into the editor are stored.
So don't be shocked when you
on your iPad, typing furiously
in the editor, and you think
but when you bring it back
the Contents.swift
like you authored it before.
Where's all the changes
That's by design.
The authored content
by Swift Playgrounds
Swift Playgrounds stores a
in this Edits folder, and
and this keeps the
and it's how the Playground
So that is a very
a subset of the underlying
up the new Playground
As mentioned, please go
grab the reference
the examples we have, take apart
by our content team.
It's all there, and we want
to make sure you have
to make awesome stuff.
Now I've led you through
that an author has when they're
But as you'd expect, this app
with on your own as
It's great stuff.
And next, I'd like to invite
of the things that
with Swift Playgrounds.
Izzy.
[ Applause ]
Thank you Jonathan.
That was awesome.
Now, we're going to jump
So like all of you, I've
of the features and
that have been announced
And in particular,
that I was really interested
is procedural content
The idea that a computer can
like a real world is
So when I saw that GameKit
I wanted to jump right in and
I wasn't quite sure what
at the new APIs, and I saw
that they added this function
and we have help in the app
that shows us all of
So if I tap Help here,
we can see that
that make it good for
such as clouds and terrains.
That sounds like
So I took this, and I just
and I turned it into an image.
So I wanted to look at my image.
So if we run our playground --
to Playgrounds on the
on the right-hand side,
For those of you who
as your playground executes,
And we can tap on this,
and it'll show a little
Now this a little bit small, so
to zoom in a little bit and
to think about the pixels.
We're going to talk
So now, I have a much bigger
in line with the Add
with our code as we scroll.
So now that this is
about our image a little bit.
So we generated our noise,
and we want to generate
So what we're going to do is
through this image, and
we want it to be a very
And when the image is bright,
we want that to be a very
So you can see in the
it's a very sort of dark area,
And in the bottom left
so it's going to be high.
So I wrote a just little
It takes an 8-bit grayscale
through the rows and the
for every position with the
which we're going to
Now, because we have a very
255 for the full range of 8-bit
So I wrote a small bucket
and just to prove to myself
of the possible values of
and you can see with our
to a nice stair step function.
So we just get a range from
And then we can go over
and then we end up with a graph
And this is interesting.
It's kind of cool looking, but
Like, you can see each point
in our image now has an
but it's not exactly
And normally, I would
I don't have the deep knowledge
from scratch the
and I don't have the 3D skills
but I happen to know
to Code playground has a
that I can use to progress
So I'm going to move over into
and we're going to already
So this is the Create
and if I just run
you can see that we're just
So I'm going to paste the
and I want to type for a
to hide the live view.
And here, where we have our --
where we just echoing
we want to turn this
So what we want to do is our
us with a world.
So in our world, we want
and y value that we're at.
And we're not taking
so we need to make a height,
and we want to call our
and then for our height, we
And I just love this
to do it one more time.
Then if we run this
oh. We forgot to add
So if we run this, you can see
that we're putting
And I can see pretty quickly
that this isn't quite
There's these weird
and I don't want that.
I'm not generating a fantasy
I want to generate something
So let's stop that
So these blank spots didn't
at first, but after a
it's clear that when our height
from 0 to 4 and not 1 to 5,
we're just not putting
So our 0 spot seemed like a
So if our height is less
we want to place water.
And now, if I tap If with our
we can add an L statement,
and just do what we
And this, I want to speed
So my world also
and I just want to
Let's
Oh, perfect.
All right, so let's run
So now you can see
So this is pretty cool.
[ Applause ]
We went from just sketching with
and then when we
we moved over into the
So the Learn to Code
very valuable tool for learners,
for seasoned developers
and develop ideas against.
So that was pretty cool.
Now you have the spectrum of
and that includes things
So I'm going to switch over to
And here, I have a playground
to talk to a peripheral.
I have a Sphero SPRK Plus here,
to place this on the ground,
because we need a
But what we can do,
the Sphero will light
And it's just moving
but I'm using Core Bluetooth
from my iPad, and
[ Applause ]
I want this to just be just
so I'm going to hide
And what I'm going to
So one of our other
we can just drag our array
[ Applause ]
And I'm going to make
You know, these colors right
but I can't quite
So in a rest function,
to iterate three of these.
And then instead of
we're going to set to color.
Let's bring our little
Let's run this.
Now we're changing colors
[ Applause ]
Stop. That was really fun.
Now I'm going to bring Matt
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much Izzy.
That is really cool.
So we've seen a lot today.
We started out with Max, who
of the great touch controls that
to interact with
that we've never been
Jonathan showed you how to
of the great new features
that way you progressively
and disclose content
And Izzy showed you that you're
that come in Learn to Code,
with the iOS SDK and
in the physical world or even
We think that you're going to
really cool things with Swift
to see what you do with it.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
We've got more information
on developer.apple.com.
We're session 408.
There are, of course,
some related sessions you might
Thank you so much everybody,