[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
My name is Zoltan.
Later my colleague, Eric,
We're both engineers
Software development
like conducting an orchestra.
You and I maintain suites
of them is not performing well,
we need to quickly understand
Okay. Maybe you're a
of thousands of tests.
Well, Xcode has tools
to conduct even the
and today we're going
First, we're going to
that haven't been addressed in
we'll introduce some
in Xcode Server, in particular,
the configurable
And then, we'll conclude with
Let's get started.
So, as a brief recap of testing,
as these four characters.
There's XC test.
That's the framework
for both Objective-C
And your tests are compiled
Xcode, that's the IDE
and you can also run individual
Xcode is also where
from both local test runs
And talking about Xcode Server,
that's the continuous
for your tests.
You set up bots to
and Xcode Server will
And if something goes
There's a great way to keep
So, Xcode Server is built
and you can use xcodebuild
You can run tests and see
Xcodebuild is the
continuous integration
So, you can learn more
in our previous sessions.
But, today, we want to
that we haven't covered before.
We want to take you
and show you exactly how
And to do that, it helps
After your tests are
That gets the test
And then, once the
you can see detailed progress
in your tests using a
So, we're going to look
hosting and observation.
Let's look at hosting first.
So, the hosting story,
on whether you have
So, for unit tests, your test
into your application.
And, in this case, we
host application.
But for your UI tests, your test
into a UI test runner which is
And in this case, we
as the target application.
Now, this has some implications.
For your unit tests, you
to your applications
but for your UI tests, you have
to access your application using
and see your application as a
For your unit tests, all
in the same launch of
So, you should be
up between test invocations.
But for your UI tests,
and relaunch the application.
So, that's great if you want
to test how your
Okay. That's hosting.
That's how your test gets
and once your tests are running,
then you can use a
to see detailed progress
So, let's zoom in
Here you can see two test cases,
And these test cases
Test suite corresponds to a
And you'll have multiple test
And maybe you're interested
in doing some setup work
Or perhaps doing
after all the tests
Or maybe you're interested
in doing some custom
Well, you can do that with the
You write an object that
and after registering it with
your object will
So, for instance, before
you'll get this BundleWillStart
And then, before
you'll get a SuiteWillStart
Then, for every test
you'll get this
and testCaseDidFinish call back.
If something goes awry,
you'll get this testCaseDidFail
And then, as the
you'll get this
and your final chance
in this testBundleWillFinish
So, here's an example.
This object conforms to
In the object initializer,
with a shared observation
Then, as the tests progress,
I'm going to log
When things go wrong with the
And then, once the show is
So, an ideal place to
in your test bundles info.plist.
So, you do that using
You add this NS principal
and this is a test specific
It's independent of the
Okay. That's hosting
They're useful concepts to help
tests are running
and to help you diagnose
Let's look at some new
Crashes are a frequent
and the crashes can be in
and the target application.
So, normally, Xcode will
to complete your test suite.
But it's up to you to gather
to resolve the crash.
I'm please to say that
to help with this issue.
We will now gather the crash
So, this is both for UI
and server runs of your tests.
The crash logs will be
And you can see the
of the crash there, or you
in the context of your source.
And I'd like to show
Eric and I have been
We've been working on a tvOS
So, I'll run the application
by control clicking
It's an application
with some strangely
I can move in the
on the keyboard here.
So, we're adding a new
to support users who have
Let me show you what it's
I'll go to the settings
I'll disable location services.
So, now, back in Xcode, we've
to support those users.
They can enter in a zip code.
Let me just add one more
So, I want these tests to
So, I'm going to go
and I'll duplicate
I'll call this something
And, in the settings
I'm going to disable
So, that's a technique to
It allows all the tests
without breaking
And it's similar to how your
So, I'll disable tests
to location services.
I'll share the scheme.
And then, I'll run the
So, here's a new
who have location
They can choose to
So, right now, the tests
and that's an unexpected crash.
So, right now, Xcode has
and it's reported
And, let's have a look at that.
So, here's the failed
to jump to the test report.
I'll disclose the
Here's the events as the tests
and here at the bottom
Now, I can click to see
of this crash, but in this case,
in the context of the source.
So, I'll click on
So, here's the exact line
And you can see in the
in the debug navigator.
Now, I can see the crash
and diagnose the issue.
So, I happen to know
to the wrong ViewController
Instead of parent, this should
So, I'll make that change,
by going to the test navigator
So, earlier, I showed
for a local test run, but that
same if it came from
So, now the tests are
Great. So, these
We would now check in this
that we're supporting users who
But, for now, let's
So, you've seen how Xcode will
and capture them
And you can choose to see
of those crashes, or
in the context of your source.
So, that's a great way
and to make the fix right in
So, we have some new
and to show you more,
Eric Dudiak, on stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
I'm Eric Dudiak, and I'm
about Xcode Server and what
So, let's go over a
of what we're going
in Xcode 8 with Xcode Server.
So, we have custom
that you can now
We have advanced
that we've improved in Xcode 8.
We also have some enhancements
to make sure you get
as they come up on your bot.
And we'll see how that plays
a new feature we have for you.
And finally, we'll talk
about the configurable
which is new in Xcode
So, let's jump right
about custom environment
Now, this is a little
It's actually new in Xcode
to configure the exact
to xcodebuild on your bot.
And it controls how your
so you can configure any number
for your bot to run on
than you might have locally.
This is a great way to customize
integrations, and it's a great
to create a lot of extra
Now, on to what's
So, we've significantly improved
So, we have two types of
First, let's talk a little
These run either
or after your integration, and
So, we've improved the editor
to see the scripts, and you
in them, so you have a lot
Along those lines, we also
This is great if
Your other teammates can see
supposed to be doing, and if you
scripts that are part of
you will see that
as Xcode's integrating.
So, when you see a project
you can actually see which
Finally, if you have a script
that you actually really wish
other scripts, you can now
Simply add a new script
and it will become the
Now, let's talk a little bit
about the other type
We have email notifications.
Historically, in Xcode Server,
this was always a one
which can leave you
So, in order to help you and
in your inbox, we've split
up into two different types.
We still have the report
that come out every time
Of alternatively, you
to run just once every
This way, no matter how
your email isn't flooded,
or your inbox isn't flooded
And we think this is great
up on the health of
but don't want all their inbox
Additionally, we also, now,
let you configure certain
So, you can configure
as your reply to fields.
This lets you have a lot more
of emails you're sending out.
Now, I hinted a little bit
have two different
The other is issues.
So, new issues come up.
We will now send you an email
for that particular issue.
We'll go over a little
But, if you do have more
of the code that
than you necessarily
we do let you filter
to make sure you're emailing
So, if we take a look at that.
If you have multiple
to only send emails
from certain repositories,
which domains all the
from that you want
you can add those right here.
So, let's take a minute and
or build issues anyways.
And, nobody is perfect and
That's the whole reason we
That's why we have unit tests.
We have unit tests
that they will inevitably fail.
That's why we write
We also, occasionally, commit
and some of us don't
and that's exactly
that continuous integration
And, in these types of cases,
and notify you that
But those aren't the only
Sometimes, even if you write
things can change around you.
That can be when you install a
of other new features, too.
You get new SDKs that might
You might get new issues
And, we like to make
that we ship is smarter than
So, you might see issues
that have always been
such as static analysis issues.
So, the important
of these emails is
to make sure it's
that you're receiving this
when it is because
that you can do something about.
So, the first type is if
And that's because you broke it.
So, this will call you out,
You'll see an email like this
that says you introduced
And we know this because
or near a line that you
We also might know if,
where the issue showed up, you
In that case, that's
that it's you that broke it.
Now, that's not always the case.
Take, for example, a
on top of a framework.
A change in the framework
in the application
to the application.
So, in this case, you'll see
like this, and it'll be a little
and will simply say
to help fix an issue on the bot.
And we know this because you
where the issue showed up.
So, we, essentially, assign
And, keep in mind, that this
than when we're directly
So, expect this email to go out
It casts a very wide net
out who might be of interest
Now, that's great for issues
but sometimes, you can
up regardless of code changes.
One of the easiest ways
by reconfiguring your bot.
So, Xcode 8 or Xcode Server in
to your bot configuration
Whenever possible, we will
that come up to changes
such as if you enable testing
Those types of issues may have
but we can actually attribute
in the configuration
than a change in your code.
We also make sure to include
for the next integration,
of these emails, you know that
because you're picking up
Let's go back to something
of installing a new
of new features in the process.
Well, when that happens,
on Xcode 8 will actually
and we call this an
We take the exact same revision
of all your repositories and
rebuild everything, rerun
and when this happens, we
up in your project at this
are specifically
since we took the exact
This saves you a ton of time
in your source code
because the issues came up
So, that's some of the new
but I want to talk a little bit
in Xcode Server and
configurable integration user.
So, we now give you full control
of the macOS user that's
And this gives you a lot
into how your integrations
and more to the point,
to configure exactly how
Historically, in Xcode Server,
that was running all of your
You wouldn't have
and you wouldn't be
This meant that you were
no matter what, and you
Now, you'll own and
You will be given the password.
This user will be a
It'll be any user on the system.
Can be anyone you want.
We suggest a new user.
But it will available
and it's fast user switching.
So, you can log in to that user.
You will notice you're
through a menu extra that
integration icon.
We'll see that in just a minute.
Let's go over how you
So, here I've opened the server
and in order to enable
I need to go ahead
So, I'll choose a new Xcode
and I'll be presented with
up which integration user I
to go ahead and create
for running integrations.
I'll go ahead and give it a name
and a password, normal
And I'm going to leave
And when I push "create user,"
and do a little bit of work
in the background while
to run integrations, and once
we're going to be
Now, we are asked to log in
to go ahead and run a little
Remember, it is a real,
So I can log in, I can sign
into a test iCloud
I can stage any data that I want
Anything like that.
When Xcode's ready
you will see a notification
in the top right here, and in
you'll notice that there is
that this is the Xcode
With that all done, I can
and I'll be back in server app,
that the user is ready
and integrations
So, now, we've seen how
Let's take a look at some of
that we have access to
And for that, let's go
All right.
Here we have that same
and we saw an issue
because it didn't have
And we had to go in
and turn off location
But, as we're developing
we might not want to do that.
We probably want to leave
on on our Apple TVs
so that we're running,
of our users will see it and
But, now that we've fixed
we definitely don't want
and we want to be
So, it just so happens that
on right now, happens
So, I don't have to go
I can actually just go to
and I see that have a
integration user
And I'm just going to
and enter my super-secret
characters long.
And we will log in as this user.
So, I've gone ahead and
so that I know that it's
And, here we see the hammer
that this is Xcode Server.
We see it's on and
So, it's all configured,
but I want to go ahead
So, I can actually configure any
on this user, and they will be
So, I'm going to use
If I go to the devices
and simulators that are plugged
Now, being generous at
of every device we've ever
for you, for absolutely free,
by clicking this
Now, the Apple TV 1080p
that I got when I
I've gone ahead and created
location, and I've
And if I go in, I can double
has location services
So, I go to settings,
Location services is turned off.
So, this simulator is
and my other one's still usable
for when I want location
Now, let's do a quick
and just log back
Normally, I'd be
to my actual work machine,
And here we see all
Now, I already have a bot that's
but I want to go
that will integrate
where we don't have
So, I'm going to go
and use the Harmony no
Going to go ahead and
access to my repository so
I'm going to disable
because this will be the
So, I don't care about that,
And, let's leave
And I want to be notified
but probably once a
So, I'll know within 24 hours
our UI test will catch
So, we'll just run it every
to select the devices.
By default, every integration
So, this is a tvOS
on all tvOS devices
Instead, let's do specific TV
to select the Apple
This is that environment
about earlier.
I don't have any
I'm going to go ahead and
when a new issue comes up
and go ahead and create the bot.
So, that is going to go ahead
which we see running here.
It's checking out building.
We've already seen the
so let's actually
that I prebaked a
And if we go to the test,
we can see that it did run all
code test.
And we can see, if I look at
it is, indeed, running without
that ViewController
So, we saw how you were able
to get significantly
into how your user runs.
You can log in as them and see
We saw how you could
such as simulators to run
that you want to run
We saw this was a
that I was able to switch
and that I had the password to.
And, we got to see
that shows you a little bit
in that integration user.
Now, with this great new
of responsibility, and so
for you.
First, we highly recommend
You want this to be as similar
as possible, so you don't
to be causing impact
We also recommend you avoid
Keep in mind that anyone
on your serve will have
through triggers, so
for any private or
Try to avoid storing
If you want to stay logged in
use fast user switching.
Integrations can continue to run
in the background just
However, if you do want
as the front most user,
make sure that you
Just like iOS screen
so does macOS screen lock.
And finally, make
for whatever needs you have.
That includes, as we saw
If you have any specific
that you need for
any stage user data or settings
go ahead and configure those.
And finally, if you have
such as if your administrator
profile, however you
you can actually configure
that in your configurable
and make sure that code
So, with that, I'm going to
about some new features
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Eric.
So, you've seen new features
and now we have new features
xcodebuild has the test action
for custom continuous
You give it a workspace, a
and xcodebuild will
It will install built products
It will run your tests,
to you on the command line.
So, this year, we're introducing
With the only testing option,
you can effectively
that the action will run.
So, you can specify TestCases or
to the exclusion of other tests.
And you can also use
to specify TestCases to exclude
from the tests while
And the big news this year is
that we're introducing two
So, we're effectively splitting
These actions are already
but we're going to bring
And so, we'll look
Build for testing is just
of the test action.
So, you give it a workspace,
as before, and it will
perhaps making certain
and then it will output the
It also produces
It's a kind of manifest
for everything your
We'll come back to
Test without building then, is
You give it a workspace,
and a destination, as before.
And, xcodebuild will find the
It will install those
and then run your tests and
But the cool thing
to provide a workspace.
Instead, you can just
and Xcode will run your
So, it will ingest
It will find binary products
and then it will run the
in exactly the same
but without having any
So, this is ideal
for distributed testing
You would build your tests
for building, and then
onto machines optimized
And then, in parallel, you
So, this is all made possible
that manifest for your tests
to run and which to skip
It provides environment
and command line
and you can read
in our man pages
[ Applause ]
So, we covered a
We first reviewed testing in
and then we looked at some
They were great for diagnosing
and then we introduced
in Xcode Server,
I hope these insights and
to develop test suites which
that will help you
You can read more about
Thank you.
[ Applause ]