[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
And welcome to Visual
I'm Chris, and I work
You know, debugging tools
It wasn't all that long ago
when our debugging tools
A little while later,
our debugging tools began
But fast-forward to today,
and our debugging tools have
at the same time becoming
A big part of this is because
visual, which helps us
and more intuitively.
Today, my colleagues and
about the latest in Xcode's
First, a quick overview
We're going to tell you about a
to report on issues detected
We're going to tell you
that we've made to
and how we've made auto
than ever before.
We're going to tell you about
to visually debug state machines
to the FPS performance gauge to
and SceneKit frame rate issues.
Finally, we're going to tell you
a visual memory graph debugger.
Let's get started by
We all know that
such as compiler
and static analysis
by Xcode's user interface
for our issues detected
However, the same can't be
by our expanding suite
of runtime debugging
These tools have
with their best option being to
Not the best experience.
We thought we could
In Xcode 8, we're
[ Applause ]
Runtime issues elevates the
at runtime to the
as traditional build
The Activity Viewer will
when any runtime
along with the number
We've enhanced the
with a new runtime scope.
This separates the
from the traditional
such as compiler
and static analysis issues.
So what issues will you expect
In Xcode 8, we're
The first -- threading issues.
Our brand-new Thread
to detect threading issues in
UI layout issues.
We've expanded Xcode's
to automatically detect
in your app at runtime.
And memory.
Our brand-new memory
which we'll talk a lot more
is able to automatically
in your application at runtime.
So, as you heard
Xcode's latest runtime sanitizer
Thread Sanitizer
and better understand
in your applications at runtime.
It can detect such
uses of uninitialized mutexes,
thread leaks, and unsafe
If any of these issues
they'll be reported
Thread Sanitizer is a powerful
You can learn all about it by
and Static Analysis session.
View debugging is
of Xcode's debugging tools
Only in the last couple of
we've gone from having
in a console like this to this.
Xcode's visual view debugger
for debugging and
If you haven't used it before,
while Xcode is running
just tap the Debug
down in the Debug Bar.
Xcode will snapshot
snapshot your view
out in an interactive 3D scene.
From there, you can inspect the
in the 3D canvas and
And you can inspect the
and constraints using
In Xcode 8, we've made view
Better than ever.
[ Applause ]
Snapshots are now
So you can go from
to debugging UI issues
[ Applause ]
The rendering of complex layouts
and transformed views is much
And speaking of accuracy, Xcode
such as visual effect views with
So what you see in Xcode's
reflects what you see on device.
You'll see the blur rendering
We've added conveniences, such
to the source code
Just tap the Jump button
And navigator filtering is
You can filter by
or text in a button's title.
Or you can filter
and that will include
For example, if you filter by
of the subclasses of UI
You can even filter
So you can quickly find
by knowing its address
We've got some great
for auto layout debugging
We show many more properties
in the inspectors,
and constraints are better
We now render badges
to represent inequality or
And we render non-required
so you can easily
and non-required
But my favorite new feature
in conjunction with
Xcode is now able
to automatically detect
in your view hierarchy
[ Applause ]
So how does this work?
While snapshotting
Xcode will inspect every
to accurately determine if any
of those views have
along with the reason
If any layout issues
they'll be reported
So you'll see them indicated
and you'll see them listed
in the Issue Navigator
Furthermore, the view hierarchy
that have layout issues,
in the context of the
For a selected view, the Size
of any layout issues, along
that participated in the
We're really excited about
to automatically detect
at runtime.
And I'd love to give you a demo.
So I have an iPhone here,
and I've got it connected
We've got Xcode up and running
That's one of our
that we've updated
On the right, I'm just
to stream the device's
to the desktop so
Our team was tasked with adding
to DemoBots, so we implemented
However, we had some issues that
So now is a great opportunity
I'll tap How To Play.
And this is our How
Not so great is it?
Obviously, we have some
We can see the DemoBots logo at
of mangled text rendered on top.
So we need to debug this.
Where do we start?
I'll give you some clues.
DemoBots is a little arcade
but this screen has been laid
So a good place to start
at the structure of the view
So let's do that now.
If I return to Xcode,
we can use the Debug
which I'll click now.
And that pauses the application
and snapshots the
In the editor, we now get back
of what we were seeing
And then to look under
all we need to do is
and we get the whole
out for us in the 3D view.
[ Applause ]
Here, we can see all
up this particular screen
container views, visual
that make up the How
Let's zoom in on those.
We see the DemoBots
and then a bunch of
And we quickly get some insight
for the mess we see on screen.
All of these views
out one on top of the other.
So we've got a layout issue.
Now our traditional workflow
of these views and their
and determine the reason
But in Xcode 8, we
information available.
Notice up here in the Activity
that we have some
We could click on that
to the issue navigator.
But you may also notice
in the Debug Navigator,
Xcode has badged some
And that's telling us that
So let's go straight to here.
If I select the first view,
that highlights the view
And let's open the Size
over here on the right.
Here, we can see
under constraints the
This view has an
Now that means that auto layout
to be able to unambiguously
in the vertical dimension.
Typically, constraints
Let's have a look
That has the same issue --
And so does the next one.
If I randomly click
it looks like they all
What I find curious is
in this list is not
So that could be a clue when
Let's go to that now.
If I select the Parent
of InstructionsLayoutView,
for laying out this
So let's jump to the
An easy way to do that
And over here on the
in the Object Inspector a button
to the source code
So we'll do that now.
We'll close the Inspector
And let's take a
for InstructionsLayoutView.
It starts by iterating
of the instructions, which
which describe section headers,
And the code lays these
So for each part, we fix
to the view hierarchy.
Then we have some code
But we didn't notice any
so let's skip over that
Here, we have two paths.
The first is for the very
to the top of the container.
Well, we already noted that the
as having any issues.
So, that constraint we
So let's jump to the other
Here, we're evaluating an
And if we have it, we assign it
And then we can constrain each
It looks like this is the
So let's have a look at
becoming true.
If we select previousPartView
I'll use Command-A to
and Command-F to
Let's look for instances
We see it's defined at the top.
It's set to "nil" before
We evaluate it down here,
and then we evaluate it
to handle the bottom constraint.
But it looks like we're
So let's quickly fix that.
So at the end of the loop,
to the current partView.
And then on each iteration,
we'll have the previous
which will be assigned
And we'll set up the constraint
Let's stop and rerun
And I'll bring QuickTime
Just note how much
to give us before
We use view debugger to look
and get some insight
But more than that,
about some layout issues
which views had issues,
and specifically what
So that gave us a lot of insight
so we could quickly
of the code that we needed to.
Now that our application is
And there, it looks much better.
We have a nice-looking
[ Applause ]
So Xcode is now able to
at runtime using the same UI as
Xcode's view debugger has
including faster snapshotting
of complex layouts
We've got some great enhancement
for auto layout debugging
In particular, Xcode is now able
to automatically detect
at runtime.
Xcode's view debugger
on Mac OS, iOS, and tvOS.
Give it a try with your
to hear feedback
with your debugging workflow.
And with that, I'd like to
to tell us about debugging state
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Chris.
Today, I'll be showing you a
debugging experience with
as well as some additions made
for Xcode 8.
Today, we have a number
of useful Quick Looks already
and these provide you the
of objects live during
And you can even provide
to view objects within your app.
And now in Xcode 8,
we're extending our
to include state machines.
So let's first dive into what
and how you could use
So, many of you may already be
which was part of our release
And it's available on
State machines allow you to more
by structuring it
And within a state machine,
you provide discrete
This could be something
that will play, or something
And then for each state,
by which the state
from one state to another.
Once assembled, state
sophisticated behavior.
However, they can quickly become
as they expand in complexity.
And simple state machines
into far more elaborate ones.
In Xcode 7.3, our support
for debugging state machines was
as well as its transitions.
However, now in Xcode 8,
we're able to visualize
so that you can see
This is incredibly useful
with very simple state machines
with much more complex
With Quick Look, you're able to
and evaluate exactly
within your state machines.
So, now, let's shift our
Any time you're creating any
maintaining good
And in Xcode 8, we've expanded
to help you with this.
Many of you may already
of the FPS performance
And at the top of the report,
of real-time statistics.
This includes your frame rate,
of frames being rendered
as well as your GPU
of your GPU are being used
for both the CPU and the GPU.
This helps indicate
to you whether you may be
Now, in addition to
Xcode 8 now provides
of your SpriteKit and
for both the CPU and the GPU.
This is available
And what's great about this is
that we breakdown your CPU frame
so you're able to see
rendering, or running
or evaluating actions
and even how much
And when your app is
through the history of
so that you can see
as you progress through
And if there's a particular
you can dive deeper to
and get some exact timings.
So let's take a look at how we
So now that we've addressed the
In our How To Play
and dive into the game itself.
The objective of our
of the corrupted robots within
And to do this, I have
and reconfigure them
Now we see here I've already
after me, so I'll use
So you see he's been converted
to a good robot --
But I see that we still have
above our character, and
Now since we're using a state
of our beam, this
to use the State Machine
out what's going on here.
So I'll go ahead and pause
to our BeamComponent.
Now our BeamComponent
and update our state machine
that manages the
And I'll add a breakpoint
and resume our game
that break point immediately.
So now that we're paused,
and find our instance
and we can Quick Look it.
And from here, we can see
In blue, we see the
which is the BeamFiringState.
And in gray, we see all
that comprise our state machine.
Now we also see the transitions
And one thing that I've
that we have a number
into our BeamFiringState but we
So this means, as soon as we
we have no way of leaving it.
So let's go ahead and take a
to see what's going on here.
So I'll remove our breakpoint
and switch to our
Now we'll take a look
And I see here we have some
into the CoolingState as
But down here in our method
where we're checking whether the
to is valid, we're
which shouldn't be the case
to either cooling or idle.
So I'll go ahead and fix that by
trying to transition to is
And we'll go ahead
and check whether this
that we were seeing.
Now when we transition
and meet the conditions to exit
to transition back
So I'll jump back into the
at the corrupted robot to
And we'll see the beam is no
so it looks like we've
So now we've also noticed
within our game.
We have a number of ground
And I notice that when
our performance drops
So I'll switch to our
so that we can see our
we're running.
And you can see on the
to you your target frame time.
And in our case, it's 16.6
to maintaining a frame rate
We can also see that
of our time is spent rendering,
as well as running
and we've got a good amount of
So I'll go into our game
where we have an enemy robot,
so that we can try to reproduce
So now I'll switch back
to see what's going on
And I'm noticing
of time is spent
In fact, now our frame rate is
So I'll go ahead
so that we can take a closer
Now that we're paused, I
within our frame breakdown
to see our frame time
In fact, here we can see
in the main menu where we spent
but most of it was spent idle,
as well as the breakdown we
And now when we are seeing
and hold to examine details
for the performance
Here, I see we're getting
and 71% of that is spent
So what that tells me
of two issues present
We could have a single action
within our scene that's taking
of time to evaluate, or we
of actions that's
So now I know where within our
So we've seen how we can use
to debug an issue we were
as well as how the FPS
where exactly within our update
I'd like to now invite
who will show you a new memory
to determine where our issue
from so we can fix it.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tyler.
So I'm very excited to tell you
about the new memory
And like the view debugger,
it's a tool for understanding
So just as the view debugger
the memory graph debugger helps
and how it's referencing
The core question though that
why does a certain object
Now objects reference
And, you know, this is more and
and annotation these days
in an automatic
So where can we go from
that we don't want, objects
Well, there's some
that can help, such as Heap.
And what Heap does is it
looks through it for a
and the counts of objects
And you can even use the
for a specific type of object
and get a list of
Once you have an instance
leaks is where you go
of information of, well,
Is it leaked?
Or is there some path
in your application that goes
Now, at any point in
you might need some
such as the allocation
And, that, you can get
And this is all not a
and that's why we pulled all of
for the memory graph debugger.
And so just a quick overview of,
On the left, the Navigator is
of information to
The center editor area is
where the connectivity
And on the right -- that's
the allocation stack
So with that, I'd just like to
where Tyler left off and
at those action problems
All right.
So here we are with the FPS
you know, actions
at fault here in
So I'm just going to jump right
in by choosing the Memory
in the Debug Menu Bar.
And on the left here,
the Navigator shows me
of the different types
And so they're broken
of module and then type.
And then under each of
And so, in this case, I'm kind
of interested in
And it's very easy to do.
I can just type into the filter,
So here we are.
We've got types in SpriteKit.
And we see that, yeah, we
So it's probably that we
that we have some
So let me select one
And the editor changes to show
of why this object
In this case, it's showing
which allows me to trace the
to the left, back to the
So I can see that
by an SKC sequence by repeat.
There's an array
And I can even disclose
that here we've got an
So, OK, it's part of
I can click on this and
If I want to take some
I can select it and
Now the Inspector shows
such as the class name,
if it is a sub-class
What I'm interested in is
so I can jump to there.
I can go ahead and collapse this
And here, we see I've got this
All right, so it's
I can use the Quick Help to
to the list of actions
But I actually wanted to only
and make sure that this was
So it's a pretty simple fix.
I'm just going to use
and replace the player action.
And the Quick Help
this is actually the
If an action using the same
it is removed before
Great. So that's a pretty simple
about a specific type.
But one of the other
when I hit the Memory
that the Runtime Issues
to some issues.
So I can click on that.
And now I'm taken to the
which has a bunch of leaks that
So I'll start out with a type
say, this LoadSceneOperation.
If I select it, now the
that same style.
It's showing me a
which is because this
It's not reachable from those
And I need to find
in the leaked set are
So looking at this
with some internal state.
It's referencing a
And then this has some
that strongly referenced
Interesting.
So if I click on the block,
and go immediately there.
And here we are --
my LoadSceneOperation
I'm even using a capture
But the graph showed me that
It was the LoadSceneOperation
within the block.
So it's a pretty
I just need to capture
and I can get going again.
But, unfortunately, that's
Because, since it's
my LoadSceneOperation
And so once it executes
the LoadSceneOperation is
and it won't be around
This means that when I dispatch
this LoadSceneOperation
and I'm going to get a crash.
So it just goes to show that
at times and require a
And hopefully the memory
in your investigations as well.
[ Applause ]
So, let's talk a little bit more
about leaked and
The memory graph debugger is a
to inspect your target
This is so your application
and changing its state, and
of the world.
It also lets you do
or PO different objects as you
and it's available on
Now, as I showed in the demo,
there's two different
And the first one is that
which shows you for
maybe you've abandoned it --
how are different roots in
and currently-running threads
Now with the progressive
it lets you work back
to different intermediate
that should no longer be there.
For unreferenced
that's when you see
And the goal there is to help
referencing itself.
And it'll let you figure out,
So, for stack logging
in the Inspector, it's not
of the mallocs and frees
And so this is a diagnostic
Just going to the Scheme Editor
in the Diagnostics Tab
And it will record, again, all
so you can look them up later.
But for memory graph debugging,
of the malloc and frees.
And previous lifetimes
of a malloc block just
So, new in our current OSs is
And so this has a lower
to get this rich information
graph debugging.
So this will set the "lite"
in target environment.
So one other thing
about memory graph debugging is
that we've introduced a
Now, sometimes you'll
and you won't have the time
And so you may want to save
on your team take
So, from Xcode, you can
and select Export Memory Graph.
And what it'll do
of the connectivity information
as well as some VM statistics
about your application
Then at some later time,
load that file in the Xcode, and
Now this does mean that there's
So you can't get back traces,
But it's still a very
for an app analyzing
Now if you want to build this
into your continuous
we've actually got some
So you can just run
and save out a .memgraph
So leaks, vmmap, and heap have
[ Applause ]
All right, now the fun part.
Let's talk about some usage tips
on the leaks infrastructure.
Now what this means is
We're trying very, very
as leaked when they're not.
And so in that attempt
there may be some
that you see in the graph.
Now these references will show
They may be valid
We may not just have metadata
And so take them
as you're reading these graphs.
Now one thing you can do
to enable Malloc Scribble,
which is another
And this will mean that
it will write over the
that uninitialized
So for references that are known
up as bold in the graph.
And Swift 3 actually has
metadata available.
And so I encourage
because it definitely is a
of understanding
And finally, I should put
out that the memory
that you temporarily
like Address Sanitizer
So this is a lot of information.
Where is a great place to get
Well, validate your
Are there more objects of a
Are objects being
Are there any leaks
Once you find an object
in investigating, then
that shouldn't be there
And two very common patterns
that you'll find are
and closures, or potentially
in your graph that need to be
So, that's a lot of information.
But I just want to thank
to our information about new
and improved visual
We're really excited
like the better visual debugging
with FPS gauge, and
So go out, try them
and solve a lot of issues.
[ Applause ]