[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
This is session 411,
My name is Chad Woolf.
&gt;&gt; And I'm Joe Grzywacz.
&gt;&gt; And we are performance
Now in last year's In Depth
Time Profiler.
And we showed you how to analyze
down to the disassembly level.
And our goal, then,
to make your code
Now at some point you may want
on multiple CPUs in order
But as you do this, you also
Now as the system
a couple of second-order effects
in preemption, lock contention,
Now any one of these
to potentially offset the
when you were doing
So in today's session,
to use system trace to analyze
And we're going to show you how
to efficiently load the
optimum performance.
So our session's going
We're going to talk a little
and why it applies to
And then Joe and I are going to
We're also going to talk a
signposts, some a little
and show you some
to get the most out
So why system trace for
Well, when your application
on the device, from the users'
They don't see your
with all these system
for shared resources
They just see your app.
And so if your app
of virtual memory
to maybe a misprioritized
to you looking for a fix.
So that's the bad news.
The good news is that when
on the device, it is the most
So the operating system knows
as much CPU time and memory
So when we talk about
we're not really talking about
about tuning your application
to use the resources
Now system trace is a
It works great in all
And when you take a recording
into a special tracing mode
that records all the scheduling
and virtual memory
Now this can accumulate
It could be a lot of data.
So one of the changes we
that we put the template into
And what that means
about the last five seconds
And the advantage here
you can start your recording,
take as long as you
to reproduce the
and when that performance
and you get that last
of actionable data.
Now this is what five seconds
These traces can
We found it's very
to correlate this data with some
of the high-level activities
such as am I updating
did I have a download
maybe am I updating a graph.
Those kind of high level things.
So this year in Instruments
of Interest instrument.
Now the Points of Interest
blank canvas where you tell
interesting and we'll put it
Now you do this using
And Signposts have been
but we used to have -- the
to call this direct system call
out of these header files
And it was kind of clunky.
Now on top of it being clucky
it just simply doesn't work.
So what we're going to do
But we have added in the new
functions to do the
And they're kdebug signpost.
So they work great from
and now SWIFT as well.
So to get started,
to drop a point event
That's one of those
And the way you do that
and that's it.
So inside of our Mouse Down,
every time we hit our
of these appear on the timeline.
Now it does take
The first one is a code that's
between 0 and 16383.
And it helps you
The next four arguments
and can be anything you want.
By default Instruments will just
Now you can name these things.
Just got to toggle over to
of the Instrument and
And so we have our code
So next time I take a recording,
of Interest are now Mouse Downs.
Now if you like Points
you'll also like
They're basically the same
and actions or things that
Now it's a little bit more
of one call you do have two.
You got a start and an end.
And you also have a pairing
Now by default it's a
It just uses the
to do is supply the same code
Now we know that
for all applications because
to issue a flurry of starts
And what that can be --
inside Instruments there
to pair those things up.
So we do allow you to
Come down here to
You can select Code and First
So Code and First Argument
and end have to have the same
So in this example what
of URL downloads in parallel,
and we've used the URL
as a first argument.
So now you can see
on the Instruments timeline.
If you use Code and Thread,
you have to issue
and end on the same thread.
And here's an example
But you can see it's
of a dispatch apply block.
So now we have four Regions
that are -- we've got one for
Now so far, the Regions
of Interest you've seen
It's all monochromatic.
But if you're willing to
you can come over here
that says use the last
And in your fourth argument,
of these enumerations
and those are the five
And in this example when
successfully, I've
And if it completes with
So you can see very
between pass and fail.
So now when we put
you can see how it's much
complicated trace I showed you
with the high level
So for example, you can see
that this flurry activity
by our download tasks.
So let's talk about our
We're going to be
for you guys called Graphasaurus
to Graphasaurus from
But just like last
we're going to be looking
So these are problems
when we were tuning
And we decided to
in an iOS application for demo.
There is a new graphing style.
This looks more like the state
in Instruments because
that we're tuning this year.
And another difference from
to assume that our code is --
and it's already optimal
And just like last year,
we're going to be
on the CPU using core graphics.
Now, what we did is we
And we found that to generate
It was going to take about
And that's in the worst case
Now that is larger than
if we wanted to hit
So we decided that
to introduce some parallelism.
Because what we know
of these graphs can be
And they take about five
So we're thinking if throw
and we have perfect scalability,
over here should be able to
To see how we did, show you
I'm going to turn
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Chad.
[ Applause ]
All right, so what
at here is a Quick Time mirror
of the iPad Pro I'm
So you can see just
you can pan around
But when I eventually
the animation gets just a little
It's not awful, but
So what I want to do now
So let's go to it here to Xcode.
And let's click and hold on the
So that'll build your
Install it on the device.
And then Instruments will come
where you decide how
I'm going to go ahead
on the System Trace template.
And now from here before I
and added some of the kdebug
to my code ahead of time.
And so I want to configure
of Instruments.
And so you do that down
in the Record settings.
And first off, I did want to
so I put some unique numbers
And I added three
Code 0 is CADisplayLink.
So that's that 60 hertz timer
So basically this region
to my frame time because this is
Next is Code 1, and that
So this one I'm actually
the rectangles and the
to be appearing on the screen.
Finally Code 2 is
So that's when I take those CG
into a CG bitmap context and
Finally, since my code's going
and they're going to be emitting
I need to tell Instruments
And in this case, the
since it'll be running
All right, so I did
I don't want to be
and again every time
So we go to file and
I'll give it a descriptive name.
Graphasaurus System
And now let's say you close this
you come back a week
to the template chooser,
there's your template
You don't have to redo
Just hit record.
Now Instruments is going
of reproduce the problem here.
So I'm just going to pinch out,
Pinch out where it
And then I'm going to just
for a couple of seconds so that
with the data I'm interested in.
And once I do that,
So now Instruments
of that data off the device
And since this was a
you only get those
Make sure that when you
you stop the recording
Otherwise, newer events are
of push out the stuff you
So we'll wait here for
And there we go.
So we're looking at a
So let's make this
so we can see what's going on.
All right, so this first
new Points of Interest
So let's zoom in on a
of see what we're looking at.
So now we can see there's
I see DisplayLink, the
And it looks like I'd expect.
I have my big blue
And inside there's four pairs
and rendering those graphs.
And so that looks good.
But when I mouse
you get a little tool tip
provided along with
And I'm actually running here
So it's about half of the
So that's not good.
But this was just one frame.
I rendered a ton.
So what does it look
Well, we come down here and
This is currently showing
of all those regions.
So you could look through
at the arguments and et cetera.
But we did a table here that
It's called the KDebug Interval
And when I select that
that Graphasaurus 2 emitted.
And we can see here's
I rendered 152 frames, and
about 28 milliseconds.
So yeah, in average,
You can see the min, the max,
the standard deviation
You can dive in with this
And now that'll give you a
Those are all the
that were my CADisplayLink
So I'm going to -- from
by anything you want,
whatever is important
Here I just want to
And then what I'm going
I'm going to pick one of
in the middle, and now
when I click on one
the graph view up above shifted.
And what happened was it went
and it made the region
Here it is.
And it put this blue
at the beginning of that region.
So you kind of correlate
on in the bottom with where it
So now I'm looking
You can also control-click
and choose set time filter.
And what that'll do
in the detail view that's
and it does the same up in
So you can use that to kind
that you're interested in
of a visual cue at the
So now that I've done that.
I'm looking at this frame.
I can see that my
It ended here.
But I don't really know
All this is telling you is
You don't know if your
if it went to sleep.
You can't tell from this graph.
So we need to dive in deeper.
Here in the top right of
we're currently on the
which is those list of all the
You could click here
to see all the threads
Alternatively, let's say we
at a thread in our detail view.
If you option-click, you'll see
of style that you
and choose Reveal
So that'll jump you
and preselect that
So we can see here, make
It selected the main
And if I look at
of other dispatch worker
And these two in particular,
and the one below it,
These are all those red
So if I option drag to zoom
we can actually start
by hovering over them.
Here, this is a ulock wake
up from some sort of lock.
Here's a ulock wait system call,
And if you keep hovering over
to see that pattern repeating.
There's a lot of this ulock
So if you click, you'll set that
And if you come down here
and narrative view,
it'll actually show you in that
up above, what was going on
All right, this is a list
of everything this thread
of this thread's life.
So here we can see one
Okay, well where
Whenever possible Instruments is
with those system events.
And you can find those
in the Extended Detail View.
So we can see I have some SWIFT
of it it's actually creating
Okay, and down below
where it's taking that lock.
Kind of unexpected, wasn't
of NSAttributedString,
So what are the ramifications
Let's go back over to the
and see what happens.
So it took us 109 microseconds
And then we blocked for
What's really cool this
which thread made
So basically who released that
And we can see that
by a Graphasaurus
Okay. And we can see that even
we still waiting another 98
give a CPU back.
All right, let's look at what
Why did he release that lock?
Option click on that, choose
That'll select that other thread
in the narrative view, we'll
at that time.
And we can see he was
So he was releasing that lock.
That makes sense.
So we can kind of see that we
in parallel, except they're kind
And so they're doing a bunch
of things besides
Another way to see that
We have those thread
Let me make this a
So if you hover over
you'll see it was
of time, 64 microseconds.
Then it was blocked
Then it was runnable
so that means it's
And then finally it runs.
And if we kept digging
we would see this pattern
And so what becomes clear is
over this lock.
And I'm creating a whole bunch
So if this is taking so much
why don't I see that
Well, truth be told if
at the time profiler,
But it's only like four
It didn't really stick
And a big reason for that is
because these threads are
in the blocked and
And time profiler only
on a CPU, so it's not
And so what I need to do to fix
I'm just putting some attributed
There's not that many states
I should just cash them ahead
up in a dictionary lock free.
And everything should
And to show you what that
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Okay, so what Joe is
Contention pattern.
And this is where we have
And they're contending for
in the attributed string
Now even though we're
for a few microseconds,
the performance impact is much
And Joe showed you
But I want to talk about
So when your thread is in
that the thread is on the CPU.
It's running its full stride,
and all of those
that you were making with a time
Now at some point, you
and then some short period
after that it puts the
And so what's happening here is
that that lock is being
and so it asks the kernel
and put you back when
sorry, when that lock
Now 3.42 microseconds
We do go into the
But now when we're in
this is the amount
to get back onto the CPU.
Now if you'll notice we're
for about 7 microseconds.
That's nearly twice
that that lock was
So we're getting a
Now another way to look at this
into the thread strategy,
create a time filter selection
and then change the detail
over here to the thread summary.
And what that will show you
thread state.
In this particular example,
we can see that our
about 82 percent of the time.
Now what that means is
that we're still getting some
We are getting some work
that linear scaling, perfect
We are still wasting
Now when Joe makes the fix
what's going to happen -- well,
The first one is that the update
to get a little shorter
when we're caching
But more importantly,
that thread is no running a
So you're going to get
So if you add a -- so if you
you're going to half the amount
And that's great.
So if you have a fix like that,
you should definitely
Now let's talk about preemption.
We didn't get to see any
it is something that shows
up quite frequently
And what preemption is is
of your thread from the CPU.
So some other higher
needed the CPUs.
There were none available,
and so your thread
Now there's an exception
There is a voluntary
that you might see
And that occurs inside
When a spin lock realizes it's
progress, it can call into
and essentially yield
over the holder of the lock.
And so what that looks
in the thread narrative
thread switch.
And then the preemption
that it was yielding
than being I think
So another lighter weight form
of preemption is called
And the interrupted state is
on a CPU and that CPU has to
So your thread is suspended.
The interrupt handler runs, and
Now at this point, the priority
You can have the
It really won't matter.
The interrupt will
Now the good news is that
a couple of microseconds.
And typically they won't add
of performance problem
But they do show up, so that's
Now another nice feature
of Instruments 8 is called a
And what that instrument does
in your system trace that
to dropped frames, for example.
Now it does that in two ways.
The first way is this
And this shows you a picture
of what the scheduling
All of the threads
to run underneath the
So you can tell that
in time, we had three threads.
One was a kernel thread and
And these are the threads
that were not blocked
You can see the core
Now the other feature of this
Interactive Load Average graph.
And what this is is a --
each one of these bars
window of time.
And the height of the bar is the
in that 10 millisecond period.
So that's threads that are
preempted, or interrupted.
Essentially threads
Now since it's the User
we only include threads that
or equal to 33 because
those are the threads with a
with the user interactive
Now to make it stand out
when the thread bars
that your load average has
on that particular device.
So wherever you see
you can see that that's a
So you might want to zoom in
that are orange, make
that you have running
at the right quality
Now when Joe makes this
up with a little
We're going to be able
And that new feature are these
to the hover labels that
except on Graphasaurus
And then the hover labels
So to show how that
I'm going to turn
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Chad.
So yeah, so I added the
went back to 60 frames
added the new generation
and things got slow again.
You can kind of tell there's a
and there.
So looked in at time profiler,
wasn't anything obvious
There wasn't any extra
So I went back and
that you're looking at here.
Before I took that
and added a new Signpost code,
to represent my GenToolTips
And you'll see that
So let's zoom in on one
All right, so we can see
these GenToolTips.
And so it's important
of describe how my
Basically whenever this
for every single
I go and do a dispatch
for that graph and
to go generate the tool tip
And I do that for every
But then I had kind of a clever
to kind of call my rendering
to wait for the tool
And so I do a dispatch group
And we can see that actually
Here's my start of my frame.
The CADisplayLink time.
We can see some of those
Let me scroll over to the right.
You can see actually
Actually, barely
until my render frame is done.
So it looks like
I can give myself
That looks nice.
However, when I look at my
it's taking 17.4 milliseconds.
Pretty close, but it's
So again, that was just
Let's look at what we
Let's go back to that KDebug
Here we can see our
I did about 260.
That's more than we did the
Sixteen milliseconds on average.
That's actually less
So that actually
However, this max is still
And if we look at all
let's sort this by duration
we can see here's
There's a bunch in the 18s.
There's some here in the 17s.
A lot in the 17s.
More in these upper 16s.
So we still have
that are actually
Not by much, but
That means we're going
So this time, where
We could go back to diving down
at all our threads and the
and thread events and
But whenever possible, well
bunch of instruments up here,
of like higher level aggregate
of useful to look at that first.
So before you go diving down
take a look at these
And so what I'm going to
at this User Interactive
That's part of that
And let's go ahead and zoom
so we can see all the data
And when we've done that, I'm
You can see there's a fair
Make this a little bit larger.
So you can see there's a
which means we have more user
than we have cores, right.
These are threads that are
to do, and I need to do it now.
Give me a CPU.
Well, we're running out of CPUs
and that's why our
So let's zoom on one
of orange over here.
You can tell what the value is
Zoom in a little bit.
So we can see this particular
on average there's about
that we're trying to run,
so about .8 threads
And that's why that's orange.
And we can see on
of regions here that
Here actually it's four.
We were trying to run twice as
So let's look at that
So let me scooch this
As Chad mentioned, you can see
trying to run in that
in the ruler view up
that blue inspection
and Instruments will tell you
to run during that
And if we come down
I'll sort it by the priority.
We can see, I looked right here
and there are two Graphasaurus
There's actually two location D
at a slightly lower priority.
And that's part of
You're going to see
and trying to do their work.
But it's okay.
They're running on a slightly
so I still have the
I do, however, have this
at the same time, well, trying
And he's not getting
And I know what these
The two of them are
And then I have the third
to do my generation
And so what's happening is one
of them is not able
And we can kind of
If we look at, say,
Let's go back up to that
You know, we could see
that we're doing our rendering
and the generation
so it gets a little
But what it's doing is when
it's taking away
And so basically I've kind
because when I stop and
I need that rendering
Being at that user interactive
because I want it to be nice and
But these tool tips, they're
I do want them done
as that user long
I want them to show up.
But they're not really as
And you can see it
They are definitely taking
that CPU resources from
being delayed.
And that's what's
out that CADisplayLink time.
So the fix for that is
Let's go over to Xcode.
So I have this view
And one of the things it does
We can see that created
This is where I do
And it's created with
One is, you know, it's
they can run on multiple
And it's set for the user
And that's that same QOS class
that my render work
so they're all contending
So like we said, it's not
so I'm going to change
You can read about the
in the header file.
I'm going to take it a
with the utility level class.
And what that'll do is give
to do my rendering work, and
of CPU time at the end
then the tool tips will run.
And they're still at a high
that user taps on the screen,
And so to show you what that
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Okay, so when
the graph's going
We're going to notice that our
down to about 12.7
which is much better
But even better still is
about 14.6 milliseconds.
So we're not dropping any
within our 16 millisecond
Now we're doing that in
to overload the system.
If you think about it,
we are still running
But because we've correctly
our Gen Tool Tips
down here at priority four.
So that's going to
of the User Interactive code.
So we're still getting a
We still have a very
But at the same time,
we're still getting a perfectly
So what is Quality
Quality of Service, in case
is an attribute that you attach
And it's basically an expression
of the system resources you're
that particular piece
Now the different Quality
of Service classes can
So you can see that our
down into a priority of four,
so in our User Interactive
in the high 30s, high 40s.
But the Quality of Service
like IO and also
that the code is running at.
So when you pick a Quality
make sure that you look through
and make sure that
of work that you're doing.
Now another thing that
of your application is
They do get a little
as memory pressure increases.
But the good news is
Now System Trace has all the
to analyze virtual
Inside the thread strategy,
as these little blue capsules.
Inside the thread narrative it
and even attaches a
that fault was resolved
Now we also have an
to analyzing virtual
So for example, you can see
where your code is
to one type of fault or another.
So for example, maybe
that is experiencing more zero
Now the next thing
about virtual memory faults
on access rather
So you can ask for a large
let's say 500 meg, but
that with physical memory
or accessing the pages of that
So it's something to think about
The other thing that's
about virtual memory faults is
So there's no explicit
to resolve a virtual
All you need to do is touch any
as requiring a fault, and
of your thread, resolve
and then give you control back.
And so when you see those blue
on the thread strategy that's
So what do you do about
your application?
Well the easiest thing
The easiest thing to do is
What I mean by that is leave
performance budget where you
of virtual memory faults
This will make you more
So as memory pressure increases,
and you have enough slack,
you won't notice the
Now we realize that some
of lax deadlines in terms
So another alternative is
on a background thread.
So let's say you have
and your player is coming
and they're going to
Well, what you might
to a background queue and then
of level two on that
And then by the time your
around to pick up that
no stutter.
Now, we'll have to give you a
Make sure you only
that you're absolutely
Because if you start touching
then you're actually going
And that about does it
We think that the System
to the Time Profiler.
The Time Profiler helps
but System Trace
to scale better under
We encourage you to try a System
We know that when we try
we always find something
And if you've used System Trace
to come back to Instruments
because we've done
to both the approachability
We think it'll make a great
For more information,
We have some related
that happened also happened
Enjoy the rest of your morning.