[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, I'm Anna.
Welcome to the Thread Sanitizer
Since our team works on
to tell you about new
I'm going to start with
of Address Sanitizer and
into Thread Sanitizer which is
this year.
Later, Devin is going
about the new checks we've added
But let's start.
Sanitizers, [inaudible]
that combine compile
and runtime monitoring
They're similar to Valgrind.
However, their main advantage is
that they have low
They work with Swift
and they have tight
So last year we've
to macOS and iOS.
This tool finds memory
and heap buffer overflows use
It's extremely effective
So if you're not using
highly, highly recommend it.
This year we've extended
to provide full support
Which will be especially
who love to live
So what does it mean if you
Run your test with Address
it will find some bugs for you.
Now, while Address
on memory corruption issues,
of bugs that are
These are even harder
They're sensitive to timing.
They might occur only in
which means that
that contain them will have
So this year we introduce
Thread Sanitizer which
and better understand
TSan reports mainly
so let's take a look
It will tell you about use
This might not seem
However, if you are
that is not appropriately
to very subtle bugs
because you're not actually
when you use such a mutex.
Another example are
If your application
and if those threads
and if there's memory leaks.
Another one unsafe
and unlocks from a wrong thread.
However, data races are by
because they're so
They happen when multiple
location without using
So let's see how this tool works
So here I'm going to demo
on an alpha version of
So here as you would expect,
it brings up a schedule
However, notice this
Even though all the session's
the network activity
Now, I know I use a global
and hide this indicator so there
Let's see if Thread
In order to turn on Thread
Choose diagnostics tab.
And click here on
Now, here you can choose
on every single issue and
Or you could choose
collect all the threading issues
and explore them later on.
The second workflow is new in
by Thread Sanitizer, so let's
When your launch application
Xcode is going to
with extra compiler
to launch it in a
to find threading issues.
So here is our application
And Xcode tells us that Thread
by displaying this
in the activity viewer.
Clicking on this purple
to the issue navigator.
And while previously
to display build time issues
compiler errors,
This year has been extended
to provide support
And this is where Thread
its home.
So Thread Sanitizer
Let's take a look at each one.
The first one is use
Now, this problem occurred
that application
Thread Sanitizer is going to
by providing a historical
Even though this is
you can walk its frames as
So let's take a look.
At some point we
That called pthread mutex lock,
and passed an invalid
That was called from
which was called
Now, as you can see here
but we initialize
It's a simple ordering bug.
So just reordering those
to statement should
Okay, let's go on to the second
Also, here Thread Sanitizer
on the variable called
Now, that's the same global
when to show and
Since this is a data race,
Thread Sanitizer will
The two race accesses.
A read and a write here.
So the read happened
and the write happened
Notice that neither of
and the stack traces
that they are probably
from multiple threads
So let's take a look.
Okay, here we are updating
Now, I could have fixed
But notice that this
The next line here
And we know that the UI
on the main thread.
So the proper fix here is
to dispatch both the counter
onto the main cue with
This will both take care
in our application and
because all the threads
that count variable
Now, I'm sure I sound
and you all believe me
However, the best way
to run the tool again
So we should rerun
with Thread Sanitizer turned on.
And again it's going
with this extra checking and
Now, the application is up.
We see that the strange
and Thread Sanitizer
So all is well.
Let's go back to slides.
[ Applause ]
So just to recap the demo, you
in the Scheme Editor when you
like you did with
In addition to ASan's workflow
on the very first issue,
Thread Sanitizer it
Where you could keep routing
and then you could explore
They will stay there until you
So let's now talk about what
to make this all work.
In order to use Thread
Xcode passes a special flag to
that instruct them to produce
This binary links to a TSan
by the instrumentation to
of the program and detect
So if you're building and
you can pass an option to
And Xcode will also
by providing
Now by default, TSan
as the errors are detected.
But you can instruct it to
by setting this TSan options
on error equals 1 when
That will allow you to have the
with Address Sanitizer.
So where can you use this tool?
Thread Sanitizer is
and in the 64-bit simulators.
It is not supported
So now you know how
how to launch it,
Let's talk about what, how you
And we'll focus mainly
because this is the biggest
So what is a data race?
Data race happens when multiple
location without using proper
at least one of those
And the problem here that
up with stale data, but the
You might even end up
So what are the reasons
Well, it often indicates that
in the structure
And only you will
On the other hand, it also means
that we are missing
So let's talk about
Here is an example of
We have a global variable data.
We have a producer
and a consumer that prints it.
If those two pieces
by two different threads,
So how about this code?
We introduce another variable
And we set that flag after we
and in the consumer we are going
and then if once it's
Well, this looks very logical.
It seems like it should work.
The problem here is what you see
The instructions here can be
or the CPU, so you cannot
after the data is updated.
The order of the instruction
in the producer nor
So what is the point
I just want to demonstrate
to roll your own synchronization
good idea.
What should we do instead?
We should use something
For example, Grand Central
You can dispatch
onto the same serial
that they execute it
and there will be no data race.
So now as you might recall
for both Objective-C and Swift.
So let's use Objective-C
Here is lazy initialization
And we are implementing
That makes sure that we return
to all of its callers.
Now, if this code is
without proper synchronization,
when both threads try to update
Okay, so what about this code?
We tried to fix the
and initializing
and then we are using atomic
to make sure that
that global variable.
So there will be no
This might look like a step
but this code still
So let's take a look at them.
First, it's very difficult to
when you are using atomics.
So, for example, here you
if you are using ARC.
And if you are using MRR, this
in case there is a race.
So that's not good.
That's not the only problem.
Another problem here is
that since the read
there could still be a race
to read that shared variable
and another one is trying
So this is undefined
What should you do instead?
I mean, if you know
use Grand Central Dispatch.
Dispatch wants performed
It's even simpler in Swift.
Both global variables and
one semantics.
So you can choose either
whatever works best
Okay, so just to summarize,
you should use the highest
to your needs.
And most people should be
If that's not suitable, you
for example, now, we do have a
on our platform this year,
And they also have
They are supported
But as you've seen in
they're very difficult
And besides the performance,
being here is either not
So don't choose to use those
that they actually have
So for more information
please attend Concurrent
So now let's talk
What are those?
Some developers argue that
for example x86, you do not
between a read and a write
because the architecture
of those operations
Now, it's important to
even at a benign
to be undefined behavior
So not only will you be
with benign races write, runs
on an architecture you have
But the compiler is free to
as if no other thread saw that.
So the bottom line
up with very subtle bugs.
So as our engineering lead
for Thread Sanitizer
[ Applause ]
Now, to the most
As we all know, data races are
so sensitive to timing.
So the most interesting thing
that it can detect races that
that particular program run.
Let's see how it does that.
When you compile your
it instruments every memory
with a check, with a code.
But first, records the
And second checks if that
So let's take a closer look.
For every aligned 8 bytes
Thread Sanitizer
keeps track up to four accesses.
So suppose we have four threads.
Thread one writes to
Thread sanitizer updates
to shadow thread to
Again, we record that, and
So now what happens if you
Thread Sanitizer uses
onto what cell to evict next.
So here it evicts access
which lets it not
However, if we had access
it would evict a random cell.
So bounding the number of
that we might not catch
Okay. Now, let's talk about
Thread sanitizer uses
of vector clocks
So how does that work?
Thread local storage for
of threads own counter
of all the other threads.
This counter is initialized
and every time a
its counter is incremented.
So, for example, here
memory locations.
Thread two accessed
Thread three accesses
Now, this timestamps
Each thread uses those
to order the accesses to
Okay. So let's go back and
and its shadow and see
and how they update
We'll also add the
to synchronize access
Okay, thread one writes.
It's a well behaved thread.
It's going to acquire a lock.
It's going to update
It's going to write to
Now, Thread Sanitizer sees that.
It's going to update the shadow.
Before updating the shadow,
in the shadow, stored in
that that memory location
So it just safe to go
Now before releasing the lock,
with its own timestamp,
Now, it's time for
Again, thread two is a
It's going to acquire the lock.
Now, acquiring a lock like
that thread one has
Now, thread two implements
it writes to that
Thread Sanitizer sees that it's
Now, here it sees that there
before, so that means
that memory location has
so it's going to
By comparing the timestamps,
that thread two has synchronized
after thread one has
So there is no data race.
And we can just proceed
Before releasing the lock,
with its own timestamp.
And it releases the lock.
Okay, now it's time for
Thread three has been
It's so excited to write
Guess what, it forgets the lock.
It implements the counter,
Thread Sanitizer is
It's trying to update the
So here the Thread Sanitizer
of thread three is too old.
The reads and writes stored
after thread three
This allows Thread
[ Applause ]
So what's important to know
that the sensitivity of
with data races does
TSan can detect races even if
that particular run
if you run your application
or your users run
And this makes using Thread
than debugging and trying to
in the [inaudible] without
Now, another thing
that Thread Sanitizer is a
so it will only catch races
if you provided sufficient
So please run all your tests
And that was Thread
Use it. It will find bugs,
it will make your
[ Applause ]
Now, off to Devin who will tell
to the Clang Static Analyzer.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Anna.
Unlike the sanitizers, the
without even running your code.
It does this by systematically
through the program.
This makes it great
to reproduce edge-case bugs.
It's supported for
that Clang compiles to, so
This year, we've added three now
A check for missing
a check for improper
in your manual retained
and a check for nullability
Let me tell you about them.
A common bug in localized
to localize a UI element.
This can be very
They'll be using your app
when all of a sudden,
in your language
This is not a good
So let me give you a demo
of how the Static Analyzer
Okay. So I'll demo
on the same app that Anna used.
To run the analyzer, you can go
to Xcode's product menu
This will explore a large number
and try to find a
Just like Thread
if the Static Analyzer
it will display this
in Xcode's activity bar.
If you click on it it will
so it looks like we have
A nonlocalized string is flowing
So we should localize it.
But looking at this method,
I don't see anything
So I'm going to click
This shows me more information
about how this nonlocalized
to the user-facing property.
I can explore this path
at the top of Xcode's editor.
Working my way backwards, I can
from a TableView
and then an intern it's passing
in this nonlocalized
So let's localize it.
To do so, I'll use the NS
This will load a
of the string at runtime.
Now, it's really important
to also include a comment
to help them correctly
So I will say "This
that resets the session filter."
Okay. Let's run the
to make sure we fixed the issue.
Looks great.
So I'll switch back to slides.
[ Applause ]
To recap, you can run the
and it will display any of
in the issue navigator.
As we saw, it's super
on that diagnostic
This makes it easy to
and ultimately how to fix it.
So the analyzer can now
as we saw.
But it will also warn us if
that comment to our translators.
Here I've provided a comment of
And so the analyzer will warn
about it you can
and other Static Analyzer checks
of your project's
The check for missing
on automatically by Xcode if
in more than one language.
The check for missing
but you should make
on if you don't communicate
to your translator
For example, you might
in your strings file.
This year we've also
in your manual retained
It's really important under
to not release instance
for assigned properties
If you do so, this can cause
of that value also releases
So the analyzer now
On the other hand, you must
that are synthesized for
Because if you don't,
The analyzer warns
Yeah!
[ Applause ]
So this is an awesome check.
It found a bug in every single
that we ran it on.
So try it out.
Of course, the best way to get
to update your project to
[ Applause ]
Fortunately, Xcode can help
If you go to the edit menu
and choose convert
This will have the compiler
of retained release for you.
Finally this year,
for nullability violations.
This builds on work from last
to indicate whether methods or
For example, Core Location's
This is because every
of a location also has a
In contrast, its floor
That's because this
when the location is in
location enabled.
You should annotate your
because it enables a
where you communicate
about nullability
This is important
of those expectations can cause
In fact, we thought it was
into Swift where the optional
for nil before using a value.
Now, it's important in
and so we've added a check
to the Static Analyzer.
And this check is
that mix Swift and
And it finds two
There might be logical
Maybe you're returning
Or you might have an
So let's take a look
of these two kinds of issues.
A common mistake is to
with nil and then later
of non-exhaustive branches.
This method, for example,
returns a short description
Either the name of a
that contains that location.
But we fail to consider
What if the location is
Then there will neither
And so this method will
And the analyzer will
Fortunately.
This is awesome, too.
[ Applause ]
Fortunately, the
All you need to do is
with a nonnil default.
In this case, we'll use the
of course, we'll make
On the other hand, it
in the implementation
and it's the annotation
And we found that one way
when you use the convenient
and end macros.
These macros wrap a portion of
of the reins that they wrap,
that types will be
This can save you
but it also makes it
to mark a property as nullable.
In this example, the
when the device doesn't
But the property is
Fortunately, the fix
We can simply explicitly
as nullable inside
And this will tell clients
that they shouldn't
to always be available.
Now, you do need to
That's because the nullability
And so you shouldn't change it
Instead, you should carefully
to expose and use that.
If you do decide to change
to carefully think about
This is particularly
where nullability changes
You might also find
where you can change
of your method nor
And in these cases, you can
with a cast.
One way that this commonly
that defensively return nil
In this example, the
when an index is out of bounds.
If there's existing code
then you can't remove that check
and you can't replace
Instead, the right thing
that that's what you meant
by casting the return
So that's what's new in the
[ Applause ]
So let's wrap up.
Today we told you about
These tools find real bugs.
Address Sanitizer and Thread
in threading issues at runtime.
And the Static Analyzer
without even running your code.
So please use these tools
They will help you find your
for you.
If you're interested
you can go to your
And there's also
that we think you
Thank you.
[ Applause ]