[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to Introduction
My name's Najla and I'm a
Along with my colleague Rick
through the essential
So Xcode is a development
for iOS, watchOS,
It gives you the tools
from designing your user
to testing and debugging
to provisioning your app for
So today we're going to take you
through the most
of Xcode by creating an app.
You'll learn how to create
in the simulator, how to test
how to review your changes and
and how to configure your
Now, we want this session to
to use Xcode and less
so the app that we're going
to be very simple, but
of the demo app fool you.
There's information in
whether you're brand
or an experienced developer.
So the best way to learn
so let's get started
So what you see here is
On the right, you can
and on the left, you
Let's create a new project.
And when you create a
you have a number of
and there are basically
for your application.
You can have, there
for all four platforms --
Now, I'm going to choose the
which is a single
for the iOS platform.
It's, it provides the code for,
to support an iOS
So let's name our project Hello,
and if you have a
you can add it here
Now, your organization name is
and your bundle identifier
of your organization name
It's a string that uniquely
Now, when you create a
you can choose between
as your programming language.
We're going to be using
to be universal, meaning
and support both
So when you create
there are different options
We're going to choose
Now, let's save our project
and I'm going to click
so that our project will be
under version control
Awesome, so here's our project.
I'm going to resize the window
Now, this is called
On the left is the
of your files and resources.
In the middle is the editor
that you've, that you
And on the right is the utility
contextual information based
in the navigator
Now, if you're brand
you're probably wondering,
what does this app
You can run your application
at the top of the main window.
But before we do that,
about what actually
So when you click Run,
to run here and where
Now, in your project, you can
or even multiple configurations
A scheme is how you
and it also contains information
For example, I could have
and a Watch app, and in that
to run my iOS app and one
Currently, we only have
It's called Hello, and
Now, your run destination
where you want your
and in Xcode, you
You can run your
or you can run it on a device.
A simulator simulates what
like on a device, and this is
iterative development and
on how your app is
Currently we have the iPhone
so let's click the Run
to run our scheme Hello on
So our application is
I said that we were going
to choose the simplest
and there's nothing here,
to make it a little
I'm going to stop the simulator
by clicking the Stop button
So in Xcode, you can lay
of your application in
Now, since we created our
we have a couple
We have a launch
and a main storyboard.
Your launch screen storyboard
for your launch screen, which is
when you launch an
And your main.storyboard
for the rest of your
So let's open main.storyboard.
In the storyboard, you have
which is this white background,
of your canvas, which
and it represents one
Now, for a feature, I want
but I also want to be able
so I'm going to implement
that when tapped says
So at the bottom of the utility
such as the file library and
Now, third icon from the left
which contains all
that you can add to your scene.
You can view them as
when you don't exactly know
and you want more information,
Now, I already know that I
in my scene, so I can use
of the utility area to
Let's drag it into our scene,
and guides appear to
Now, earlier I mentioned
so let's take a closer look at
Now, the first two, the file
they're available
no matter what you have selected
but since I have the buttons
the rest of the inspectors
about the button.
For example, I can click on
to get information about the
such as the size,
I can click on the size
to see information about
and the position in the scene.
I'm going to change this
and I can do this in the
but an easier way of doing
on the button and just
Great, so now we have
Let's go back to the filter
I'm going to drag
above the button
And once again, I can go back
or the size inspector to
but I like it the way it
One thing to note about our
that we haven't specified how
on the device that it's on.
Currently, we're viewing our
of the iPhone 6s simulator or
I can change it to
such as the iPhone SE device.
And here we can see
and our button actually
that we thought.
So let's go back
and we need to add some
to set some rules for how the
We can do this using
at the bottom of
So for our button, I want
and vertically centered in the
on the Align icon and set
and vertically in container.
Now we can see our
Now for my label, I also want
in the view, so I'm going
and check Horizontally
Now, when we did that, the
meaning that something
And at the top of the
there's actually an arrow that
about what went wrong.
And here we can see that we
for the label.
Now, I don't actually care
of this label is.
I just always want it
So what I can do is I can
Oops, we didn't select
So once your label is selected,
and pin the bottom of the
It's at our constraint,
I'm going to rerun it
if we have the behavior
So here's our user interface.
Looks pretty great.
What were to happen if
Well, with the simulator,
by clicking on Hardware and
Let's rotate left, and
Now, the great thing
that you can simulate a lot
such as rotation, shaking,
I'd recommend checking out
around with it because it
to do some quick testing
to pull out your device.
So now that our user
we need to add some code so
changes the label to say Hello.
Let's stop our simulator
about scenes and
So every scene in a storyboard
class, which contains code
I only have one scene in our app
and I only have one
in our navigator, so I can infer
that this scene is
in view controller's Swift.
But what if I had multiple
and multiple view
How would I know which
which view controller file?
Well, when you select a scene
on the identity inspector,
to the attributes inspector.
It actually lists which
So now we know for sure where
So I want to display
and our view controller files
by clicking on the
at the top of the main window.
It's looking a little
to create a little bit of room
by hiding the documents outline
by hiding the utility area
Now, one thing to note is
of our editor, it's called the
of useful information about the
about the files themselves.
Now, the great thing about
that it actually knows
which files are related to
in the primary editor and
in the assistant editor.
For example, if we opened our
in the primary editor,
up the generated
Now, another cool thing
that it actually, you can
that it's using by selecting
of the jump bar and changing
For example, you can change it
up all of the files that inherit
So let's go back to
by using the back
So we have our view
and we have our storyboard.
We need to create
and our label in our class.
Now, I can do this by selecting
so I have it selected.
I'm going to Control drag from
Now, I want this
which means that I want
when I tap the button.
And let's name it Say Hello.
Let's do the same
I actually want this
which means that it's a
and let's name it Hello Label.
So now we have references
We need to add some
that actually manipulates
Now, I think a label has a
but I'm not exactly sure, so
and Command Click in
So we, when we created our
it declared it as an instance
I can Option Click on this
to get a quick help description
and also its availability.
I can also Command Click on
to the, to where it's declared.
And if I just want to look
I can navigate to Help
and search for the class.
So I'll search for UI label,
overview, and all of the
So here it says that a
so that's what we can use
Let's close documentation
to our view controller file
in the jump bar and
So I want to manipulate
so I'll start typing that,
Xcode will provide suggestions
This is Xcode's code completion.
I can autocomplete
and I want to access
I can also autocomplete that.
And let's set it equal
So now we have some code.
We have our references.
Let's see if this
by rerunning it in
So our app is launching.
Here's our button,
Very exciting, right?
[ Applause ]
Yes [laughter].
So now you know how to create
how to add a simple feature, and
But it's very likely that you'll
on an existing project
than our button and label, so
Now that Rick and
we've been implementing
so I'd like to invite Rick
through the rest of Xcode's
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Najla.
So for the past week, we've been
We decided to write
so we could see what earthquakes
We're nearly done, and of
so that we could make
and I think we still have a
Let's take a look and dive
into Xcode's debugger
So to start out with, we need
to check our project
Xcode supports the Git
and Subversion source
To check out our project,
I can go to Xcode's
and choose the Check
This gives me Xcode's check
in the repository path, so
and our project is
I'll hit Next.
Xcode will give me
in my authentication
Whoops. And now Xcode
like to check it out, so our
I'll say Download, and
out of source control and
Now that we have a project
that the source control menu
We'll come back to
So to start out with, let's
We could browse through our
and try to manually
but there are some better ways.
At the top of the navigator
of different navigators.
These each give you
onto the content
One of these views is the find
I can search textually through
So for example, we know that
with the word Test, so
with the word Test.
Just hit Return.
And here Xcode has found every
in my project, including
and some comments
So that's great, but let's do
If I want to find just my test
These are where my symbols, like
Again, starting with
and here it's found
So the find navigator
through the content
but since we're specifically
for our unit tests here, Xcode
and that's the test navigator.
In the test navigator,
Xcode automatically lists
and performance test that Xcode
Some of these are grayed
and that's because those
to run in my current scheme.
I have a separate scheme for
The rest of the tests are
that when I perform the test
so let's go ahead and try that.
From the product menu, I
as the other four
Run will run my app
Test will run my tests.
Profile will run my
so I can measure
Analyze will run
and help catch problems I
And finally, the Archive action
and put it in the archive that
to my testers or to the
for future crash
or symbolication.
This command will become enabled
in this menu once I select a
I'm going to go ahead and select
I want you to watch the activity
because it'll tell you
So I'll select Test, and you can
and then it's going to build my
but it looks like we
When a compiler error
up at the right-hand side
showing that there was an issue,
and Xcode automatically
to the issue navigator
This behavior, like
to the navigator that shows
is something you can
and as you learn to make it work
to dive in and configure
You can do that in Xcode's
If you choose to edit behaviors,
Xcode will give you
that lets you configure all
So when a build generates
we show the issue navigator.
When a test generates
we show the test
As you start to get comfortable
to make it work the way you
I recommend checking
So let's take a look at what our
I'm going to go ahead and
in the issue navigator,
to our source code where the
Xcode lists the error
where it's occurred,
like here my data source
or a property named
You know, I think we had
and just yesterday we
and I guess we forgot to
so let's figure out how
of this method is.
To start tracking that down, I'm
down and click on Data Source,
where this variable is defined.
So I can see that
as a quake data source
I'm then going to hold the
on Quake Data Source, and this
where quake data
I could start scrolling
for my property, but
The jump bar at the top of the
that Xcode has found
in the order in which
There are a couple extra
If I hold the Command key when I
down in alphabetical
of in an order of appearance.
Or I can simply type
and Xcode will filter
So it used to be
Probably still has
I'll type Quakes, and here are
that include the word Quakes.
One of these is orderedQuakes.
I think that's the new
This is actually a
so you can find things
If I simply type OQ, Xcode
because the letters
in this property
One last thing I want
You'll notice that I
Here's a to-do item reminding me
and I have a header dividing
You can actually configure these
in your source code like to-do:
and that will let you organize
you want to make it easy to
All right, so let's
I'll type OQ again and
It's found it for me right
and copy this method name.
I'm going to use the back
to my test file, and
and paste the new
When I do that, I want you
on the left-hand side of the
in my issue navigator
and both of those
And that's because the issue
you're doing in real time, so we
as you edit it without having
to see whether things are right.
Okay, so we fixed
Let's go ahead and
When I do this, Xcode's going to
and it's now preparing to run
as you can see from the
Looks like our tests are
to the test navigator to see
from the spinner here
It looks like one of
and this might take a while,
so let's actually hit the Stop
Performance tests are great
to iterate on fixing my unit
to wait for my performance
So we can do that by
that doesn't run my
To configure my scheme, I'm
and choose Edit Scheme.
Here Xcode will bring down
You can see that there's a
to each of the five scheme
at the top that lets
which targets this
to perform the actions on the
For an action like
like what executable
In this case, it's my app.
What command line arguments
and environment variables
Even special diagnostics
like Xcode's powerful
that will help you
Since these diagnostics are
they won't have any effect on
for distribution, so
about these diagnostics
with what you submit
I'm going to go to the Test
where I've configured what
Before I start changing that,
that I often do when
and that's to make
and make the edits in the copy.
That's because I still
around that knows how to
because I do want to run
I just want a different scheme
that lets me run
So to do that, I'm going
to select the Duplicate
Xcode will give me a chance to
so we'll call it
And now I can go
find my performance tests,
and uncheck the checkbox
From here, you can
on a per-test basis
you have a test that's failing
that you're not going
All right, I think we're done
but before I go back
I want to show you one
and that's how to
The Manage Schemes
of this sheet will bring you to
and here we show
that Xcode has found
I'd like to especially
to the shared checkbox
If a scheme is shared,
that scheme into source control,
that same scheme when they
and any edits they or you make,
assuming that you check those
will be shared with
so this makes it really easy to
that you want everyone to use
and share it with
Since my coworkers might want
without the performance tests
and share my new scheme.
Okay, I think we're done
and run our tests one more time.
It's preparing to run my
attaching to my tests, and
And you can see from the test
of my tests have passed,
If I want a closer look
I can find that in
The reports navigator shows
that I performed grouped by
to perform that action.
So here I just perform a Build
to test and then the
If I select the Build log
to show me everything, I can
to build both my
If I select the Test log, Xcode
its status, and I
down to find the
In this case, one of my
because an earthquake
I'm going to hover
and I'll get a little
So if I select that,
to the failing test.
Here you can see where I declare
to the left of the
that that test is
If I scroll down, I can find
Here I have a test assertion
of my test data or earthquake
like this range check
Actually, this looks
I think I just have a less than
than because I'm trying to check
so I think that should
Let's go ahead and run this test
but since I'm trying to iterate
there's a faster way than
I can run just this test.
To do that, I can go
and mouse over my test.
You'll see that the badge
when I do that that would
or I can run just an
or if I don't want to switch
I can even run my test right
by mousing over the
of the test method and clicking
So let's click that now.
It's building my change to
to run my tests again.
So it's ran my tests
like my test is still failing,
I'm going to scroll
of my earthquakes
that graphically
and for my test earthquake
that every earthquake
but one of them has a nil badge,
This doesn't look like a
It's probably a problem
up these earthquakes, so I'm
and take a closer look
We're showing you a
around your code in Xcode today,
but I'm about to show you the
gesture that we have.
In Xcode's file menu,
whoop -- called Open Quickly.
This is one keyboard shortcut
to memorize, Command
to use this all the time.
If I select Open Quickly, I
of my window, and I can type in
like my method names, in
as all the symbols in Apple's
to find whatever I'm looking
or in the system frameworks.
This also is a nice, fuzzy
to know exactly the name
In this case, I think
up in some method
so let's try typing
and you can see it's found my
even though I didn't have
because it's a fuzzy match,
where this method
but the first one that's
up my test data, so
So I'm just going to hit Return
Okay, so here I'm setting
I don't see anything obviously
to take a closer look
And to do that, I'm going
Xcode's debugger is available
or Test action in Xcode.
And you can get it to stop
by setting a break
I can set a break point by
of the editor, and you'll see
that a break point
I can click on that
and temporarily disable it
or I could just drag it out
to delete my break point.
In this case, I do want my
to click again to create
and run our test again.
I'm going to show you one last
There's a command in
and Test Again will run whatever
so it makes it really easy
to repeatedly run the same
I can get at Test Again
under the Perform
There's actually a number
but here's Test Again, so
Xcode's going to run
It's attaching to my
starting to run my
that Xcode has now stopped
in the debugger on
When the debugger stopped,
First, at the bottom, the Debug
of different controls to allow
such as Continue, Step
Below that is a variable area
that are visible in
Here I declare three
but I haven't assigned
so it shows no value.
On the right-hand
that shows all the output my
out or standard error, and we'll
Finally, you'll notice
in the debugger, one of
and Xcode automatically switched
Here Xcode shows
in my code in every thread.
This code is actually running on
Thread 6, and all of my stack
for are shown in black,
that contain system code that
and can't look at
You'll notice that there's
aligning some of these frames.
It's because I don't really need
that I don't have source code
to see exactly what's happening,
at the bottom of
All right, let's try stepping
where we initialized this first
I'm going to use the Step
When I do that, Xcode continues
and you'll see that my first
initialized in the
I can actually twist this open
of this new earthquake,
Since this is an image and I
at what this is, Xcode
to quick look objects like
Xcode will read the image right
and display it graphically here
so you can inspect exactly what
Well, this badge
since this one isn't
out the next earthquake.
And to do that, I'm actually
of this next earthquake
I use the Step Into
into this initializer,
and here's where we
So I can just start stepping
Here's the switch
which magnitude badge to use.
And here's the badge
I don't think this
I don't think IIII is
So that's probably the problem,
stopping it, running
but Xcode makes it possible to
to stop and start
And to do that, I'm going to
In the console area, I'm
which stands for Print Object,
and this command will
or Objective-C expression
So I can simply copy
and paste it right
So let's make this console
and let's also clear
with the Clear button so
And now I'm going to hit Return
in my application, and you can
so there is no image
I'm going to press the up arrow
and let's try IV, which I think
for 4.
So I'll hit Return
and you can see the
in actual image instance,
so it looks like that's the
So at this point, I'm going to
and I'll change my image to IV,
and let's run our test one more
So Xcode is building the
It's preparing to run my tests.
Let's switch to the
so I can see how it goes.
And, oh, it looks like I
So I want it to run my tests
so let's take a look at how
Xcode's break points navigator
that I have set in my project,
and I can disable them
or select them and delete
I can add special
in the break point
on any Swift error that's
that fails, or on any symbolic
If I find that there's a certain
to have, like, say, a
I can make it available in every
by selecting the break
bringing up the contextual menu,
and choosing Move
This moves that break point
and makes it available for
working with.
All right.
In this case, I'm
to delete all my break points
so let's temporarily
so that we don't stop at them.
I can temporarily
with the Break Points
I'll now press the
to finish running my test.
Let's go back to the test
that all my tests are passing,
Let's review what
To review my changes,
to Xcode's project navigator
at the bottom called the
This will make the project
files that have a special
such as Modified.
This both lets me see
and is really useful if I
a set of files I'm all
to jump between quickly.
If I modified those files, I
down to just those
If I want to see the actual
of these files, I can select it
and use Xcode's third
So we've already shown
and the assistant editor.
Xcode's third editor mode
and it has three variants.
The comparison editor
between two revisions or
against the last
The blame mode lets you see who
in your file and
and the log mode will show
for your file.
In this case, I want
When I select this, Xcode shows
On the left is my
so these are the
and on the right is the
to source control, so this
between what I've done and
In the bottom middle are
between my changes, and when
Xcode will visually show me
and even highlight exactly
where the change
If I want to compare
I can actually pop this up
to the file I want
or I can even compare two
against each other by
on the left.
I think these changes are great,
to go ahead and commit
To commit, I'm going to go to
and choose the Commit
down Xcode's commit sheet.
On the left, I can see all
including some settings
I'll get the comparison editor
to give me one last chance
From here, I can even discard
on the change marker and
if I only want to commit some
In this case, I want
so let's give it
I'll say Fixed Tests, and I
to my coworkers when I commit,
And let's go ahead and
So Xcode's committing.
It's pushed our changes off to
When you're ready to go
to your testers or to the App
to do that or if there's
today that you want to learn
out Xcode's Help Book.
You can get at the Help
by choosing Xcode Help, and
for whatever you want more
through a list of topics.
For example, Archive and Output
Here Xcode tells me how
for distributing my app.
All right, well, we've taken you
through a pretty complete
but there's one more key
like to leave you with before
to customize your source
sorry, how to customize
and configure them
To take you through Xcode's
I'd like to invite Najla back up
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Rick.
So now you know the basic
and when you're just
that's probably all you'll
on more complex projects,
to configure your
So let's take a quick tour
of Xcode's core configuration
so that you'll understand
So there are five concepts that
Xcode projects and the
the Build settings
that configure how Xcode
for organizing your project.
So let's begin by
A project is a document
to organize your code
You have references to source
on disc, targets which actually
like your app, Build settings
which configure how your
and schemes which configure
such as Run, with your targets.
Now, to access your
you select your project
you select the popover
and select your project there.
Now, your project settings are
your Info and Build
And most common settings
There's one that I
which is the deployment
Your deployment target
that your app can
Currently, our app only supports
to support iOS 9, I could change
Let's move on to
A target contains the
like an app or a framework.
The thing that your target
The set of steps that
to build its product
And lastly, a target
to configure how it
Now, one thing to note
and targets have Build settings,
and targets inherit the value
but can override them with
A target's build phases do
to build first, compile the
and link the target against
You can also add what's called
to configure other aspects
You can access your
by selecting your project in the
at the top of the editor,
and picking the target
Now, your target settings are
such as the Build Settings
and the Build Phases tab.
So let's talk a little bit more
about those Build
A Build setting contains a
that controls some aspect
For example, there are Build
which architectures
whether your code is optimized,
and even how you
The Build settings are
and the target level in
in a big table that contains
Now, Build settings
by what's called a build
a project has a debug and
For example, when you're
you probably don't want
but when you're building
you do want your
In addition to fine-grain
Xcode also offers
to easily turn on
For example, for iOS,
for enabling in-app purchases
and if you want more information
you can twist it open in
You can also enable or
by using the On/Off switch
Lastly, let's talk
So you may find over time
on a group of projects as a set.
For example, you might
that share the same
like to work on them together.
In this situation, you can
that references your projects.
So when you open your workspace
of the contents of the
which makes it easy
across them as related code.
So now you know more
about Xcode's core
Armed with this knowledge
to Xcode's basic development
to make some really
So today we showed you the most
by building an application.
You learned how to create a
in the simulator and how
We also talked about some
such as Command and Option
We also showed you
in your project using the
You learned how to review and
to configure your project and
to submit it to the store.
We hope that after this session
of all of the different kinds of
and we're really excited to see
If--
[ Applause ]
Yeah. So if you want more
you can navigate to
And if you're interested in a
there are a few sessions that
For example, there was a session
which is really important
about to submit your
There was a session on testing
and on debugging
Thanks for watching our session,
and we hope that you have a
[ Applause ]