[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone, welcome to using
and extending the
I'm Mike and I work on Xcode
between you and the
So what are we talking
Well I'm going to start off and
that we've added to Xcode
I'd also like to show you
that are already in the
that I think you probably
but I think they're really cool.
And I use them every
and navigate the
And just to be clear,
to show you comes
Then, my colleague Chris,
and show you how to go
and further extend the Xcode
You can write the extensions
of the things you've
and then you can even
with your friends,
or even the whole world.
The first thing you'll
or if you just looked up and
is our new source
This is the mono
to our system font
Our font experts have
for retina displays.
And have carefully designed
for code punctuation
and legible, even
The next thing you'll notice
in the editor, is that we have
that shows you where
Each of our built-in
hand tuned highlight color,
So you can change it to be
to completely transparent
So you're probably already
and uncomment command,
Well we've added a new command
by dropping the option
and that inserts a
[ Applause ]
So, this works directly on or
anything that you know is
And, you'll notice that these
give you a chance to
or discuss the parameters, the,
or you know, say
about the return value.
And what's really valuable is
that you add in the code
and at the bottom of the
And also notice that we've
with more weights than
The documentation comment uses
use SF mono medium which
and just a little heavier
that the rest of the file is in.
Unlike most other
we've given SF mono a full
through semi-bold,
and we've included
This keeps the spacing between
letting you customize exactly
So in the next feature I'm going
to another file, I'm
by pressing Command, Shift O,
to get to my
And you may have
this is the document items
by pressing Control 6.
It has all of the classes,
everything that's
But that's not really
Did you know that if you just
up, it filters the items?
And you'll notice, here that,
that I have, it actually
bandage icon on it,
of cute [laughter].
So, jumping here to my load view
that we have an image in a
for a designer to deliver to us.
But I actually got those P&amp;G's
into the jogger asset catalog,
down here in the library.
So this is for the Timer Button.
So I'm going to go and I'm
of the line here by
while holding down Shift.
And I'm going to
by pressing Command Space.
Now watch carefully, I'm going
by using code completion.
I'm just going to type t,
And you'll also notice
as in Xcode 7.3 now uses the
that we use for open quickly,
and even our new search in
And you can see here on the left
of the image so you know
that you're picking
So, boom right there,
this is an image literal.
[ Applause ]
So every image in the library,
from an asset catalog or it's
it's available from the
in the source editor.
So, the way this works is we
into the source which is
and it dereferences out to a
So you can see all of
instead of just the name string.
And we have this for colors too.
So I'm just going to select
and invoke code completion
And what this will,
you notice that I get this
From here I can just arrow
like this, lovely green here.
And what's really important to
and color literals are the,
they're fully keyboard
If I just hold down Shift and
and hit Return, I bring up
And, you know to which I
but if these colors that are
in the pop-up aren't exactly
and there, it's not exactly
you can use the recent
with interface builder, or you
down here and it brings up the
So in this case, I
out this lovely navy blue,
since this is going
as I'm constructing it.
But we still have a little
the color literal is, is a
that we're assigning
and it's expecting a cgColor.
So I can fix that
[ Applause ]
Hopefully this makes it
and color literals are really
real type objects in Swift.
So the next thing I'd like to
and in fact, it's not
It's actually been part of
since before macOS 10.0, and
Now you may not have
that if you've done a find
like say Pause here
to the clipboard
And then you bring down
and then you paste it
That that same search, shows
That's kind of weird isn't it?
Well, that's because the find
across applications just like
It lives in parallel
and the two exist side by side.
So there's actually a really
if you have something
onto in the clipboard and you
But if you still want to search,
you can just press Command
into the find pasteboard.
And this allows you to then, hit
of the remaining
Now, if you just want to
in the exact same file, we
for that too.
If you hold down
you'll actually perform
and this modifies every instance
So here I can just
because started sounds
And, and this one's a
and I use this a lot.
Now, if all you want to do is
you don't even need to use
We actually have a
So if we just select
down Command Option
that I can actually move this
of if functions and
And they just flow
So this is all great
out in the same one file
to do a find across other
to find all instances of timer,
you can do that by holding
to do a full project find.
And here, I'll just push timer
into my find pasteboard
And, this was actually
out to me recently, I don't have
to actually start to arrow
Command G also works here too.
The only difference
down the Control key while
and it actually cycles through
of my different files, including
and all of the instances
And it works in reverse
just like Command
So, I don't know, I know
of writing some of this down.
But, you really don't have
to because there's actually
that has the full list
and all their keystrokes.
And that's inside of the
So here, in the Key
you can actually do a search
find, and you can
Also, if you kind of vaguely
sort of like reveal command that
This actually searches across
So this is really powerful.
And if you don't like
for all of Xcodes
you can actually set
And, if our built-in
or they don't do that
that you've always wanted
I'd like to invite Chris up now
to show you how you can add
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Mike.
As Mike said, I'm Chris
to show you how you
with source editor extensions.
Now what we're offering you is
to the source editor as
Your commands can
as well as selections
say to perform navigation.
And unlike some other types
you can implement any
as a single Xcode
Now we chose to base
on application extensions which
across all our operating
Since Xcode extensions are
each one runs in its own process
and can do pretty much whatever
without interfering with Xcode
Of course, as application
Xcode extensions are also
for doing anything that
And Xcode only gives access to
and metadata that
to perform their operations.
They don't get access to
they don't get access to
And why are we doing
Well, stability.
We want to ensure
as possible for all
Also, security, application
of allowing you to enhance
and now our tools while
of the entire system.
And of course, we're also
Application extensions are built
and are fully asynchronous.
So they can work as
and not slow down our users.
And, there's another
to use application extensions as
and that's so you can distribute
[ Applause ]
And just like all other
Xcode extensions are built
And this application
to put your extensions
or configuration information.
For example to control which
to make available
And it's also a great
that you want your
Since all Xcode is going to
for each of your commands.
And being part of an application
extension, an Xcode extension
to be distributed on
Of course, you can also
and your Xcode extension
and distribute it
[ Applause ]
Now, let's talk a little bit
about how Xcode brings
To ensure the best possible
to find and automatically start
on in its own startup process.
Before your users
And source editor extensions
of application extensions
that are only used
Xcode will actually try to keep
as possible so that it
as the user wants to invoke.
Now when your extension
if it needs to do any
Xcode will send
to it.
And this is a good
as long as it's quick.
That's right you need to do your
and that's so your users
as soon as they want to.
And to help you there,
up your extension is
up other extensions and
Now once your extension is
for its commands, and
from one of two places.
By default you'll have an entry
in your NSExtensionAttributes
that specifies all of the
But you can also
of the commandDefinitions
from your extension class
that are given back
So if your extension has a
say because it's downloaded
that it actually uses
it can provide a new collection.
Now once Xcode has
it'll give each extension its
when the user is
And the extensions are listed
as they are in the
in a stable place for the
However, because order of
and often, conveys a
Xcode will preserve the order
to it, and list them in
Now to invoke a command,
of course a user can choose the
or they can press a
that they have assigned.
Your command object
and sent an invocation
Now the invocation packages up
that your command
And, the command then uses the
to tell Xcode that it's done.
And let's take a look
Here we have the
of your command classes
Just as I said, it's
and a completionHandler
And that invocation just carries
It has a commandIdentifier which
or in you command
And that lets you
that are handled by
After all, there are a
in source code editing that do
So you'll probably
of things using the
and just handle a couple
in each one.
And this identifier lets you
that the user has invoked.
We also provide a
a cancellationHandler block on.
And this cancellationHandler
if the user cancels
And that can happen if your
and we'll get a little bit
on in the presentation.
And finally, of course,
the invocation also
of text the user
And that SourceText is
of another object,
And it has a bunch of metadata
We give you the uniform
that Xcode thinks the file
and that way you know if you're
XML data, and ObjC++, header
We also provide the
that Xcode has for that file.
So that as you're making
you can also conform to what
when it's indenting that file.
Now because tabWidth,
and whether
to useTabsForIndentation have
We've also provided
about how they work
So I encourage you to check
see exactly how those
Now, we provide the text
with in two different ways.
If you need to process the
say by piping it to a command
to work with the completeBuffer,
which represents the text
the entire file as
However, if you only need to
this is a really
since your extension
that whole buffer back to Xcode.
And that's we also provide
containing the lines
We found ourselves, that
with source code, we
and column abstraction works
with a single huge
And this, by being
also lets Xcode actually
so that we only need to send
you've made, we don't need to
And this can really
for editing extensions.
And in addition to providing
we also provide a mutable array
There will always be
which is either the user's
and because Xcode's
of the Cocoa text system,
we support multiple
And if you want to change
to do is change this
And what's in that array are
Now we use SourceTextRange
because we really do
and column abstraction that
to do most text editing.
And that's why a source range
and a length, is actually
and those positions
in terms of line and column.
Now, I'm going to
of how you can create
Let's go to the demo machine.
And, let me get my
So I was really impressed
about Swift literals, the
And I'd really like to
So I think what I'm going
to do is create a new
that can automatically convert
to the corresponding
I'm just going to create a new
to create a new OS
After all, my app
has to be carried
So I'll create this
to call this Chris Literals.
And I'm just going to give
identifier of com.example, and
to put this project
And now that I've
I'm going to add a new
to add an OS X application
And you can see we have our new
template right here at
And I'm going to name
to Literals and just finish.
And when I clicked Finish, Xcode
for me, just as with
So I'm going to accept that.
And now let's take
that Xcode generated for me.
In this convert to literals
that represents my
And this just conforms
to the XCSourceEditor
And it also added templates
and a property that I can
to override these and
I don't want to right now,
for this particular project,
so let's just take a
In the next file
I have my first command class.
And just as I showed
to XCSourceEditor command,
within vocation method.
Now let's take a
that Xcode created for me.
And you can see, in my extension
of
which is an array
And that dictionary specifies
for a command, the identifier
and the name that the menu item
So I'm going to change
to Swift Literals
Zoom out, and go back
Now I'm going to cheat
because I've already written
to use a code snippet it
to insert what I've
I've named it Chris
that it's actually not
So what I'm doing is just
in the file, and if the
or a UIImage invocation in
with its corresponding
And then, if the line
that's when I replace the
that way I'm not replacing
and I'm certainly not
I'm only modifying the lines
And I'm also keeping track
so that later I can also
to represent those lines.
I set those selections,
completionHandler to let Xcode
I see Xcode in the
And if I click Run here, what
beyond of course
Well you can see we launch
for you to test your
And we actually provide
of visual distinction here too,
and we darken the icon in
so you know at a glance
in which you're testing
Now I'm just going to open
because I noticed he had some,
that weren't converted yet.
And you can see another case
in the activity view up at the
at a glance, that this Xcode is
And Mike's left me actually
and UIColor that I think
So I'm just going to
I see my Chris Convert
and I see my convert to
Now if I go back to
and just set a breakpoint,
If I actually run
you'll see that nothing happened
at that breakpoint in the
So you can actually bring all
and LLDB to bear in debugging
I'm just going to
And I've still got my breakpoint
And if I go back, I can see
of the lines that I've
and it's converted everything
to using the new
[ Applause ]
Now let's say I actually
on a pretty regular basis.
Well it's easy enough, I
by just adding a key
I do that in Xcode's
and I'm going to search
which I know starts with Chris.
And we're right there
I think I'm just going to name
that's easy to remember
Now let's go back to the slides,
and talk about something
to my heart when working
with Xcode extensions,
Text editing is a user
Your users are really going
on the keyboard and just
even while they're
And your extensions really
from just continuing
Now in order to prevent
between your extension and
out changes to the document
with when they invoke
And fortunately, this means
about reconciling the
and the changes the user made.
On the other hand, it means
that if your extension takes
as a couple of seconds,
out from editing their document.
So, what do we do there?
Well we give the user the
And we do that by bringing
And I think the system's
that this slide is taking
let's cancel out
Now Xcode helps keep
by starting extensions early
as they're likely to be
as soon as they're invoked.
And as we talked about earlier,
that your extensions data
for performance.
And when a user needs
that cancellation is actually
As soon as the user hits Cancel
Now your extension will still
and still needs to react to it,
but the user doesn't
Of course there are a few ways
with performance as well.
Your extension can startup
so it's ready as
In implementing your commands
of our asynchronous
to ensure you're making
of the user's system and
as quickly as possible.
And of course, you can avoid
of text if you don't have to.
And finally, as I said, you need
Because until your command
cancellation, it won't be
Now today Mike showed you a
in the Xcode source
to add documentation comments
and image literals
And he also showed
that were very recently added
in Xcode 7.3, like
And I showed you how Xcode
and how you can make them
to see what you do
There'll be some more
at our page on the
And there are a couple
that you can check out on video,
in particular Optimizing App
to apps, it also
because they use a lot
Our Introduction to Xcode is
up to speed on the
and what your users will expect
And finally, we have
from previous years
to be an app extension and best
And we'll also be at the bash
to WWDC and if you
for us, you can see us there.
[ Applause ]