[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
My name's Philippe Hausler, and
and today we're going to
We'll go over why Server-Side
how all the pieces fit together,
what you don't, some real-world
on the server, and, most
to contribute to making
Modern application
for one platform.
It's an ecosystem.
You'd be hard pressed
that doesn't have some sort
be it from analytics,
or shared state being
servers are an integral
in making rich and
Now building the
often there are contact
You end up humming along,
and the next thing you
in a different language.
This can cause downtime and
and we all know how much we
in code.
But Swift running on the
to just provide a seamless
but also a richer and more
By sharing the right
time can be saved not
but also testing and QA.
But it's not just the language.
It's the API's.
It's often hard to disambiguate
from the construction of
like strings, arrays,
They often become a core set
of libraries expressing
And with that, it brings us
not just on the server,
on all platforms.
As in early design
Swift wouldn't just be
It can by its very nature
and with the community's help,
to be realized with
like [inaudible] SD,
and even things like
Some pretty exciting stuff.
On all of these, Swift relies
Building on top of that, you
It provides some of those
blocks and data structures.
On Darwin, we have an
that aids system frameworks
but since there is no foundation
a portable interface
in those fundamental pieces.
We started off with an outline
and a few initial
and with the community, we have
that are needed for
So when you application
you can see that all
of the pieces just fit together
With Swift built in this
you can pick the right pieces
for the server and use
that you're used to using.
Swift.org is the central place
for getting the most
Signing up for the
for the GitHub repositories or
or a great place to
on the most recent
It is the place for
So what comes in this toolbox?
Out of the box, you get
on both Linux and Mac.
So you can develop on your Mac
There are continuous
that the changes that are made
and continuously integrate
so that everything
You have the standard library.
That gives you those basic
structures, and types
in building any Swift
but you also get Foundation,
within the, the Swift
These give you a cross
that can keep your code
across multiple platforms.
But you also get a suite of
and debugging Swift apps as well
try out some of those new
of these things on
Now there are a few things
There was a design, a design
that some things just
in a cross platform nature,
better served to let developers
since they're highly
New platforms are not just code.
They are continuous
and the champions reporting
to new platforms usually know
User interface is a very
On iOS, you have UIKit.
On Mac, you have
that they share a
there have to be
because they're solving
For that matter, UI
and sometimes the user in user
instead, it's another
that is routing a
These are all clearly something
Now deploying your
and of itself is a
This way you can pick
that fits your requirements,
of course, your application.
This shouldn't have to be tied
Running on the server, you
running with multiple
It's amazing to see the
and sharing community,
of the great things,
to enrich the Swift ecosystem.
There have already been some
of these areas and more,
over at IBM have been making
We've gone over some
So let's dive a little
So here to present some
of how they're, they are
at IBM is John Ponzo
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Philippe.
Hi. My name is John Ponzo.
I'm the Technical Leader for
and I'm thrilled to
We at IBM are very excited about
of the open source, and
for the language.
For those unfamiliar, let me
and our involvement with Swift.
Apple and IBM announced
on enterprise apps
And, subsequently, IBM became
of Swift when it was announced
Since that time, we've created
over 100 enterprise
building those apps and
and we also have one of
of Swift developers at IBM
Our experience building
and solutions consistently
of the backend, enabling
As developers, we know
to have a backend, to enable
We also know it's
and safely deploy the right
and that's why we're so excited
to help bring Swift
We appreciate the
around Swift.org community,
to code contributions and
that are forming.
I'd like to highlight some of
at IBM to help the open
to the server.
First, I'll tell you about
and tell you about
and Swift package catalog
to help developers to
and share Swift assets.
Next, we are motivated by
that links the client and
we created the Kitura web
to motivate and prioritize
into the core libraries of
And next, Cloud enablement
of the development
to make it even easier and fun
Through early support in the
and the introduction of
to help deploy that
When Swift.org was
one of the first things
to help grow the
We saw the value of the
to quickly introduce
We created the Sandbox that
to easily run and
The Sandbox runs in a
you can easily start writing
and see the execution
Since we released the
of enhancements based on
The Sandbox currently supports
autosaving of code,
to select multiple
Also, to help developers to
around Swift, we added code
by a persistent URL.
You could use this to share
and developer forums
Thank you, and we've seen
in the Sandbox since we
and this is over
since just this February.
And the Sandbox is
to Swift from other platforms.
In fact, we're seeing
in executions and
from other operating systems.
We're very pleased to see this,
and we'd like to see
We're also seeing usage
Developers using the Sandbox
Our intent is to continue
to help grow the community.
A vibrant package ecosystem
While the Swift Package Manager
technology, everything
on the server is based on
of Swift-based packages.
Because of this, we found
and to publish our own packages.
So we created the Swift package
We continue to update
as the Swift Package Manager
And today we have over 1,500
packages on the catalog,
and this is up 400
Next, when we start
a foundational requirement
for any server language
to stand up web interfaces.
While web frameworks are
on ports and routing code
we thought it was very
as consistent as possible
with the client-side
And towards that end, we
We open source Kitura
It's a modular package
It leverages libdispatch and
and utility library support.
It's also driving IBM's
We're using Kitura to build
and we're working with the
of committers outside of IBM
It's an important part
to server enable Swift.
We're also optimizing our Cloud
And I'm pleased to
to our Cloud foundry-based
that includes everything
to rapidly deploy your
to the IBM Cloud.
These build packs include the
core libraries, and
They're needed to deploy
But in addition, development
to announce IBM Cloud
a Mac companion application
to easily build end-to-end
The tool helps you to quickly
and easily connect
with service-side Swift
Just continue developing
and service-side projects
to link those projects and
Now with that introduction, I'd
Patrick Bohrer, up to the stage
who will show you
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, John.
I'm Pat Bohrer.
I'm the Technical Lead for a lot
of the fun stuff we're
So we're thrilled to be
to be leading what
and exciting part
It's fun because I'm going to be
on the server, and it's
of my demos are dependent on a
So wish me luck.
So as we talk about server-side
of things to a lot of
and for this session,
we're really talking
So what are web services?
In a very simple
that are off running
They're listening.
They're listening for
They're responsible for
to some server-side logic,
And now as far as what's out
it could be another application.
Who knows?
It could be another service,
but as simple level,
So to get started, that
Let's go ahead and jump in,
OK. So as I mentioned,
oftentimes these web
and we've heard about
So let's go ahead
for this first demo
Let's go ahead and do that.
So here we have Linux
Make sure I'm not lying.
So let's go ahead and
to do some, to play around.
So we'll very creatively
You can see we have
And now we'll use the
So every, as John mentioned,
on server-side is
And so we're going to
of the Swift Package Manager
this syntax changes, but for the
it has an initialization step.
And so if we issue this command,
we can see that it's
So based on the structure
the Swift Package Manager knows
And so as you can see here,
and it's created a Sources.main,
to build a Swift, a
So with that said, let's
So we can issue Swift build,
And so it's created a
So let's run that.
Ah. Hello world.
But we're building web services.
So let's get real.
OK. So here, this is what
created for us.
So, again, it's best that
on our directory called Plays.
It's named our executed play,
and so that's why
And we want to add one piece
on Kitura, and that's
So now we will go
Let's delete our
and let's add a bit
So what this code does
We're pulling in Foundation.
We're also importing
of Kitura support packages.
Here, we're specifying a
for incoming requests.
We have to route these
And we're going to
right here, that is /hello.
So if any, if any requests
Simple enough.
We'll specify some
and we'll send back a
Now down here we specify
and it's the 8095, and we
and we specify our
and then we start the server.
So it's pretty simple.
Let's go ahead and save that.
Now we're going to build
and so we've added
As John mentioned,
we're leveraging
And so what it's doing
the Swift Package Manager's
So we wrote the code
and the Swift Package Manager
it's pulling down our
down some system support,
that you'd need in a, in a web
to listen on sockets
And so each of these are
out on GitHub that
And it's compiled and built.
So now let's go ahead and
So we can see that it's now,
it just says it's
So let's go ahead and
We'll bring up local host 8095
on our, on our Mac and Linux,
and you can see we
So this basically, if we haven't
it'll bring up this page
and specify other
You can always override this,
but for us all we've
[ Applause ]
And so, of course, the
to do is say hello world, right.
So the first step, but,
about it, let's go back,
Let's go back and
We have a lot of
So we have Foundation,
and we also have the
So add a little helper code here
We'll also add a new
So now, again, here's a new
saying /today, it'll do,
to go get the current date.
We'll go ahead and create
like we would on the client.
We'll use that DateFormatter
a time string, and now we'll get
and so here we'll create a
and now because in the Internet,
So we specify message is hello
our time is our time,
we convert that into a string,
and that's what we
So let's take, see
Let's go ahead and rebuild.
Much faster.
All the packages are here.
So that's good.
So, again, we'll run this again.
You can see we're
We'll reload and see we're still
and now let's look at today.
And there we go.
We have our JSON payload.
And now, again, every time
it's executing that code,
So that's at a very simple
OK. My wife said to take
So that was pretty fun, but now
more interesting.
So as we go through, first
to a really interesting sample
to this community, and
So BluePic is a sample
that's social.
It has a rich client interface,
that we've built and provided
It also has a really
That is, a Swift server backend,
running the IBM Cloud, and it's
services that I'll mentioned
[inaudible] SQL databases,
And if you're, if you're
it even has some use of
programming model
that also supports Swift.
So, again, this package
and it's available now
who want to get started.
So before we dive
I want to spend a little
about the design pattern here.
So unlike before where we had a
we, of course, have
It has our model
and you can see it also
with requests and responses.
And it's talking to
which is similar to
It's just a little bit more
accepting an incoming
routing those to some logic.
And then, finally, we
where we have some interesting
into in a bit, for holding all
So, again, just to dig
So we have the client-side.
It's responsible.
It's very user specific view
you know, interactions
of the application, and
The midtier is responding
with the things they have,
but it's also doing some
So as photos get submitted
it'll accept those photos.
It'll save them into
It'll create some
but it'll do a few other things
So it will take those
over to Watson's Vision Insights
and extract just tags
Is it mountains and lakes and
So it's kind of adding
to our application
It will also notice
and call Watson's
and pull down information.
What was the weather
So we're adding all of that.
So, again, instead of
from the client-side, we're
which is always on, always
and do our service
And the fact that this is
the right code to
So now here is BluePic
It's running on a device.
It's connecting into
The application server,
to all the different services
Now if something comes
or develop this application
Right. Well, as iOS developers,
We pull down the source for
we load it all up into Xcode,
We can debug this.
We can debug the application.
You can even be calling
and making other requests.
So this is something we
but now that this midtier
what do we do?
Right. You probably don't want
to be using VI like
But, again, we can
We can pull down the source code
onto our Mac, load
and now we can also just
and debug locally on our Mac.
So we're debugging
It's exciting.
So now our development world
So we actually control
from the client to the midtier,
even to the services
So we, we really are
because we think it brings
you know, as you're doing things
to add some capabilities
it's all in the world
Towards that end, as
we thought we can go
So just like we've done
and the Swift Sandbox,
we created this application
as a Mac application to
development world.
So we're really excited
This application actually
to manage this entire stack
there's a lot of things
but why not have some tools
So we're excited to hear
like we have the
And we'll keep, you know,
with this application, and,
we know what we want it to do.
We'll keep adding things, and
as well, but we're
about the possibilities here.
So our goal is really to
to keep creating great
by Swift on the server.
So now with all of that
in and do some demos again.
Going to show you just
with Swift.
OK. So first off, this is the
If you want to get
with an interface that's
and for those wanting to
it even has an ability to
to create just a Kitura project
Now the part that's interesting
about this is not only is it
in bringing them down, it's also
under the covers provisioning
to deploy that project when
in fact, when you create these,
because it knows it's
So, again, to get up
it's a great way to start.
For us, we've already created
and you can see we
Very cleverly named.
And here you can see we
a binding between a client
Both of these are in Swift.
Additionally, if we drill in,
you can see it has a reference
on our, on my machine as well
into the Cloud as well as all of
on behalf of this application.
So, again, I can manage all
As well as I can go ahead and
to look at my client-side.
So here's the BluePic
It is also created, let me zoom
It's a Bluemix.plist.
Knowing this development
against your Cloud
versus remotely it's very
It'll either listen locally to
and pass in the,
So, again, the thought here
So here we'll go ahead and
that somebody's filed a bug
So here's our application.
Again, it's got a
We can scroll through.
We can see some pictures.
If we click on these pictures,
we can see there's
So the name is nature
We can see who took it.
We can see, supposedly,
which we don't have mountains.
So. We can also see what
and then thanks to
we see that there's
So this is interesting.
If I click on tags, I
we have one photo
If I go back, let's
and we can see there's a few
again, all of this was done
We didn't have users
This was just auto extracted.
But we heard that
about when I click cloudy skies.
So let's look at that.
So we click cloudy sky,
So we know what's going on here,
and somehow the server's not
So now let's switch.
We want to go ahead and figure
And so we'll go over
on our server-side code.
It will launch us and
where the server-side code is.
And if I go ahead and
you can see a lot of the
we're doing Swift
We have our Package.Swift.
We have our sources.
But, additionally,
and created an Xcode project
So let's go ahead and open that.
So here's the code, and, again,
So we know that when we
we'll call this get
So if we look at this, we want
somehow when we pass in a tag,
we're not returning
So let's set a break point
And now we can see our server is
Now let's switch back.
So here we're going to have our
yes so that it will actually
and let's rerun the simulator.
By the way, I'm getting
with all this network
So keep up whatever
OK. So let's just scroll down
problems with.
Let's click on here.
Let's click on cloudy skies.
Ah, great.
Here, we hit a break
[ Applause ]
So if we want to get a feel
and say we want to print tag.
And we can see, kind
We can see that the
in as cloudy percent 20 sky.
That's no good.
We don't want that.
So let's take a look at that.
We also know that we
So what if we go ahead
to clean this up a bit.
We'll remove the
Oh, this is now a variable
Let's go ahead and build this.
We'll run it again.
Rerun the server.
Let's go back to
Oh. There we go.
Timed out waiting for us.
Let's go back.
Let's click cloudy sky again,
Print to tag.
Ah, much better.
That's what we want.
So let's go ahead and turn off
And we see we got our result.
[ Applause ]
So now additionally, since
I can go back into
and I can do a redeploy of
So it will start redeploying
So, again, it's that simple
and your server-side and
[ Applause ]
So I hope you really like these
I feel a tremendous amount of
So on behalf of IBM,
like to thank everyone
This is a really exciting
and we invite you to join us and
and bring, to bring the
And for more information about
about what we're,
we have our
Center that you can go to.
And with that, thanks again.
I'll hand it back to Philippe.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So as you can see, IBM has
things with Swift.
They've not just been
but they've also been
with their vast experience
and streamlining
Some of their work
in making server-side
But you, too, can help make
and there are a number of things
that definitely you
Portions of Swift
There's a lot of work to be
that are not yet
and unimplemented just means
There are number of easy ways
The bug tracker even has a
as starter bugs, but code
Designing new API's and
in Swift are something
on on a daily basis
Many of the discussions are
and coming from contributors
And, of course, your packages,
to make Swift on
And if you have any questions
to what we've actually talked
this session, we have
and there are number of other
that I would highly
The API design guidelines
of our thoughts behind actually
and I would highly suggest
at the What's New in
All of the new value
that are being added are
on the server as well.
Of course, performance is
local application.
We all, we need to
that our servers are going
So performance, all across the
by far, something to look into,
to take a look at the
that are being released
And with that, thank