[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and welcome to
I'm Kyle. Arnold and I are so
to you guys about Swift.
As developers, Swift
and powerful design
Swift has a variety
and various mechanisms for
All of these language
in interesting, emergent ways.
So, how do we go about
and picking the right
Well, first and foremost,
into account the
of Swift's different
Are value or reference
How dynamic do you need
Well, Arnold and I also
to use performance to
In my experience, taking
into account often helps guide
So, we're going to be focusing
We'll touch a bit on modeling.
But we had some great
and we have another great talk
for modeling your
If you want to get the
I strongly recommend watching
All right.
So, we want to use performance
Well, the best way to understand
of Swift's abstraction
to understand their
So, that's what we're
We're going to begin
by identifying the different
into account when evaluating
mechanism options.
For each of these,
through some code using
to deepen our mental model
And then we're going to look
at how we can apply what
and speed up some Swift code.
In the second half of this talk,
we're going to evaluate
of protocol oriented
We're going to look
of advanced Swift features
to get a better understanding
and performance implications.
Quick disclaimer: We're
at memory representations and
of what Swift compiles and
These are inevitably going to
and I think we've struck
between seeing simplicity
And this is a really
to reason about your code with.
All right.
Let's get started by identifying
of performance.
So, when you're building
and choosing an abstraction
you should be asking
to be allocated on
When I pass this
how much reference counting
When I call a method
is it going to be statically
If we want to write fast Swift
to avoid paying for
that we're not taking
And we're going to need to
between these different
for better performance.
All right.
We're going to go through
at a time beginning
Swift automatically allocates
and deallocates memory
Some of that memory it
The stack is a really
You can push onto
and you can pop off
Because you can only ever add or
we can implement the stack --
by keeping a pointer to
And this means, when we call
that pointer at the end
of the stack is called
And when we call into a
that memory that we need just
by trivially decrementing the
And when we've finished
we can trivially
by incrementing the
where it was before we
Now, if you're not that familiar
what I want you to take away
from this slide is just how
It's literally the cost
So, this is in contrast to the
but less efficient
The heap lets you do things the
with a dynamic lifetime.
But that requires a more
So, if you're going to
you actually have to search
to find an unused block
And then when you're done
you have to reinsert
into the appropriate position.
So, clearly, there's
than just assigning an integer
But these aren't even
involved with heap allocation.
Because multiple threads can be
at the same time, the heap needs
to protect its integrity
or other synchronization
This is a pretty large cost.
If you're not paying attention
in your program you're
just by being a little
you can likely dramatically
All right.
Let's trace through some code
and see what Swift is
Here we have a point struct
It also has the draw
We're going to construct the
to point2 making a copy,
to point2.x. Then, we're going
to use our point1
So, let's trace through this.
As we enter this function,
before we even begin executing
on the stack for
and our point2 instance.
And because point is a struct,
the x and y properties are
So, when we go to construct our
of 0, all we're doing
that memory we've already
When we assign point1 to
of that point and initializing
that we'd already
Note that point1 and point2
That means, when we go
to point2.x, point2.x is
This is known as
Then we'll go ahead and
and we're done executing
So, we can trivially deallocate
and point2 just by incrementing
where we were when we
Let's contrast this to the same
which is a class
All right.
So, when we enter this
we're allocating
But instead of for the actual
on point, we're going
for references to
References to memory we're going
So, when we construct our
to lock the heap and
for an unused block of memory
Then, once we have it, we can
of 0, a y of 0, and we can
with the memory address to
Note, when we allocate it on the
for our class point
This is in contrast to
when our point was a struct.
This is because now
in addition to these
we're allocating two more
to manage on our behalf.
Those are denoted with these
When we assign point1 to
to copy the contents of point --
like we did when
Instead, we're going
So, point1 and point2
to the same exact instance
That means when we go and assign
both point1.x and
This is known as reference
to unintended sharing of state.
Then, we're going to
and then Swift is going
on our behalf locking the heap
to the appropriate position.
And then we can pop the stack.
All right.
So, what did we just see?
We saw that classes are
than structs because classes
Because classes are
and have reference semantics,
classes have some
like identity and
But, if we don't need those
we're going to better
And structs aren't prone
of state like classes are.
So, let's see how we can apply
that to improve the
Here's an example
from a messaging application
So, [laughing] basically
And my users send a
that text message I want to
My makeBalloon function is
and it supports a
or the whole configuration
For example, this balloon
with a right orientation
We also support, for
with a left orientation
Now, the makeBalloon function
because I call it frequently
and during user scrolling.
And so I've added
So, for any given
to generate this balloon
If I've done it once, I can
The way I've done this is
orientation, and tail into
Now, there's a couple
String isn't particularly
I'm using it to represent
but I could just as easily put
So, not a lot of safety there.
Also, String can
because it actually
of its characters
So, that means every
into this makeBalloon function,
we're incurring a
Let's see if we can do better.
Well, in Swift we can represent
of color, orientation, and
This is a much safer way
to represent this configuration
And because structs are
they can be used as the
Now, when we call the
if we have a cache hit,
because constructing a struct
like this attributes one doesn't
It can be allocated
So, this is a lot safer and
Let's move on to
of performance, reference
So, I glossed over a
about heap allocation.
How does Swift know
to deallocate memory it
Well, the answer is Swift keeps
of references to any
And it keeps it on
When you add a reference
that reference count is
When that count hits zero,
to this instance on the
to deallocate that memory.
The key thing to keep in mind
with reference counting is this
and there's actually more
and decrementing an integer.
First, there's a couple
to just go and execute the
But, more importantly, just
there is thread safety to
because references can be added
on multiple threads at the
to atomically increment and
And because of the frequency
of reference counting
this cost can add up.
So, let's go back to our point
at what Swift is actually
So, here now we have,
some generated pseudocode.
We see our point has gained an
And we see that Swift has added
or a call to retain and a
Retain is going to atomically
and release is going
to atomically decrement
In this way Swift will
of how many references are
All right.
And if we trace through
we can see that after
on the heap, it's initialized
because we have one live
As we go through our program
we now have two references
to atomically increment
of our point instance.
As we keep executing, once
Swift has added a call
to atomically decrement
because point1 is no longer
as far as it's concerned.
Similarly, once we're
Swift has added another
of the reference count.
At this point, there's no more
of our point instance and
to lock the heap and return
So, what about structs?
Is there any reference
Well, when we constructed
there was no heap
When we copied, there was
There were no references
So, there's no reference
for our point struct.
What about a more
Here we have a label struct
of type String and
String, as we heard earlier,
the contents of its
So, that needs to be
And font is a class.
And so that also needs
If we look at our
labels got two references.
And when we make a copy of it,
we're actually adding
another one to the text storage
The way Swift tracks this --
these heap allocations
to retain and release.
So, here we see the
to be incurring twice the
that a class would have.
All right.
So, in summary, because classes
Swift has to manage the lifetime
It does so with reference
This is nontrivial because
are relatively frequently
of the reference counting.
This is just one more
But if structs contain
to be paying reference
In fact, structs are going
to the number of
So, if they have more than
to retain more reference
Let's see how we chain apply
from my theoretical
So, my users weren't satisfied
They also wanted
like images to each other.
And so I have this
which is a model object
It's got a fileURL property,
on disk for this attachment.
It has a uuid, which is a unique
so that we can recognize this
and different client devices.
It's got a mimeType, which
that this attachment represents
Probably the only
in this example is the failable
if the mimeType is one
for this application because
And if it's not supported, we're
Otherwise, we're going
to initialize our fileURL,
So, we noticed a lot of
and if we actually look at
of this struct, all 3
of our properties are incurring
when you pass them around
to heap allocations underlying
We can do better.
First, just like we saw before,
uuid is a really
It's a 128 bit randomly
And we don't want
to put anything in
And, as a String,
Well, Foundation this year
for uuid, which is really great
in line directly in the struct.
And so let's use that.
What this is going to do is
of the reference counting
for that uuid field, the
And we've got much
because I can't just
I can only put a uuid.
That's fantastic.
Let's take a look at
at how I've implemented
I'm actually only
of mimeTypes today,
And, you know, Swift has a
for representing a
And that's an enumeration.
So, I'm going to take
put it inside a failable
and map those mimeTypes
to the appropriate
So, now I've got more type
and I've also got more
to be storing these different
Swift actually has a really
for writing this exact code,
which is using enum that's
And so this is effectively the
more powerful, has the same
but it's way more
So, if we looked at our
it's way more type safe.
We've got a strongly typed
and we're not paying nearly as
because uuid and
to be reference counted
All right.
Let's move on to
of performance, method dispatch.
When you call a method
Swift needs to execute the
If it can determine the
at compile time, that's
And at runtime, we're just going
to the correct implementation.
And this is really cool because
to be able to have visibility
into which implementations
And so it's going to be able
to optimize this code pretty
like inlining.
This is in contrast
Dynamic dispatch isn't going --
we're not going to be able
to determine a compile
which implementation to go to.
And so at runtime, we're
up the implementation
So, on its own, a
that much more expensive
There's just one
None of this thread
like we had with reference
But this dynamic dispatch blocks
and so while the compiler
optimizations for our static
the compiler is not going to
So, I mentioned inlining.
What is inlining?
Well, let's return to our
It's got an x and y and
I've also added this
The drawAPoint method takes in a
Really fancy.
And then the body of my program
0) and passes that
Well, the drawAPoint function
and the point.draw method are
What this means is that
which implementations
and so it's actually going to
and it's just going to replace
that with the implementation
And then it's going to take
because that's a static
that with the actual
So, when we go and execute
we're going to be able to
run the implementation,
We didn't need those two --
the overhead of those
and the associated setting
up of the call stack
So, this is really cool.
And this gets to why
and how static dispatches are
Whereas like a single
to a single dynamic dispatch,
of a difference, but a whole
the compiler is going
through that whole chain.
Whereas the chain of
to be blocked at every
at a higher level without it.
And so the compiler is going
of static method dispatches just
like into a single
with no call stack overhead.
So, that's really cool.
So, why do we have
this dynamic dispatch
Well, one of the reasons is it
like polymorphism.
If we look at a traditional
with a drawable abstract
I could define a point
that override draw with their
And then I have a program
can create an array
Might contain lines.
Might contain points.
And it can call draw
So, how does this work?
Well, because point --
and line are all classes, we can
and they're all the same size
by reference in the array.
And then when we go
we're going to call
So, we can understand -- or
about why the compiler can't
which is the correct
Because this d.draw, it could
They are different code paths.
So, how does it determine
Well, the compiler adds
which is a pointer to the
and it's stored in
And so when we go and call draw,
what the compiler
on our behalf is a
to something called the
and static memory,
to the correct implementation
And so if we change this d.draw
on our behalf, we see
up through the virtual
to find the correct draw
And then it passes
as the implicit self-parameter.
All right.
So, what have we seen here?
Well, classes by default
their methods.
This doesn't make a big
but when it comes to method
it can prevent optimizations
like inlining and
Not all classes, though,
If you never intend for
you can mark it as final to
and to your future self that
The compiler will pick
to statically dispatch
Furthermore, if the
that you're never going
in your application,
it'll opportunistically turn
into static dispatches
If you want to hear about
check out this great
on optimizing Swift performance.
All right.
So, where does that leave us?
What I want you to take
of the talk is these
Whenever you're reading
you should be looking
"Is this instance
on the stack or the heap?
When I pass this
how much reference containing
When I call a method
is it going to be statically
If we're paying for
it's going to hurt
And if you're new to
in a code base that's been
over to Swift, you can likely
than you currently are today.
Like we've seen with my examples
of strings.
One question, though,
about writing polymorphic
We haven't seen that yet.
Well, the answer is protocol
And to tell you all about it,
I'd like to invite
[ Applause ]
Go get it.
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Kyle.
Hello. I'm Arnold.
Come and join me on a journey
of protocol types and
with protocol types.
We will look at how variables
and copied and how
Let's come back
to our application this
protocol types.
Instead of a drawable
we now have protocol drawable
And we have value
and struct Line conformed
Note, we could have also had
to the protocol.
However, we decided because
that reference semantics that
with it to not to do that.
So, let's drop it.
Our program was still
We could store both values of
in our array of drawable
However, compared to before,
Note that our value
and struct Point don't share a
necessary to do V-Table
that Kyle just showed us.
So, how does Swift dispatch
While it's going over
The answer to this question is a
Protocol Witness Table.
There's one of those
that implements the
And the entries in
to an implementation
OK. So, now we know how
But there's still a question,
in the array to the table?"
And there's another question.
Note that we now have
Our Line needs four words.
Point needs two words.
They don't have the same size.
But our array wants to
at fixed offsets in the array.
So, how does that work?
The answer to this question is
that Swift uses a special
Existential Container.
Now, what's in there?
The first three words in that
reserved for the valueBuffer.
Small types like our Point,
fit into this valueBuffer.
Now, you might say,
What about our Line?
It needs four words.
Where do we put that?"
Well, in this case Swift
and stores the value there and
in the existential container.
Now, you saw that
between Line and Point.
So, somehow the existential
to manage this difference.
So, how does it do that?
Hmmm. The answer to this, again,
In this case, we call it
The Value Witness Table manages
and there is one of those
Now, let's take a look at the
to see how this table operates.
So, at the beginning of the
of protocol type, Swift calls
of that table.
This function, because we
a Line Value Witness Table,
on the heap and store a
of the valueBuffer of the
Next, Swift needs to copy
of the assignment that
into the existential container.
Again, we have a Line
of our value witness table will
into the valueBuffer
OK. Program continues and we
of our local variable.
And so Swift calls
in the value witness table,
which will decrement any
that might be contained
Line doesn't have any so
And then at the very end,
Swift calls the deallocate
Again, we have a value
so this will deallocate
on the heap for our value.
OK. So, we've seen the mechanics
of how Swift can
with different kind of values.
But somehow it still needs to
Well, the answer is obvious.
The next entry in the value
In the existential
to the value witness table.
And, finally, how do we get
Well, it is, again, referenced
So, we've seen the mechanics
of how Swift manages
Let's take a look at an example
to see the existential
So, in this example
that takes a protocol
and executes the
And then our program
of drawable protocol type and
And passes this local
to a drawACopy function
In order to illustrate the code
that the Swift compiler
I will use Swift as a
this example.
And so for the existential
that has three words storage
to the value witness and
When the drawACopy
it receives the argument and
In the generated code we see
that Swift passes the
of the argument to
When the function
it creates a local
and assigns the argument to it.
And so in the generated code,
Swift will allocate an
on the heap.
Next it will read the
and the protocol witness table
from the argument
and initializes the fields in
Next, it will call a
to allocate a buffer if
In this example we
so no dynamic heap
This function just copies
into the local existential
However, had we passed
this function would allocate the
Next, the draw method
up the protocol witness
in the existential container,
in the fixed offset in
to the implementation.
But wait a second.
There's another value
Why is that there?
Well, the draw method
of our value as its input.
And note that depending
on whether our value is
into the inline buffer, this
of our existential container,
that does not fit into
the address is the beginning
of the memory allocated
So, this value witness function
depending on the type.
A draw method executes,
at the end of our function which
for the parameter
And so Swift calls a
to destruct the value,
which will decrement
if there are references in the
if a buffer was allocated.
Our function finishes executing
which removes the local
on the stack for us.
OK. That was a lot of work.
Right? There is one thing
from this is this work is what
such as struct Line and struct
to get dynamic behavior,
We can store a Line and
of drawable protocol type.
If you need this dynamism,
and compares to using
that Kyle showed us
through a V-Table and they
of reference counting.
OK. So, we've seen how
and how method dispatch works
Let's look at stored properties.
So, in this example,
that contains two stored
of protocol -- drawable
How does Swift store those
Hmm. Well, inline of
So, if we look at --
Swift will store the two
for the storage of that pair
Our program then goes
of the Line and the Point
for our Line, we will
Point fits into the inline
in the -- inline in the
Now, this representation allows
value later in the program.
So, the program goes and stores
This works, but we have
OK. Two heap allocations.
Well, let's look at a
that cost of heap allocation.
So, again, we create a
and initialize this
So, we have one, two
And then we create a
two existential containers
and then two heap allocations.
Now, you might say, "Kyle
are expensive.
Four heap allocations?
Hmm." Can we do anything
Well, remember our
for three words and
into those three words because a
So, if we implemented our Line
and class is a reference
by reference -- this reference
And when we copy the first
in our pair, only the
the only price we pay is then
Now, you might say,
Haven't we just heard about
that reference semantics
So, if we store to the x1
in our pair, the first field
And that's not what
We want value semantics.
Right? Hmmm.
What can we do about this?
Well, there's a technique
that allows us to
So, before we write
we check its reference count.
We've heard that
than one reference outstanding
the reference count will
or three, or four, or five.
And so if this is the case,
we copy the instance and
This will decouple the state.
OK. Let's take a look at how
Instead of directly implementing
we create a class
that has all the fields
And then our Line struct
And whenever we want
we just read the value
However, when we come to
we first check the
Is it greater than one?
This is what the
here achieves.
The only thing it does is
Is it greater or equal to one?
And if the reference
greater than one
of our Line storage
OK. So, we've seen how we can
to get indirect storage
Let's come back to our example
to see what happens here this
So, again, we create a Line.
This will create a line
And then we use that line
This time only the references
When we come to copy our Line --
Again, only the references
and the reference
This is a lot cheaper
It's a good trade off to make.
OK. So, we've seen how variables
and stored and how
Let's take a look what
If we have protocol types
that can fit into the
of the existential container,
If our struct does not
there's also no reference
So, this is really fast code.
However, because
through value witness and
we get the full power of
for dynamically polymorph
Compare this with large values.
Large values incur heap
initialize or assign
Potentially reference counting
if our large value
However, I showed
namely using indirect
that you can use to trade the
For cheaper reference counting.
Note that this compares
Classes also incur
And allocation on
It's a good trade off to make.
OK. So, we went back
protocol types provide a
We can use value types
and can store our
of an array of protocol type.
This is achieved by
and value witness tables
Copying of large values
However, I showed you a
around this by implementing
with indirect storage
OK. Let's come back
and take a look again.
So, in our application
a function that took a
However, the way that we use
that is we would always
Here we used it on a Line.
Later in our program we
And we thought, "Hmm.
Could we use generic code here?"
Well, yes, we can.
So, let's take a look.
During this last part of the
of generic type are
and how method dispatch
So, coming back
to our application this time
DrawACopy method now takes a
to be Drawable and the rest
So, what is different when I
Generic code supports
of polymorphism also known
One type per call context.
What do I mean by that?
Well, let's take a
We have the function foo, which
T constraint to be drawable,
and it passes this parameter
This function, again, takes
And then our program
and passes this point
When this function executes,
Swift will bind the generic
at this call side, which
When the function foo executes
to the function call
the local variable has the type
that was just found,
And so, again, the
in this call context is
As we can see, the
down the call chain
This is what we mean by a more
or parametric polymorphism.
So, let's take a look
of how Swift implements
Again, coming back to
In this example,
Like when we used
there is one shared
And this shared implementation,
like I did before
the code would look
It would use protocol
to generically perform
of that function.
However, because we have
Swift does not use an
Instead, it can pass both
and the protocol witness
of the type used
as additional arguments
So, in this case, we see
for Point and Line is passed.
And then during execution
when we create a local
Swift will use the
to allocate potentially any
and execute the copy
of the assignment
And similar when it
on the local parameter, it will
passed, look up the draw method
and jump to the implementation.
Now, I just told you there is
So, how does Swift allocate
for the local parameter --
for the local variable
Well, it allocates a
Again, this valueBuffer
Small values like a Point
Large values like our Line
and we store a pointer
of the local existential
And all of this is
of the value witness table.
Now, you might ask,
Is this any better?
Could I not -- have not just
Well, this static form
of polymorphism enables the
specialization of generics.
Let's take a look.
So, again, here is
that takes a generic
to that function
And we have static polymorphism
so there is one type
Swift uses that type to
in the function and create
that is specific to that type.
So, here we have a drawACopy
that takes a parameter
and the code inside of
specific to that type.
And, as Kyle showed us, this
Swift will create a
at a call-site in your program.
So, if we call the drawACopy
it will specialize and create
Now, you might say,
This has the potential to
Right?" But because the
that is not available
optimization, Swift can actually
size here.
So, for example, it will
of a Point method -- function.
And then further
because it now has
And so that function
to this one line and,
this can be even further reduced
Now that the drawACopy
of a Point method is
the compiler will also remove it
and perform similar optimization
So, it's not necessarily
that this compiler optimization
Can happen.
Not necessarily the case.
OK. So, we've seen how
but one question to ask
Well, let's take a look
So, we define a Point and
of that type.
Point -- initialize it to a
as a -- for argument to
Now, in order to specialize this
to infer the type
It can do that because it can
walk back to its initialization,
and see that it has been
Swift also needs to
of both the type used
and the function -- the generic
Again, this is the case here.
It's all defined in one file.
This is a place where whole
improve the optimization
Let's take a look why that is.
So, let's say I've
of my Point into
Now, if we compile those
when I come to compile the
of my Point is no
because the compiler
files separately.
However, with whole
the compiler will compile both
and will have insight into the
and optimization can take place.
Because this so greatly improves
we have now enabled a
for default in Xcode 8.
OK. Let's come back
So, in our program we had this
And, again, we noticed
Whenever we wanted to create
to create a pair
say a pair of Lines
Now, remember that the storage
of Lines would cost
When we looked at this program,
we realized that we could
So, if we define our pair to
and second property of that
type, then the compiler
that we only ever create
Furthermore, we can't store a
in the program either.
So, this is what we
the representation of that any
Let's take a look.
So, here we have our pair.
This time the store
Remember that I said that the
What that means for
that Swift can allocate
of the enclosing type.
So, when we create
the memory for the Line will
of the enclosing pair.
No extra heap allocation
That's pretty cool.
However, as I said, you cannot
later to that stored property.
But this is what we wanted.
OK. So, we've seen how
the value witness and the
and how the compiler can
type-specific versions
Let's take a look
of this first looking
at specialized generic
In this case, we have
identical to using struct
the generated code
as if you had written this
No heap allocation is
of struct type around.
No reference counting
if our struct didn't
And we have static
which enables further
and reduces your runtime
Comparing this with class
we get similar characteristics
and creating the
for passing the value around,
and dynamic dispatch
Now, let's look at unspecialized
small values.
There's no heap allocation
as we've seen, because
into the valueBuffer
There's no reference counting
if the value didn't
However, we get to
across all potential
of the witness table
OK. So, we've seen during this
characteristics of struct
and how generic code works
What -- what can we
Oh. Hmm. There you go.
I forgot the punchline.
So, if we are using large
we are incurring
But I showed you that
using indirect storage
If the large value
then there's reference counting
of dynamic dispatch, which
implementation across our code.
All right.
So, let's come to
Choose a fitting
for the entities
with the least dynamic
This will enable static type
that your program is correct at
the compiler has
to optimize your code so
So, if you can express
in your program using value
you'll get value
no unintended sharing of state,
and you'll get highly
If you need to use classes
an entity or you're working with
Kyle showed us some techniques
of reference counting.
If parts of your program can be
form of polymorphism, you
with value types and,
but share the implementation
And if you need dynamic
in our array of drawable
you can combine protocol types
get a code that is comparably
but you still can stay
And if you run into
because you're copying large
or generic types, I showed
using indirect storage with copy
and write how to
OK. So, here's some related
and about performance.
And I especially want to call
about Protocol and Value
in your UIKit Apps.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]