[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and welcome
It warms my heart to see
out for this topic.
It's near and dear to my heart.
My name is Kate Stone
and I manage the core
for debugging technology
So again it's really exciting.
I hope we'll be able to bring
from my team to tell you
if you're just starting but
to you even if you've been
for the last ten years.
It really is a deep area and
for you so let's get started.
Specifically we should note
that I'm talking about.
If you've used Xcode for
that behind the scenes there's
the low level debugger,
of the core technology,
in Xcode it's everywhere
But of course one of the more
it is in Xcode in
Xcode hosts that console as
and you'll see of course
but also this LLDB console and
to be talking about here today.
That prompted and
that you can do from
Of course that area contains
and allow to interact
but it also contains
and allows you to
for console based applications.
That may not be the
in case your application
of other console features like
other ANSI cursor
So there's a new option
to use a standalone terminal
for your application
in Xcode and it's simple.
Bring up the scheme options
at the very bottom you'll see
to switch from the
to use terminal instead.
And then when you run you'll
for your application's input
[ Applause ]
For the remainder of the talk
So if you're interested in
definitely check out the
Of course they've past by now
but the videos are there
You should also note that
but the Swift REPL
When you bring up the Swift REPL
you're interacting inside a
so that the power
of the debugger is there
In fact every command
about here you can use directly
by prefixing it with a
So colon followed by command
to LLDB.
So let's say I'm at
At this point I'm interested
on a type and of course I
at the help, but right from the
and simply say colon
And I'll have looked up this
in fact it derives
and adds the following
If you're familiar
it's a great feature
but you may not be
that despite the name type
to lookup a wider
I can actually lookup functions
or even lookup entire modules,
of content as it will
of every type in that module.
We've abbreviated it here.
So the REPL is fantastic
of additional commands but
to interact with the code
Let's say I write a
I've written a function,
in the function and find out
so I can issue the breakpoint
with a colon, colon b 2, I
and when I call this function,
And because execution has
to the LLDB prompt and from the
LLDB commands to interact with
And the REPL will also do
into an overflow
that would normally
so that you can take
of the debugger directly
You should also note
between the two prompts
If you're at the REPL prompt
by enter will bring
and the command REPL will
so you can use the two
The REPL has slightly
and may even be desirable
where you're debugging
So that's great.
It's a couple of the key ways a
but LLDB is also a
and that's fantastic if I'm a
I have a very slow
to use typical benefits
But it's also useful
You might want to use it
to automate debugging tasks.
I want to setup my debugger the
so I might go ahead and provide
of LLDB commands to
LLDB -- source followed by
and source all of those commands
to setup my debug session
If you don't want to go
up a file, you can invoke LLDB
on the command line; -- one-line
and that will be issued
and if I want additional
I can just repeat
in its abbreviated form -o
as many times as I like.
So it can be really trivial
to setup LLDB just the way I
And of course this is especially
where I have an application
out of a hundred times.
It's a race condition, I'd
like to run the same debugging
and we have a special
LLDB -- batch starts
It will execute the instructions
from one line or
and presuming my application
then exit.
If my application
at the LLDB prompt where I
And of course just
with a few other shell commands
of actions ad infinitum
until my application
to investigate the problem.
LLDB has a wide range
If you haven't looked at LLDB --
help before, I'd encourage
It describes these
I'm going to introduce one
for us as a team that's actually
thing in this entire talk.
So if you've going to forget
with this one because
You shouldn't really
but there are some
that I want to introduce.
Starting with Xcode 8, LLDB runs
in a completely separate
It's totally transparent to you.
You start debugging the way
that allows us to do is support
of the debugger.
It's selected for
so if I go to debug Swift 3
I get all of the
to introduce in this session.
And in fact if I'm using
the same thing is true.
I get the latest
of the features we'll
On the other hand, if
I'm going to wind up with the
we shipped earlier this
That means some of the newer
but we have the full support
of the Swift compiler.
But most importantly
of our open source
to debug using the
that matches the open source
So if you download a snapshot of
if your start adding
you will have a debugger
and you can actually
with debugging other programs
and everything is
There is one additional benefit
into a situation where it cannot
down the debugging session,
the debug session
LLDB can exit gracefully,
To talk about what you can
that it is and how you can
I'm going to invite up one of
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Kate.
Hi, everyone.
One of my favorite things
about LLDB is how customizable
It's not only great fun
that enables this, but it's
to be more productive in
and LLDB offers a
for you to customize it.
You can start with command
to custom commands or
and in Xcode 8 we have
for you; stepping actions.
The way to think about
like what the next command does?
Do you like what the
But do you find yourself
in just one or two little
With stepping actions
But the simplest way to
to suit your needs is to create
to take a piece of
for something you frequently do
and attach a shorter
And now in Xcode 8 we also
so that for your own purposes
or for whoever you
with you can remember
Let's see an example.
First of all, to create
with the command alias command.
Then as I said you can pass
with a short syntax, and then
command you want to replace.
And now shell is just as normal
of the ones we built into it.
You can for instance say
so you help text including
And for those situations
where debugging becomes a little
who you are as you pursue your
to remind you your identity
that it looks like I'm Enrico.
And that's great but if you want
than simply attach a new
we also vend you a Python API.
It's a fairly extensive
that lets you band the
Getting started is
We've talked about this at great
which you can find online.
We have a website with
to look at and if you
there's a community that's
around scripting LLDB.
Let me give you a quick example.
Let's say that I want a command
that lets me retrieve the return
that I exited out
Couple caveats here.
This command will work
out of a function and don't
right after.
You can type expressions,
just don't step around
Let's look at an
First of all, you import a
and then as I said
and the return values is
Okay, that's great.
That happens by default, no
But what if I type
and that's quite a
and now I don't remember
Okay, I could go up in the
but luckily enough we actually
about it, and here that return
This is all it takes
And by the way don't
that slide now, it will just be
On the other hand, you see
and now you can type your shell
and you'll find yourself
because they're awesome every
and you'll type them
until you're a literal
and all you're actually
debugger customizations.
Nope. I say no to that.
I say save yourselves
There's no need to do that.
LLDB has an initialization file.
It's called .llbdinit and
And if you need LLDB
to do something special
when launched under Xcode
there's a .llbdinit -Xcode
when launched in the
One more trick.
If you have Python commands that
don't try to type
Put them in a .py file and
that in LLDB init with
Those of you that have used LLDB
for a while are probably
with the p and po commands.
These are great commands,
at data because they
They have the entire power
of the language you're writing
for you at the debugger console.
On the other hand,
great responsibility.
These commands run coding
They have potential
and also sometimes
to run the code you
where you're currently stopped.
And if p runs code once, po
because not only does it
provide it also uses
to print the customization
in a way that's customizable
if the type author customized
in exactly the way you want it.
If you're not that lucky,
the p command provides
of variables that may be
And also po is also a command
that runs again twice
with all the potential
If that scares you, we have
at variables; frame variable.
This is a very predictable
it will not run any code.
On the other hand,
that code running ability,
the syntax it offers is
And that's quite a few ways
but spoiler alert, in
Two new ones parray and
They sound a lot like p and po
but they do something
What do they do especially
Well, if you have used
or Swift arrays you're
that knows how many
C pointers don't do that.
C pointers don't come with a
They don't know how many
when we print a C pointer like
that we're told is
But now we know that this
so we can start printing
printing the second one and we
to the little typing monkey
Well, in Xcode 8 you can say
pointer and it will
as if it was an array of the
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
That's already nice
to guess at the element count?
It's right there.
We have the count right there.
What I really want is being able
I almost can.
All I have to do is
That backtick is a general
which lets you take an
and replace the value
in the command before
And now I've got my
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Pretty much the same
poarray, number of
and I get po style
On that same topic of po,
that could write Objective C
have actually done something
without even thinking about it.
You take po, you say po followed
to know is a pointer value
and you get a pretty
And you try doing the
and all you get back
Why? What's going on?
Well, I'm sure you've heard
but I'll say it one more time.
Swift is a type safer
We can't assume that numbers
because not all Swift objects
to them.
So when we say po a number
Okay, that's great but come
on I know there's an
to me already.
There's a way to do that.
There it is.
It looks like a lot of words,
of words but it's actually
Expr -O just means po.
If you're at the LLDB
what it will tell you is that
So all we're actually
as if we were in
that we actually get the
And that's great.
On a topic related to actually
and trying to make sense of
If you remember one
about low level debugging is
Don't do it.
[ Laughter ]
Unfortunately, sometimes
Maybe you're debugging
in optimized code in the
That happens to me sometimes.
Or you're debugging
for which you have
If any of that applies to you,
follow me as we sail
of Hercules on this journey.
But please know that on
at your own risk.
It starts just like this; I
up to me in the lab with his
in that state, crashed in
And he tells me a story.
I have my app and it's
but then my framework vendor
of my frame, just
And I did update,
and now my app crashes
What do I do, please help me.
And so we sat down
we know pretty much nothing here
but one thing we can
by reading machine registers.
LLDB offers a facility to
at all the registers, only
and it even lets you
What does it look like?
You say register read and
and that's a lot of registers.
And why do I even care about
and the words on the screen?
Well, you do care because
in registers.
Okay, that's fun, but that
How do I know which ones
That is a question for your
interface ABI, the colon
those rules.
But LLDB also exposes
to you convenient pseudo
and so on which in the case
in which your arguments are
or pointer types
between the registers
Similar convenience is available
So for example, if
that takes these three
those arguments will
to $arg1, $arg2, and $arg3.
Okay, so that applies
We're in Objc msgSend, we
The first argument is
the second argument
by appending string.
We happen to know that Objc
object we're trying to message
and the second argument is the
and we can also use the memory
up with the object
It turns out that's
What is happening is that
on a bad object.
How did we get there?
Well, we're in Objc
something called Objc msgSend,
that called it and so on and so
to the entry point
In LLDB we call the frames from
to frame N the oldest and if
you can use the up command
on the stack and
to go back to a younger frame.
Another thing worth knowing
which lets you look at the
You can do that for
for an arbitrary frame, for an
you can customize the way
and in some cases
where you do have source code
to compare those instructions
to machine instructions
to always show you always
with source code.
So in our case, we crashed there
that called our function
that did finish launching.
So let's go there real quick
that function is doing.
That function is
that our framework vendor
that initializer,
It's moving some stuff around
to Objc msgSend that
So we can step around
and see what these calls
First of all we step over
and then I'm going to
I happen to know that the
return value of that
that's just the bad
Interesting.
Let's step around a
No, that isn't changing
All we're doing is taking
and moving it into rdi and
I wonder if that's connected?
If I reg read $arg1 at this
msgSend, rdi the
What have we proven
We've proven to ourselves that
that our framework
to get us calling actually
and upon trying to send a
big surprise, our
And on that note of patting
for conclusively proving
over to Sean Callanan
about the great new features
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Isn't that magic?
It feels like magic.
Your program is just
arrays of numbers and yet you
to represent that data in
Sometimes though it's not
at a number and figuring
Sometimes you need
Now, Enrico has already
where the expression parser fits
in in the general
but there's a lot
The expression parse's job is to
and the SDK and get from
through some contortions to get
that you're actually
Now, I said we work
and we work with the SDK.
Working with the SDK hasn't
if you remember from
So for example if
in an Objective C
to get the program's undo
at least once or twice
It wasn't at all relevant to
and it was really puzzling.
But last year we told
to get out of this.
If you just manually
expression works.
All right, but why
It's already there.
I hear you cry.
[ Laughter ]
You're not the only ones.
So this year we thought what
and it was pretty obvious.
We looked at which modules the
and we import them
No more of that manual
[ Applause ]
Cool. So we're getting out
That's great, but this is
Let me tell you about
that you can do with it.
Now, sometimes these
in your way.
You're actually trying
to manually import
There's a feature, a
to disable this automatic
and get back the feature
We think you're going to like
Great. Now let's
about using the expression
by reusing code.
Now, the most simple case
of reusing code is
Now remember I said you might
to get to the data that you
where you currently are.
In Swift you can do
as defining a temporary
This just works.
It's as if you typed
Now what might be
if you try to use it again.
Then we say, what's
Well, actually we intended
The reason is you might
in different places, maybe
where you're program
Do we want the A you used
as a temporary valuable
Probably not, but there
The affordance we
that your variables don't escape
in that way is we actually
It's as if you actually put a
put the let A in there and the
to break out, all you have to
a name with a dollar sign.
That means that it
with your own program's names
as long as your debug
Awesome. What else can
It turns out quite a lot.
Now in Swift ever
and Swift you've been able to do
Now when you did that
to use multiline
if you typed the expression
you're immediately going
where you can type
If you define your function then
remembering the dollar sign.
Now, those of you who
and said that's awesome might
and it wasn't so great.
Function definition
Come on these LLDB guys
All right.
Well, turns out we
we think it's awesome,
But we can't just make
The reason is remember
We want to act like we're
If you're in Swift you can
it's no big deal, the
It won't love the dollar
but the rest it's fine with.
This is totally legal.
In C, C++ and Objective C though
like that, that's no good
to yell at you.
Well, the way you get
around that is using the
That's an extension of
that makes it break completely
out of the current
and just define global
or variables or what you will.
Now you can define your function
and use it just the
All right.
Now the functions aren't
can define.
I've already talked
You can define closures too,
of variables and code.
In Swift you can define
New in Xcode this year
in Objective C.
Blocks can be defined and
who are diehard C++ fans,
you can do the exact
Now, what can you do
What's special about them.
Well, you can pass them off
Sometimes you might need
to manually run something
That works.
You can send stuff for
and the block will simply run.
Now, sometimes it
because these complex
in much more likelihood
Now, what's the difference
to the previous slide between
from the previous slide?
You probably missed it.
The compiler sure didn't.
It will yell at you about
but there's a better way.
If you were to type this
we would have told you,
semicolon here.
Did you mean to put it in?
Well, it turns out LLDB
and we can do one better by
in the semicolon
running your expression.
This is called fixit.
It's been in clang for a while
and LLDB now applies
Swift has fixit too.
In Swift you're less likely
but boy those exclamation
[ Laughter ]
Yeah. Well, they are as valuable
for you to understand it,
when you're debugging you
out of your way, and
So if you try to use something
we just apply the fixit
Now, there may be
who say I don't want
Now, for those people I
and we have settings that will
fixit feature and
like the debugger
out every little thing in your
then you can turn just
All right.
[ Applause ]
Thanks. All right.
Great. That's a nice convenience
up with just one more thing that
You can define your own types.
In Swift for example you can
that defines a class and
that class indeed it
as if you had defined the
In the same way in C++, you can
Now let me show you an example
and using them in
Often especially in your
with web APIs you get a lot
to filter it especially
The way you filter data
by defining a predicate.
Now in the expression parser you
In this case we're
that takes the result
and filters them to find strings
that have the text
Probably useful for debugging.
Now if you simply take
from your web server and you
you can get right
that you actually cared about.
All right.
Now you've hopefully seen how
can be for you, I'd like to
to show you more
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Sean.
So, so far we've sort of
of things and told you
of your program when you're
yet told you how you
to such interesting points.
So that's with what I'm going
Of course breakpoints
that you would stop
So I want to talk a little
about breakpoints naively as the
but that's actually not
or how LLDB thinks about them.
To LLDB a breakpoint
through your program space
or many different kinds of
So breakpoints are
and what the individual
what you thought of
we call breakpoint locations.
So to make this a little more
to Xcode's breakpoints because
when it debugs is LLDB
so all the Xcode breakpoints
So for instance when you click
what you're really doing is
some breakpoint setting command.
Similarly when you make a
running a by name
So I want to give
that these are really
in which you would end up
from what you thought of as
setting, so the first example
that I'll show you is
So here's an example
to just set a breakpoint
That should be a simple
But then it says, no
Well, while did you
Do the break list
of your breakpoint
that the breakpoint name
matching search, so for instance
within a class and
in many cases because like
and you have a name space, and a
and a method, you don't
of the full path to that but
that the search is perhaps wider
We provide many different
so of course we provide a
which is the full name
to match the entire name of the
We tried that but even
Well, for some reason somebody
to have a function called main
So you can even specify
to a particular shared
So then finally then you
I'm going to give you
because I don't think
but because this one actually
with file and line breakpoints
because Swift has
that you can call a
and define the closure simply by
and then on with the
But then if you try to set
what you're going to find out
Why do you have that?
When you look it's actually
That source line actually
to the closure function and
location on the closure
but it also was the invoking
and so you also have a
So anyway that's for that so now
let me give you the general
on to some more interesting
So the breakpoint set
You say break set and then
which specify the type
and that's really
of search that you're doing.
Is it a file and line
or so on and so forth?
And the values for that
for the search and then there
like ignore count,
The way to think about those
where to break, they
So that's the whether can be
where can't because we've
and you would just
if you wanted to do that.
So let's talk a little bit about
which are the places where
They are the individual
they always have some
at which your program
When you look at them
by the generating
and a location number
So if you actually notice
and you stop at one of your
at the little PC ribbon, the PC
on the far right and
but it always says 2.1.
It never said breakpoint 2
because you only ever
so 1.1, 1.2 or whatever.
By the way, the locations
of symmetrical with
of these other options
They all take the same sort of
and conditions and so forth,
and you can specify a
on a breakpoint and then it
but you can also override
of the commands or
on the location instead.
One other little convenience,
oftentimes if you have a
bunch of locations,
you don't want five of
which you can do independently,
but then if you you don't want
to be able to disable the whole
by disabling the breakpoint.
But it turns out that doesn't
of it locations so then you
and all of the location state
So that's just a little thing.
So now that you've
the notion of how breakpoints
let me show you a couple
of breakpoints that
So again these are
What kinds of searches
It's just what name spaces
in your program might
It turns out all of the
of stringy things because
of functions or whatever, so we
as the way to express
So if you know regular
this will make you feel lovely,
and if you don't
I would have said a couple
in your office that
on them although
for somebody old you
for somebody who
[ Laughter ]
[ Applause ]
So anyway, so we provide
one is fairly obvious which
of functions in your program
and one that might be
but I'll convince you
as we go along, are sourced
And this is the option
Okay, so let's give you the
pattern matching breakpoints
and I'll just show
So suppose somebody has
and you don't know what it does,
so what you want to
on all the methods implemented
by going through the source
on the beginning of all of them
but that would quickly
And by the way, you
on the parent or
What would be better
up a regular expression
which matches all the
So in Swift this is an
or in Objective C this is an
So then you would have
of those then you could run your
through and see what's going on.
And remember because you can
when you do this
you find that you hit one of
you're uninterested in that
that location then
The second one you figure out
So that's kind of a nice
An even more radical version
of the same thing is somebody
library that does some stuff.
You want to just see
when it's running then set a
I'm using the short
and the regular expression
that's what .star
to the library you're
Combining this with breakpoint
nice way just to sort of
of execution through this
and maybe print the
and you'll just run your
of the execution
Of course it slows
but you know whatever
And then the other trick
that you don't care about,
So let me talk about
of pattern matching in source.
So the point here is that
that are really obvious
at your source text but
in the generated code
So an example of this is macros
which generally just
into your program and then
where they're inserted
because they're the things
So you want to do a search
or for the particular
But you can even be
so for instance I
that a particular field
which is something that in
because it's going
but in generated code
quite difficult.
So that's another instance
in your source can allow
that you might not be
Then another use of this is to
that you can set
by inserting patterns
into your source code like
or break here when
in inspecting this
of my program's functionality
and then using these source
to catch it.
So here's how the source
command works.
There's source regular
the data you're providing for
and then you can limit it to
to multiple files by just
times and there's also a flag
So let me just give you an
Suppose I had like a complex
which is computing stuff
from many different places
in some horrible huge case
like that, and I'm interested
to return null but I'd like
in this particular run through
and that's a hard thing
because you can stop
and check whether it's null.
You can go click on all the
but you might miss one or you
There's one other
in the source regular
which is you can specify not
to a particular function so in
that case I'd do
I'd break my pattern
and then I'm doing showing
because I'm showing off, space
and then my null pointer I limit
to a file I'm interested in and
through exactly where
in this particular usage.
So it's worthwhile
of extra breakpoint options that
One of them is along
or the filter kind that's
and Objective C together in
to specify a language
So for instance, there are a
in the world and if
on the name count you're
of Swift code but you're also
of Objective C methods
about the Objective C methods,
then you can just
and it won't set a
of the Objective C names
So that's just a useful little
And one other option that's
to narrow your search
So you've got some code that's
of different threads, it's like
but you've starting working
and you don't want your
for the investigation
onto other threads,
There's a thread ID option and
by thread name which you set
with this pthread
That one is convenient because
that persists over
where of course the thread ID
and you can even restrict it
on a particular queue by name.
One other thing that
that you can add all these
and particularly that's
and line breakpoint
but then you decide you want to
to a particular thread and
after the fact, the
and the other useful thing
in this slide is showing
because you can specify
by breakpoint location number
and there's also a little
That's that.
So now you've come up with
that you want but you run into
that it turns out Xcode
at present only persists
that it knows you set and so
to write in by hand
So how do you make them persist?
The first way is what Enrico
to hold for all projects,
in your LLDB init file
But if you want to make
here's a cute little
to get the breakpoints
that particular project.
What you do is make an
preferably something that's
on in your program execution,
and then you put
as commands in that one.
So you know if you're a main
main is a very convenient place
so you would make a
and then you would put main in
and then you would remember
where I told you about our
so you would specify
then you would add an action
which is a debugger command
in all of the breakpoints
because that's just
It's much easier to put
and then use LLDB's
to load those commands in,
and then finally
if you autocontinue then just
automatically have all of
So I want to show you one other
to overcome one particularly
in modern languages which
to step you're trying
but the problem is that in
of the variable access is
or through accessor
and they're generally that's not
So you end up in a scenario
like this you know I'm
into this function,
I want to step in there.
So I try that I step and I
of the arguments that I was
so I ended up in the accessor.
I don't want to be there because
so what I'm going end
out and stepping back.
So is there any way that we can
And it turns out that we've
stepping so the option
that you would say by
to do is I want you to step
in this particular place,
that's what you're
So let's try that in this
that it almost but
and the reason it
because though we didn't
we ended up on the next source
And that makes sense
because actually stepping is
and that was the multiline call.
So we've also added the
of the stepping operation
by saying what the
or even more conveniently
through this block and get me
And there's even
which is sif step in function.
So then what you would do
and you would say step in
in the right place or if you
on the slide.
So that I want to conclude
of troubleshooting information.
One piece of information
to know is what is actually
For instance maybe I built
and I want to know which
or somebody gave me a
Did the dSYM get read in?
So the command that inquiries
about that information is
You can either give
in which case it will
about just one module
or for amusement's sake you can
of them which is
So here's an example just
I say image list example
to the binary so for
to check whether I was
okay it does look like
and if there is a
it will always be
so in this case I see
I want to tell you one thing
I put on this slide the why
to tell you the why because
of time, but I'll tell you
through too fast
The TLDR is that because of
with one another all the
that has debug information
so copying binaries from other
and stuff like that.
You have to have made sure
that everything has been built
that goes along with
that you're currently using.
I want to say this is one
and so Enrico's rule of
as we saw earlier is don't do
since most software developers
write a corollary to that
who debug optimized code
So now LLDB will tell you
that a file was compiled
It will only tell
and you'll get a little
And then you run quickly
and change them back.
One other new feature
to clang a while ago was
So modules are a way to
at all the headers that
for your program, compile
and then reuse that
So then we thought well why
for the debug information?
Why don't we allow that parsed
to be also done once and then
that you have debug information?
So that's called clang
We can also use PCH
The setting in Xcode is
and here's the flag for
This is great because again like
up the generation of the debug
up your compile times but it has
that or actually one major one.
So that caveat is that now
on your .o files but also
in some cache somewhere.
So normally that's not a
but when you go to ship
to somebody else, how
Well, if it's an application
or a framework then you just
and it does the right job,
it gathers everything
But remember that dsymutil
it doesn't work on .o files.
So if you are shipping static
then you must turn off
or you will ship broken debug
And also by the way, if you're
and you delete your module
to be able to debug anymore.
So that's the only down
So with that let me tell
We hope that you see that LLDB
debugger providing you many
that expressions actually
for investigation and I
of how you actually
and find what you're interested
that we have more
of in your Xcode and that
into super deep trouble
than source level debugging,
and in general we hope we
for exploring your code.
And here are a couple
that might have interesting
There were a couple of sessions
or did see but anyway they
And with that thank
that you enjoy the little tiny
[ Applause ]