[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Kris Markel.
I'm a member of Apple's
And today we're going to talk
about using Time
So here's our agenda.
We're going to start with an
What it is, and how
And then we're going
of making an application
And then finally, ensuring we
in our application.
But before we do that,
let's talk about why
And the reason we're doing
to provide a great
We want our users to love
We want them to love
because they're fast.
Cheetah fast.
So it saves them time and
We want to make sure our users
So that they're able
to use their devices
And you don't want to be that
of the battery usage chart.
And finally, we want to make
and a really responsive
so users love using it.
And how are we going to do this?
We're going to use a
Profiling is answering
about your application.
How much work is it doing?
And what kind of
And, if you hadn't
we're going to use a tool
Time Profiler answers
of when is my app
Time Profiler is part of an
that is a collection of
that measure all kinds of
And how do we get started?
Well, it's really easy.
From Xcode's Product menu,
you just go ahead
So let's go ahead
Okay. So first I'm going
Give you an idea
My application uses the
at the user's photo library
So I'm going to go
And it takes a little while
when my test data has
So it comes up with
Okay, that's done.
Now I'm going to go ahead
And then let's find a good one.
Here is one.
And then it uses the core
So I can add some
And then it uses UI
to make the googly eyes jump
around when you shake
Okay. So that's the application.
Let's go ahead and profile
So from Xcode's Product
and just like I said,
This is going to do a release
and then launch Instruments
It's important to do
because you want all
that you'll get from
So this will take just a moment.
And it's copying the
Here we go.
So now Instruments comes up.
And it's going to show
And this you get an idea
of tools Instruments
Today, of course, we
So I'm going to go
Now if you've never
this user interface can
But getting started
All I have to do is go
up in the corner, and click it.
That's going to start
and start measuring it.
So let's go ahead
Okay, so now my application
It is starting.
There we go.
Right? I'm going to do
Just one moment.
Okay. And then I'm
and do my duplicate checking.
And let's see if we
There we go.
Okay, now that's done.
Now I'm going to
And then I'm going
Add some googly eyes.
Shake it around.
Now let's go ahead and
And then I'm going to go
I'm clicking the Stop button.
And now we can see here, I have
of what my app was doing.
Time Profiler gives
This top part of Instruments
The first graph is my CPU usage.
How much CPU my app is using.
And I can actually hover over
The second graph is what
is in, and how long
So that gives me
of how much work my
and when it's doing it.
But how do I know what
And to figure that out,
we go down to Instrument's
Which is this part here
And the Call Tree View
stack samples aggregated
and shown in the Detail view.
Now what exactly does this mean?
Well, this is a lot
in pictures, rather than words.
So let's go ahead and
So here we have time,
And here is our very
We have a main method
That's calling into method2.
At this point in time,
to get a call stack
and it looks like this.
This is just like the call
in the debugger in Xcode.
But Instruments or Time Profiler
And it does that so it can
which we'll see in a moment.
So time continues on.
Oh, and then it records
And it records the number of
or function within
So time continues, and
method1 calls method3 which
Then we go ahead, one
And Time Profiler's going
And in this case, it looks
So we'll go ahead
And we just increment
And time's going to
And now we see our application
We have main calling directly
into method2; calling
Time Profiler's going to take
And now we can see our
It only has two methods
And then so when we update our
So now we know that
and sometimes it calls method2.
And we know exactly how
of those things.
So time continues on, and we
These happen to be identical
And so we're going to update
So now let's take a look at
telling us.
One thing to note is that
measuring duration.
It's not recording
and then when it exits and
It's aggregating the samples
So when you see time
it's not an actual
That's the number of
by the time between samples.
Which is 1 millisecond,
This does have some
And one of them is that Time
between long running methods,
that are called repetitively.
And we can actually see that in
and method2 show up in the
From Time Profiler's
they incurred the
But we know that method1
and ran for longer, method2
and was much shorter.
Time Profiler's also really
It's answering the question;
what work is my application
And another result of this
capture everything.
In fact, what's missing
There's no method3, right?
If you have really
or really fast methods that
they won't appear
And this is actually okay.
This is what we want.
Because they're not having an
to be doing over time.
So now that we have a better
let's see how we can use it to
Okay. So looking back at my
at this big, first
I can see that I'm
for a significant
So I want to see exactly
I happen to know, that's when I
I know I expect that
of work, so I'm not surprised.
But wherever you're
there's usually an
So in order to get a better
I'm going to use the
to pinch to zoom in; un-pinch.
So I can get a much better
on in this time period.
And then I'm going to go
across the Timeline view.
And this is going
So now my call tree is only
that were collected
If you notice, now you can see
that the call tree is actually
It's only really focused
So now let's take a look at
You'll see a few columns here.
There's Weight and Self
The weight represents
that that particular portion
And you'll see next to the
And like I said before,
That's the number of
by the time between each sample.
And then there's
which is actually the amount
within that method itself,
and not some other
And you can see actually
If I go ahead and just
It's still 0.
What this is telling
99% of my samples were in main.
But actually, all of
within UIApplication main.
And all of those were
within whatever UIApplication
And instead of disclosing
I'm going to use a new
Where I hold down
and click the Disclosure
And this gives me
So it's going to just
until there's actually
And if we go ahead
we can see now we
that have some self
In fact, if I look at this
I can see, you know, its
and its self weight is the same.
So it's spent all
Didn't call any subsequent
And actually, you know,
I see a lot of these
And they're actually all have
These runtime methods are
and run really quickly.
And they're usually
that Time Profiler
because they run so quickly.
But since they're showing up,
I know that generally
So they're showing
This is usually the case if
of Objective-C objects, you'll
So the other thing the
over here on the right.
We can see which
of the call tree came from.
That particular method call.
And here we can see
with the photo's framework.
And we actually work our way up.
Scroll to the right here.
We can see, here's
from my app that's causing
You know, this particular
It's not doing any
But it's the thing that's
You know, I'm not
to make Objective-C release
if there's something here I
So I'm going to double
And it's going to
And Instruments annotates
of samples that appeared in.
So looking at this
of my time is spent on
But if I take a closer look,
I actually see something
I have nested four loops.
And in fact, each of
over my entire photos
And this is pretty much a
as N squared behavior.
As I throw more data at this
and slower, and slower.
And since I know
over a lot of data, this is bad.
So I want to go ahead
So I'm going to go into Xcode.
And here's my code here.
A typical way of avoiding
set-based implementation.
I'm not going to go into
and created a new algorithm
for doing my duplicate
That uses a counted set and
Now let's go ahead and verify
that I actually made
So again I'm going to
And I'm going to choose Profile.
It's going to rebuild
and install it to the device.
And then since Instruments
it's going to go ahead and
So as it's copying it
starting the profiling.
Here's Instruments.
And my application has started.
Okay, and it's starting
I'm going to zoom out.
Okay, I'll zoom out so
And I'm going to go ahead
Duplicates.
All Photos.
And I can see the data come in.
Oh, I'm actually at minutes.
I thought this was seconds.
Okay. So my duplicate checking
In fact, we no longer
across the timeline anymore.
So that's a good change.
I want to go ahead and
I'm going to select some photos.
I'm going to add some eyes.
I'm going to shake it.
And then I'm going to
So now my application is static.
It shouldn't be doing any work.
But let's go ahead
at what the Time
Let's stop the recording.
It's taking a minute to
Whoa. Okay, so I can see
at the end of the call,
It's not much, but I'm
So I want go ahead and
I'm going to zoom in
And then I'm going
to see what's going on here.
And then I'm going to go ahead
to see what's going on.
And now if you look
this time I can see
of calls in CoreMotion, right?
And I know what my app is doing
to detect and make
But moving back up the call
of my code in this call tree.
So there's nothing I'm doing
But something in my app is
when it shouldn't be.
And what I know about
that I'm not turning off
when there are no
So let's go ahead
We go back to Xcode.
And then I actually have
It's just a matter
So let me go ahead
And then we stop observing here.
Okay. Now let's measure this
and make sure it changed
And again, Instruments is going
to rebuild the application;
And also, since Instruments
it'll start recording again.
This time I'm going to
And I also click outside of the
Okay. And once the
Instruments will start
Okay, there we go.
Okay, so this time
and just go ahead
And then I'm going
Select it.
Add the eyes.
Do the shaking let's actually
I'm going to choose a new photo
And then let's go ahead
and see if it changes
And now if I zoom in on the end
processing the data.
I can see that my CPU usage
So I'm no longer doing that
So let's take a look and
So the first thing we did, is
out how much work our app was
And it was a good way to find
And the trackpad or the timeline
But it also works
You can option-drag, and
So we found an area
that was using a lot of CPU.
And we wanted to
So we went ahead, we zoomed in,
We examined the call
out where the work was happening
And then we walked
until we actually
What part of our app is
even though it's not
We took a look at our code.
We thought about it.
Scratched our heads.
We ate a sandwich,
out a way to make it faster.
So we went ahead and implemented
that they actually
It was a significant
And as a result, we saved
Now when they're using my
they won't be looking
It'll finish much more quickly.
Now in terms of doing
Again, we focused on an
where this time it
but it was using an
We zoomed in.
We applied a filter.
We took a look at the call
at the frameworks involved
but none of our code
So this time we had to think
about our app in
What portion of our app is
We went ahead and again,
Ate another sandwich.
And figured out how to make
so it's no longer happening.
We went ahead and
Verified that our changes did
And actually, as
we significantly improved the
is running.
Any time the CPU can go
that represents significant
So even though our
it still has a battery cost.
So now that we've gone
let's talk about making
So the way your application
that does all the
It's responsible for
and then updating your views.
And the way it handles
is that it's got a main thread.
And the main thread has a run
queue called an Event
for events to appear on it.
When an event appears, it
or NS application instance.
Which then passes the event
down through the responder
And if you application wants
then it goes ahead
And you can actually see
Here's the call stack
And we can see there,
It calls the main function
where all our applications
Now in here, I don't know
but they're clearly
And I can see here, here's
So it's clearly got an
and it's handling it.
I can see it gets passed into my
through the responder chain
And in this case, this is
And then my code does its work.
So what does this mean in terms
Well, when busy, the main
So it starts to back up
And then as a result, you
And in the worst case, your app
The user closes it, and maybe
So it's really important to
so it's able to respond
in a very quick manner.
So now with that in our
with our app in order to
All right, I'm going to
on the track view this time.
And now the area I want to focus
on is this big CPU
And here I'm seeing
So there's probably
for optimization here.
And I happen to know,
when I'm adding my
So again, I'm going to just
I'm going to go ahead and click
Now if we look at the call
to specifically focus on what
I can see here that actually,
about 63%, 64% of my samples.
And so I know that
it's clearly doing some work.
But I want to know exactly
And to do that, I'm going
in the upper right-hand corner,
we have what we call
and Instruments.
So you can view your data,
This time I want to look
And I can actually see, if I
that over here on the left,
you can see all the
And the main thread
And so I can actually
on just the main thread.
And here, clearly, it's
And when it's in that state,
it absolutely can't
There's no way it's going
on the queue if it's busy
So what work is it doing
This time, I'm going
on our extended detail view
And this is going to show me my
work on my main thread.
Because my main thread is what's
So I scroll through here,
I can see again here's
And then here we
And this is the code where
And then doing some
And then here it's
So that's the face detection
And then we can actually see the
into Core Image.
If I go ahead and click on
it'll expand the call
Now again, reasoning
There's no reason for me
to do face detection
It's not a responding
And it's not an updating
So this can easily be moved
So here's my code that
And I can see once the face
and calls the displayEyes
Now an important
that displayEyes is
So that's work that has to
So what I need to do
on a background thread.
Switch back to the main thread.
In order to update my UI.
Oh, there we go.
Okay [applause] thank
That's not supposed to be
but I'll take it.
So here we go.
Here's my code that does
I'm going to very
So we go ahead and we get
And we dispatch our
Then just like I said,
to the main queue,
This time to do my
on the Run menu,
This will do the same thing.
Hopefully rather quickly.
Oh, I deleted my code.
Let's do that again.
So now since I've already done
is it going to be happy --
There we go.
It's going to build
Install it to the device.
Okay. Now Instruments
and start recording
Oh, so I'm going to go
to the Instruments view.
And then let's zoom out so we
Okay. Very quickly, let's
And then let's do
So there we go.
So there I can see
Let's go ahead and
And now let's see if this
So again, I'm going to
of the graph using a trackpad.
I'm going to click and drag
across the Timeline
Now, if we go ahead and look
actually what I see here
in 4.8% of my samples.
So that's a really good sign.
I already know my main
And those two worker threads
So let's go ahead and switch
And now I can see here, my main
free for the vast majority
[ Applause ]
So let's go ahead and
and talk about what
So in order to make my
I've found an area where the
And I went ahead and zoomed in
and applied a filter
I focused on the main
to make sure my app
I identified some work
on the main thread
So I went ahead and moved
Once again you can probably
I verified my changes.
Made sure the app was behaving
And as a result, I got a
My user interface will remain
face detection.
Which is really great.
A couple notes regarding
The fixes we made today
but they did add
And in general, the practice
of optimization is trading
But fortunately, because
in my development cycle I
I now have time to verify
that my app continues
I can add additional unit tests
if I think that's
And focus on where
and make sure it still works.
Just before you're about to ship
you want to be adding
So the real takeaway
to profile your app
Especially after you
And profile early.
And then profile it
And sometimes, just
and seeing what you can find,
you can find a really
So it pays just to
if there's anything
Some best practices about
The general overview here is
as close as you can to what
So you always want to
Not only do you want the
but release builds are what your
You always want to
The simulator is not going
to give you useful
Profile on the oldest, slowest
A pretty good rule is, if
on slower devices; you
on faster devices for free.
And you want all of your users
to have a great experience
Even the ones on slower devices.
And use large data sets
In my case, you know, sometimes
or hundreds of thousands or
in their photos collection.
It's important that I
under those circumstances.
So I can make sure it runs well
as my customers will
So, to wrap everything up,
to love using your app because
It helps them achieve
And your UI is really
to do is profile early
If you want more information,
Here are some related -- oh,
Last year we did a session
Which goes into more detail
if you want to know more.
And then this year we
System Trace in Depth.
Which is how you can use
in situations where Time
Thank you, and have
[ Applause ]