[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon,
I'm Alex, and Jacob and I are
about how you can use
to make your app better.
And we're going to focus today
on something called
Local reasoning means that
right in front of you, you don't
of your code interacts
You may have had
and that's just a
For example, maybe when
and you have tons of code to
can you understand what's going
And so the ability to do
because it makes it easier
and easier to test, and easier
to write the code
And so we're going to talk
about how local reasoning
in the context of model view
which is what Cocoa uses, where
the view presents that data,
and the controller
And so we need a real app to
Unfortunately, we actually
that we needed to solve.
So I'm going to tell
about how we plan
Engineers have dreams and
about for what they're
And so somehow we need to take
but we noticed a lot
of engineers don't actually
by the time they get into work.
They forget them.
So Jacob and I developed this
and the app is called
I want to show you
that people had over
Some people dream of unicorns.
This is serious [laughter].
Strangely, some people were also
and even more wanted to just get
out of the office
And some engineers
[ Applause ]
And so that was the
But since we're going
to be using the app
I want to give you a quick
for what this application does.
And so if we launch the app,
to the list of dreams
And if you tap one of the
And so you can see we
We can scroll down and we're
like laser focus and rain.
And so if we scroll back up, you
of a unicorn with laser focus,
And so when we're done editing
to the list of our dreams.
And so that's the app.
And we wanted to think really,
really hard about how we could
And so we watched these
from last year.
These sessions focus on
and protocol-oriented
And these ideas were so powerful
of them because they can
in our application.
And so we wrote our app with
Now some of these ideas
to you and that's okay.
When we were initially
they felt foreign to us too.
So don't worry.
Just stick with us.
And so we're going to
of value types in
This was already
so it's going to
Then we're going to focus on
in the viewing controller
where we think most people don't
of value types, even
tangible benefits.
And along the way we're going to
and protocols made
And as you just saw this awesome
We've shipped this
so you can go download it
and log your own dreams.
All right, so now it's time
So what is a dream?
A dream is our model type
that represents a dream
A dream as a description, a
as you saw in the UI earlier on.
Now I want to show you a
that we used last year in
We started with a dream
Now classes have
meaning that references
to the same instance
and that sharing is implicit.
So why is that a problem?
Well, let's say someone tries
If we only care about
that the variable's
from underneath our control.
And this really hurts
And we had exactly this kind
even though our test passed.
But why was that?
And so this diagram
of the first version
Some of these relationships
some of them can be
and some of them can even
And so these relationships can
So what happens when we try
and test just the
Well, even if you create a
this doesn't reflect
because there are
that actually exist.
And so that's not good.
And so we can solve this by
which has value semantics.
This means each variable
So changing the value
in one doesn't change
And so if we modify
we only change dream2's
And so this guarantees us
in the complicated relationships
And so this really improves
because no code can change
from underneath our control.
Now using value types --
So we just saw how
of value types in
And using value types
in the model layer is actually
But wouldn't you want to take
that we just saw in other
And that might actually
So I want to share with you
on the Internet and that
for simple model types."
That doesn't seem encouraging.
But do we believe everything
And the answer is no, if you
And so for the remainder of
on how you can use
than just simply model
and at the same time we'll
There we go.
And with that, I'd like
to talk about the view layer.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Alex.
I'm really excited to tell you
about how we use
together with views.
So we spent a lot
on our app's table view cells.
We had a specific design for
to implement to make sure that
about showed up exactly right.
Now when we started our
as abstract subclasses
For example, this simple layout
it just shows a small
and a larger content
Then, we made a concrete
that added our specific
And we did this separation
to reuse our layouts
But as we worked
we found that this
It helped us reuse our layout in
to use outside of a table view.
For example, we had
that showed more
but we couldn't reuse
So we wanted to find a
where we could use our layouts
but also in plain UI views.
And we also want to add
to show those cool particle
to use our layouts with
So those are our goals
about Swift to achieve this.
Now although I'll be talking
I want you to keep in mind
that these techniques can
All right, let's get started.
Now this is what our layout
It has two views that it lays
for this layout logic to be
It's just some math
out the right set of frames.
So let's change this from a cell
It will still have our two
of that layout logic into a
in to, to lay them out.
Now just with that small change,
we now have a really isolated
to do our layout
Then, we can update our dream
to lay out its children.
And what's great is
in our UIView subclass as well.
Now that this layout logic is
we can use it in any UIView.
And there's another
Now that our layout can be used
for us to run a unit
We can just create some
and then lay them
Then, we just have to verify
that the resulting frames
Our test doesn't have to
for the right view layout
It can just tell our layout to
And this is part of a general
Our new layout struct is
This change has made
to reason locally
So if we want to understand
we just have to understand
We don't have to
of view capabilities it
Okay, now let's go back to
So right now, this still only
But as I said earlier,
to support SpriteKit as well.
So we don't want to have
but SKNode is not a
So there's no common
So how can we combine these
Well since the only thing
with these children is
that's the only functionality
And we can represent that
So we'll make the protocol
and it'll just have a single
This isn't very flushed out yet,
but we'll improve
Then, we use this
of our children instead
And finally, we can use
to make UIView and SKNode
And now we have a layout that
and this is one of the
on protocols instead of
We can use this, add
to unrelated types
Now, our layouts no longer
on UIKit as well.
And so another thing that we
system to AppKit
out NS views just as easily.
I think that's pretty cool.
So we're really close now,
but there's something
When we're using a
we want to be able to add all
And similarly, when we're
we want to be able to add
But right now, content
and decoration can be any
And that means that for
that was a UIView and
But instead, we want our
of only UI views or only
And that way we'll
to their appropriate parent.
Now Swift has a great way of
So we can update our
with a type parameter
Then, we can make the content
and decoration properties
And this gives us
We can enforce that they're
And so we can have
with just UI views or one
So generics are a great tool
that let us have
over the types in our code.
Another great benefit
that the compiler
about what your code is doing.
So it can optimize more.
And you can learn about
in the Understanding
It's a great talk for learning
to write fast Swift code.
Okay, we now have a
of our DecoratingLayout.
But our app also includes
like this fancy cascading one.
And this layout is very
that we just looked at.
They both show a large
with a detailed decoration
And we don't want to
to create this new layout
because that would miss
to create a shared abstraction
So how can we share
Well, one tool you've
to share code is inheritance.
But with inheritance,
and please don't try to read
to consider what your
and what your subclasses might
So instead of just
that you're working
to pull together a large amount
of code that's spread
And this is just the
A lot of the time you also
like UIView or view
of magnitude more code there.
So inheritance is another place
where you really sacrifice the
But we can share code in a much
Composition is a simple idea
pieces together to
But when composing, you can
pieces in isolation.
And you can also enforce
about subclasses or
in your abstractions.
But composition isn't
You've probably used in the past
with Objective-C
And one way that we could've
to compose views together.
So you could've written a UIView
that does this cascading layout
that does our decorating
Then you could've added
in your table view cell.
But there's a big
Class instances are
When you make another object,
you have an extra
and this is even
There's a lot of work that's
to allow to do things like
And because of this,
to minimize the number
So making a view that does
as a layout abstraction
And that's why doing composition
with views doesn't
But with Swift, we have a much
and that's with value types.
Structs are very lightweight,
without paying the high
with classes and views.
And structs are also better
With value types you have
so you can use these pieces
without having to worry
about someone else modifying
So let's apply this
Well, we can write the cascading
with an array of
Then, we want to compose this
to get the final effect.
But there's one more small
These layouts only
that are UI views or SK nodes.
So let's generalize this
and compose them together.
Well the layout protocol
for our children
But we never need to call
We're only ever setting
And we don't actually care
if our children have
We really just want to
to lay itself out
So let's change this to a
When we decide a rect
we'll tell that child
UIView and SKNode can still
When they're asked
they'll just use it
But now we can make
to this protocol as well.
They already know
When they're given a frame,
and give it to their children.
Now we also need to make one
to allow it to have
in the types of its children.
And we'll look at that in
So now we can build
by composing together a
with a Decorating Layout.
The composition lets us build
in a very declarative way and
of this in the sample code.
So when you're working on your
to reuse code or
trying using Composition.
It's a great tool.
So earlier I mentioned
to add the contents
to either a superview
And an important part of
in the right order.
For example, our CascadingLayout
so that they line up on top
So let's expand our protocol to
We'll add a property to our
to return its contents.
And our combining layouts will
in the correct order from this.
And then leaf views and nodes
But once again, if
of the contents just be our
for mixed environments
and SK nodes as the contents.
And since we're adding
we only want to allow
of just UI views
So to enforce this, we
to our protocol.
An associated type is
The conforming type
that it wants to use.
So our protocol's
for what we'll be
of contents that our layout has.
This allows us to write
to lay out views and specify
And similarly, we
that only have SK nodes
And this type safety
But just like before,
to write a separate
But with the generic
we can still have a single
And for our content type,
we'll just use whatever the
And this means that we can make
with just UI views and one
Both are strongly typed so that
and know exactly what they are
and they can still share
So associated types
that you make your
So now that we have our
we can also revisit the types of
Now here they're
And this works great if they're
to have a CascadingLayout
like we talked about
What we really want here
to have the same type.
So let's update our
We can change our struct to
parameters, one for
Then, we can also add a
that those two types have
And this lets us express the
Our children's content
So this is our finished
which represents our
and this is a much
that what we had earlier.
This now has real meaning.
It's a complete set
that represent what it means to
You can also see our sample
about how all this works,
to do layout for rendering
And one last place that
of our new layout protocol
So we can write a struct
and conforms to our
and then we can change our
of UI views as the
Now our layouts will
on these simple structs.
And this means that our test is
and only relies on the logic in
So we're unit testing our
I think Crusty would be proud.
[ Applause ]
So those are some examples
and protocols in ways you
in the view layer of your app.
And we also saw some great
that you can apply anywhere.
First, we looked at how you
by using value types.
Then, we saw how you
to get better type
And we also saw how composition
for customizing and building
Now I'd like to bring Alex
with controllers in our app.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jacob.
Now I'd like to focus on
in the controller layer.
And we're going to talk
of our app's Undo functionality.
So we implemented Undo
and that worked really
that we had a small bug
for our favorite
Now to reproduce this, we can
Right now we have
as our favorite creature
that to be the dragon.
And to finish the change,
we can just tap the Done
All right, so we've modified
but the problem is that if we
And so that's a bug.
So let's take a look
that actually happened.
So we have two model properties
on our view controller right
for our favorite creature.
This is a pretty typical
especially as they grow larger
And so again we started off with
and so we implemented
and it worked, which was great.
But after we added the
we didn't have that Undo code.
And so the bug was just
And so to fix this, we
that implemented Undo for
That sounds like a
because now every time we
we have to add another code
And so that doesn't seem good.
So we don't want that.
And so after that we took a
out a solution that
as we add more model properties.
And so the solution is to
into a single value,
And our undo logic is
in terms of that one type.
Note it's really important
that our model still have
because it's composed
And so this approach
because we now have
for our two model properties,
and if we add another
we still just have
And so this is really great.
And so we can accomplish
by moving our two
on our view controller
And from there, all we have to
to the view controller.
So that's how we're going to
to implement the Undo code.
So how do we do that?
Well, I want to show you first
and we'll see why
And so on the left, we have
model value.
And on the right, we have our
Now in the original
we thought of the undo stack
Each step was responsible
and then the view to match.
For example, in the
we're going to remove the
and then we're going to delete
And we can continue
And so in this undo step,
to be back to a pink unicorn.
And so this approach of mutating
and updating our view
to get wrong and that's because
in the model to the change
And so failing to do so leads
between your model and
up with bugs like this.
And I'm sure all of
I run into this all the time.
And it's really hard to debug.
But why is it hard to debug?
Well, let's take another look
at our Undo stack
Where do these undoable
Well, each undoable change
and each of those undoable
And as we add features
these opportunities
And so there isn't one place
about the correspondence between
And so this is bad because
So let's think about a
What if instead of
each entry in the stack
a whole new model and so
on the model is really simple.
Just replace the current model
and that way we don't even
And then we just
And so now that we have that
we need to figure out how
And so in our view controller,
we're going to call this
Now, I recommend you go
at this method for more
But in that method, we need
between the old and
and update our UI to match.
So for example, we
if the old model's favorite
than the new model's
And if it is, we're going to
that contains the
And there's a more flushed out
like I just mentioned, so I
of the UI that we
And finally, we can just
where we reset our
Now this is great because
or we're only registering
So what were the benefits here?
Well, as we saw, we now
for updating our UI,
and operations are
which was not the case before.
This really helped us reason
about our UI update code.
We also saw how values compose
If we have two values as
that value still
Okay, so we just talked
in the controller layer
And now I want to do the same
with our controller's
And so you've seen
It's just our list of dreams.
But this view controller has
and so I'd like to show
for our view controller as it
that we have, the ability to
So let's take a look.
So this is our basic
We're going to start off
Now we can tap the Share button
to take us to the
And then we can select
And then we can tap
to go back to the sharing state.
Then when we're done, we just
And so that all worked well.
But let's go back
to the selecting state
You'll notice that we
through by tapping the Cancel
And so this moved us back
And you can see that our
since it shows the
But there's actually a
because of an inconsistent
The UI on the left side of the
to allow users to select dreams
So when we went back to debug
of our state properties
out during a state change.
And so in this case, even though
we forgot to clear out
of the selecting state.
So let's take another look
if we can come up with a fix.
Now each state here has
And those properties
on our view controller.
And the number of
in our view controller
as your app's feature set grows.
And so it's important that in
mutually exclusive.
And so when we're
And when we're sharing,
But the way we've written it,
you need to clear out
and this is really error prone.
And so how can we
Well, enums are actually perfect
And so we turn all of
into cases on an enum value.
And from there, we can
to our view controller.
So by using an enum,
that our states are
And that's great because
that we had before
and it's enforced
And so this approach also means
at once, without any possibility
So we don't to coordinate
with implicit timing
And as a bonus, having
in one places makes it
in exactly the same state
So I really recommend
and download the project again
to see how we implemented state
Okay, so we covered a lot today,
of improving local
by introducing value
into our model view
So how'd we do?
Well, we started off by making
by making the dream
And this makes it easier for us
because there's no implicit
Then Jacob showed you how
like DecoratingLayout
These small components
in generics to make sure
that the generic components
SpriteKit nodes,
And all of this led to better
of these types were
and isolated value types.
And then we saw how
of composing model properties
on a view controller
This made it easier to implement
even as our model type grows
And this approach also
for updating our
to understand the UI logic
of our view controller
And finally, we saw how we can
state properties into an enum
Now this reduced the
in inconsistent state.
And so those were the value
But if you go and download
you'll see that there
in the project.
And so pretty much our
with value types except
for where we have a
Now these are required to
but we've still moved most
of our functionality
And so we spoke about a lot
with just a few things in
So the first is customization
through composition
The next time you're
and you're drawing a class
I want you to think how you
of inheritance to solve that
of value types that
And the second technique
for generic reusable code.
You can make small reusable
to locally reason
And so I highly recommend
that in the sample with
of having class hierarchies.
We also showed you how to take
The important thing
that if you have a value
that are values, the larger
And finally, we talked
Now, local reasoning is actually
not specific to UI
to mobile development, and
This is a really
of all programming language,
So when you get back to your
I want you to think, regardless
how well does that code
Now it's no accident that Swift
because they're a hugely
to be able to locally
And that's it.
So you can find the sample code
and more relevant
I highly recommend you do that.
We have some related sessions
that we mentioned
and I recommend you
And thank you for a great WWDC.
[ Applause ]