[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to optimizing
My name's Jonathan Davis.
I'm the web technology's
for Safari and WebKit.
Now let me get something
I've had people tell me I
but I promise you I am not him,
but with all the
they may be all out to get us.
That aside, I'm really excited
that will help you
out of web content in your app.
And we've all known for a long
to a great user experience.
So if you're an app
and JSContext in app today.
And you care about performance,
So we're talking
And in this day and
by performance is battery life.
I mean battery life is the
It can be the difference in
or sending that last critical
And performance really
and they naturally choose
and don't drain their battery.
So what's we've all learned
and from each other, is that
because battery life matters.
So this year we focused on
and fix performance
Now we have tools for
and Objective-C code,
And we have Web Inspector
creating web pages and sites.
But don't think that
to use web technologies
that you don't have any tools.
In fact, I'm going to show you
that are developed to help
as well for web technologies
So I want to start
to connect Web Inspector to
so you have the right tool
Then you're going to learn
that will help you understand
in your JavaScript code and how
find performance
And if you've ever wished you
by your web content, we've added
that I can't wait to show you.
They're going to save you
so much time finding
All right?
So let's get started.
And the first thing
to do is connect Web
Now there are all
to use web technologies
It could be some modular
so it's easy to swap
or add new modules
And some of you may
with TVML in a tvOS app.
And another reason to
when you want to
Like a web page from
A site you don't control.
And for that, you're probably
and if you're not, you
at last year's session
View Controller.
But if you're showing content
or can customize content that
CSS or JavaScript, content that
WKWebView is the best choice.
And it's essentially a rectangle
where web content is
It was introduced in iOS
And if you're still using
you're really going
at upgrading to WKWebView.
In fact, upgrading to WKWebView
of the Nitro JavaScript
and the four-tier JIT compiler
So if you want to learn
I recommend taking a
that introduced the
So last year we added some
like load file URL,
and the WK website
And today, with iOS
we've improved 3D-touch support.
And now we allow your app to
and Pop events in WKWebView.
Now like I said earlier,
to use web technologies
doesn't mean you
In all of these cases, you can
into what your web content
But before you can
you'll need to enable
So just load up Safari
over to the Advanced
you'll see this check box.
And it says Show
Just give that a
and the Develop Menu will appear
Now to allow Web Inspector
there's a setting
So in the Settings app,
Then down at the
and toggle the Web
Now you can connect your
out the Develop menu in Safari.
Now something that's really
something you may not
is you can see a list
There's an iPhone
and the simulators there.
And all you have to do
and start using the tools
for debugging is just
And you get a list of all
that are running on the device.
And this Mac app here
It's using JavaScript.
And I can connect right
Now for iOS, apps will
and run them from Xcode.
But when we're talking
there's just one more
To protect the integrity
we don't let just
and use Web Inspector
So you'll need to
to your app's Entitlements
You probably already
but if you don't, it's
You just create a new plist
set the code signing
in Xcode's build settings.
So you add this while
and then you take it back
Then once you have this
and app will show up
and you can attach to it.
And it's easy -- just that
to your JSContext and WebViews.
Okay. So we're up and running
Time to move onto some new
And I want to start with
So we've had a profiler in
and this year we have a
to be way more effective at
out where your most expensive
And the reason is simple.
The new profiler uses
that doesn't affect your
as much as before.
So we had a profiler in an
a compiler.
It was an interpreter.
But now we have this very
and the right profiler for that
And the sampling
where time is being
It helps you answer questions
like what code is
It samples the running
and it pauses execution
of all the code that's running.
And it can also take samples
with all four tiers
So that means it's sampling
at near the true
And since handling breakpoints
we temporarily ignore them.
So while you're profiling,
you get the truest
There isn't nearly the
to using the sampling profiler.
And that literally means
it can run at up
It makes the whole process of
and easier, and you get much
This was such an exciting
our Web Inspector team, was
to find places where we
in Web Inspector itself.
All right.
So we have a sampling profiler.
Let's see how Web Inspector uses
So there's a lot going on here,
but it's actually pretty
And it's even more helpful
with code you're
When we're talking about
what we really mean is
for JavaScript in Events.
And this is the Events
of separate discrete
In particular, this is for some
so it's even helpful
and profiling code that's in
And each entry here is an
It's where a code enters
and exists the JavaScript
And that includes event
like these animation
for request animation
Or script evaluated entries
where we see JavaScript files
And we also have some
showing you the time cost
So if anything is more
you're getting really
that smooth 60-frames-per-second
Now the Events view is helpful
that we've added for you and
If you've used other
this ought to be
Just click this Menu and
And now it shows you
for functions in the call stack.
And this is what we call the Top
to dig down through
to uncover hot functions
But my favorite view
It takes me right to the
that are sampled most often.
And this is the list of
and it's sorted by the
So it inverts the Call Tree
so you can quickly compare
And you can see exactly
of your time is being spent.
You can expand the entries and
to the functions
And this tells you when
and where your most expensive
And to see this in action, I'd
Brian Burg, to the
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Jon.
So the sampling profiler
because it can take
and still profile it and get
And you can make it even faster.
So to show this off, I've
It's called Satellite Tracker.
Let me get the display here.
So Satellite Tracker will show
where the satellites
So you can choose
You can choose different
Different times.
So that's great.
If you're worried about
to put on a tinfoil hat when
But there's a small problem
of satellites overhead,
that blew up, in this case, the
This is definitely not
It's jittering all over.
So we can use the
out what's going on
So what we've got to
and we go to that Develop menu.
Find the iPad here
And the first thing
over to the Frames view here and
in terms of frame rate.
So let's just start recording.
I'll switch back to my iPad.
And start doing stuff.
It'll sort of spin around here.
Maybe a change the satellites.
Change the time.
Okay. Let's go back and see.
Okay. Let's zoom way out.
Okay. Wow.
Yeah. Our performance is
So sometimes we're getting
on the left.
In the middle, it's just sort
as we're changing the views.
And here we're sort
So if we want to figure
we want to switch over
and then we can click on the
to focus in on that
So as Jon showed before, the
to show everything that
And in this case, it's an
so we're just rendering
So it's not really helpful,
out what's taking the most time.
So let's switch over to the
that Top Down Call Tree.
And this shows aggregated over
where we spent the most time.
And here we can expand this to
and that calls some of our
And you know we draw some things
and the time and these things.
So this is great, if we want
to understand what
But if we want to figure
out which functions
it's better to go over
So here we've listed all
of who called them.
And we can see that fillText
and our tangent [phonetic]
so why are we calling
We can expand out this row here
and see who's calling
So right here, we're
It looks like we're
so we can draw this globe.
Okay. These things
Maybe I can pull
and make it a little faster.
Let's go up to fillText.
So and to refresh you, if
we're drawing text on
and also for every data point.
So that makes sense.
But if we look really
we're actually drawing
and that seems kind of strange.
So if we expand this out, we
and it seems that we're seem
to be drawing two different
This is probably
So let's figure out
If it was the case that we were
then we're doing twice as
So over here, just to
we have this sort of flat map.
And then we have the
So
let's go back into the code,
and figure out what controls
two maps.
Maybe we messed up somewhere.
So we switch between
when we change the location.
So here's updateLocation.
Okay. So when we have one map
So that makes sense because here
and that's just going
And here for the globeMap,
when the whole thing is running.
And also in the place we're
projection, so that makes sense.
When we're showing the flat
when it's not running.
Up here for the flat map, it
if the UI is running at all.
So that's kind of strange.
Well let's go back to the
So we'll go up to our
And if we go to Earth, it seems
than if we just did
And well, that makes sense.
I think we're drawing two maps
but only one map when
So if we go in here and
We want it to be the opposite.
Okay. So let's stop, and
So go back to our iPad here.
Okay. This looks pretty smooth.
Let's go here.
Oh that's great.
Yeah, it looks really nice.
So let's go and check that
if it's 60-frames per second.
So I'll switch back
and start recording and yeah.
That's pretty nice.
I'm spinning the globe, and
But the steady state
okay, we're definitely
And over here we have
under it, then we're in luck.
Okay. So now Satellite Tracker's
when to put on our hat.
This is great.
So this is a small example
of how we can use a
into really busy content
Okay. Next.
Jon's going to tell us about
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Brian.
So you can see that
It allows you to see the
so you can get really
So give the JavaScript and
and use it to find slow
or slow script initialization
And use the new Call Trees view
up across the time
Remember that Bottom Up
It really helps you find the
Okay. So we've looked at
and new JavaScript
I'm really excited that
for optimizing CPU time.
And we can give our users a fast
of their battery life.
And this is great and
on to the other side of
figuring out where
So you want to be efficient
because it's a limited resource.
Being memory efficient helps
to scale really well to
Plus, using lots of
and we don't want to do that.
and it can also bring
and we really don't
Now the good news is if
it runs in a separate process,
so it won't bring
But still, it's not a
So to help you with all of this,
to Web Inspector and Safari 10.
When you fire up the
the new timelines will
so you need to turn them on.
You just click the Edit button
you can now configure the
So you can just work with the
Just like in the
So just toggle the new
to record a new timelines.
But you probably don't want
to keep them all
The sampling profiler
and Events Timeline has less
And the JavaScript Allocation's
process during garbage
that can have a performance
Okay. So we're going to leave
And when you record a timeline,
You get this new
and it shows you how
across different
And there are a series
to help you understand
and how it's being divided up.
The Breakdown chart here shows
for JavaScript, for images,
up your page, and for the rest
of the engine-related
And the Max Comparison
memory spikes.
So we have a high watermark here
and that helps you see
And you can even isolate spikes,
or a specific range of time
And then, you can use the
to see what's contributing
And each of these graphs here
So you can easily see
So if there's a spike in
where lots of new objects are
And that includes Objects like
and all the engine
like structure data
So when you see usage
you're seeing garbage
And images shows you the
that have been decoded
so that's the larger image
that are visible
And layers is showing you
memory used for WebKit's
and other engine layers.
Pages is everything else,
all the other things the
like the DOM and page
memory caches and
So this breakdown gives
that memory use lines up
If you have JavaScript-heavy
you'd expect the
that JavaScript is the largest
And you'll likely see
in the Timeline graph.
But for an image-heavy page
then the layers and images
largest, with more
So that's the Memory
And to complement the Memory
Allocations Timeline.
It's one thing to see
but it's another
down to see what actual
And a very powerful tool
for this is JavaScript
What's powerful about Snapshots
of a moment in time,
And you can dig in to see
But it's even more powerful
and this allows you to go back
And comparing Snapshots is
for answering the question, am
So to really make use of this,
So that's why, by default,
and also at the beginning
So the Snapshots are
so you can correlate them
to things happening
I just have the others
And the Snapshots are listed
like timing and size
Now, to dig into a
you'll often need a Snapshot,
where you think a memory
And there are three techniques.
You can rely on the automatic
Or you can take one yourself
by pushing the Take
Or you can do it from your code.
And really the easiest way
to modify your code a little.
You call the takeHeapSnapshot
and pass it a custom label
that can help you
And again, you want a pair
and after the code you think
Now you could also use
between doing some
So just some quick
about the takeHeapSnapshot API.
Remember that Snapshots do
garbage collection and that
which you'll definitely notice
if your code is firing off
You'll also want to capture
and after code that's doing
between work in a loop.
And don't leave this in.
I mean, if you leave this in,
for most customers
But if anybody's running
to be taking all
and you probably
So just remember to be sure and
So what are these
Let's take a look.
You just click on the
or on the Arrow button of any
And you'll get this
that were allocated in the heap.
And we have two views
This is the Instances view, and
in the heap, grouped
And the other is the
And this is really an
and everything that's
So if you're readily
this can be a useful
or where they should be.
But actually the far more useful
in the Instances view.
And it's powerful because you
matter how deep-down the
And the Count here can help
when they don't meet
Like was I really expecting
So you can expand the
of the allocated
Then to figure out what
different clues.
The Class is a clue.
Another is the actual
It's a really quick
But the easiest way to know
over this Object Identifier
Look at this.
It literally shows you the
This is telling you exactly what
It almost always gives
especially in a world of
This is the kind of
through the confusion.
But the most important feature
of this is to be able to
Now watch this.
Once you've collected
you just click the Compare
and you select a
and a second to compare against.
And boom. You get a new
Now this is a really big deal
because now we're only seeing
between two points,
Expanding the Object
of these Object Allocations.
And their previews are showing
like some telemetry data.
And that's a clue that
And the pop over here
in the Satellites
Since this is a Snapshot
these Satellite Objects
And that's a big clue as
So to show you all of these
I'd like to invite Brian back up
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Jon.
So I gave Satellite Tracker
up all night playing with it.
And he had a lot of fun,
and he never got tracked
But there's a problem.
Eventually it just
and slower the longer it was up.
And to me that sounded like
The longer the thing is
So I want to look
with these new memory
out if we're leaking
So the first thing
Okay I've got iPad here.
I'm going to go back
And inspect the app.
And the first thing
when I don't really know what
to use the Memory Timeline.
And that's going to show
of what's going on on the page.
So let's start recording.
I'll switch back, and I'm just
between two satellites.
Maybe I'll add some
Okay, I'm switching
Okay. Let's see what's
So in the Timeline overview you
showing all the different
but if you click here, you'll
And so there's no
This is all canvas.
The layers is pretty flat.
The page sort of
stuff's getting garbage
That's fine.
If you look more
you see that like you know some
but overall, it's really
And if we had this
it would probably
So the next step here is to
or allocation Snapshots
out what's being
So to do that, we're going
And one cool quick trick here
or Shift Space, and they'll
and not append to the old one.
Oh wait. I forgot to
So let's put away Memory.
And let's put in
Okay. So let's start recording.
Go back to the iPad.
Here I added this little
so I already added some
about takeHeapSnapshot
between the two satellite
So for this recording, I'm going
to switch between two
We should look at
That seems kind of relevant.
Okay. And you'll notice
because we're taking
in the JavaScript heap.
So this you know we're
so this is going to slow
So it's important to not
You want to take them
So here, you can see
and those are the
So if we zoom in over here,
we can see that there's pretty
as we start switching
So if we want to investigate
we need to start
to see what's being
So let's go between
And right away, we can
that was allocated
and is still alive right now.
So that's a pretty good sign
and you know we probably
So we can start looking
There're some Arrays.
It looks like we have
And you know we use coordinates
in this app, but
we can see the path
So these seem to be saved
which is what we use to
the satellites.
So okay. That's fine,
but I don't think we
trajectoryHistory for satellites
That seems kind of like a bug.
We allocate some Objects too.
And this is sort of
between Snapshot 9 and 11,
we've already seen
So I wouldn't expect that
for each satellite.
We should just use them
if we already fetched
So and then here's a bunch of
so it seems like we might be
like re-parsing them
But I'm not sure, so
in this view is you know
You can't read all of them,
but what I like to do is find
And in this Snapshot here,
lots of Arrays, lots of Objects.
But there's only one
between these two Snapshots.
So I think if I want to debug
in our code to see where we're
that that's being leaked
So we search for Promise.
Okay. There's D3 library, and
Okay. Let's go to this one.
Okay. So in the [inaudible]
we switched between
and then the code that's
So someone left comments.
That's nice.
So here it looks like
the satellites.
So here we asynchronously
for the satellites from the TRL.
When it comes back,
and then we're going
with the satellite
And then we're going to save
That's all well and fine,
it seems that we're leaking
So if you look more
to a data set that we
It seems like we're not
So if you look more carefully
between the two satellites,
we're doing a new
So if we go to this Timeline,
it seems like we're requesting
over and over.
And that makes sense
to the code, we request that.
Then we make a bunch of
And then we push it onto
and that thing never really gets
So it seems like
of unnecessary work
So I think what we can
if we already have this
Because this is a Promise,
we can still call .then on it.
Since it's already solved,
next time we evaluate
it's going to go through and
So let's add a [inaudible] here.
And if this doesn't exist,
Okay. Let's stop and rerun
So we need to go
And okay, here's our app, and
And when we go back to the app,
I'm going to turn
Turn on some effects.
And we'll go down south.
Okay. So Spy Satellites.
Science Experiments
Science Experiments.
Okay.
So if we go back here, we're
Maybe 1 megabyte,
so there might be some
But at the end of the Snapshot,
as when we started rendering
So I think we've fixed
So this shows how we can use the
to figure out where
in apps like this.
And it's great because like this
But still, with the dipping
we can really drill
in some Timeline we care about.
Okay. So that's the end
Back to you, Jon.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Brian.
You can see how it
and simple these new
to zero in on memory issues.
So remember you want to use
out how memory is being used and
so you have an idea
And then, take multiple
in the JavaScript
into code that's driving
Also, don't forget to get
from your code before shipping.
And remember the
that the JavaScript
while recording.
So that's a look at the new
in Web Inspector with Safari 10.
I think you're really
And as I wrap this up,
with some next steps to take.
I want to encourage you
if you've not made
And turn on the Develop
connect Web Inspector to your
of these new features.
Save a ton of time using
and Call Trees for the best
The Memory Timeline to
are happening.
And Heap Snapshots
and compare Object allocations.
And stay updated on features.
There's more this year in
that you can take advantage
to deliver great
Along with the features
our team added some
to Web Inspector
Quick Open will jump you right
into the resources
And Tail Call Stacks will now
functions in the debugger.
And earlier this spring, we
and with an updated
And that shows the
in the DOM Tree of
And there's also the new
And if you aren't already aware,
Web Inspector is a developer
of the WebKit Open
WebKit is the web browser engine
and drive WebViews
And of course, it's also
In this past year, our teams
to WebKit.
We hit 100% support for ES6.
We improved support for the
We also added Shadow DOM support
and the Picture Element.
So there's a lot going on and
you can follow development
Most of you here will want
And if there are some of you
of these, you have
because of the way WebKit
So you can find out more
about the WebKit
And the WebKit team, the
blog about development work.
In fact, we have two
that cover the Memory Timelines
that we talked about today.
So if you want to
you can dig in there.
We also have a feature
that gives you at-a-glance
for our web standards progress.
And there's also
for WebKit nightly builds
the Safari Technology Preview.
It's updated every
with an updated WebKit
and experimental features
in WebKit every two
Our teams pore a lot of work
into Safari WebKit
And the Web Inspector
to use these new performance
to find issues and
in Web Inspector itself.
I can't wait to see what
So for more information,
and download the slides
There are lots of other relevant
as well as in past years.
You can find those on
So on behalf of Brian, myself,
thank you for being here.
enjoy the rest of WWDC.
[ Applause ]