[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Morning everyone and
I'm Brad Ford.
I work on the Core Media
and AV Foundation
And this session is all
Hopefully you've
This is the most popular
And it's also about photography.
If you develop a photography
about developing
then this is a very
I think you and iOS 10 are
Today we'll be focusing on
which is our lowest level
for accessing the camera.
AV Foundation is broad and deep.
If you're new to camera
to review our past WWC camera
They give you a good base for
you get to watch
Here's what we're going to
I'll present a brand
for capturing photographic
to focus on four feature areas.
We're going to focus
You'll learn how to capture
just like Apple's camera app.
to DNG files, which is a
You'll learn about
or thumbnail images along with
for a more responsive UI.
And lastly, you'll learn
vivid images in wide color.
Let's get started.
Here's a quick refresher
on how AV Foundation's
At the center of our
the AVCaptureSession.
This is the object you tell
In order to do anything useful,
Inputs like a camera
And they provide
And it also needs outputs
such as a StillImageOutput
or a QuickTime movie
which records QuickTime movies.
There are also connections, and
as AVCaptureConnections.
That's our overall object graph.
You've kind of seen how we
All of these features,
relate to taking still images.
So we might expect that we'd
in the AVCaptureStillImageOutput
Today we're introducing a brand
And it's called the
emphasizing the fact that
than static still images now.
AVCapturePhotoOutput addresses
challenges in four main areas.
It features a functional
There are clear delineations
between mutable and
We've encapsulated
into a distinct object
And the PhotoOutput can
from request to completion
through a delegate-style
And lastly, it resolves your
early in the capture process,
so you know what you're
Let's talk a little bit more
Here's what an
Even with all its new features,
smaller even than
It has a small set of
that tell you whether particular
such as is
It has a smaller set of writable
in for particular
Some capture features affect how
built, so you have to
One such is
If you ever intend to capture
such as five-megapixel
you have to opt-in for the
startRunning on the
Lastly, there's a single
to kick off a photo capture.
Just one verb.
That's it.
Now you're probably asking
to all the per photo state?
How do I request
How do I get BGRA?
How do I get still
These features and
to a new object called
This object contains all
to one single photo
Think of it like the
from when you're buying a MAC
You fill out the online
that you want and then you
And placing the order is
passing the
as your first parameter.
Now when you place
the store needs your email
with you about your order.
Within AVCapturePhotoOutput's
the email address you provide
to AVCapturePhotoCaptureDelegate
This delegate gets called
to your photo capture occur.
This object gets passed
to CapturePhoto.
Okay, so what's good about
First of all, they are atomic.
All settings are
There's no potential for
because they are not properties
but rather, a per-settings
They're unique.
Each photo settings instance
You're only allowed to use
and never again.
So you'll receive
for each photo capture request.
After requesting a photo
you can hold onto it and
as they're returned to you.
Sort of like making a
your online order form.
So then, what's good
Well, it's a single
Again, per photo settings.
The ordering is documented.
You know exactly which
and at what time
And it's a vehicle for resolving
That one I think I need to
Let's say your app requests
on this timeline.
You've specified photo
and auto still image
I shortened still image
so it would fit on
You're telling the PhotoOutput
but only if you need to, only
if they're appropriate
So very soon after
the PhotoOutput calls your
which is willBegin
This callback is always,
It's sort of like the
from Apple saying we've
Here's what we'll
The callback passes
of a new object called
It's just like the photo
except now everything
They have the same unique ID.
Your unresolved version
and resolved version
so you compare them together.
It also tells you what features
So notice, in this case,
and SIS has been
So clearly we're in a
such as this conference room.
Next comes willCapture
It's delivered right when
or like when the virtual
and the shudder sound
If you want to perform some
this is the appropriate
And then shortly thereafter
ResolvedSettings, just after
and read out, and the
Then some time has to pass
because the image
applying all the features
And when the photo
you get the
callback, along with an
waiting for.
So, yay. It's like getting the
And finally, you get
ResolvedSettings callback,
which is guaranteed
It's like the follow-up
from Apple saying all your
A pleasure doing business
This is a good time to clean up
So let's talk about those
The callbacks track a single
The photo output holds a weak
so it will not keep that
Remember to keep a strong
All the callbacks in this
but some of them become
depending on your
For instance, when you're
compressed photo,
to implement the one callback
Otherwise, we would have
The rules are clearly spelled
out in the
headerDoc.
All callbacks pass an instance
of that nice
talked to you about.
So you always know what you're
about to get or what
So speaking of settings, let's
to initiate photo captures
with various
Okay, the first one,
as I said before, the
on iPhone 6s supports
selfies, but it can't
It can only do individual
So you have to create
opting in for the HighResolution
This gives you the
AVCapturePhotoSettings,
And then, by default, it sets
and opts you in for still
I then set
to true and then
In the second example,
Notice that the flashMode
of the settings object.
If you've worked with
you'll know that Flash was
so we had a problem
to access two different objects
Here, it's all part of
Nice. The final sample here
of AVCapturePhotoSettings.
This time we're going to pass
In this case, we want an
So we make a dictionary of
and then pass it
as the parameter
and we're good to go.
Now when you call capturePhoto,
AVCapturePhotoOutput will
and make sure you haven't
It'll ensure self-consistency,
that you've asked for
And if it's not, it
Result settings, as you might
All the properties
They're purely for
Again, this is the functional
It has a unique ID
with the unresolved settings
This is kind of a nice feature.
It tells you the dimensions
to get before you get it.
So you can plan, do
whatever you need to do.
It tells you whether it was
And still image stabilization
It also supports
It's a specialized
where you request
sometimes with differing
This might be done, for
to fuse differently
to produce an effect
I spoke at length
of captures in 2014 Session 508.
Go check that video
As with
we support auto exposure
and custom exposure brackets.
But the new way to request
to instantiate an
So it's like the photo
and it has the extra
for doing a bracketed capture.
When you create one of
of AVCapture BracketedStill
This is an existing object
from the
You specify one of
For instance, -2EV, +2EV, 0EV.
Also, if you're on
you can optionally enable
isLensStabilizationEnabled
So you recall the
on the previous slide, where
to didFinish ProcessingPhoto
When you request a bracket
that callback is going
Once per image.
And the fifth parameter
which particular
in this image request
Okay. So we like the new
that we want you to move
And so we're deprecating in iOS
and all of the flash-related
and instead, this is
Like I said, there are parts
and parcel to the
it's a much better
Move over as soon as you can.
The last item is -- let's talk
about the photo benefits
They're good for
Immediate settings resolution.
Confident request tracking.
And it's good for Apple.
It's good for us because
of callbacks for us.
We can add new ways to
and that last little bit is
that I'm going to talk
So Apple.com has a
on Live Photos and
It says, "A still photo captures
With Live Photos, you
into unforgettable
The beautiful thing about Live
in value the further
So, in this picture, this
in and of itself.
Huge disgusting sand crabs my
A great photo.
But if I 3D touch it --
[ Inaudible ]
Okay. So now I remember.
It was a freezing day.
He'd never been in the ocean
He'd been in for too long
And I also hear my brother's
So all of these things
because I have more
Then there are people
to use Live Photos as an
This shot is a twist
Our camera products team calls
A high degree of
Also popular is the
with Live Photo.
Try that one out.
I'm a big fan of the
but unfortunately,
A three-second window
for my natural-borne
So Live Photos began life
from Apple's design studio.
The premise was, even though
screens now for sharing
the photo experience itself has
JPEGs that we swipe through
versions of the chemicals
through in our shoeboxes.
And yet, it's the primary way
that people store
So isn't there something
And after a lot of
we converged on what this
A moment or a memory.
Well, first of all and
It's still as good
It's a 12-megapixel JPEG
and it has the same
Let me emphasize that again.
Live Photos get all
that Apple's non-Live Photos do,
so you are not sacrificing
Also a big deal was the idea
That means there's
You take photos the same
Still the same spontaneous
nothing additional
A Live Photo is also
It has to engage more senses
It has to aid in memory recall.
So it's nominally a short
with 1.5 seconds coming before
after the still, and we take it
at about screen resolution
And it includes audio.
And we're constantly
In iOS 9.1, we added
of automatically
in case you did a sweeping
or your pockets.
So now we'll auto trim them
that you don't want
New in iOS 10, we've
Now all of the Live Photo
Also new in iOS 10,
interruption-free
So if you happen
[ Applause ]
Yeah. That's a good one.
I like that one, too.
So in order to be both
a Live Photo consists of two
JPEG file, QuickTime Movie file.
These two assets
that uniquely pairs
The JPEG file's UUID is stored
within the Apple Maker
And the movie asset
nominally three seconds
roughly 1080p, with a
It contains a timed metadata
in it that corresponds to the
within the movie's timeline.
It also contains a piece
that pairs it with
and that's called the
And its value is a
Okay. So what do you have to
In AVCapturePhotoOutput,
there is a property called
You have to make
It's not supported
And currently it's
when you're using
You opt in for it using
PhotoCaptureEnabled,
You have to opt in for it before
Otherwise, it will cause a
of the session, and
Also if you want audio in
you have to add an
for the microphone.
Very important.
Don't forget to do that.
Also not supported is
of regular movies using
and Live Photos at
So if you have a
in your session's topology, it
You configure a LivePhotoCapture
It's got the default
but additionally you specify a
This is where you want
And it has to be
and it has to be
You're not required to specify
but you can if you'd like to.
Here I gave an example of
And I set myself as the author,
so that the world will
But you could also
like add GPS tagging
So now let's talk about Live
Like I said, we have
of delegate callbacks,
When capturing a Live Photo,
your first callback
that a Live Photo
by telling you the movie's
See that? Now, in addition
you also know what dimensions
You receive the expected
including a JPEG being delivered
But now we're going to
A Live Photo movie is
with a still image
So that means up to 1.5 seconds
you're going to receive
And this one has a strange name,
didFinishRecording
EventualFileAtURL.
Try to parse that.
It means the file hasn't been
that need to be collected
for the movie are
In other words, if you have a
this is an appropriate
Let people know that they don't
A good time to dismiss
And soon after, the movie file
And you'll get the
LivePhotoTo MovieFileAtURL.
That is a required callback,
And now the movie's
Lastly you get the
We've delivered everything
So note that the JPEG portion
of the LivePhotoCapture is
as static still photos.
It comes as a sample
using didFinishing
callback, as we've already seen.
If you want to write this
We have a class method
for rewriting JPEGs as a
that's suitable for writing
And you can see it
I'm going to gloss over
to that function, the
We'll discuss it
So here's a suggestion for you
LivePhotoCapture is an
that delivers multiple assets.
Sort of like a multi-order,
to get the computer in one
to get the dongle
So when it delivers multiple
in our own test apps
to instantiate a new
for each photo request
So then, within that
of the things that
The sample buffer, the movie,
And then, there's a convenient
when you get the
saying that we're done.
That's just a helpful tip there.
Once your assets have
there are still several more
to get the full live
Though the video complement
it's not meant to be
with an AV Player like
There's a special recipe
It's supposed to ease in and out
When you swipe between
of assets have a little bit
So to get the full Live
you need to use the photos
And there are classes
to ingest your RAW assets
and properly play them
with the LivePhotoView.
And new in iOS 10,
photos framework lets you
as you would a still
and I'd like to demo it.
Okay. So we have a bit of sample
which has been out
but now we have spruced it up,
so that it has a specific
That's because you can only
And notice it's got some badging
that Live Photo mode
And you can switch cameras.
I'm going to try to do the
Let's see how successful I am.
So you have to start and
in the middle and then finish.
So notice, while I was doing
that came up, and that's
that I talked to
So here it is.
It was written to the
then take it somewhere in
But that's not all we
In iOS 9, when you tried
you would lose the
But now we can either, in the
that you provide in your app,
such as this little sample
that I've included as a
I can apply a simple
This just does a
of applying a tonal filter,
but notice it didn't
I can still play it --
in the middle -- so, nice.
You can now edit
[ Applause ]
All right.
AVCam. Now, like I
and photo recording modes,
so you get the best
You get the best
And it shows the proper
that I was talking about.
It also shows you how to
and that sample code
If you go to our sessions'
It was even Swiftified.
If you want to know more
please come to session
You'll hear all about it.
Okay. We also support
LivePhotoCaptureSuspension.
Here's a quick example of
Let's say you have an
and makes obnoxious
Okay, just go with
It takes pictures.
Makes obnoxious foghorn sounds.
Now let's say that
your user takes a
and then they play an
And then after it's done
Photo there.
So this is a problem because
of photos one and two overlap
with the obnoxious
you have now ruined
You're going to hear the end
and the beginning of the
That's no good.
So to cope with this problem,
you can set
to true, just before you
And that will cause any
to abruptly be trimmed
And you can do the same thing
by setting
to false, and that will
on the endpoint, so
than that point will appear in
A nice little feature.
So let's talk about support.
Where do we support
We support it on all the recent
to remember it is every device
that's where we support
All right, onto our next
and that's RAW Photo Capture.
So to explain what RAW
with a very high level overview
CMOS sensors collect
through two-dimensional
The top layer of the array is
and as light passes
it only allows one color
green or blue, in
Green is twice as prevalent in
because our eyes are twice
as they are to the other colors.
The bottom layer here is
Now what actually gets stored
of the amount of either
that hit the sensor through each
to be stored that Bayer pattern.
In other words, the arrangement
so that later on it
You have to store a lot
about color information,
And so RAW converters
A RAW converter that basically
and turns it into an RGB image.
Demosaicing is just
A lot of stuff needs to
presented onscreen.
So to draw an analogy,
like storing the ingredients
And then you have to
around with you wherever you go.
It's kind of heavy.
It's kind of awkward.
It takes some time to
If you ask two different bakers
to bake the cake using
you might get a slightly
But there are also some
First and foremost, you have
So you're carrying
but you can make a
There's no compression involved
like there would
You have more bits to work with.
It's a 10-bit sensor
in 14 bits per pixel
Also, you have lots of
And some greater
to make different
So basically you're just
until later.
Okay? Now what's JPEG?
RAW images offer many benefits
but they're not the
It's important to understand
that there are tradeoffs
and that JPEGs are still
JPEGs are the cake, the lovingly
and it's a pretty good cake.
It's got all of the
Much faster rendering.
You don't have to carry as
You also get some secret
As I mentioned, we use multiple
You can't get that with
no matter how good it is,
I guess it's kind of
Okay? So yeah, you can't do
Also you get smaller file size.
So all of these things make JPEG
and you should decide
which is better for your app.
We identify RAW formats
just like we do for
in the Core Video framework.
We've added four new
to describe the four
that you'll encounter
and they're listed there.
Basically they describe
greens and blues in
How do you capture RAW
It's pretty simple.
RAW is only supported when
the preset photo,
It's only supported
And we do support RAW brackets,
of three RAW images,
To request a RAW capture,
you create an
but surprise, surprise,
This one takes a
So how do you decide which
to deliver to you?
Well you can ask the
It'll tell you here are my
formats, and you can
The RAW format you specify has
Now also important is that
SIS has no meaning because
fusion scenario.
So autoStillImage
to be set to no or it
And also
meaningless because you're
so it also must be set to false.
There's a separate
for RAW photos called didFinish
And if you are really sharp-eyed
that it has exactly
as the previous callback,
of image, the didFinish
PhotoSampleBuffer callback.
So now you might ask yourself
new delegate callback
if it has the same exact
There's a good reason, and that
image support.
So we do support, just
mirrorless cameras, a workflow
and JPEG simultaneously.
That's what I mean
The ability to shoot
of a professional feature,
So you can get RAW
It doesn't have to be a
The processed image is
the didFinish ProcessingPhoto
and the RAW is delivered to
RAW plus processed
so see if you can wrap
That would be --
and I'm asking for
So if I'm doing a
I'm going to get three
RAW plus still image
though, is not supported.
Okay, so to capture RAW plus
there's yet another constructor
In this one, you specify
and the processed
Here I'm choosing JPEG as the
Now when you select JPEGPlusRAW,
HighResolutionPhotoEnabled
Because now it's
All right.
Let's talk about
They're not that useful
if all you can do is
So rather than introduce an
format, like so many other
to use Adobe's digital
DNG is a standard way of just
It doesn't imply a file
So going back to our cake-baking
like a standard box for
It's still up to individual
to interpret those ingredients.
So DNGs opened by one third
than DNGs opened
So storing in DNG
You just call the class function
passing the RAW buffer
in the delegate callback.
This creates a capital
that can be written to file.
And this API always writes
to save space.
All right.
I feel a demo coming on.
Okay. So for RAW capture, we've
of sample code and
We released this one in 2014,
when we showed off our
So it lets you choose focus,
and you can manually
And then there's a new thing
that lets you select
So you can choose to shoot
Let's go to exposure.
Let me see if I can purposely
and then I'll take a photo.
And now I'm going
I'm going to go to an
Now this was not written
This was written by
but they graciously let
And we'll go down and we can see
Now this one is a RAW.
It's reading the DNG file.
And we can do things with
with the JPEGs, like we restore
We can adjust the
All of these things
and are completely reversible.
You can also look and see
or without noise reduction.
So all of these are part
of a new Core image
Okay, let's go back to slides.
The AVCamManual sample code
You can go get it.
It's associated with
And also, if you want to
you need to come to that
about before, session 505, where
The second part is RAW
It's a great session.
Where is RAW photo
By happy coincidence, it's
as where we support Live Photos.
So anything with a
where you can do RAW photos.
Onto our next topic, which
also known as thumbnails.
Photography apps commonly
to quickly show a
such as Apple Zone camera app.
So take a look in the bottom
And you see, as soon as it
almost instantaneously
in the image well
That's good.
That's comforting to
that what they did just worked.
It gives them instant feedback.
Also a number of image
such as Core Images,
or CI QR Code Detector work
smaller uncompressed images.
They don't need the full
Unfortunately there is an
You request a high-quality JPEG
because that's what you
That's what you want to
to get a preview on
So if you have to do
you're decompressing the JPEG.
You're downscaling it.
And finally displaying it.
All of this takes time
and buffer copies
Nicer would be to get both the
and if the camera could give
directly from the camera, not
Then you could skip all those
with the preview image.
And this is exactly the
in AVCapturePhotoOutput.
The delegate --
[ Applause ]
I'll pander.
The delegate callback can
with the processed or RAW image.
The preview is uncompressed,
or BGRA, you're choice.
If you know the size you want,
you can specify the
Or if you're not sure what
for this current platform,
the PhotoOutput can pick a
Here's some sample code showing
After creating a photo
of the usual ways, you can
Again, the photo settings
which formats are
so that the most
So here, I'm getting the very
And when I say optimal,
that requires the
from the native camera.
You create a CVPixelBuffer
with that format type key, and
So if you want preview images,
you have to at least specify
Optionally, you can also
if you want to custom size.
And you don't need to know
of the image that
Here I just specified
I don't really expect to get
as the max for both
And AVCapturePhotoOutput
of resizing the preview image
preserving aspect ratio.
Retrieving preview images is
Here we've requested a JPEG plus
So when we get our first
your order, you get a willBegin
and a ResolvedPhotoSettings
the previewPhotoDimensions
They're 160 by 120
to something that's
for the 12-megapixel
When the didFinish
callback finally comes, you
The full-sized JPEG is
and the previewPhotoSampleBuffer
So if you're following
and adding things
If you do a RAW plus bracket
then you're going to get mRAWs,
Another great use of
as an embedded thumbnail in your
In this code sample, I'm using
parameter of my didFinish
callback as an embedded
So when I call PhotoOutput's
I'm passing that as
You should always do this, okay?
Embedding a thumbnail
because you don't know where
Some apps can handle
the RAW bits, and some can't.
But if you have an
everyone's going to be
You definitely want to do
to the Photo Library so
quick preview.
Preview image delivery
All right, onto the last topic
And as you might suspect,
You've no doubt heard about the
on our iPad Pro 9.7 inch.
It's a wide-gamut
with the 4K and 5K iMax.
It's capable of displaying
and yellows and deeply
To take advantage of the
we introduced color management
I'm not sure if you
but we're now color managed
And with displays this
to also capture photos
so that we enhance the
And so that when you look at
you've got more color
Beginning in iOS
on the iPad Pro 9.7 will
color captures.
Let me give you a brief overview
wide color terminology, starting
with the concept
A color space describes
in which colors are represented,
And the most common
in computer displays is sRGB.
The s stands for
It's based on an
It has a gamma of roughly
of 6500 degrees Kelvin.
sRGB does a really good job of
like faces, sky, grass,
that sRGB does not
For instance, more than 40%
of pro football jerseys are
Who knew? The iPad Pro 9.7
color space that
It's similar to the
That's a color space that's used
The color primaries are the same
in gamma and white point.
The gamma and white point
Why would we do that?
The reason for that is that the
toward the green side.
It was chosen to
in dark home theater
that with the white
we get a more compatible
So here on this slide you
and then you can
around it, the Display P3.
And it does a nice job of kind
of broadly covering
And that's why we chose it.
Using Apple's color
you can see a visual
So I took a little screen
You can compare it with
So here I'm selecting
and then I do the hold
That's a neat trick.
And then I select sRGB.
And then I see the one
of the other, so you can see
on the outside, and
for just how wide the Display
And the range of representable
So now let's get down
of capturing Display P3 content.
For highest fidelity, the color
to be determined at the source.
That's not something that
and then be up-converted
It has to start wide.
So, as you might expect,
the color space is
of the AVCaptureDevice,
So we're going to
about the AVCaptureDevice
about the AVCaptureSession.
The session is where automatic
determined for the whole session
Okay. AVCaptureDevice is how AV
or a mic.
Each AVCaptureDevice
Formats is an array of
They are objects themselves,
that the device can capture in.
They come in pairs,
For each resolution
there's a 402v version
That stands for v for
or f for full range,
So new in iOS 10,
AVCaptureDevice formats
spaces property.
It's an array of numbers
for sRGB or 1 for P3 D65.
We refer to it as Display P3
to as P3 D65, the d
for the 6500 Kelvin white point.
On an iPad Pro 9.7, the 420v
But the full-range 420f
or Display P3.
The device has a settable
That's not new.
So that one of the formats
in the list is always
As you can see here,
around the one that is active.
It happens to be the
And if that activeFormat,
happens to support Display P3,
that you can set
And if the activeFormat supports
from your source to all
That was longwinded, but what
from this is hopefully you
Most clients will never need
to set the activeColorSpace
because AVCaptureSession
for you automatically.
So in iOS 10, AVCaptureSession
automaticallyConfigures
When does it want to
Wide color, in iOS 10,
Let me say that again.
Wide color, in iOS 10, is only
I'll explain why in a minute.
It can automatically,
the session can automatically
to configure the whole session
It will set the activeColorSpace
to P3, depending on your config.
You have to have a PhotoOutput
in your session for
If you don't have a PhotoOutput,
you're obviously not
so you don't need wide color.
There are some caveats here.
Like, if you start adding
maybe it's not as clear
If you add an
the session will automatically
because you're just previewing
If you have a MovieFileOutput
and a PhotoOutput,
You might really care
so it will not automatically
VideoDataOutput is a special
to you via a callback and there,
the session will
if you're using the
It's pretty sure if you're
to do photography stuff
If you really, really want to,
to do wide color and here's how.
First you would tell the
that thing for me.
Get out of my way.
And then you would
and set the active
to a format that's
And then you would set the
Once you do this, wide color
that accept video data.
That includes VideoDataOutput,
even the deprecated
So while you can forcibly set
to display P3, I want
against doing it
really know what you're doing.
The reason is wide
because we have a good photo
not so much for video.
So the main worry with
that the consumer has
or your content will
and the colors will
They'll be rendered badly.
Most video playback
So if you store a wide Display
to play it back with
it will likely render
So if you do choose to do this,
make sure that your
That it's propagating
That it's doing something
That it's color-aware.
And if you do choose to capture
MovieFileOutput, just be aware
that they may render
This is -- we do allow this,
that it's important for some
to do wide color movies as well.
So now dire warnings out
that we do have a very
in sharing wide colors.
We should be aware that wide
profile and consumers of
to be color-aware.
The good news is photo services,
they are color-aware these days.
iCloud Photo Library
It can intelligently convert
that don't support wide color,
but store the nice wide
We're also an industry
so some photo services
but most of them at
to render it as sRGB.
For mixed sharing scenarios,
like say sending a photo
You don't know where it's going.
It might be going
Some of them might
Some might not.
So for this situation, we have
Wide Color Sharing Profile.
Your content can be
that we generate a content
that's specific to
And what's nice about it is
who doesn't know about
in the sRGB gamut renders
The extra information is carried
in the extra ICC profile
that they can recover the
with minimal quality loss.
You can learn more about how
in sessions 505 and 712.
Both of those are on Thursday.
I've talked about the
The working with wide color one
On iPad Pro 9.7,
the AVCapturePhotoOutput
It supports it in 420f, BGRA
So if you have your session
but then you say you
it will be converted to sRGB.
Live Photos support wide color.
Both the still and the movie.
These are special movies.
This is part of the
So those are just
And bracketed captures also
Here's an interesting twist.
While I've been talking
iPad Pro, we support RAW.
And RAW capture is inherently
of those extra bits
We store it in the
and there is enough
to be either rendered
Again, you're carrying the
You can decide later if you want
So shooting RAW and
you can produce wide
of iOS devices, not
As I just said, you can learn
not just sharing but
The best session to view is
on Thursday afternoon.
Use AVCapturePhotoOutput
And we talked about four
We talked about capturing
in your app, RAW,
Nice little preview images
And wide color photos.
And believe it or not,
to cover everything
So we've done an
It's already recorded.
It should already be online.
It's a slide plus
that we're calling a Chalk Talk.
And it tells you
that we didn't have time for.
Scene monitoring in
Resource preparation
And then an unrelated topic,
changes to camera
So please take a
It's about 20 minutes long.
More information.
All you need to remember
Go to that and you'll find,
of sample code as well
for AVCapturePhotoOutput.
The documentation folks
and they've documented
And here are the related
The one that is the Chalk Talk,
we're calling
the basics.
And you can look at
All right.
Have a great rest of the show,
[ Applause ]