[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Alright.
Good afternoon, everyone.
[ Applause ]
Welcome, and thank you for
My name is Ryan Griggs, and I
and I am thrilled to be here
about some of the great things
how to get set up, and
So we have a lot to cover
through a quick agenda
in the presentation as
So first we'll do a quick intro
of sort of why News exists,
We'll also take a quick look
as far as where your,
and your publication
And then next we'll
up your channel using News
that we use to manage
Then we'll do a quick
and then we'll dive a bit
Then we'll also talk about how
to publish articles
We have a few different
to author and then deliver
We'll talk about how to
Talk about analytics
Specifically, what's
as an Apple News Format
about a few best practices
for making your publication
So, first, let's do a quick
So News was launched with
of delivering the best stories
and then personalizing
And so News is built right into
to anyone with an iOS device
of the three countries News is
in the U.S., U.K. and
And so one of the big parts
which is our JSON
It makes it possible to create
experiences within
And so we'll talk a bit
But in order to understand
I wanted to show you a few
of what you can do with it.
So this one is an
and we'll actually
and take a look at
You can see there's a little
There's beautiful imagery.
This is a photo mosaic.
Can tap in on the photos,
It's really great,
And you'll also notice, too,
of course, a, a "Wired" article.
This looks like "Wired".
And so we give you the
and your channel
So here's another
Very different look to this,
with some beautiful photography.
You see we have some of
As you scroll, some really
Great use of parallax here.
It really shows a lot of emotion
So another great example.
Show you one more.
This one in iPad.
You can really do a lot of
and this is an example of
who really created something
that makes you want
and see what other great
So Apple News Format gives you
So let's take a quick
Just understand where
So News is organized
So first we have For You.
For You is a personalized feed
that you're interested in based
and what you're reading.
And it's got a huge update,
We have a completely new
and feel but also the concept of
like trending, topic groups
in News, and then featured
to find some of the
engaging Apple News
and feature them
Favorites.
This is where your
when a user taps the Plus
and it allows you just to return
And then we have Explorer.
This is where users will
and then new topics, and so we
to publications, and these
of articles from
around a specific topic.
So you can follow
or heavy metal or
Then, of course, we have Search.
We have hundreds of
and you can search for topics
and publications
And then, finally, your
If a user starts reading
to finish reading it
at your history and clear
So that's how News is
So during this session, we're
of the best practices when
to get set up, but, first,
and how it shows up in News.
So publications in News
So what is a channel?
Well, this is what a
and this is the one
in News today in
So channels represent your
of like your home page.
Articles you publish
and it's where users can
and directly specifically
So a good example for, of
a magazines, a newspaper,
They're very customizable.
So you can really make them
So you can do things
add a cover image, which
and customize sections
And you can create
So if you have more than one
you can have a separate
They can be based on Apple News
to them just using
So how do we set up a
or to set up a channel
You go to our web, online web
And so News Publisher
to manage your presence
It lets you do things like
for your channels to
and works like you want it to.
It lets you assign roles to
It lets you view analytics, set
on how your articles and
It also helps you set
and helps you manage it.
It even lets you create Apple
from News Publisher, and we'll
So a few things to think
about before you sign
You want to consider who will,
who's going to manage
Think about people like interns.
They eventually leave, and
to your account to an intern
that won't be here
So make sure you give
who will be with
So a common problem
You also want to use a real
Sounds like an obvious thing,
with you via this e-mail
for example, your RSS
in your Apple News
And so we want to be able to
And also think about
So News is available in the
You want to make sure
to deliver whatever
etc. in Apple News
And so the easiest way to sign
to go to our developer page or
to the bottom, and then
That will take you
So News Publisher
If you don't have one already,
to set one up, although I
have one.
And then once you've signed
the News Publisher icon
to your other icons so you can
It's one of the great things
that when you use the same one
as on your iOS device
to easily preview articles
on your device.
So this is what News
We're not going to dive into
to start up by talking about
when you're setting
So every channel, no
or Apple News format,
One, it needs sections; two,
and it needs a cover image.
And so let's talk about the best
So, first, sections.
So sections make it possible
So, like, entertainment,
You can have a lot
but we really recommend
because essentially we
to find more channels that are
to fit on an iPhone
And for the same reason as
as you need, keep
You don't want to
that push your other
It's important to note that
the default.
So when users come to your
this is what they
It's sort of like
that they'll, that
Another really important
and builds the For You feed,
that are in your default first
from there and not
So if you want to have your
For You, for, in user's Apple
that you're publishing them
So for the channel logo,
the channel logo is
of your publication's logo.
And so for maximum
to be horizontal
use transparent background
If you don't use a transparent
up with a logo that looks
Something that we see fairly
to reach out to publishers
Also avoid using
They're going to end
in the various places
and sometimes we end up just
because they don't
We recommend having a logo
and then not more than
but don't make it any
Otherwise, it will make
in some places like 4U Feeds.
If you can, avoid
and trademarks alongside
In many places, the logos
and they just get lost
And then, finally, with
you typically want to avoid
The promotional text will be
and just makes your
And then URL's set
that they will be tappable,
And so this is what a channel
And so this is a
for your channel logo to look
of our users spend time in 4U,
that your logo looks great
So your logo also appears
and so the channel tile is a
and what we call a cover image.
And a channel tile is
within News to bring readers
like in favorites, but it's also
in News, including our
This is where users first
about who they're going to
And so this is going to be
especially for those users
about your publication.
You want to make sure
and a great cover image
of what your brand is all
We also have channel
where editors can feature them,
in the For You feed
So it's a really important way
to follow your channel
So to make the cover image look
please submit a high-quality,
We recommend 600 x 600 pixels.
You can choose two
You can either do
which means that it
This is great for brands
that have a really
an image that users will
but you can also choose to have
This is great if you want users
and they see your tile,
from articles in your feed,
and dynamic with what's
So when you're signing up
you'll eventually
where you can choose whether to
or whether to use RSS.
So we're going to talk
Let's briefly talk about RSS.
So when does it make
So News supports displaying
if you have one, and it's
if you already have a website
and you want to get your content
But, ultimately, we only
as a stepping stone to
It's important to note that the
in Apple News are using
and so they're really engaging.
They have animations and
that Apple News format allows.
And so if you're not using
it's not a great comparison.
So we, it's always best
But if you do need to use Apple
to use RSS, these are some
of the features that,
Gives you the ability
headlines, and excerpts.
We also show a preview
that it pulls from your feed.
And so this allows
to load really quickly
to load from your web page.
We host the RSS excerpt.
So when you use a [inaudible]
And then, of course,
you ultimately will host your
through to your web page.
So there's some best
You want to make your
If you make it really short,
see that it's only a sentence
and look for one of the many
that offer a full experience.
So use long form, full
and avoid links to
Things like boilerplates,
terms and conditions, user
You don't really need
and it just clutters up the
from the simplicity and
And then Apple News
into some great sharing features
to using to share your
to include links like tweet
The app already takes
it just adds noise
Make sure your actual web page
The worst thing you can
through the preview,
and then they have a big
Then, finally, similar to
make sure you provide a
So something happens
and we're having trouble getting
we want to be able
So when you first set up your
you can configure your feeds,
up your sections that
So you start out with
This is the one that
and you can customize
You can change the name, and
up your RSS feed, you can have
per section if you like.
And so this is what it looks
You can reorder them, and change
And so once you're up and
in Apple News, this is what your
look like.
You'll see we have a couple
and manage your sections,
But, ultimately, you want to
as soon as you can, and so
at the top that makes
Once you click that, you can
and that'll move you on
So what can you do
Why is it so great?
Well, first, we provide a, a
We have points of
that ensures lightning
Nothing will ensure people
like an article that
We also supply rich analytics,
and we also automatically
Apple News format is really
and having it look great on
We provide simple but
We have a dedicated Apple News
looking for great
and that's a huge
if you're creating really
We also have built-in
So if publish an article
it's really easy to have at
from your channel and related
It's a great way to
Apple News format itself
like animations,
videos, photo mosaics.
It's incredibly powerful
to add these elements
We also support dynamic
If you have that set in iOS
and then we're also
We have great support for
in iOS like voice over.
And we have lots of
of content into Apple News.
So lots of advantages to
And so we clicked our
and we've been approved
And so we've got our channel
to deliver an article into Apple
and make sure that it's
and is working as it should,
and so you can do
You can do that by creating
authoring tool, or you can
And so we'll talk about both
but let's say that you've
We'll take a moment to look
through a pending state.
And then once you're
you'll see at the top
and that means your channel
You're starting, you're ready
to start publishing
And so once you're approved,
that you're going to have more
to RSS, to your RSS channel.
And so there are
and some of these
than the RSS sections.
So one example is the
You can see here that there
that are associated
You don't need your
because Apple News format
And, of course, you
rename them here as
We also have the
and roles within Apple News.
So if you work in a multi-person
to invite new users,
which has full access
in News Publisher all the
who only access analytics and
who can only view
So very powerful.
So a few best practices when
First, you want to make sure
subject matter.
You want to avoid
or misleading headlines.
It's really not what
News is also not
to be used as a marketing
We really encourage you to
to engage, inform,
And then take advantage of
So use things like the animation
and imagery that
and makes them come back
And use analytics
Pay attention to what
and maybe they're reading a
or a specific article that
and they may want
to write more articles
Then, of course, you
which we'll talk
So three ways to get your
One is web authoring,
and the third is plug-ins.
And so, first, let's
So News Publisher supports
authoring experience.
The output's beautiful, simple,
Apple News Format
to your channel in News.
So rather than showing
let me show you a quick demo,
Alright. So this is News
to make a new Apple
you can just click create
in the authoring interface.
And so just a quick
We have our standard
You have undo, redo.
We have a styling palette
and feel of each article.
We have a Publish button
that lets you publish
We also have a Help Link up
and very rich, very deep
with publishing in Apple News.
And then we've got
and the content of
So let's start off
So for our header
to have an image
You can have the
or we can have a text-only
So let's go and create
that has a beautiful image.
OK. And so let's go, and let's
Alright. So that looks nice.
Let's add a nice
Let's go to an extra space here,
let's put that in
And let's add some body text.
Rather than typing it, just
Alright. So now we've
of a beautiful Apple
So you can do a lot of things
to make it really
So it's really easy to
if we can just, let's
and we can just select the text
and then we get a
We can just click the link
hit OK, and we've got a link.
And so you can also
For example, if we
we can make it italic.
We can also make it bold.
And so pull quotes are one
about Apple News, and
Let's grab a piece of text,
and then if we select
into a pull quote
And so that really makes it
Now let's do some, some work
So if we click on
we can very quickly jump
Here's modern.
A nice sanserif.
Here's bold, and let's
I think classic looks,
OK, and let's mess around
You can go with a darker
or you can try different
since that looks pretty nice.
It's also really easy to add
So we just grab a
from the desktop and drag it in.
The images pop right in, and
just by typing right
So that looks pretty good.
I think we're ready to publish.
So we can just go up
and then remember what
to your default section if you
So let's publish it to Top
and then let's also
because that's what
And we click publish, and
into Apple News.
Alright. So you can see
and this is what the articles
Beautiful, formatted
and iPad automatically.
You can see at the
from this channel
to the end of this article.
So a few things to think
about when you're
First, choose a striking
Great imagery drives
Use a consistent methodology
You want to have an
that you follow regularly
Try to include images
This is really true for any
Use imagery and, and multimedia.
Also try to use pull
You know, use all of the
in the authoring tool.
Alright. So that's
Let's talk a little
We're just going to
So Apple News offers
This is great for medium
with existing CMS'
to plug directly
It provides functions like read,
and also offers plug in support.
So if you want to
if you have specific questions
up with the Apple News
that we have a lab today, and we
We'll have Apple News
to answer any questions
Alright. Third, let's
the third way you can get
So WordPress is one of
We actually offer
and the published Apple News
to publish articles directly
It's also one of the most
have today.
And so this is what it
As a, WordPress is a nice
and there's an Apple News
that gives you many
in Apple News including
adding a pull quote,
So it's really simple
We also support publishing
which is a content
that many websites that you
And so you can publish directly
And today we also announced that
with Apple News, and
from their system.
It's very exciting.
And then next, I'm really
in this session that we have a
with Squarespace.
And so Squarespace,
helps anyone build
The Apple News integration lets
seamlessly publish into Apple
with the world, and, of
it's really beautiful
So, it's a really
We're thrilled to, to
So integrations of these four
to publish into Apple News using
day instantly.
So I really urge
out if you use any of these.
So next let's talk about
and channels in News.
So News makes it really easy
Now as a publisher,
in a few key places
in articles, and
And so one of the great
in Apple News are
So if you sell your own ads,
you get to keep 100
And for the inventory
you can have Apple backfill, and
So it's a, a really great,
One note, though, is that ads
for articles delivered
So a quick look at
that are available
So we've got standard, we've got
mrects in articles,
This is when you're swiping
between articles
We also have sponsored
And then video ads, if
and this is what they
So they're really simple, and
So a few things to think
about when you're
Avoid some common mistakes.
Keeping, keeping an
that you have for your ads.
If, for example, you've booked
and you have mrects
Those, obviously, aren't going
to make sure that you're not
like that.
You also should enable backfill
on selling ads, but you should
if you can.
That's the best way to
Also, we also give
to exclude certain categories
but if you exclude too
up with too low of an ad
where you need to so you don't
You can also experiment
We found out the larger ad
click-through rates.
So think about things
And then consider video
that users are engaging
And so we have a tool that's
which is called Workbench.
And so you can do a couple
First, you can monitor
for the campaigns you
It's really easy to keep
and you can also
You can book, manage, report
on individual campaigns
It's a really simple
Next, analytics and insight.
So we offer powerful
Once you've started
you can get some great insight
on how your content
which articles are doing
how your traffic
It's a really great
for Apple News Format
We offer a dashboard that gives
on the content performance,
you can download the
but Apple News Format only.
This is what the analytics
This is a view of channel data,
and so you can see these are
particular channel has over
So it's a really nice,
some sense at a glance of
You can even see at
a list of the best performing
which you can sort
And here's a chart for,
and so this one shows shares
that they're split up
So you can really get a sense if
or Twitter or messages or mail,
and that can help you
And then, of course, if you have
and you want to pull the
you can download the CSV
from the analytics tab
So we've talked about a lot of
Let's talk a little bit
about how you can make
in Apple News.
So there are lots of ways
to your channel.
We're going to cover
So, first, you, you want
from wherever you can
Use the promoted articles
And then use conical URL's,
that is in a minute, too.
And, in addition, we have a link
to our Marketing
There's lots of information
can promote your
So getting the word out about
and make it really easy to
you just go into News Publisher
see that there's a
So you click on that, and
where you can just
and then share it
So we also have a
and so what this does is
it will ensure that every user
of your channel when
And then when they come back,
down as you deliver more
that everyone sees it at the top
And it also, make sure it
at the bottom of articles
You can promote up to
It's really easy to promote.
You just click on the little
and then it moves up to the
in News Publisher.
So you can always see what you
So a great way to add some
Alright. So, finally,
It's really easy
You can just swipe
In iOS10, we've made
You can, we have a share
So users will be sharing a
that users can get to your,
which platform they're on.
And so conical URL's are
to your original website.
So if you have a website, and a
if you included a conical URL
if a user visits that link on
it will redirect them to Safari
So it's a great way to make sure
that users can read your
they're on.
And so it falls back
And this is an example
and then its accompanying
If you don't have a conical
which isn't an ideal screen.
And so if you do have a website,
you should include
so users can view
Alright. So some of the
for publishing in Apple News.
Write great stuff.
Try to check for errors and
If you have errors or
it makes it harder
and then recommend it to users.
So really make sure you're
you can.
Deliver high-resolution
Nothing drives engagement
Use Rich Text and pull quotes,
Anything else that Apple
and be creative.
There are so many interesting
Dig around in the documentation,
We really recommend that you
great articles.
And then use Apple.News
but use conical URL's
And then we also recommend
publishing cadence so
if you're publishing
They'll come back
on a regular basis as well.
And so Apple News is very much
beautiful, and inspired stories,
on the Apple News team, the
and look for amazing
They're looking for the
and so we encourage you to
with what you publish,
and if you're doing great
stories, our editors may notice,
and help you find
that you wouldn't
So a few places we do
in our new Featured
in the Explore tab, in the
We also have an Apple News
out some of the best articles
that have been published
and then we have a weekly
many users, and it's another
So some homework to do.
So first you want to sign
create a channel, and then start
your CMS via the Apple News API,
or you can author
So this is more information
and other places
And then there's also a
This is an amazing session
to create incredible Apple
So I can't recommend this
Casey and Dan will help
that really engage and
They use some really cool stuff.
So I highly recommend
So thanks, and I hope you're
[ Applause ]