[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to our session
in AVFoundation Playback.
My name is Sam Bushell.
Today we're going to talk
that we've added to try and
that some developers
So AVFoundation provides APIs
of multimedia activities,
export, and many
I'll be focusing
AVFoundation supports playback
of media formats
And in most cases you
and you can put it
and then AVFoundation can
The file format in
but the IO is over the network.
We call this progressive
Once we start downloading
even if the network
we will continue
HTTP Live Streaming
Generally, the base URL
which introduces multiple
but varying in bit rate and
And each of these playlists
the actual compressed media.
So let's talk about what we're
We're going to discuss
with the pre-playback
We're going to introduce
to simplify looping
We're going to discuss some
under the hood.
We're going to discuss
for wide color video.
And then we'll spend the rest
of our time discussing a
of static time in playback apps.
Let's start by waiting
Because when we play media
we're at the mercy
We don't want to start too
We don't want to start too late
We want to start at
and start playback when we have
to play consistently
Here is the existing API.
AVPlayerItem provides
playbackLikelyToKeepUp,
and playbackBufferEmpty.
playbackBuffer -- sorry --
if AVFoundation's algorithm
to stop playing now, you could
until you got to the end.
playbackBufferFull is
as much as it's going to.
So if you haven't
you might as well.
playbackBufferEmpty means
or you're about to stall.
So for progressive download
AVFoundation clients must
themselves and wait until
or playbackBufferFull is true
rate property to 1.
For HTTP Live Streaming,
You can set AVPlayer's
as the user chooses to play,
to buffer sufficient media
We are streamlining the
in the 2016 iOS releases.
iOS, Mac OS, tvOS.
For apps linked on or after
the same rules for
to progressive download
When the user clicks play,
you can immediately set
or call the play method,
And AVFoundation will
to buffer enough
If the network drops out during
the rate property
And so it will again buffer
when sufficiently buffered.
If you're using the AVKit
to present your playback UI,
it already supports automatic
and it will continue to.
If your application uses
and you build your own
to make some adjustments.
So what should we
Well, the word Autoplay has
in HTML 5, but we
that from the perspective
the playback is not
It's the waiting.
So the formal name for
WaitsToMinimizeStalling.
But you can call it
The network playback now looks
like a state machine
Paused, waiting, and playing.
We start in the pause state
And then the app calls play, and
When the playback likelyToKeepUp
the player progresses
Now, if the buffer
the player will switch
until we're likely
Should the user pause, we'll
Now there's one further
Recall that in iOS 9 and
you could call play before
and playback would
if it might stall.
So we preserved this semantic
playImmediately (atRate:)
into the playing state
or the waiting states.
Be aware that this
that the patient waiting
So be careful.
AVPlayer's rate property might
it meant.
Let's recap so everyone's clear.
The player's rate property
playback rate.
Not to be confused with
of the player item
at which playback is
We've added two new
to give you more detail.
One is the timeControlStatus,
which of these states you're
And if you're in
the reasonForWaitingToPlay
For example, you could
so the AVPlayer's rate
The timebased.rate would be
The timeControlStatus
WaitingToPlayAtSpcifiedRate.
And the reasonForWaitingToPlay
WaitingToMinimizeStallsReason.
So with that background,
I'd like to introduce my
who is much braver
to attempt a network
So everyone cross your
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Well, good morning everyone.
I want to start by
of the setup we have
And I have my iPad which
on the screen there.
And that iPad is
that is hosted by my Mac.
And what that allows me to do
conditioner to actually
that this iPad has available.
Can do that using the
preference pane.
Sam will tell you in a
And I've set up a profile called
to a mediocre network connection
than the media bitrate that
It's currently turned off.
And we'll leave it off, and
in a decent network situation.
So what I have here
and I can just select one video.
Let me do that.
And what you see is that
and we see that we're
You see this wonderful
that gives us all the properties
and functionality involved
This is really just taken from
So these are the properties that
to know what automatic
So right now we are paused,
Current time is at zero.
But the interesting thing is
we've loaded 39 seconds
which is actually
And we're currently
What that means is that
the video just starts
Now we wanted to
in a bad network situation.
So let's turn on the network
Here we go.
And now not much
Because as I said, it
It had already buffered
So when I go back
I want you to pay
and isPlaybackLIkelyToKeepUp
So let's do it.
Relaod the video.
And now what we see is
that loadedTimeRange is
And isPlaybackLIkelyToKeepUp
Eventually it will become true.
And at that moment we're at the
where now ready to play and
Now let's try this
and this time I will hit play
So this time we don't
and we go into this
And you see the spinner
that playback is waiting.
Eventually we will
and playback just starts.
There's one more
And that is immediate playback.
So let's also try this.
I go into the video
and immediately click
And we see that playback
into a stall because we
to play to the end.
In that case, we'll go into
until we have enough
And with that, it was a short
Go back to Sam and the slides.
[ Applause ]
Thanks, Moritz.
Let's recap what was
So when we set a slower network
of the movie, the movie
When he hit play, it went
Because playback was not
Notice that at this time,
but the timebase rate was 0.
After a few seconds,
that playback was
and so it set the
it set the state into
that the player rate and the
It may have occurred to you
that there's a little
in the timeControlStatus than
Remember the player's rate
desired playback rate.
The timeControlStatus also takes
into account what's
So that might be something
when you build a playback UI.
In case you want to try this at
to find the network
It's not something we
It is part of the
To get it, the easiest way
to More Developer Tools.
And after you log in, you'll
Okay, so on the 2016 SDKs if
your app will act as though
automatically
You can set that property
to go back to the old behavior.
And there's a few reasons why
In particular, if you use the
to synchronize playback
then you must opt out by
WaitsToMinimizeStalling
Otherwise, you will meet
Your helpful reminder.
Finally, a reminder never
to extrapolate current
If you want to do that, use
for that instead.
Or use the other APIs
That's what they're for.
All right, that's
Let's move along to
I have a question for you.
What's the best way to loop
Well, one idea would
for the notification that fires
when playback has
And when you get called,
seek back to the
Well, this idea is a good start.
But unfortunately,
between the playbacks
The first reason is that
to the time it takes
to reach your program and for
to get back to the
The second more significant
for prerolling.
It's not actually possible
to start media playback
without some preparation.
It's necessary to load
of it before you can
This process of filling
up the playback pipelines
called preroll.
So what we'd like to
to have AVFoundation
If AVFoundation knows
but early enough, then
and decoding before item A
And so it can optimize the
If item B is super short, then
on the transition to item C.
AVFoundation's tool for
AVQueuePlayer is a subclass of
of AVPlayer items
The current item is the one in
Now you can use AVQueuePlayer
between items that are
of looping, you can create
from the same AVAsset.
This is just another
since AVFoundation
and pause the media
And just a reminder, the
Please do not load
that you think you might like
That's not going
The purpose of the play queue
about items to be
so that AVFoundation can
The design patent when you want
to loop a single media
to make a small number of
in the AVQueuePlayer's queue
with the action item end
When playback reaches the end
from the play queue as playback
And when you get
that that has happened, you
set its current time back to
of the play queue to reuse it.
We call this patent
And you can implement the
using AVQueuePlayer.
We have sample code to help.
The slightly tricky detail
up key value observing to
and then seek it
And then add it to the end
As you can see, in this code
observer while we
to avoid any chance
So this is clearly doable.
It's just a little fiddley.
And the feedback
that it would be awful swell
So we're introducing
which implements the
You give it an AVQueuePlayer.
[ Applause ]
You give it an AVQueue Player
and it constructs a small number
which it then cycles
until you tell it to stop.
Adopting AVPlayerLooper,
the code for the symbol
So I want to give
on an iPad I have over here.
So here's a piece
Video Looper, I'm
And I have added a media file
to play it with AVPlayerLooper.
[ Music ]
Don't you feel mellow?
Okay, this is clearly looping,
and the code is pretty
It's fairly simple.
This would be an appropriate
if you have a tvOS app and you'd
like to loop background
All right, let's
We've talked a bit
I want to spend a
Ideally, if you have both
they should be precisely
Why? Well, if the audio track
that near the end
when audio should be
We have an empty
so what should the video do?
Should it go away?
Should you freeze on one frame?
Conversely, if the video track
of time when the audio
So when you build media assets
to make sure that the
In QuickTime Movie files,
the track duration is
Now if the media asset
under your control,
that you could set the
end time to the length
This will have the effect
of trimming back the
All right, next look at an
in the playback pipeline
that may have an impact
Suppose that we are currently
of playing tracks changes.
For example, we could
or the audio language.
Audio from English to French.
Here I'll change the
from English to Spanish.
Or we could remove
that was displaying the video.
Or we could add an AVPlayerLayer
Well, in all of these
AVFoundation will
adjust the playback pipelines to
and then resume playback.
In some cases, this
to snap back to a key frame.
Well, I will say we have
from users and developers
And so I'm happy to
and its other 2016 siblings,
these changes will no longer
Adding or removing
on a playing AVPlayer,
or the audio language
or manually disabling
We think that this
for users and developers.
However, it's a significant
and so I would ask you please
if it leads to any
If you find an issue with this
on our side, then
by filing a bug using the
And as always when filing a bug,
please try to give us
to reproduce the
Our industry is undergoing a
for digital photography
Many developers on iOS have
that wasn't using the standard
Since that's the standard
and that's what we've been
But wider gamut color
As you may have seen
when running iOS 10, you can
in the P3 color space.
Some third party products are
So I wanted to give you pointers
in your apps to be prepared
for making your apps
But I need to give you a
In media files, color
of the metadata of video tracks.
In QuickTime Movie files, it's
In several Codecs also store
There are three principle
Color Primaries, which specific
100 percent green, and 100
and also the white point.
Transfer Characteristics,
which you may have heard
or transfer function.
These define the mapping from
and answer the question is that
that gives you more
where our eyes are
And the YCbCr Matrix,
from their RGB space
for efficient compression.
So up here I have some examples.
Now if you haven't heard of
like the video equivalent
SIGB is actually based on Rec.
709. Wide color can be achieved
by using a different
The P3 color primaries specify
100 percent green,
that are more vivid then
One more point I want to make.
In our APIs, we generally
through the use of enumerated
to print and display and debug.
But in media files, these
And these standard tag
in an MPEG specification called
That sounds like a
How can you be coding
Well, it's less than a
as Codec independent
The job of the spec is to
of these tag numbers
that is harmonious all
So the interpretation of
in QuickTime Movie,
All right, with that background,
We have introduced a new media
that at video track is tagged
something wider than the Rec.
709 primaries.
If your app finds that
it might be appropriate
to preserve it, so it isn't
If not, it's actually generally
709 for processing.
So you can specify a working
up an AVPlayerItemVideoOutput
And you will then receive
into that color space.
You can also specify a target
up an AVAssetWriterInput,
in which case the
that you provide
into that color space
With AVPlayerItemVideoOutput
if you don't want image
into a common color space,
then you should set the
and then you'll receive buffers
This is effectively a promise
and processes those buffers,
it will examine and honor
There are analogous properties
for configuring video
First, you can specify
for entire video compositions.
Alternatively, if you have
you may choose to make
You can declare that your custom
aware and that it examines
on every single source
by implementing the optional
property and returning true.
Running it out with a reminder,
if you create picture
using a pixel buffer
then you should explicitly
on every buffer by
Most developers won't
In most cases when you're
for source buffers, that'll take
By popular request, I'm
of our time discussing
for optimizing playback
I'll talk about local
And then we'll move on
Now some of these
counterintuitive at first.
They require you
from the perspective
And to think about when it
to do what your app
For example, here is a
for setting up playback
We start with the
We create an AVURLAsset
depositing that file.
We then create an AVPlayerItem
for playback, and an AVPlayer
And then we create
to connect video playback
Now this code is correct,
which maybe you may
As soon as the player
as the player's current item,
up the playback pipeline.
Now it doesn't know the future.
It doesn't know that
to set an AVPlayerLayout later.
So it sets things up
And then when the AVPlayerLayer
that the video needs
And so now it can
for audio and video playback.
Now, as I said earlier,
in this year's OS releases
to the list of playback
of enabled tracks do
an interruption.
But it still ideal to
that AVFoundation needs in order
So I'm going to change
I'm going to watch where the
to the AVPlayer.
So now the player is
which means it has no reason to
And that doesn't change when
Playback pipelines
until the player item
And by that point, the
to get things right first time.
We can generalize this.
First, create the AVPlayerLayer,
and AVPlayerItem objects.
And set whatever
to on them including connecting
or an AVPlayerItem to an
Now this might seem crazy,
to start right away,
to play before you give
Why would you do this?
Well, if you do it
the player initially
to display the still frame
And it might waste some time on
that actually you
Again, starting with the
few milliseconds.
Let's move on to HLS.
The timeframes we're trying to
because they're donated by
than local file storage.
So the potential benefits
of optimizations are
The network IO breaks
Retrieving the master playlist
to AVURLAsset.
If the content is protected
retrieving content keys,
retrieving the selected
for the appropriate bitrate
and retrieving some
that are referenced
Now the media segments
of actual data transfer but
about round-trip latency.
Some of these stages
You can't download
until you've received
So a thing to think about
of these things before
For example, maybe in your
when content is first selected,
is this actually the
Or do I want to read some
So the question is, could
of network IO speculatively
when the user has identified
to play before they
Well, AVURLAsset is a lazy API.
It doesn't begin loading
until someone asks it to.
To trigger it to load data
we need to ask it to load a
like duration or available
with media selection options.
Duration is easy to type.
You don't have to provide a
you're actually going to do
Speaking of playlists, they
and we've supported compressing
So make sure you're doing that.
Possibly it's just a matter
If your content is protected
then there's round-trip involved
in negotiating content
And you can trigger
by setting the
property of the
For this to work, the
SESSION-KEY declarations.
So how are we doing so far?
With these techniques,
they can get the master playlist
while we're still
Now that's pretty cool.
The variant playlists
of data will still
So you might be asking
can we push this
Well, there is a new
preferredForwardBufferDuration.
Setting it to something low
like five seconds will
that AVFoundation thinks
But once playback begins,
to allow normal buffering
Here's a list of video variance
that might be in
They vary in dimensions
For an Apple TV on a fast
the 1080p variant
For an iPhone SE, even with
the 720p variant
It's already higher resolution
so going bigger probably
On a giant iPad Pro, there are
up to a big variant
But if we play
we don't need such a
And a lower bitrate variant
of our cache and help us
for other apps.
If the network connection
then that's going to
So what this means is that
into account both the
and the network bitrate
AVFoundation uses the
to evaluate the dimensions.
So set up your AVPlayerLayer at
to the AVPlayer as
It can be hidden behind other UI
if you're not ready
On a retina iOS device,
to set contentsScale manually.
As for bitrate, well
of a chicken and egg
to playback first beginning.
It has to choose some variant,
but it does not know what
Once it's begun downloading
it can use the statistics
to adjust the choice of variant.
But for that first variant,
it hasn't gathered
So AVFoundation's
to pick the first applicable
If that's a low bitrate
out seeing something blurry,
but AVFoundation will soon
bitrate is and switch up
Well, the question is, what
to improve that initial choice?
Well, remember, there is a
between initial quality
A higher bitrate first segment
And that means it will
You might decide that
with a lower bitrate variant
Well one way to make the
out a minimum acceptable
on a particular size of
Then AVFoundation will
after playback begins
And maybe you know one thing
Maybe your app just played a
And maybe you can use
to make a better guess
that the next playback
So let's suppose that you come
on startup quality and
And you decide on
which variant you
Well, how do we plug that
There are two techniques
Here's the first technique.
On the server, you have
from highest to lowest.
Like that.
And then in your app, you need
to set the player items
to you bitrate guess.
This will eliminate the
from initial selection.
Shortly after playback
that control back to zero, which
up to a higher bitrate variance
The second technique is
to dynamically rewrite the
and move your preferred
To do this, use a custom URL
and implement the AV asset
protocol in which you can
in response to the load request
I want to remind you to
Look for any delays before
In particular, you do not need
to become true before
You don't need to now, and in
Make sure that you release
from old playback sessions
so that they do not waste
You can use the Allocations
to check the lifespans
and AVPlayerItem objects.
And if you have an application
that does other network
consider whether you should
playback so that the user
of available bandwidth
All right, in conclusion,
to minimize stalling,
It's set to true by default
or after this year's SDKs.
And it provides uniform
for progressive download
We've introduced a new
to simplify using
to loop playback
Changing the set of enable
always causes a brief pause.
And we've looked at
that you can use to prepare
Finally, we talked about
for local files and for HLS.
In short, avoid accidentally
And for the work you do need,
We'll have more information at
including sample code
We have some related sessions
up to see in person
The bottom one is an
that you can watch in the app.
Thank you for attention.
It's been a pleasure.
I hope you have a great week.