[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Is this thing on?
[ Applause ]
Good afternoon.
I'm Roger Pantos.
This is what's new in
We have been talking about
And yet, every time I do one
"You've got to tell the
And so here we go.
Here's what's new.
But, first, HLS in 20 seconds.
So HLS is about playing
What's a playlist?
It's one of these things.
It's a TXT file.
It's got tags, which are
And it's got segments, which
Each one is 10 seconds of media.
If you want to play one,
through the tags looking for
I don't know -- this one
So, load it first.
So you do that.
Then you load segment1.
You play it.
You load segment2.
Maybe it's a live playlist.
So you refresh the playlist.
You load segment3.
You play that.
And that is basically
So now that we're all on
let's go on to what's new.
Sweet. OK.
MPEG-4 Fragment Support.
Who is this MPEG-4 guy
Actually, most of you
with MPEG-4 files.
If you've got a movie on
in MP4 format or one
And if you've ever
it consists of one
usually it's at the beginning --
and then all the sample
And we did that originally.
Then, we introduced a new
called fragments.
And fragments are basically a
and divide it up into these
A little sample table,
A little sample table, a
And these little islands
So what we're announcing
that what you can do now is
of these things, these
and use it as a segment
like you can do with
or elementary audio streams.
And we're updating
of give you the details of that.
There should be a link to
But what it allows you to do is
and you can do anything
with transport streams
That includes iframe playlists.
That includes discontinuities.
That includes live streams.
All that stuff.
Same set of features.
And of course, we're delivering
so you can choose to encode
and deliver them
Why would you do that?
Well, in a word,
If you're in a situation
to encode your entire media
to Apple's platforms,
to encode it again in another
for instance, that
But if you could have
then your delivery
your storage costs
you would get better
because you're no longer
on the edge, and as
Also, if you've got a
you can use the same set
across all of your ecosystems.
And as a fringe benefit, because
of packetization that
you get slightly more
So that's sort of a gimmie.
So how does that change HLS
Well, as it turns
If we take our playlist here
and we convert it to fMP4,
We change the initialization
to a movie box instead, and
MPEG-4 fragment.
And that's it.
Everything else is pretty much
On the segment level, there's
to talk about, which
Now, as you know, HLS
of encrypting your stuff.
You can either just
AES CBC the entire thing.
And that's the same whether
For sample encryption,
to use FairPlay Streaming, it's
because you have
of the files are encrypted
And this time around --
last time, we did it
We essentially made
This time, we decided
And so this is what MPEG
It's a standard.
It came out a couple years ago.
The newest edition of the
which is compatible
And so if you're doing
you'll be using common
And so with encryption, and
we pretty much have a whole
around fragmented MPEG-4.
But if we're going to get to
where everybody can just have
and deliver it everywhere,
And one of the things we need
down a set of rules that
to author your fMP4 segments
so that they play everywhere."
And we've been working
It started as sort
between us and Microsoft.
And once we got to the
like it was practical, it seemed
and proposed it to MPEG.
And a lot of folks there seemed
to think it was a
So what it comes down to is
for how you construct
So you've got to deliver your
You've got to put an
of every video segment.
You have to make sure you
across your different bit rates.
You don't have to
if all you want to
But if you want the broadest
of your media library, then
of recommendations for you.
And so I think that
up benefiting everyone
So now I'm going to switch
about something else --
everyone's favorite
So to sort of frame this,
about some of the existing
for you in HLS for metadata.
Static metadata and ID3.
Static metadata is used
No surprise.
So it'll offer for
or something like that.
Most of it is text, and that
into the playlist file
or you can package it as a
Now you only get one
or one copyright per
But the benefit of that is
that it's available
It's available right away.
So let's contrast that to ID3.
Because timed metadata
of the media presentation,
for signaling events
For instance, the start of an
It lives inside the
so it's a binary
And that makes it compact.
It also makes it kind
because it requires
It's kind of a pain in the
It's hard to read ID3.
But you can have as
and you can put them anywhere
And so that's powerful.
The flipside of that however
we can't give it to you until
So where does the new guy fit?
What we're adding is a way
to author timed metadata
And so you can use it
that you're using ID3 for today.
You can author them as text.
So that's pretty easy.
You can easily put
and you can have as
They can be overlapping.
They can nest.
They can do whatever.
And on the other hand, because
we can give you the
as we read the playlist
where the playhead
And so that makes
For doing things particularly
So what does it look like?
How do we make it sort of sit?
Well, we already had the
We have the PROGRAM-DATE-TIME
to precisely signal
So we built on top
each bit of metadata is going to
that has a set of
And some of those are ours.
Some of those are yours.
We set up the syntax so
and remove these
So it meshes really well
So what does it look like?
Let's take a look at
We called the new tag
Here's another playlist.
The first guy says
The second one is
And if you look at it, what
of attributes.
These guys here, these
that are defined by the spec --
the ID, the START-DATE,
These guys, we reserve
to HTTP for all you guys.
So you can use that to put
in whatever attribute
In this case, someone
in an AD-ID and a beacon URL.
So that's an example.
That's what one of these guys
When you're doing your
you can use it either
It just has to have a
You can obviously
in when you're creating
But the other nice thing is,
to manipulate, if
like a post-production workflow
or something like
to augment the playlist
with metadata at the same time.
By popular request, we
to map SCTE-35 that you might
into the DATERANGE tags.
So you can carry SCTE-35
And finally, we've added support
And I actually wanted to take
to the new set of tools we have.
We put together a talk --
we don't have time to talk about
but we put together a talk
And so I'd encourage
It's on demand on your apps
And you should check it
of new tricks the validator
So for playback, when
on the metadata that's
you have a set of
And so you have to be
And the APIs are essentially,
give me all the data
And then if you've
tell me when something
And it's centered around
AVPlayerItemMetadataCollector.
And so we've got a
You can see it doing
You create your asset.
You create your PlayerItem.
And then you say, "Hey, I want
So you create the
You set yourself
so we can tell you stuff,
and then you add it
And that's it.
Then you get all
And so it's really easy to use.
It's really powerful.
And I think that it's going
to carry metadata
So the next thing
about today is another feature
And that is the ability to
[ Applause ]
And to talk about that, I'm
Jordan Schneider, to come
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hey. So, let's see
There we go.
In iOS 10, we are bringing
and then play HLS content
So now you can bring
to your users using
video library.
So as part of this feature,
we are extending the
that we introduced to you last
and we are providing you a way
to download your HLS
is backgrounded.
And finally, we are
to play partially-downloaded
might still be in progress.
So the first question - when
Well, yes, if you want to
when your user might want to
that they might not have
such as when they go
However, this feature is not
loading media.
We have other ways of doing
So why use HLS for
than just downloading
Well, for one, your content
as HLS.
So adopting HLS for offline
convenient story for you from
But also, in addition
movie files can contain
and subtitle tracks that your
or want to persist offline.
So in HLS, because all these
on the server into
we can have a little
Specifically, we can
over which media
saving your user
and storage space
So, for example, by default
media selection, which is likely
about when they play offline.
What we're also providing
to configure exactly what you
to have available
So another cool thing about
using the same asset,
we can still download
that have not been downloaded so
on your server, which is nice.
So how do you do this?
In iOS 10, we're
to download AVAssets
This class inherits
Most importantly, the
in the background even while
of its mechanisms.
As I mentioned before,
to control which media
And because this is HLS,
to select the quality of
to download for offline as well.
So the interface
of AVAssetDownloadTask
It inherits from URLSessionTask.
I want to mention here
from URLSessionDownloadTask.
It behaves similarly, but
that I'll point out as the
So to create one
you want to set up a URLSession.
Now we have a specific subclass
of URLSession called
that you have to use
And so you call
to create an asset
And then for your
we have a minimum required
as well as a media
Now I should note here that each
to a single set of
So if you want to download
on the same asset, then
up multiple AVAssetDownloadTasks
I'll show you how to do
So to use one of these
The first thing is to set
configure it how you want
Next, we want to
that might occur
such as monitoring the
Then once the download
to store the location
when we're actually offline.
And then you might want
to download additional media
And finally, you're going
So to set up one of these
after you have your asset set up
up a backgrounConfiguration
from a background
Then you're going to create
and then create your
Here, I have the download
at about a media bit rate of
But by default, we'll
video available.
Then once you have that set up,
because this is a
you just call resume
So once you have your download
to want to monitor it.
To do this, we have
for you called
So this inherits the
that URLSessionTaskDelegate has.
But I want to point out two
that we are introducing to you.
One is our method that we use
to monitor the progress
In this method, we express
and time ranges as
for better parlance
And then we have a
delegate method which
where the download
So this is similar
to URLSessionDownloadDelegate's
But your expectation
when you get this
bit differently.
So I'll point that
So here's an example of our
Here, I'm just converting
to a percent -- complete
I'm not going to go
but that's how you
Another thing that might happen
might be killed.
The process might be terminated.
And then what do you do?
Your download continues.
Well, to respond to that, you
to URLSessionDownloadTasks.
And that's by, when your app
to set up another background
identifier you used to set up
and then create a
And then from there, call
And then here, you can restore
which will have the
And you can use this
that you might have in the app.
And you can even use it to
that you used to set
So once your download finishes,
to want to do is store the
So this method is called
at this location, including
when a partially-downloaded
by your user.
Now you can use this
cancelled download to resume
Or you can even use it
to playback whatever has
But if you really don't
or that content there on
then here's where you
So, unlike
we ask that you do not move
And we do this because
that the system be able
as the system may want
in low disk space
at some point go out
from your app container.
So what you're going to
to be the relative
And then from there, you will
in the future for playback.
So, now that you have a version
let's say you want to download
A good place to do this would be
in our didCompleteWithError
This is the same one
And the reason why it
because media selections
on the same asset are
And this is generally the
of the complete download.
So, to augment with an
option -- say, the
we would first grab
that we want to download.
Then we would mutate
that we originally passed
in to select the
And then once we have that
to create a new
on the same session with passing
we want to download.
And then we call resume,
and then the whole
And then we could download
after that if we wanted to.
So let's talk about
So, say we had a --
of how we could create
And notice that I pass in an
When we playback offline
that original urlAsset
that AVAsset instance to play.
And we can grab this from
the AssetDownloadTask.
If you pass in a new
AVFoundation will not know
where to find the
So you should use
and then you will
However, if you no
to that original AVAsset --
for example, a long
when your app might not
then what you're going to want
to create a new AVAsset
that we supplied to you
in the didFinishDownloadingTo
and create a PlayerItem
Now even in this case, if
on the asset -- for example,
augment with an additional
you really should
You shouldn't have a bunch
of AVAssets pointing toward
This helps AVFoundation
about reusing already-downloaded
So we also have an additional
about what you let your
and this is called AVAssetCache.
You grab this from the asset
And it can do two things.
One is that it can tell
of this asset is
And the other thing it can do
specific media selection
Now, remember, if it's
it's still playable so long as
and that media selection option
that you downloaded it from.
So, that's how you use
and play the subsequent
And I should note
playing the download asset
at any point in this process.
It can even happen before
or even during the download.
And AVFoundation will be
to reuse what has already been
So I want to switch gears
about securing the
So, last year, we
to bring strong content
However, in iOS 9, FairPlay
connection to a key server,
which doesn't really work
So, this year, we've extended
without an internet connection
Now we do this by packaging your
to store on disk and reuse
But your app is still expected
and respond to key
on every single playback without
its key cached.
So support for these keys
in your key servers,
so your key servers have
to be eligible for
And finally, we have
They must be declared in your
if you want to make sure
So, storing keys for offline
off the request flow of
And so what you have to
with how you modify
I'll give a quick recap
out what you need to do.
But for more information, you
where we go into this
So just like in FairPlay
AVFoundation will
and trigger a key request
which will give your
to save the key for
So the first thing your app
to AVFoundation to get
Then it would talk to your
that streaming key request
and give you a content
And then in online
this is where you would finish
to AVFoundation with that CKC.
However, in offline FairPlay
to give that CKC to AVFoundation
so AVFoundation can freeze-dry
for you to store into
And this is something
on subsequent playbacks.
So once you have this thing
you want to return that
to complete the request.
Now if your app were offline,
to do is read that freeze-dried
and return it to AVFoundation
without touching the network.
So let's look at how this
So in online FairPlay Streaming,
as a part of
specifically as a
on
So the first thing you
of these requests
to create a streaming
which sends that to your server.
And then you get a CKC
to AVFoundation with that.
Now in offline FairPlay
This is the method that you
You pass in the CKC you
and it returns back that
for you to store offline.
We also have a new content type
the persistentContentKey type --
and a new option to pass
into our streaming content key
So here is how we would modify
that we want to save offline.
The first thing that we want
to do is ask AVFoundation
The difference here is
in the required persistentKey
So that way, AVFoundation
to request a key
for that freeze-dry process.
So it sends this SPC to
And then once you
you call your
to create this freeze-dried
Then, you want to actually
And then, you want to
to a persistentContentKey type
and then finish the downloading
that you saved to your disk.
So now if you are offline,
or say you already satisfied
then this is what you will do.
You get your resource
and you just simply read
from your app storage.
Then you set your
and you respond to the
without hitting the network,
as you may potentially
and don't have any
this process.
So that's how you modify
with your offline HLS content.
So now I want to talk
for managing your assets.
So it's important to note that
to your app's disk usage,
so you want to be a
You should really clean up
Specifically, you should
to your users to see everything
and allow them to delete things
Remember that downloads that
Now you can use those to
at some point if you like.
But if that's not what you
to go ahead and delete those
We're asking that you
by explicit user actions.
So you shouldn't just go ahead
that your user might not
We've gone ahead and taken
out these downloads
As I mentioned earlier,
for the system to delete your
in low disk space conditions.
Now this won't happen while
This will only happen while
After your app is launched, you
about assuming whether you
that you had previously
You do not move your
which we provide them to.
Again, it is very important
that the system be able
And finally, because these
media selections that have not
to mutate the asset that
If you really must change,
of a media playlist
and mutate your master playlist,
that modified asset
than changing the one
So, that's offline HLS.
And we're really happy
and excited to see you adopt it.
So, in summary, we
for you to use this year.
We have our fragmented
which will bring a
across different platforms
Remember that this is
and requires minimal changes
Next, we have our new
DATERANGE tag.
and this is just really
with any live content that
metadata, like ad boundaries
And finally, we're giving
So part of this we have a
engine as well that you can
and quality to download.
And we're also extending our
to work without an
So for more information,
on how to use
and more documentation on these
on the development
I want to point out the session
our version of authoring
You can watch this video
I highly recommend watching it.
So, thanks for coming.
And I hope you enjoy the
[ Applause ]