[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much,
And my name is David Hayward and
about editing Live Photos
and processing RAW
We got a bunch of great
First I'll give a brief
for those of you who
Then we'll be talking about
for this morning.
First we'll be adjusting
Second, we'll be
And third, we'll be talking
in a new way using
So first, so a very brief
The reason for Core Image is
high-performance API to
The basic idea is you start with
from a JPEG or a file or
to apply a filter to it and
and it's very, very easy
All you do is you take your
and specify the name of the
that are appropriate
It's super easy.
And, of course, you can do
You can chain together multiple
or graphs and get
One of the great features
of Core Image is it provides
and this is very
We now have a variety of devices
and wide gamut output.
And what Core Image will do is
appropriate nodes
so that it will match
to the Core Image working
to display, it will match
from the working space
And this is something you
of because wide color images
and wide color displays
and many open source libraries
for doing image processing
So this is a great feature of
of all that for you in
Another thing to be aware of is
that each filter actually has
with it, a small
And all of our built-in filters
of the great features is if
of filters, Core Image will
subroutines into
The idea behind this is
by reducing the -- and
of intermediate buffers.
Core Image has over
They are the exact
of our platforms;
We have a few new ones this year
One is a new filter
for generating hue
It creates a gradient
and then you can specify, as
of the image and also
that the wheel is in.
And as you might guess, this
as the basis of the color
of the different types
Another new filter we have
and NinePartTiled.
The idea behind this is you
like this picture frame here,
up to fit an arbitrary size.
This filter is very easy to use.
You provide an input image and
two horizontal and two vertical.
Once you've specified
you can specify the size
It's very easy to use.
The third new filter is
quite interesting.
The idea is to start
In this case it's an image
but it can also contain
So imagine you have a small
and maybe it's only 6 by 7
that to the full
The idea is to upsample
the small color image,
but respect the edges
Now, if you weren't to
if you were just to stretch the
as the full image, you'd
but with this filter
You can actually get something
that preserves the edges while
And this is actually a
of other types of algorithms.
In fact, in the new version
to improve the behavior of
I look forward to
that in your application.
We also have some new
and do things that
in Core Image this year.
One is we have Metal
So if you use any of
or your own custom kernels,
all of those kernels
to Metal on the fly for you.
It's a great way of
with very little
We've also made some great
which is creating a
and this now produces
than it has in the past.
So you can actually use
to animate an image
Also another new feature is
that Core Image now
to Core Graphics, which is
that Core Graphics
Let me just talk for a
because this brings up
We're all familiar with the
of RGBA8 and it takes just
and has 8 bits of depth,
in the range of 0 to 1.
However, this format
for representing wide-colored
and it's limited to the
So in the past the alternative
which takes 16 bytes per pixel,
but gives you all the depth and
Another feature of the fact
that what quantization there is,
it's distributed
which is a good fit for the way
Well, there's a new format
and now Core Graphics does
to as the Goldilocks pixel
and this allows you to,
store data that is 10 bits
in the range of minus
And again, those values are
so it's great to store
that won't be perceived
So I highly recommend
There's another new format
which is that Core Video
with the long name
of 30RGBLittle [inaudible]
and this also supports 10
in an only 4 bytes per pixel by
So there's many cases where
and Core Image supports
or to CV pixel buffers
So now I'd like to actually talk
of our discussion today,
with Core Image, and
to talk about this today.
We've been working on
It's been a lot of hard
about the fact that we've
In talking about this, I'd like
how to use the CIRAWFilter API,
some notes on supporting
and also tips for
So first, what is a RAW file?
Well, the way most cameras work
a color filter array
And the idea is light from the
through the color filter array
and it's counted by
And this data is actually
of course, but in order to turn
a lot of image processing
to produce a pleasing
So I want to talk a
But the main idea here is
that was captured by the
If you take the data
after the image processing,
RAW files store the
and JPEG files store the
Another way to think of it is
that the RAW file
from which you can
a JPEG stores the
after they've been baked
In order to go from
to a final baked product,
of stages, so let me just
First of all, we have to
that tells us how
to extend the metaphor.
Also, we need to decode the
We need to demosaic the image to
from the data that was captured
with only one RGB value
We need to apply geometric
Noise reduction, which is a
We need to do color matching
that the sensor captured
into the output-referred
And then we need to do
and temperature and tint.
And lastly, but very
contrast and saturation to
That's a lot of stages.
What are some of the
Well, one of the great things is
that the RAW file contains
which is what enables
Another feature is that RAW
every year.
So with the RAW you
that an image you took yesterday
when you process it next year.
Also, RAW files are
They can actually be rendered
which is also a good
of displays we have today.
Also, a user can choose
to interpret the RAW file.
Just like giving
to two different chefs, you
and some users might prefer
That said, there are some great
First of all, because the
they are fast to
They contain colors
that target a specific
And that also gives
Also, it's worth mentioning that
of producing JPEG images,
and our iOS cameras are an
So on the subject of RAW,
about how our platforms
So the great news is that now
and upcoming seed
This means we support over
from 16 different vendors.
And also, we support DNG
by our own iOS devices.
The iOS devices include
and also the iPad Pro 9.7.
That is really exciting.
I recommend you all go back,
and watch the Advances
which talks about the new
to capture RAW on these devices.
Another great thing is that
performance RAW pipeline
and this is actually
I counted the other day
and it involves over 4,500
and this all works
and it's a great testament to
of Core Image to be able
to handle complex
Our pipeline on iOS
and you can test for this in
for the iOS GPU Family 2.
Another note on platform
We continuously add
as new ones become available,
of existing cameras
New cameras are added in
And also, we improve our
And our pipelines are versions,
so you can either use our
and use previous
So without further ado, I
of how this looks in action.
So what I have here
There's an early version of that
and it's called RAWExposed,
and this latest version is
So what we can do is
and actually use
We have three RAW images here
that were taken with
And you can see here that
overexposed, but one of the
that you can actually
So we can go here and edit it
and use our photo
to edit this as a RAW file.
So now, since we're
we can actually make
We can adjust the
You can see we can pan
and we get great results.
Once I'm happy with the
than it did before,
and it will generate a new
and now it is actually
in the Photos application.
[ Applause ]
One of the other things
that you can make
on white balance in an image.
Again, on this image
but it may be a little crooked,
but also the white
So I'm going to go in here
and adjust the white
and I can make a much
And again, we can zoom
And we can adjust
So we hit Done and save that.
Another image I want to
which is actually
I want to show you a little bit
about our noise reduction
Over half of our 4,500 lines
of kernel code relate
So if I go in here
you can see that there's some --
hopefully at least
you can see the grain
One of the features we expose
to turn off our noise
and then you can actually
of the noise that's actually
And it's this very
of doing the noise
that doesn't have
but still preserves
that are intended in the image.
So I'll save that as well.
Lastly, I want to demonstrate an
out in the lobby, which
Yes, I was one of those people
[ Laughter ]
And here I want to
this is an image that's
because it's got some
and some areas that
One thing I could do here is I
well, I have a highlight
to bring the highlights
I can also bring
And now I can really see what's
But now the shadows
so I can then increase those.
So this gives you an idea of the
on RAW files, and
of having deeper
that you get in a RAW file.
So I'll hit Done on that.
So that's our demo
[ Applause ]
And a huge thanks to the team
So let me talk about the API,
to provide a demo application.
We want to enable your
to do this in your apps as well.
So we have an API
to as the CIRAWFilter API,
and it gives your application
It gives your application
extended range, half-float
It also gives you control
in the RAW processing pipeline,
such as those that
It also provides fast
the GPU on all our devices.
So how does this
The API is actually very simple.
You start with an input, which
or even in our next
that works using CVPixelBuffer.
That is our input.
We're then going to
of a CIRAWFilter
At the time that filter is
default values for all the
that you might want to
Once you have the
for a CIImage, and you can
Let me just show you the code
and how simple it
All we need to do
We're going to create
of the CIFilter given that URL.
Then, for example, if
of the current noise
we can just access the value
for key kCIInput
If we want to alter
We just set a new
When we're done making changes,
we ask for the outputImage
That's all we need to do.
Of course, you might want
so typically you'll take that
in a UIImage view or
or other type of view system.
In this case the user might
maybe this image is a
so in your UI you can have
and then the user can
You can then pass that in as a
Then you can ask for
and then you can then
with the exposure
And this is very easy as well.
You also might want to take your
you want to export your
to produce a full-size image,
or you may be exporting several
So you might want to, in those
for passing to other APIs, or
and we have some easy to
If you're going to be
of large files like RAWs,
we recommend you create
for that purpose.
Specifically, you want to
in a singleton variable,
to create a new context
This allows CI to
of all the kernels
However, because we're going to
we don't need Core Image to be
so you can specify false there,
and that will help reduce
in this situation.
Also, there's a setting
to use a low priority
The idea behind this, if
you don't want the
for that background operation
of your foreground UI,
in Core Image or Core Animation.
So this is great for
And a great new thing we're
that this option is also
Once you have your context,
You get to decide what color
For example, the
And then we have a
for taking a CIImage and
Super easy.
You specify the CIImage,
the destination URL,
This is also a good time
to specify what compression
Now, in this case this will
that has been tagged with a
of producing a wide-gamut image
on any platform that supports
However, if you think your
that doesn't support
we have a new option
This is an option
of the CGImageDestination API,
and it's CGImageDestination
The idea behind this is it
in the P3 colorSpace, but
and with a custom profile,
such that that image will
if your recipient of that
color management.
So this is a great
Another thing is if you want
from a CIImage, we have a
with some new options.
We have this convenience
to specify what the
that you want to render to is.
You may choose, however,
that has the format of RGBAh,
the Goldilocks pixel format
And in that case you
to use a special color space,
which is the extendedLinearSRGB
Because the pixel format
of the range 0 to 1, you want
Another option that we have
to specify whether the act
of creating the CGImage
in a deferred or
If you specify deferred,
in rendering the CIImage
when the CGImage is drawn.
This is a great way
especially if you're only
of that CGImage later,
to be drawing that CGImage once.
However, if you're
that image multiple times, you
and in that case Core Image
into the CGImage at the time
So this is a great new,
for your applications.
Another advanced feature of this
like to talk about
As I mentioned before, there's
in processing RAW files, and
how can I add my own
Well, one common place
to add processing to the
in the middle; after the
but before all the nonlinear
and contrast and color
So we have an API just for this.
It's a property on the
to specify a filter
into the middle of our graph.
So I look forward to seeing what
of and what can go
Some notes on wide-gamut
The CIKernel language supports
However, whenever a
to an intermediate buffer, we
of the current CIContext.
On macOS the default
our Goldilocks format.
On iOS and tvOS our default
which is good for performance,
but if you're rendering
that may not be what you want.
Our RAW pipeline, with this
in our pipeline force the usage
which is critical for RAW files.
But as you might guess,
about wide-gamut input
that data throughout
you should modify your CIContext
that you want a working
I should also mention again
that Core Image supports
of wide-gamut output spaces.
For example, you can render to
or DisplayP3, whatever
Now, as I mentioned before,
I was demonstrating
RAW files can be a lot
RAW files can be large and
intermediate buffers to render
And so it's important
to reduce the high water
that you use some of these APIs
such as turning off caching
where you don't need it,
or using the new write JPEG
which is very efficient,
or specifying the
when creating a CGImage.
Some notes on limits
On iOS devices with 2
we support RAW files
So we're really proud to
[ Applause ]
On apps running on devices with
up to 60 megapixels, which is
And this also holds true for
which run in a lesser
So that's our discussion of RAW.
Again, I'm super proud to be
I would like to hand the
who will be talking about
and how you can edit those in
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, David.
Hello everyone.
I'm really excited to be
about how you can edit Live
So first, we're going to go
of what are Live Photos, then
and then we'll go
and see how you can get
how you can then set up a
how you can apply Core Image
and how you can preview your
and finally, how you can save
into the Photo Library, and
All right.
So let's get started.
So Live Photos, as you may know,
are photos that also include
and after the time
And Live Photos can be
such as iPhone 6S, 6S Plus,
In fact, Live Photo is
on those devices, so you
to already have plenty of Live
So what's new this
So first, users can now
in Photos.
They can apply -- all the
to a regular photo they
Next we have a new API
in your application and for
about that, I strongly recommend
in iOS Photography session that
It also includes a lot of
from the capturer point of view.
And finally, we have a new
and that's why I'm here
All right.
So what can be edited exactly?
Right. So first, of course,
of the photo, but
of the video frames as well.
You can also address
and you can change the
Things you can't do though is
that you can't change
or the timing of the Live Photo.
So in order to get a Live Photo
to do is to actually get a Live
So there's two ways to do that,
depending on whether you're
extension or a PhotoKit
In the case of a photo
to start first by opting
by adding the LivePhoto
of supported media types
And next, in your implementation
that's called automatically,
you can expect the content
and you can check the media
to make sure that
Okay. On the other hand,
if you're building a
you have to request the
from a PHAsset, and then
and media subtypes
All right.
So the next step would be to set
A LivePhotoEditingContext
that are needed to
It includes information
such as its duration,
the size of the Live Photo,
It also has a frame processor
to actually edit the
and I'll tell you more
You can adjust the
You can ask the
to prepare a Live
and you can ask the
and process a Live Photo
for saving back to
Creating a
really easy.
All you need to do is
from a LivePhotoEditingInput
All right.
So now let's take a look at how
to use the frame processor
So the frame of a Live
by a PHLivePhotoFrame object
which is a CIImage
Type, which is whether it's a
And the time of the
as well as the resolution
that frame is being rendered.
In order to implement a frame
frame processor property on
to be a block that takes
and returns an image
And here we just simply return
so that's just necessarily
So now let's take a
This is a Live Photo, as
and I can play it right there.
And so let's say we want
to apply a simple basic
That's start with a
Here's how to do that.
In the implementation of
to start with the input
Then you compute your crop rect.
Then you crop the image
which is called the
and just return that
That's all it takes to actually
Here's the result.
I can place side photo, you
but the video is also
All right.
So that's an example of a
Now, what if we want to apply
and that is one that will
and will change while the
So you can do that, too.
So here let's build up
and implement the dynamic crop.
So here's how to do it.
So first we need to capture
about the timing of the Live
of the photo because we want
and have your crop rect really
Next we take it so we capture
And you can notice
of the frame processor
to avoid cycling dependency.
Here in the block we can ask for
and then we can build a
that information to
And here's what the result.
So you can see the Live Photo
the photo is the same,
you can see that the crop rect
All right.
So that's an example of
Now let's take a look
This effect is interesting
because it's a
What I mean by that is that the
specified, they're
which mean that you
when you apply these kind
that the effect is visually
of the resolution at which the
So here if I play it, you
the effect is applied
to the video the same way
So that's great.
So let's see how to
So in your frame processor
to this renderScale
This will give you
of the current frame compared
to the one-to-one full-size
So keep in mind that
and the photo are
Right. Usually the video is
So you want to make sure
In order to do that, you can
down that width parameter
on the full-size photo
but it will be smaller on
Another way to apply your
is to use the extent of
for the inputCenter parameter.
I actually use the midpoint of
to also scale [inaudible].
All right.
One more edit on that image.
You can notice that I did a logo
and when I play it, you see
that the logo actually
So this is how you would apply
and not to the video,
In your implementation of your
at the frame type, and here
then we composite the still logo
into the image, but
So that's as easy as that.
And you may have, you
that are local advertisement or
to apply or you can't
and so that's a good
All right.
Now that we have an
let's see how we can
So in order to preview a
with the PHLivePhotoView.
So this view is readily
and is new this year on macOS.
So in order to preview
to ask the
to prepare a Live Photo
in the target size, which is
in pixels, and then you get
on the main thread with
And then all you need to do
of the LivePhotoView so that
with their Live Photo
of what the edited Live
Now, the final set will be to
And that, again, depends whether
extension or a PhotoKit
In the case of a photo
implement finishContentEditing.
And the first step is to create
from that contentEditingInput
And next you will ask your
to save the Live
And again, that will process
asynchronously and call
with success or error.
And in the case everything
make sure you save also
with your edits and that will
to your app or extension later
And then last step is
to actually call the
for that extension
If you're building a
the steps are really similar.
The only difference really
they are from the changes
a PHAssetChangeRequest.
All right.
So now I'd like to
So I've built a simple demo
like to show you today.
So here I am in Photos and I can
can pick to see the contents.
I can swipe and see
All right.
That's the one I
So I can go to edit.
And as I mentioned earlier,
I can actually edit the Live
Let me do that.
I'd like to apply
that David mentioned earlier.
All right.
So here in Photos I
Right. Of course, I could
to apply my sample
So I'm going to pick
And, yes, we actually apply the
through for the slides.
And you can see this is
but it shows a LivePhotoView,
and I can actually press
right in my extension.
So that's real easy.
And the next step is to actually
And this is going to process
and send it back to
And there it is,
All right.
So that was for the quick demo.
Now back to slides.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
All right.
So here's a quick summary of
So we've learned how
out of the Photo Library
up a LivePhotoEditingContext,
to edit the contents
We've seen how to
in your app using
And we've seen how to
into the Photo Library.
Now I can't wait to see what
A few things to remember.
First, if you're building
do not forget to opt
in your info.plist
Otherwise, you'll get a still
And as I said, make sure you
as well so that your users
and continue the edit
Finally, I think if you
application, adopting Live
for LivePhotoEditing should be
especially if your app is
And if not, there's actually
to let you integrate your
into Core Image.
And to tell you all about it,
I'd like to invite
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Etienne.
So my name is Alexandre Naaman,
to you about some new
of Core Image to do
that weren't possible
to be using a new API
As David mentioned earlier,
of Core Image using our
and you can extend
by writing your own
Now with CIImageProcessor
and we can insert a new node
that can do basically
in perfectly with
So we can write our own custom
So there are some analogies
with writing general kernels.
So in the past you would
specify some string, and then
on your CIFilter and
which is the output image
to be creating, and
and then finally whatever
to pass to your kernel.
Now, there are a
with creating CIImageProcessors,
into detail with them
Instead we refer
from our WWDC talk from 2014.
So if you want to
we strongly suggest you go
because we talked about
and ROI parameters
So now let's look
for creating a CIImage
and this may change a
but this is what it
So the similarities are there.
We need to provide the extent,
which is the output image size
give it an input
There are a bunch of additional
however, such as, for example,
that we'll be creating.
We then need to provide a
of all our input parameters.
And this is really
because this is how Core
or not we can cache the
or not we need to rerender.
So you need to make sure
that every time your
that you update the hash.
The next thing we can
In this case here
but you can also specify zero,
which means you'll get the
as an input image format.
You can specify the
In this case we're using
that we're going to be going
of precision, so we'll
And then finally we get
which is where we have
our CIImageProcessorInput
and it's inside of here that
to do.
So let's take a look
and why you would
So CIImageProcessor
for when you have some algorithm
that implements something
and something that
for the CIKernel language.
A really good example of this is
An integral image is an image
contains the sum of
and to the left,
And this is a very good
that can't be done in a
which is the kind of
when you're writing CIKernels.
So let's take a look at
in a little bit more detail.
If we start off with the input
let's say, corresponds to some
our integral image would
So if we take a look
it actually corresponds to
on the left, which would
The same goes for this other
of all those other pixels above
So now let's take a look
of the image processor block
and you could also use V Image
that we have on the system.
So first things first.
We're going to get some
So from the
the base address,
that we use 8-bit
And then we'll get
which is where we're going
as float, because we specified
that we wanted to
The next thing we do
with the relative offsets of
It's highly likely that
with an input image that
or at least not equivalent
so you have to take care of
when you're creating your output
And in this case,
out whatever offsets
and execute our four-loop to
at location i, j by using
plus whatever offset we had.
Now that we've seen how to do
let's take a look at how
In this case we're going to be
And there's a great
of Metal Performance Shaders
to compute integral images
From our CIImageProcessorOutput
the Metal command buffer, so we
with that commandBuffer.
Once again we take care of
to deal with, and then we
to the commandBuffer,
as input the input
from the CIImageProcessorInput,
and as a destination
And this is how we can use
of an existing CIFilter graph.
So now let's take a look
with this integral image
So let's say we start
Our goal is going to be
where we have a per
So each pixel in that image
of blur applied to it,
and we can do this really
So, as I was saying, box
for doing very fast box sums.
So if we start right off with
to get the sum of those nine
this would require nine reads,
which means it's an
That's obviously not
That's not completely true.
If you were a little
you could probably do this as
in two n reads, but that
at six reads, and obviously
With an integral image,
if we want to get the sum of
to read at a few locations.
We will read at the lower right
from just one pixel off to the
and subtract that from the
And then we read at a pixel
and subtract the row which
of all the pixels
But now you can see we've
corner with a 1 because we've
so we need to add it back in.
So what this means is we can
blur with just four reads.
And if we were to --
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
If we were to actually do the
that these numbers do add up.
So 2 plus 4 plus 6, et cetera,
as 66 minus 10 minus 13 plus 1.
Now let's jump back into
and see how we can
that we've computed
or using the Metal
and continue doing the work
of actually creating
So the first thing we're
to compute our lower left corner
and upper right corner
Those will tell us where we
We're then going to compute
and they're going to help us
should be, so how
that we're currently
We take our four
and then finally we do our
and multiply by what we've
amount of transparency
Now, this particular kernel
as an input radius, which
to call this on an
that same radius applied
but we can very simply go and
by passing in a mask image,
to determine how large
on a per pixel basis.
So we just pass in an additional
We read from it.
We take a look at what's in the
from any channel, and we then
So if we had a radius
that current pixel
it would give us
We can then take those
into the box blur kernel
And this is how we can very
blur using Metal
and the CIImageProcessor nodes.
One additional thing we haven't
that we now have some
on your CIKernels when you
we have this just one right
In this case we're
which is not really
but the key thing here is
like to write only
or two-channel data.
So if you wanted to do --
[ Applause ]
As some people have
to reduce your memory usage,
that you want a certain
in your graph that may
of the graph, which
when we're processing
All of our kernels
So one or more thing we need
to provide some sort
We can do this very simply
and then ask for
with a few parameters,
to determine how
and where it will be located.
And then we're going to be
which is going to
And then we ask for the
and we have a perfectly
So now let's take a look
like when running on device,
and this is recorded
If we start with our input
we can move it around.
It's all very interactive.
Change the radius, even
And then if we apply this
of our variable box
we then get this type of result.
And it's very interactive
because the integral image
and Core Image caches
So it literally, everything
is just involving four reads.
So it's superfast.
[ Applause ]
Some things to keep in mind.
When you're using
if the data that you
of your image processor
of the context current
to want to call
WorkingSpace(to, and then
Similarly, on the way out,
in a different color space,
you can call
ColorSpace(toWorking, and
Now that we've seen how to
and how to use it, let's
when we use the environment
which we use to get an idea
that we're trying to
So this is what it looks
like when you use the
TREE with the value
And this is read
And it can be quite verbose.
It starts off with our input
We then have our input image
which gets matched
And then here's our processor
and that hex value is the
And then both the processor
from the radialGradient get
And finally we do the color
So this is the original
to specify this effect, but it's
If we were to set the
TREE to 8, we can now see that
and the processing looks
We still, once again,
which lives on a
which means that it
of an intermediate buffer,
which is why the
but you should only use them
the effect that you're trying
that you have cannot
of the CIKernel language.
As you can see, the rest
of the processing all
So we have our variableBoxBlur
of the color matching, and
in a single pass.
So this is why there are always
And if you can write something
you should.
That may be a little
So we have an additional
when you're using CI PRINT
In this case we're
along with the graphviz option,
and we can see our
in perfectly with the
And we can also see that
So let's do a little recap
We saw, David showed us how
Then Etienne spoke to us
about how you can edit Live
And then finally, we got to
on CIImage called
to specify an output
to help reduce the memory usage.
For additional information
visit developer.apple.com.
There are a few related sessions
especially if you're planning
There's Advances
that Etienne mentioned as well.
There's also a talk later on
that's taking place right here.
And on that note, I would like
I hope you enjoy
[ Applause ]