[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
How many of you have apps
on apps that play video?
That's quite a few of you.
Good. Whether for sports, news,
What's the most important
Is it the Play/Pause control?
The scrubbing?
Maybe the audio and
No. Of course not.
It's the video presentation.
So it's important when users
and watching your video
on your video presentation.
And they aren't distracted
out your user interface.
That's why it's important
consistent and predictable
between apps on their Apple TV.
Video playback on Apple
but it's no easy task.
There are many different
including the buttons and touch
Siri voice commands, older Apple
Bluetooth keyboards, game
infrared universal remotes.
Wouldn't it be great if you
I'm Dan Wright and
about how you can accomplish
AVKit provides modern playback
with a consistent
Let's take a quick look at some
Here is AVKit playing a video
with a transport bar visible
the position in the video
Touching the surface of
And clicking on the edges
Or by holding down
viewers can fast
And when paused,
on the remote will scrub quickly
Swiping down reveals info panel,
about the video and navigation
to settings related to
Finally, AVKit supports Siri
And as I go back
or "What did she say?"
to skip back 30 seconds
with captions turned
AVKit uses the modern
the same as on iOS and macOS.
AVKit provides the
AVFoundation and CoreMedia
And UIKit or on macOS AppKit
Today we're going to
First, we'll show you how easy
Second, we'll look at several
of the ways you can extend
with features unique to tvOS.
And third, we'll talk
All right, let's get started.
Let's talk about
AVPlayerViewController uses
and AVAsset provided
The AVAsset represents
AVPlayerItem represents the
The AVPlayer controls playback.
And AVPlayerViewController
Let's look at how you'll
There are four steps.
First, create an
Second, create a
Third, create a player
And fourth, associate the player
Now, you can simplify
to create the player directly
to the player property of
All right.
Next, let's see how you can
First, you'll set up your
Next you're going to set the
We're setting the
but you should use
And third, add the view from
to your view.
And add the playerViewController
as a child view controller
Now, once you're ready
for interactive full-screen
you can just present
and it will automatically
from the inline playback
All right.
Let's talk about extending
AVKit for tvOS was introduced
with several enhancements.
Namely, the ability to add
Restrict playback interaction.
Provide informational metadata.
Navigation markers.
And identify interstitial
With tvOS 10, we will introduce
The ability to modify
and presents content proposals.
And now let's talk
Overlays are for logos and
The playback overlay view
but below the controls.
Views may be static or animated.
But views will not
Let's move on to
The requiresLinearPlayback
of the player view controller
when set to Play and Pause.
Things like fast forward,
chapter navigation and so on are
Typically you'll set it to true
of a particular section
for example ads or
The external metadata
or replaces information
Things like title, description,
PG-13 or R, that sort of
Let's go back to our screenshot
that showed the info
And I want to direct
to this top section right here.
This is where the informational
Now, in addition, it'll also be
Here we see the artwork,
like a still from the video.
We have the title.
We have the duration, which
a media content rating
Now, let's look at
to create external
And we will create a
to make it a little easier.
The first one called
and a value.
And it's going to
And so metadataItem has a
You really need to set three,
the identifier, and
the extended language tag.
Now, you see here I've set it
for undefined and it
So if you do not have a more
available, this is the version
If you don't have any
for example, is in English
then just use und so that users,
regardless of their
Now, artwork is a
The value of the artwork
image representation.
So it's raw data.
You can use PNG or JPEG.
You also need to set the data
of data you're providing.
And once again, you
and the extended language tag.
Now we're going to
We're going to create several
We create an array.
Then we're going to use our
a description and the poster
oh, and sorry, also the genre.
And then finally we're
to the external metadata
All right.
Back to our info panel.
Now we're going to look down
This is the navigation section.
And this is displaying a
Navigation markers most
But they allow for easy access
to different parts
Navigation marker groups
Examples of events would be
in a sports video you might have
A navigation marker group
of class
And it contains an array
in this case chapters.
Every marker has a title.
And in most cases
usually a thumbnail
But that's optional.
An event group itself also has a
All right.
Another little helper function,
This takes a title, a
Now, the time range is the
that you're navigating to.
However, the duration
If you don't really care to set
Here again, we're
In this case, for a
And then finally we're going to
with our metadata
All right.
Now let's talk about
Here we see a video with several
by the dots on the
The user is watching
And the time above the
down the time remaining.
The time below is the
Interstitial content is content
that is unrelated
So for example, advertisements,
other things like that.
An interstitial time range
of an asset that contains
And interstitial
The dots on the transfer bar
in the previous slide.
And finally, during scrubbing,
So the user just is navigating
and they're not getting
by ads popping ups
Now here we have a diagram
of your asset on the top
by the user on the bottom.
We have a nine minute asset
both of which are going
And you'll notice
on the transfer bar has
or rather the duration
Now let's look at creating and
First, on your server you should
directly into your HLS asset.
Then, in your client app,
you will declare the
And implement a few
to enforce playback policy.
Here's a short snippet
to declare the interstitial
For each interstitial create
Then set the
of your player item
In this case we're just
time range.
Next, the delegate methods.
There are three important
The first is willPresent.
willPresent is called when one
of your interstitials
Typically, this is
to change requiresLinearPlayback
So for example, if this
you probably need, for
to require the user to watch
they start.
You set it to true.
Then they can't skip out.
They could still pause,
or something and come back.
But they can't navigate,
over it once they're inside.
didPresent is called at the
And usually you set
to False so that the users
And finally,
timeToSeekAfterUserNavigatedFrom
So this is called when the
that they want to navigate to
For example, they
They scrub and hit Play again.
Or they use the navigation
to another part in your video.
The oldTime is the time
at just before they skipped.
The targetTime is the time
The time returned
where you want playback
So by default, if you didn't
it would resume at
AVKit would seek to the target
If you provide the start time
AVKit will automatically
Now, if you do redirect
unlike in our very simple sample
to save the target time.
And when your interstitial
seek back to the target time
so that the user can once
that they wanted to watch.
Now let's turn to
Here we see the skipping
And this is a new skipping
the skip by item indicator which
which is the skip forward
In tvOS 10 you can choose
between these two
If your app is displaying
or a TV show, it's probably
to navigate skip 10 seconds
to more easily find the scene
If you have a series
for example exercise videos,
to let users easily skip to the
or the previous video,
around a little bit
So, to accommodate that, you can
There are two skipping
The default, which
or minus 10 seconds,
And there are three properties
in the PlayerViewController
The skipping behavior
and disable the skip forward and
So let's look at
of skipping a few seconds.
First thing we're going
to set the three properties.
Select the new skipping
In this case we're just going
to always enable skip
I'm being a little lazy.
And then we're going to
Skip to next item,
to do is replace the current
And skip to previous item.
Same thing, but going backwards.
Okay. Now for a demo
I'd like to welcome
Jonathan.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
My name is Jonathan Long.
I work with Dan on
And today, we are going
to be demoing an app
I have the project
And this is the main
It is the subclass
And we have a reference to
We obtain this reference in
In addition, we also create
and an AVPlayer, which we assign
to the PlayerViewController's
I'll go ahead and
so we can see what
[ Music ]
So here's our
in full screen with all of the
If I swipe down to
you can see that
of interesting information here.
Most notably we are
So the first thing we're
to add some external metadata
so that info tab shows up.
Jumping back into Xcode, the
to do is we are going to
To do this we need to
add them to an array
to the
property.
I'll go ahead and add some
These probably look
as they are the same ones
that Dan showed you
The first creates and
setting the data
The second creates
for all other value types,
setting the extendedLanguageTag
Now, I have one more
that takes a dictionary
And it simply maps the key
to create AVMetadataItems
and returns an array
So now with these
we can set the
property to be our array
Cool. So we created
added them to an array,
to the
property.
So now let's move on and
I have some helper
The first creates an
with a title, a description
The second creates an
with a name and four
that represent different
So now with these functions,
I can set the
on the playerItem to be an array
We'll name this one
Cool. So we created an
with some time metadata
We added that to an array.
And then we assigned the array
to the navigationMarkerGroups
So, let's build and run
So here is our Player
And I can swipe down
And now we see in the
that we've specified as well
And if I select down
one of the navigation
we can skip to that
So with just a little
to add external metadata
to provide a rich user
Now I'll hand it back
about new APIs in
Dan.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jonathan.
All right.
Content proposals.
Content proposals are about
You may have seen Up
of your favorite apps such
When you reach the end
"The West Wing" you'll
up to watch the next
on until it's 3:00
Many apps implemented their
And then it was kind of tricky.
No more. With tvOS 10 AVKit
to present your own
We call these Content Proposals.
Here is one example
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Now, you have the entire
So you're not limited
This is just an example.
In the lower right
and some big buttons
Up here we have the
And here is the thumbnail
Now, a content proposal is
of class AVContentProposal.
This is basically
Now, there are several
I'm not going to spend a
But I want to highlight
The first is
This is the time within
that you want your proposal
So, if you specify the
as a shortcut, that means
at the very end of the video.
However, if you're presenting a
like that, you probably
that the user may not
And you may want to present
of those end credits, in
property accordingly.
Next automaticAcceptanceInterval
for your presentation.
You can say, for
Which means that if the user
they take no action
then the proposal will
and advanced.
If you don't set this, then your
until the user takes
Title and preview image
of information that you
You can, of course, provide
as you like: Description,
to set a user rating,
maybe additional suggestions
And finally, the way you
to set the next contentProposal
on the current playerItem.
So let's look at creating
Well, this is pretty easy.
We just create an instance
We're going to specify
for our
This means we want it to
This is a nice shortcut if you
For example, if your
And we're going to set the
In this case, our proposal
of a fictional TV show
In this case we're going set
of the content proposal, a URL.
And we're going to set it
for our own use later.
Now we assign the
which should show the proposal.
Naturally, this is
for Season 9, Episode 1.
And, once again, we've got three
shouldPresent is called
is to be presented to the user.
Now, you could take this
and prevent the proposal
But you can also use it as a
up to prepare for
And we'll show an example
didAccept is called when the
That means they want to watch
It will also be called
And didReject is called
that they want out
They want out of the video.
They want to get
Now finally, you will
by creating a custom subclass of
There are a few interesting
Let's look at two,
preferredPlayerViewFrame
where you want the video to
Now, the base class
of the entire screen, in which
to fill the screen.
And your presentation controls
However, you can specify
maybe off to the side in
to give yourself lots of space,
with for your controls.
And dismissContentProposal
are dismissed.
You can specify one
Accept, Reject and Defer.
Defer means the user simply
get back to watching the
I don't know, maybe they
in the end credits if
And then as the name implies,
at the end of the video.
Now let's look at responding to
shouldPresent.
In this case, we're going
of our custom
subclass and assign it
to the
property
of the playerViewController
This lets us set that up
when we know we're going
and not allocate
that the user may never get to.
didAccept.
Here all we're going
to replace the current
with a proposed content
Pretty straightforward.
We've seen this code
You'll notice here I'm making
of the proposal that I set when
Now, if this is literally
you don't need to
Because AVKit, if you provide
AVKit will automatically do this
if you don't implement
All right, and now for a
Jonathan.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, again.
All right.
So, let's continue with
Up Next experience
by subclassing
So the first thing we
to create a custom subclass of
I have one right here
and add to our project.
So, this is our
It is a subclass of
And we have some
such as a UIImageView,
We override the
to return the CGRect that we
view to animate to when the
Now, the rest
of the viewController
of its view and subviews.
So we'll jump back into
So there's two more
First, we need to create an
and assign it
to the playerItem's next
So, here we are creating an
We have a transition time,
We're also setting the
to be 15 seconds.
In addition, we set the
on this content proposal that
that will be played if the user
Finally, we set the
as the next contentProposal
So the next thing we need to
to do, is implement two
delegate methods.
You can see here that we set the
to Self.
And the two methods that we need
to implement are
and didAccept.
So in shouldPresentProposal
of our custom subclass of
and we assign that as the
contentProposalViewController.
In addition we return
that the contentProposal
And finally, in didAccept,
we need to handle
to the next playerItem.
So, to do this, we get the
We create an AVPlayerItem
And then we simply replace the
And we're done.
So let's build and run
So I'll go ahead and skip closer
[ Music ]
And here is our contentProposal.
As you can see, the metadata
The preview image as
And if I select Play
to our next playerItem.
So I think if you
on tvOS 9 you'll be very happy
that it's much easier to use.
I'd like to invite
about some best practices
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Okay. Best practices.
I'm going to talk
Things to do and
First, some things that
Once again, present or present
zooming automatically
So there's no reason to
Second, remember Playback
when full screen.
Third, use the new
Some of you wrote it
And we encourage you to switch
I think you'll find your
It's easy to understand
And you may avoid some
that you may have
to work just perfectly before.
And observe the error property
This is how you find
that occur during playback.
And I'm going to talk about one
that you should handle.
But you should watch for
and respond appropriately
All right.
Now a few things to avoid.
Avoid toggling
This property is not
or hiding the controls.
This is for indicating
So when you set this to false,
you're saying we don't want
So if you toggle
what you're doing is
to destroy all the
Destroy them.
Recreate them.
And it's not very
Second, some people hate this,
but avoid adding supplemental
because it's going
People will not discover them.
And by the same token, do not
or touch service gestures.
Not only will that
but you'll likely
Now, some more general tips.
Replace your asset if
AVErrorMediaServicesWereReset.
If you don't respond to this
and the media services
video playback will fail.
And the user won't be able
to do anything except,
So what they'll have
go back to your menu
If you catch this error
and automatically replace
and your player, basically
then you can more
And the user will barely even
Now, some other sessions
for playback include this year,
Advances in AVFoundation
It was earlier this week.
You can catch the
And two years ago we had
Mastering Modern Media
for both AVKit and
to work well together.
So in summary, AVKit provides
and behaviors, support for
and Siri, full access to the
and it's easy to get started.
Be sure to check out the sample
And we're excited
So, for more information,
We'll have links to the sample
And check out some of
We also have on here the HTTP
earlier this week.
And a pair of sessions
which is an alternative approach
So, thank you.
[ Applause ]