[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
So, how many of you
with really cool audio
that that might be hard?
Or how many of you
on your application's overall
up spending a little
Well, we've been working
My name is Saleem.
I'm a Craftsman on
I want to welcome you
on delivering an
So let's look at an overview
We'll start with our
We have a wide variety
that let you simply
For more advanced use cases, we
And you may have
These are a fundamental
If you have to work with
we have our CoreMIDI framework.
For game development,
And over the last two years,
we've been adding many new
So you can see there
that you can use audio
So, our goal today
to choosing the right API
But don't worry, we also
to share with you as well.
So, on the agenda
at some essential setup steps
Then, we'll dive straight into
and recording scenarios.
We'll talk a bit about
And then later in
we'll look at real-time audio --
how you can build your
and generators -- and then
So, let's get started.
iOS, watchOS, and tvOS all
and numerous writing
So users can make calls,
work with various
And they can do all of this
So the operating system manages
in order to provide a
So let's look at a diagram
managed service.
So you have your device,
of inputs and outputs.
And then there's the
It may be hosting many apps,
And lastly, there's
So AVAudioSession is your
for expressing your
Let's go into a bit
Categories express
highest-level needs.
We have modes and
which help you further customize
If you're into some
such as input selection,
to choose the front microphone
on your iPhone instead
If you're working with
and multichannel content on
in things like channel count.
If you had a USB audio device
you may be interested in
So when your application
to use audio, it informs the
So this will configure
for your application's needs
in interrupting other audio
mixing with them, and/or
So let's look at some
when working with
The first step is to sign
And the three most important
interruption, route change,
and mediaServicesWereReset
You can sign up for these
activate your session.
And in a few slides, I'll show
Next, based on your
you'll want to set the
and options.
So, let's look at
Let's just say I was
And in that application, I
when the user saves
Here, we can see that audio
but it's not necessarily
So, in this case, I'd want
This category obeys
It does not play audio
and it'll always
If I was building a podcast app,
I'd want to use the
the SpokenAudio mode.
And here, we can see that this
other applications
Now if you want your
in the background,
to specify the background
And this is essentially a
It's just expressed
For your navigation app,
let's look at how you can
Here, you'd want to use
the DefaultMode.
And there are a few
You'd want to use both
AndMixWithOthers as
So, if you're listening to
and that navigation prompt
turn left in 500 feet,"
it'll actually interrupt
If you're listening to music,
it'll duck the music's volume
For this application,
to use a background
So, next, let's look at how
of our session.
So what does it mean
Activating your session
to configure the hardware
So let's say, for example,
I had an application
to PlayAndRecord.
When I active my session,
to use input and output.
Now, what happens if I activate
to music from the music app?
Here, we can see that
of the system is set
So, when I activate my
to configure the hardware
And since I'm in a
I've interrupted the music app.
So let's just say my application
Once I'm done, I
And if I choose to notify others
that I've deactivated
we'll see that the music
Next, let's look at how we can
signed up for.
We'll first look at the
and we'll examine a case
where your application
The first thing I do is I
And if it's the beginning
your session is already
So your players have been
to update any internal
When you receive the end
and activate your session,
and update your internal state.
Now, let's see how that differs
for an application
So when you receive the
again, your session
you update the internal state,
So if you have a Play/Pause
and set that to "play"
And now when you receive the end
and see if the shouldResume
If that was passed in,
and activate your
and update your internal
If it wasn't passed
until the user explicitly
It's important to
unmatched interruptions.
So, not every begin interruption
And an example of this are
that interrupt each other.
Now, let's look at how we
Route changes happen for
the connected devices
a category may have changed,
you may have selected a
So, the first thing you do is
If you receive a reason that
in your media-playback
and stop playback at this time.
An example of this is if
to the headsets and they
They don't expect that
through the speakers right away.
For more advanced use cases,
if you receive the
or newDeviceAvailable
to re-evaluate certain
as it applies to
Lastly, let's look at how we
where we set the notification.
This notification is
because demons aren't
The important thing
that your AVAudioSession
You will need to reset your
You'll also need to destroy and
such as your AVAudioEngine,
and other player
And we provide a means for
to Settings, Developer,
OK, so that just recaps
with AVAudioSession --
You sign up for notifications.
You set the appropriate
You manage activation
And you handle the
So let's look at some
New this year, we're adding
allowAirPlay and
to the PlayAndRecord category.
So, that means that you can now
to a Bluetooth and
So if this is your
and set the category
and then let the
from either an MPVolumeView
We're also adding a new
on our
that'll determine whether
or not the current
processing enabled.
So if your user is
or a Bluetooth HFP headset that
you can use this property
to disable your software
so you're not double-processing
If you're already using Apple's
unit, you don't have
And new this year, we
CallKit framework.
So, to see how you can enhance
we had a session
And if you missed that, you can
So that's just an
We've covered a lot
in previous sessions.
So we encourage you
as well as a programming
So, moving on.
So you set up AVAudioSession
if it's applicable
Now, let's look at how
and record audio in
We'll start with the
There are a number of classes
We have our AVAudioPlayer,
AVAudioRecorder,
AVAudioPlayer is the simplest
We support a wide
We provide all the basic
We also support some
such as setting volume level.
You get metering on
You can loop your playback,
work with stereo panning.
If you're on iOS or
with channel assignments.
If you had multiple files
you can use multiple
and you can synchronize
And new this year, we're adding
to volume level over
So let's look at a code example
of how you can use AVAudioPlayer
Let's just say I was working
and building a simple
where I want to play an
when the user saves
In this case, I have an
to my asset in my class.
Now in my setup function,
and I create the AVAudioPlayer
of my URL and I prepare
And then, in my saveDocument
to see whether or not the
And if it was, then I
Really easy.
Now, let's look at
This is the simplest way
You can record for a specified
until the user explicitly stops.
You get metering on
and we support a wide
So, to set up a format,
we use the Recorder
And now this is a
a list of keys that let you
such as sample rate,
If you're working with Linear
like the bit depth
If you're working with encoded
such as quality and bit rate.
So, let's look at a code example
of how you can use
So the first thing I do is
Here, I'm creating an AAC file
And then the next thing I do --
I go ahead and create my
with a URL to the file location
and the format settings
And in this example, I have a
to toggle the state
So when I press the button,
I go ahead and stop recording.
else -- I start my recording.
And I can use the
to provide feedback to the UI.
Lastly, let's look at AVPlayer.
AVPlayer works not
but streaming content as well.
You have all the standard
We also provide built-in
that you can use directly,
and the AVPlayerViewController.
And AVPlayer also works
And this year, we added a number
So if you want to find out
out the Advances in
And if you missed that, you can
OK, so what we've seen so far is
of playback and recording.
So now let's look at some
Advanced use cases include
but working with buffers
You may be interested in
applying certain effects
and mixing together
Or you may be interested
So, some examples of this
karaoke app, you want
with really amazing effects,
and really immerse
So, for such advanced use
in AVFoundation called
AVAudioEngine is a powerful,
feature-rich Objective-C
It's a real-time audio system,
with real-time audio
by providing a non-real-time
So this has a lot of
with real-time audio,
and it makes your code
The Engine manages
and these nodes let you
You can connect these
to form many different
and perform mixing.
You can capture audio
in the processing chain as well.
And we provide a special node
that lets you spatialize
So, let's look
at the fundamental building
We have three types of nodes.
We have source nodes, which
So these could be
an InputNode, or a sampler unit.
We have processing nodes that
So these could be
distortions, and mixers.
And we have the destination
which is the termination
and it's connected directly
So let's look at a sample setup.
Let's just say I'm building
In this case, I have
I'm using the InputNode to
I'm using a PlayerNode
I'm using another PlayerNode
and feedback used to the user.
In terms of processing nodes,
I may want to apply a specific
And then I'm going
to mix all three sources
And then the single
through the OutputNode and then
I can also capture the user's
to see how well they're
by installing a TapBlock.
And then based on that,
I can unconditionally
to be played out.
So let's now look at
The main node of interest
which simulates a 3D space
and spatializes its
In this example, I'm using
as a PlayerNode as my source.
And you can also adjust
on your sources as well,
And in terms of the
you can also adjust
such as the listenerPosition as
So this 3D Space can then be
and then played through
So before we move any
I want to look at some
that the Engine uses
I'll first start
So, AVAudioFormat
in an audio file or stream.
So we have our standard
as well as compressed formats.
This class also contains
which you may use when dealing
It's a modern interface
to our
structure and our
Now, let's look at
This class has two subclasses.
It has the AVAudioPCMBuffer,
And it has the
which is used for holding
Both of these classes
to our AudioBufferList and our
Let's look at AVAudioFile.
This class lets you read and
It lets you read data into
into a file from PCM buffers.
And in doing so,
it transparently handles
And it supersedes now our
Lastly, let's look
This class handles
So, you can convert between one
You can also convert between
in which it handles the
And this class supersedes
And new this year, we've also
rate converter algorithm.
So you can see that all these
together when interfacing
Now, let's look at how
with AVAudioEngine.
So if you look at
and output AVAudio formats.
If you look at the PlayerNode,
from an AVAudioFile or
When you install a NodeTap, the
in the form of PCM buffers.
You can do analysis with
to a file using an AVAudio file.
If you're working with
you can break it down
use an AVAudioConverter to
and then provide it to the
So, new this year,
of AVAudioEngine to the Watch.
Along with that, we're including
as well as all the core
So I'm sure you'd love
So we have that for you.
We built a simple game
and AVAudioEngine directly.
And in this game, what I'm doing
into space.
And at the bottom of the
And I can control the flame
And now if the asteroid
it plays this really
So, let's see this.
[ Explosions ]
I'm sure this game, like,
because it's playing
Right? And that's not possible.
[ Applause ]
All right, so let me just go
over quickly the
So, in my class, I
And I have two PlayerNodes --
one for playing the
and one for playing
I also have URLs
And in this example,
to provide data to the engine.
So, let's look at how
The first thing I
and I attach my PlayerNodes.
So I touch the explosionPlayer
Next, I'm going to
I'm going to create an AVAudio
And then, I'm going to
And I'm going to read the data
from the file into
And I can do this because my
Next, I'll go ahead and
between the source nodes
So, when the game is
and I start my engine
And when I launch an asteroid, I
to be played on the
And when the asteroid makes
I simply schedule the
on the explosionPlayer.
So, with a few lines of code,
I'm able to build a really
for my games on watchOS.
And that was a simple
to see what you come up with.
So, before I wrap up with
about multichannel audio
and specifically how
So, last October, we
with the 4th generation
And so this is the first time
And one of the interesting
on Apple TV is that many
to multichannel hardware
since many home theater
or 7.1 surround sound systems.
So, today, I just want to go
over how you can render
using AVAudioEngine.
So, first, let's review the
I first set my category
and then I activate my session
for my application's needs.
Now, depending on the
I'll first need to check and see
if the current route
And I can do that by
of channels are less
to the maximum number
And if it is, then
and set my preferred
I can then query back the
from the session and then
Optionally, I can
of ChannelDescriptions
And each ChannelDescription
and a channelNumber.
So I can use this information
and how I can map my content
Now, let's switch gears and
There are two use cases here.
The first use case is
if you already have
And the second use case is
and you want to spatialize it.
And this is typically
So, in the first use case,
and multichannel hardware.
I simply get the
I set that as my connection
between my Mixer
And on the source side, I get
that as my connection between
And here, the Mixer handles
Now, in the second use case, we
And we'll use the
to spatialize them.
So, like before, we get
But before we set the compatible
that the EnvironmentNode
And for a list of
you can check our
So, I set the compatible format.
And now on the source side, like
and I set that as my
and the EnvironmentNode.
Lastly, I'll also have
to set the multichannel
to SoundField, which is
currently supports.
And at this point, I can start
and then adjust all the
that we support.
So, just a recap.
AVAudioEngine is a
It simplifies working
It enables you to work with
And now, you can build games
with really rich audio
And it supersedes our
So we've talked a bit about the
so we encourage you to
And at this point, I'd like to
Doug, to keep it
Doug?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Saleem.
So, I'd like to continue
through the audio APIs here.
We talked about real-time audio
Saleem emphasized that,
while the audio processing is
we're controlling it from
And that's the essence
But there are times when
in that real-time
So I'd like to go
So, what is real-time audio?
The use cases where
in real-time are
Possibly the oldest
with on our platforms is
For example, you may
when the user presses a
And we want to minimize
that MIDI note was struck
And so we have real-time audio
We want to minimize the time it
of the guitar comes
through which we process it,
and then send it back
So we need low latency there
so that the instrument,
Telephony is also characterized
We've all been on phone calls
and had very long delay times.
It's no good in telephony.
We do a lot of signal
We need to keep the
Also, in game engines, we
The user is doing things --
interacting with
We want to produce those
Sometimes, we want to
as they're being rendered.
Or maybe we just have
In all these cases, we have a
in a real-time context.
In this real-time context,
our constraint is that we're
Right? Every some-number
the system is waking us up,
for that equally-small
And we either accomplish it
Or if we fail, if we take too
we create a gap in the output.
And the user hears
And this is a very small
to create our audio in.
Our deadlines are typically
And 20 milliseconds,
is still a pretty
So, in this environment, we have
to be really careful
We can't really block.
We can't allocate memory.
We can't use mutexes.
We can't access the
We can't log.
We can't even call
because it allocates
And we have to be careful not
and Swift runtimes because they
There are cases when they,
So that's a partial list.
There other things we can't do.
The primary thing
"Does this thing I'm doing
And if the answer is yes,
Well, what can we do?
I'll show you an example
But, first, I'd like
about how we manage this problem
of packaging real-time
And we do this with an API
So this is a way
and for you, for that matter,
to package your signal
that can be reused in
And it also provides an API
and interactions between
and your real-time
So, as an app developer,
That means you can let
or you can simply
to system built-in units.
You can also build
You can build them as app
And you can also simply
to your application.
And this is useful, for example,
of signal processing
in the context of AVAudioEngine.
So, underneath Audio Units,
we have an even more
which we call Audio Components.
So this is a set of APIs in
The framework maintains
of the components on the system.
Every component has a type,
These are 4-character codes.
And those serve as the key
for discovering them
And there are a number
of Audio Components types.
The two main categories
and Audio Codecs.
But amongst the Audio Units,
generators, effects,
converters, mixers as well.
And amongst codecs, we
We also have audio file
Getting into the
there are a number
that components are implemented.
Some of them you'll need to know
And others, it's
The most highly-recommended
if it's an Audio Unit is
to create an Audio Unit
We introduced this last year
So those are app extensions.
Before that, Audio Units were
as were audio codecs, et cetera.
That goes back to
Interestingly enough,
audio components also include
Node applications
with a component subtype
And host applications
through the Audio
And finally, you can register
you can register your own
of your own application.
And just for completeness,
there are some Apple
On iOS, they're linked
So those are the flavors of
Now I'd like to focus in on just
the audio input/output unit.
This is and Audio Unit.
And it's probably the one
if you don't use any other.
And the reason is that this
to the system's basic
Now, on macOS, that basic path
We call it the Audio HAL,
and it's a pretty
It makes its clients deal with
on multichannel devices
So, it's much easier to deal
through an audio
On iOS, you don't
to the Core Audio framework.
It's not public there.
You have to use an
as your lowest-level way to get
And our preferred interface now
for audio input/output
and the AudioToolbox framework.
If you've been working
you're familiar with version
of the system AUHAL on the macOS
as Watch -- actually, I'm not
But in any case, AUAudioUnit
to this low-level I/O mechanism.
So I'd like to show
like to use AUAudioUnit
So I've written a simple
that generates a square wave.
And here's my signal processing.
I mentioned earlier I
of things you can do here.
So this wave generator
You can basically read memory,
And that's all that's
It's making the simplest of all
at least simplest from a
So that class is called
And let's see how to play
from an AUAudioUnit.
So the first thing we
component description.
And this tells us which
The type is output.
The subtype is something I chose
either RemoteIO or HalOutput.
We've got the Apple manufacturer
Then I can create my AUAudioUnit
So I'll get that
And now it's open and I
So the first thing I
out how many channels of
There are ways to do this
But most simply and portably,
you can simply query
of the input/output unit.
And outputBus[0] is the
So I'm going to fetch
and that's my hardware format.
Now this hardware format
It may be inertly for example.
And I don't know that I
So I'm just going to
That is a standard format
And some number of channels.
Just to keep things short
to render two channels,
regardless of the
So that's my renderFormat.
Now, I can tell the I/O unit,
to give you on inputBus[0]."
So, having done this, the unit
to the hardwareFormat.
And in this case, on my MacBook,
it's going to take this
and convert it to interleaved
OK. So, next, I'm going
to create my square
If you're a music and
you know that A440 is
by 1.5 will give you
So I'm going to render
and E to my right channel.
And here's the code that will
There's a lot of
and I actually only
I only need the frameCount
The rawBufferList is a
which I can rewrap in Swift
And this takes the
and makes it look something
So having converted
to the nice Swift wrapper,
And if I got at least
then I can render
If I got at least two buffers,
And that's all the work
Of course, there's more work
but that's all of the
So, now, I'm all setup.
I'm ready to render.
So I'm going to tell
"Do any allocations you need
Then, I can have it
run for 3 seconds, and stop.
And that's the end of
[ Monotone ]
So, that's AUAudioUnit.
I'd like to turn next briefly to
We have effects which take audio
Instruments which take something
and also produce audio output.
And generators which
without anything going in except
If I were to repackage my square
I would make it a generator.
So to host these
you can also use AUAudioUnit.
You can use a separate block
It's very similar to the
that you saw on the I/O unit.
You can chain together
to create your own
You can control the units
And also, many units,
have nice user interfaces.
As a hosting application,
that audio unit's view,
and let the user
Now if you'd like to
the way I would start
within the context of an app.
This lets you debug
about inter-process
It's all in one process.
So, you start by
You register it as a component
of AUAudioUnit.
Then, you can debug it.
And once you've done that --
and if you decide you'd
as an Audio Unit extension --
you can take that same
You might fine-tune and
But then you have to do a
to package this as an
So you've got an extension.
You can embed it
You can sell that
So I'd like to have
now show you some of the power
We've had some developers
with it in the last year.
&gt;&gt; How is everybody doing?
Happy to be at WWDC?
[ Applause ]
Let's make some noise.
I'm going to start here by
I have my instrument here.
This is my iPad Pro.
And I'm going to start by
a very powerful synthesizer
And I have a synth trumpet
[ Music ]
So I like this sound
in a track that I'm working on.
This is going to serve as our
And now I'm going to launch
to serve as our Audio
Now, in GarageBand, I have a
on that I'm calling WWDC Demo.
Let's listen to it.
[ Music ]
Well move into what I call
And next, we're going to
This is supposed to be
I want some motion.
I want some tension.
And let's create that by
I'm going to add
Adding an instrument, I'll see
If I select this, then I can
that are hosted here
Right now, I see Arturia iSEM
Selecting iSEM, GarageBand
to give me an onscreen MIDI
It's complete with the scale
that I'm going to make use of
Over here on the left, you
You can even modify
And here is the view that the
that I can actually tweak.
For now, I'm going to record
and see what it sounds
So --
[ Music ]
All right, pretty good.
Let's see what it
[ Music ]
There we go.
That's the tension that I want.
Now, let me dig in
and show you what I've done.
I'm going to edit here.
And I'll look into this
There are two observations
The first one is that
The difference between
and using Audio Units
as a plug-in is you'll
which is much easier
The other observation I'd
that you see these
but you saw me play one
So, it's because
of the arpeggiator that's
that I've got these
And I can play around
and make them sound
But I'm happy with this
The last thing that I'd actually
I'm going to copy this
And I told you earlier that the
here is actually interactive.
It's not just a pretty picture.
So if you were adventurous,
to give a little
[ Music ]
Turn it up a little bit.
Let's wrap it up.
[ Music ]
That concludes my demo.
[ Applause ]
I want to thank you for
and always for making dope apps.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Torrey.
So, just to recap here, you can
about Audio Unit extensions.
It goes into a lot more detail
We just wanted to show you here
with it because it's so cool.
So, speaking of MIDI, we saw
performance as MIDI.
We have a number of
that communicate using MIDI,
which ones to use when.
So I'd like to try to help
Now, you might just have a
well, an ugly cellphone
But MIDI files are very
I can get a MIDI file of
I can see what all
So if you have a MIDI
with AVAudioSequencer.
And that will play it back into
If you wish to control
as we saw GarageBand doing
that with is AUAudioUnit.
And if you'd like your
into your AVAudioEngine, you
Now there's the core
which people often
of these other higher-level
But it's actually a very
for communicating
for example, an external
or a Bluetooth MIDI keyboard.
We also supply a
You can use that to send raw
and a MacBook for example.
You can also use the core
between processes in real time.
Now this gets into a
People wonder, "Well, should
between my sequencer and
to MIDI and synthesizing?"
And I would say that's probably
If you're using MIDI
I would use AUAudioUnit.
It's in the case where
in two applications
within an application --
from another developer.
In those situations, you can
or inter-entity real-time MIDI.
So that takes us to the end
of our grand tour
We started with applications
the CoreAudio framework
We looked at AVAudioEngine,
to get things setup on all of
We saw how you can
and the AVAudioRecorder
and recording from files.
Or if your files or network
you can use AVPlayer.
AVAudioEngine is a very
for building complex
and will solve a
You usually won't have to use
But if you do, we saw how in
that lets you communicate
and third-party, or
effects, and generators.
And finally, we took a quick
So that's the end
You can visit this link
We have a number of
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]