[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome to the
My name's Casey and today my
to show you how you can
and engaging articles for news
By the end of today's session,
you will have a detailed
of all the design capabilities
as well as an understanding
to construct those stories.
Believe it or not,
to identify some efficiencies
between your design
Dan's going to cover a variety
to create some beautiful
of magazine-type style,
like drop caps, side bars,
With the Apple News Format,
to look amazing on the iPad
and they will effortlessly
That's because the Apple News
It ensures that your stories are
So, obviously there's a
into here today, but first
that I give you a bit of context
around the News Application
And that's because
for how users are
and experience your stories.
News is a news aggregator
it comes preinstalled on the iOS
Okay. That's really
News aggregator.
I prefer to think of news as
News helps readers find stories
And that's really great news for
that they get to find new fans.
News makes its recommendations
that a reader chooses to follow.
And then it places
into the readers For You feed.
And that For You feed is
for users, and publishers alike.
As a reader, I can find anything
from CNN to craft beer.
Oh, this is Eddy's For You Feed,
so Formula 1 racing
At any case, the point
such a breadth of
And that breadth, it
that anybody can
You can publish today and
and begin earning revenue.
And you can do that using
Including RSS, the News
and the Apple News Format.
If you haven't checked it
out the Getting Started
it was earlier this week.
It's available on video now.
That session reviews all
This section focuses just
And that's because the Apple
for any number of things
including HAN authoring
maybe creating a translation
so that you can programmatically
and stories from your CMS to
Or, even for contributing to
for platforms, like
Knowing the Apple News Format is
And, it's just JSON.
The Apple News Format uses
that are both performant
JSON is also really great for
and it allows us to have
And that extensible nature
of the Apple News
because it allows us to
without any additional
So I feel like we've given you
around News.
So now we can really jump
of the Apple News Format.
Here's Dan to take it away.
&gt;&gt; Thank you Casey.
So now that you have
in which these articles
and bolts of how you
with Apple News Format.
So what we're going to
to take this sample
to tear it down to the skeleton.
And then we're going
up so we understand
We're going to make
And then finally we're going
So here's our article skeleton.
Let's dig into some of
Our first property is title.
And this is a title as
who are browsing the feed.
Next, we have excerpt, our
And this is the snippet
with the title also in the feed.
And finally, you get to
using a thumbnail URL.
Now let's step back
about a few thumbnail
So first of all,
for thumbnails are JPEG and PNG.
Second, definitely send
We'll take care of
The pizel size is
If you go smaller than that your
So definitely sent us your best.
And we do have a few
of width height ratios.
So for thumbnail
at least as wide as 1 to 2.
But no wider than 3 to 1.
Moving on.
Our last piece on metadata
about today is cannonicalURL.
And this is simply a web
And if you have one, definitely
It's going to be really
shares your article to a friend
who doesn't have
Having that one version
on will make a much
So we talked about metadata.
Let's dive into the content.
So, content lives
in your article,
And, each of your pieces
by a JSON object which
Each one has a semantic
intro, byline, and body.
Choosing the most
for your content is
So we touched on semantics,
but what if you want
So this is where
And component textiles is
And we're going to
in three different layers.
So the first one we're
to make a default style, that's
for all of our text components.
Then, we're going to define a
that are going to
And finally we're going to
And this is for when you need
Okay, so here's our
And let's take a look at
First we have font name.
And one thing to keep in mind
declare your font is not
So keep two things in mind.
First of all, when referencing
by their postscript name,
And two, the fonts that you use
So, if you wanted to channel
skills, you could make the real
using these postscript names.
Next we have text color.
Text color takes a hex value.
You can use the shorter
Or if you need alpha, you can
Then we have font size.
And font size is
But we shorthand
Now, just because
don't think of this
The app's going to take your
at it on different devices, it's
to optimize legibility.
And that said, a good
to go below 16 points
On a similar note, line height's
And you want to define
to the font size you've
that ratio across devices.
And finally we have
So this is where you get
for any links that appear in
Here [inaudible]
but there's certainly
from adding an underline.
So now that we have
let's add our first
So this one has a special
It's called default body.
And this is going to lay
for any body component, with
We have ParagraphSpacingBefore
And as you would hope, they
But what does it mean
in a component based system.
So let's take a look at
And this one component actually
That's our first one.
And that's our second one.
And we divide them with two
And speaking of which,
format declaration.
In Apple News Format, you get
and markdown for
And in this case, we're taking
with this markdown
Whether you choose plain
you can use these
to effect the spacing
your component.
So now that we've seen how to
let's just quickly hammer
So for our heading up top,
so to give some breathing
Kicked up the size of the
lightened up the intro.
So, subtle changes
as well as for our
So now that we got
let's move onto something
Let's make our first
And we're going to take this
So, one thing to keep in mind
in three tiers, we've already
that we want for
in default and default body.
So with this third layer,
all we're going to do is define
And we're going to do that in
And inside of that you get to
for the first character
in the first paragraph
And the interesting thing here,
is this number of
This is where you get
of text your drop
And as you can see
with a very simple
So we made our style,
but because there's no
between this component textile
we need to call it out.
We do that by adding a textile
And naming the name of
In this case it's called
And once you do that,
on the right you can see we
So, stepping back, compared
at the beginning, now that
things are looking a lot better.
But it's a bit jumbled.
We definitely need
And this is where
So, component layout is our
we're adding.
And inside we can
which gives us the
and bottom margins
We also do a few more things,
And we have flag component
by adding a layout property.
Once we do that, we've got some
and topography, things
But, let's take advantage of
to add more control over
Let's add a divider.
And let's put it between
and the title of the article.
So, there's our divider.
And you can see we have some
We can change the
But, personally what I
here is what's happening
So take a look at the divider
and see how it extends
to the right side of the screen.
This is nothing that's
It's something that we're doing
We're using a special property
And you can see I've
which means just
and go all the way to the edge.
So now we've got
we've got component
Things are looking
you know, a text perspective.
Now it's time to
And, the best way to start
So, got my photo component.
Below that I added
But, inside the footer
you might see this caption
to be sort of replicating
And what's really happening
as it will appear if
goes into full screen view,
This is also a critical
of accessibility, as the caption
to VoiceOver users.
Next, returning to our layout,
you can see that this
it's going all the way from
to the right side of the screen.
And again, this is not
to the photo component,
of the ignoreDocumentMargin
This time though, instead
I've given a value of true,
which just means
And then finally,
which points to the image asset.
And I'll step back and talk
for images that appear
So images can be referenced
just use the correct scheme.
Again, just like
definitely send us
We'll take care of down
For images inside the article
as well as GIF, and we
So, that's photo.
But what if you have
that all go together
This is where the gallery
And implementation
You simply specify
You feed it an array of images.
And what you get is a
where the user can engage
with the slide show
They can tap, go to
see the image specific captions.
And when they're done, the
Now, building on that we have an
called the mosaic gallery.
And this has the
except you switch the roll
and what you get is this
of your images that you
And best of all, users
into the gallery and get this
Next, we have social
Apple New Format has
of these including
and as you can see here Twitter.
And implementation is really
of the thing that
Next, getting into
we have support for Apple Maps.
And here's a really good example
of the Apple Maps feature.
Including one of these
to show your user a location
to get some context
So if you're adding all
and interesting content, you
to monetize your efforts and
So let's just touch real
that you can add ads into your
So first if you need control,
So you literally place these in
where you think it
to have an ad appear.
If you don't need that
the easier option is to use
And with this, all
to do is specify the frequency
to appear, and the app will
And so far what we have is a
for the phone, but what happens
So our mobile first
has left us with a few
We could be definitely making
And this is kind of like a
It would be nice to
to keep our readers engaged.
And, we have a really
especially when you put the
So the solution to all
in the Apple News
And this is really our
of the digital age, which is how
And of course there are
Notably, responsive design,
which you react to
There's mobile first design, in
as you gain more real estate.
And these are both tried
but making them actually
It's not easy.
And sometimes you end
up basically redesigning
for different situations.
And with Apple News
to design your article once.
But more than that,
for the richest experience.
We want you to focus on the
And we don't want you to get
and breakpoints because the app
that kind of scaling for you.
So how does it work?
Well, it starts with an iPad
Then what we're going
to as content creators is
Now, here I've divided it into
you get to choose how many
There's no hard and
just keep in mind the
the more complexity you're
So, once we've decided how
for our article, next we have
to assign some columns
So, in this example
of body content is consuming
And the caption on the
So then when we take that
at it on different
what we see is that the app
number of available columns
And then likewise,
is how intelligently
to adapt the components to
So as you can see like when
things get narrower,
where that wouldn't
everything falls back
So at this point,
to start doing some arithmetic.
Figuring out for such and
and such layout, what
That can get very complicated
That's really not in the
Because we want you to focus
on the visual effects
To help you do that, we
News Preview.
So as a designer, or developer,
to iterate quickly in your
and know they're
And that's where News
Because it allows you to
on how your articles
while you're messing
And best of all it
so you can see multiple devices,
multiple orientations
simultaneously while you work.
And it's available for
at developer.apple.com.
So, returning to our JSON,
of the column system, now let's
happen, in the article JSON.
So now we're going to go
we're going to look
at a top-level property
And this is your
It's got four properties.
And with these properties,
for a given width, say 1024,
I want to divide the
with a 20-point gutter
And then to the left
I'm going to have
And of course these
this is what was
Next, once we have
now we need to start
to our individual components.
And, because of the very obvious
we had with our body components,
So, we see here on our
we're using a layout
So let's take a look
And let's add two
Our first new property
And this simply says, going from
what's the first column that
I've chosen zero
Then we have columnSpan, which
to say how many columns in
And I've set it to 10, which
of columns in our document.
And you probably won't
that nothing changed
The default is for all
to the full-width
So let's make it
Let's implement a centered
That looks a lot better already.
So, what's going on here?
I've set it so that
that our body content
in our 10-column layout.
And of course if you start
from zero the third
And then I've reduced
so it only occupies six
And that looks pretty good.
But personally, I like a more
to go ahead and kick it
to occupy the first
Now, if we take this
to our other components,
starting to see our design
We switch the orientation
And we've retained that
that we had from the start.
So our one designed scaled
A piece of cake.
And now let's take that
So before we were talking
of a long block of
We can use some visual variety.
And of course the
to that problem is
So let's extract some text
and let's drop a pullquote in.
Next, let's use our component
and just like push it
So I chose a column start
to allow the pullquote to
And what you can see is
and then it sort of floated
which isn't quite the
So what we need is we need
between our pullquote
And fortunately, we have an
between the pullquote
from which it was extracted.
So, what we're going
to use something called
and we're going to anchor our
that contains the
out for the pullquote.
Step one in doing this is we're
to our body component
Then we're going to
to our pullquote component.
And inside of there, that's
out the identifier we just made.
And then we get to
to align these two things.
So in this case what
to align the top of our
to the top of our target,
And once we do that, we
We've got the pullquote
right next to it the most
that it could be near.
We have much more
But because we have an
between the pullquote
from which it was extracted,
we can actually take
and actually anchor
So this is going to
First what we're going to do is
and we're going to update it
so that it overlaps the body
And then we're going to
from which the pullquote
And once we do that, we get this
into the text pullquote look.
And then of course when
on other orientations
and devices it always
whether it's reducing the width,
falling back into a
So, at this point, things
We could probably call it
as a template for our content.
But if we look at the experience
so far, it's kind of
For instance, check out this
Now, watch how the body
up over the lead image.
And how as you get to each
as it gets to the view port.
It's a really cool effect,
so I think we can take
So let's add some
What we're going to do today is
of a really cool Apple News
scene animation.
So, step one in doing this,
and we're going to move it
so that it's the first
Now, next what we're
to do a little transformation.
We're going to take this photo.
We're going to change it
to being a background
So to do that first, we're
And we're using a semantic
called header.
Now, nothing actually changed
because we just have an
So for debugging purposes,
and add some height and
so we can see our container.
There. Now we've got
A few things to note
First of all, I added
with a new property
This allows us to find
And component styles
to some higher level
like background fills
The next interesting
that it actually
which is something I
On a technical level,
between defining things
out elsewhere as
It's really just a matter of
And then we have our height.
So I've manipulated the
with a property called
component layout.
And I gave it a value of 44vmax.
And what that means is we
at least 44 percent of
And this vmax unit is one of
that are available
So, now that we have our lovely
and switch it from
to being an image fill.
And doing this is
We just add a fill
And now that we have that,
And we've completed
we're a little be closer
Next step, we need to
And the way we're
by actually dividing our entire
semantic containers
So our first section is
where the animation
So I'm going to put our
And then everything else in
into our second section.
Now to make our scene
So, again, this is pretty easy.
You simply add a scene
And then you define what
And here, I'm using one
And what that means
to take our header container,
it's going to stick to
the rest of the article is
And then the background fill
Let's see it in action.
So here's our article.
User scrolls, and the text
and starts to fade away.
That's the gist of the effect,
but it's not quite
We have that naked text
and becoming illegible.
Not the effect I want.
Fortunately, the solution
All we need to do is
to our second section.
We're just going to let the
that white background
So again, let's see
So we still get our animation
but it's still legible.
Much better experience.
So now that we've
we need to pay a
to some design elements.
In our top of article experience
And the first issue I'd
that when we moved our photo,
suddenly the captions got
of things between it and
And there are a few different
The one I'm going to use today
and sort of kick it
So this has the effect of
with a clean vertical line.
But also, it makes our white
up top.
And then the next thing
to take advantage of the fact
with an image fill up top
And one of the coolest
to put things inside
Mainly text.
Meaning we can layer some
and add a much more interesting
So, I've taken our title and the
and I've put them into
which looks pretty cool,
of awkwardly floating up top.
It'd be nice if I could align
And I can, using another
So if you use an anchor
of a container, you get
of it relative to its container.
So in this case I'm using
at bottom.
And as you can see, my
of the header container.
And it looks a heck
So, we're really, really close.
We've got some interesting
we've got nice white
we've got good topography.
The last thing I want to
of article experience
to add some inline text styles.
So we're going to go one more
And we're going to add a
called textStyles.
And textStyles is similar
except that instead of styling
textStyles allows you to
of text and make two styles.
One for gray text,
And to apply these I'm
of a really cool
in Apple News Format.
So here's the two components
We've got our title component
And to apply my stiles, all I
to effect in square
that with the style I want
And once you do that, as you can
I've given some gray text
And then I've got a
for our first body component.
So, now I'm satisfied.
Ready to call our top of
There's just one more tweak I'd
like to make before I call
I want to add some
that are further
So, for instance the
It'd be cool if that
And it would also be cool
But as for the mosaic
I think it would be cool as
to them in the viewport.
So implementing this
Here's our pullquote.
And all I have to do to
animation property.
Inside I declare
I want a move in
With move in, I get to say from
I'm going to have it
Now, I'm going to
and apply it to our gallery.
Then I'm going to add
to the mosaic, and
And let's see it
So we've got our
here comes the pullquote.
Slide in. You can put
caption, fade, fade.
Looks a whole lot better.
With just a few animations
through the article more
And that seems like a
to end our crash course
on the finer points
So, we covered a lot.
We added some text
We saw how to make layouts
We used anchoring to make
And with just a few lines
of code we added some
Of course this is just the tip
to download the tools,
and play around with
We love to see what our
Back to Casey.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hey, Dan gave you
to the Apple News Format
and showed you how you can
to create stories that are going
I hope we've inspired you today
Check out the documentation,
earn revenue, help writers
to plugins for the platform.
This link will take you to
in order to have those
including your documentation
that Dan showed you today.
Be sure you check out that other
of our different ways that
And thank you for
It's been great having you
[ Applause ]