[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. I'm Henry Mason,
on speech recognition for Siri.
Today we're incredibly excited
which will let our speech
for your apps too.
A quick overview of what
Speech recognition is
of converting audio of
It depends on the
English will be recognized
than Chinese, for example.
On iOS, most people
but speech recognition is also
Since Siri was released
iOS has also featured
That little microphone
to your iOS keyboard spacebar
for any UI kit text input.
Tens of thousands of apps
In fact, about a third
from third party apps.
It's extremely easy to use.
It handles audio recording
It displays a user interface.
It doesn't require you to write
to support any text input.
And it's been available
But with its simplicity
It often doesn't make sense
to require a keyboard.
You can't control when the
There's no control over
It just happens to use the
There isn't even a way to know
if the dictation
The default audio recording
for your use case and you
than just text.
So now in iOS 10,
we're introducing a
It uses the same underlying
in Siri and Dictation.
It provides fast
which are transparently
without you having to
The framework also
about recognition
For example, we also provide
of what your users might
and timing information.
Audio for the API
from either pre-recorded files
or a live source
iOS 10 supports over 50
from Arabic to Vietnamese.
Any device which runs
The speech recognition API
on our big servers which
However, some newer devices do
the time.
We provide an availability
if a given language is
Use this rather than looking
for internet connectivity
Since speech recognition
audio over the internet,
the user must explicitly
to your application before
There are four major steps
to adopting speech
First, provide a
in your app's info.plist.
For example, your
might have used a
for speech recognition
to take a photo just
Second, request authorization
class method.
The explanation you provided
to the user in a
And the user will be able
to provide your app
Next create a speech
If you already have
use the
class.
Otherwise, you'll want
to use the SFSpeechAudioBuffer
Finally hand the
to an SFSpeech recognizer
You can optionally hold onto
which can useful for monitoring
and controlling recognition
Let's see what this
We'll assume we've already
with an accurate description
Our next step is to
It may be a good idea
until the user has invoked
which depends on
The request authorization class
handler which doesn't guarantee
Apps will typically want to
if they're going to do
or disable a user
If your authorization handler
you should be ready
If not, recognition won't
It's important to gracefully
when the user makes
or when the device is
from accessing speech
Authorization can
in the device's privacy
Let's see what it looks like
audio file.
We'll assume we already
Recognition requires
which only recognizes
The default initializer for
So it'll return nil if the
The default initializer uses
In this function, we'll just
While this speech
it may not be available,
to having no internet
Use the is available property on
Now we create a recognition
with the recorded
that to the recognition task
This method takes
with two optional
If result is nil, that
for some reason.
Check the error parameter
Otherwise, we can read the
by looking at results.
Note that the completion handler
as speech is recognized
You can tell the
by checking the is final
Here we'll just print the
Recognizing live audio from
similar but requires
We'll make an audio buffer
This allows us to
of in memory audio buffers
Here we'll use AVAudioEngine to
Then append them to the request.
Note that it's totally okay
to a recognition
and after starting recognition.
One difference here is that
value of the recognition
Instead we store it in
We'll see why in a moment.
When we're done recording,
that no more audio is coming so
Use the end audio
But what if the user
or the audio recording
In this case, we really
and we should free up any
by speech recognition.
Just cancel the recognition
we stored when we
This can also be done for
Now just a quick talk
We're making speech recognition
but we do have some
so that the service remains
Individual devices may
of recognitions that can
Apps may also be
on a request per day basis.
Like other service backed
be prepared to handle network
If you find that you're
throttling limits,
It's also important to be aware
that speech recognition can
of battery drain
For iOS 10 we're starting with
of about one minute
of keyboard dictation.
A few words about
and respecting your
If you're recording the user's
to make this crystal clear
Playing recording sounds and/or
indicator makes it
that they're being recorded.
Some speech is a bad
Passwords, health data,
and other sensitive
to speech recognition.
Displaying speech as it
and Dictation do can also help
is doing.
It can also be helpful for
when recognition errors occur.
So developers.
Your apps now have free access
to high performance speech
But it's important to
where it's not available
or the user doesn't
Transparency is the best policy.
Make it clear to the user
when speech recognition
We're incredibly excited
for speech recognition
For more information
check out this session's
You might also be interested
There's one on Wednesday and
on Thursday.
Thank you for your time