[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome
on Validating HTTP Live Streams.
My name is Eryk.
I'm a media engineer at Apple.
Let's get started.
What are we doing when
We're trying to ensure
At least in terms
Structural checks can't find
but it will eliminate
To be more precise, we first
to be properly formatted.
That is, is the software going
Second, we have some
For example, the HLS spec does
But we want to require them,
because they improve the
Third, we want these streams
to reflect established
Ultimately, this
of making sure the stream
So let's talk about the
The most important is the
If you've been working with
you've probably read this
It is an Internet
IETF, internet draft.
You can find it just
on the web for "draft pantos".
The first version was
We updated two or
It details the structure
What kinds of tags
And explains the
for the clients and the server.
More recently we
The HLS Authoring Specification.
This is available in
We first published it
For WWDC, we've updated it to
This document tries to cover
HLS content.
The requirements
in the authoring specification
Some echo requirements
For example, where
What your playlist
Some have to do with
For example, that all your
Or that you can't have more than
Others come from the
For example, the I-Frame
Or, the fact that we want
A number are informed
of our experience
I'm talking about the
around delivery.
The bitrates we recommend.
And our recommendations
The requirements I've listed
to give you a flavor of
The specification itself
Like video encoding.
Trick Play.
Media segmentation.
Delivery and so on.
Now of course we
to do this validation by hand.
So let's look at the
But first, you need
Everything important about
at the developer streaming page,
Now if we scroll
halfway down on the
to the "Tools" download.
Now please note you
in with a developer
in order to access this page.
But remember that
Now once you've done that, you
The download itself
which contains an
Now the screenshot here
You should see a newer disk
We do typically update the
Now by the way, if you are
the new version may not
After you've run the installer,
And I want to remind you that
The first two -- the
in the rest of this talk.
The next three tools are
streams, and subtitles.
And I wanted to mention
that the subtitle segmenter
up the large web VTTT into a
The last two tools, Variant
to create master playlists.
And the last one is used
that you can then insert
Now all of these tools
And you can pass any of these
But before we talk about
I want to make a short pitch
It's simple to call, you
It produces a media
While this tool has
it's not as complicated
The options break
Options having to do
With structuring playlists.
How to do encryption and so on.
Even if you don't use
the mediafilesegmenter
on whatever process
So on to validation.
Media stream validator
You can call it with
And it produces output on the
Now this json contains
in the output, and
A couple of options
First of all you
and the name of the json file.
And you can adjust the timeout.
Well, what's the timeout?
By default, the validator
That is, it stops
Now this may not be enough time
to process a big video
And for live content,
for your initial checks,
over a much longer
that the stream is
Here's what the media stream
So here we're calling media
And first it tells you
And then it outputs some trace
as it's downloading
And then it outputs information
and I-Frame variant
Now this can be hard to digest.
So we created HLS report.
This is a python script
and summarizes and condenses it.
And it produces an
The name of that file
of your json file, except
And again, there are some
We can change the
The dash I or dash ID option
to match HTML output to
And I'll give you some more
when I go through the examples.
Now the verbose option
that gives you a
about every variant
Unfortunately, I
into detail about that output.
But I wanted to call it out as
One quick aside here.
You should validate your
to the App Store.
And also, when you
you should include a test
so that the reviewers have a
I'd like to run some demos.
But rather than run all this
to follow along and
I've captured the output and
First, a little command
Run media stream validator.
And notice I'm giving the
And I've just got a fake URL
Now we've seen the output
But remember that this might
Now once it's completed,
Passing at the json that media
If HLS report works well,
Just the HTML file.
So if we look in our
we'll see there are
The json that media
And the HTML file that
So let's take a look at
First, I'm going to
that has several common errors.
This is what a report
The first thing you want to
Now usually, this is
These reflect a three kind --
basic kinds of streams
But you could get
And this means that we weren't
Or worse, you could
Now this can mean that
That is, that some of the media
Or worse, it could be that you
Like for example, some of your
and some claim to be LIVE.
Now the next item in the report
It has one entry for
Now if we happened to have
that will be an added
that indicates the
If we look over to the right,
we can see that there
And in particular, if
to have a percent
Now if this is less than 100%,
that means that the
Now if you have live content,
you won't see the
Instead you'll see two columns.
Average segment count, and
Now the next thing you want
to check is the percent
This shows you how much
than the value that was
Now these values
Notice that variant one has a --
of minus 10% to positive 10%.
If the value here is positive,
that means your declared
And if the value is negative,
your declared value should
Now notice we've
Because in our playlist we
and the average bandwidth.
We are able to compare
and measured values for both.
Now sometimes looking
of percentage can
to see what the real
So if you add the -- pl
to your HLS report command line,
Playlist rate.
And playlist average rate.
So with this, we can see that
the declared value is
But the measured value was
Now let's switch back to a
and scroll down a bit.
There's another table,
In this master playlist we have
That makes it a rendition,
Following this, we have
Now must fix issues are things
which are essential
Or things which we
that we made them
You see item #2 and #4 here are
The fact that the peak
that the declared and
Now item 3 we'll address
Scrolling down farther, we now
Should fix issues are things
which we strongly
Now these are followed lastly
The report information is
to which version of
and HLS report was used.
This is important if you
the output from HLS report.
Or if you're even going back
after you've downloaded a more
Now item 5 here is telling us
or subtitles in our playlist.
We'll fix this in
Let's look at item number 7.
So item number 7 says that our
what we suggest.
And it's telling us
So let's scroll back up
And we can see that item #8 has
That's how we can tell
Now remember the default
that the client's going
It's the first variant
And notice that this one, the
That's way too high
Okay. Those are some common
In our second example, we've
and fixed the problems
We've adjusted the
so now the percent
We've fixed the default variant
to be something more reasonable
by moving a different media
in the master playlist.
And if we look over on
we fixed our timeout, so
entire playlist.
Now we had a should fix
We fixed that by adding
Now notice as a subtitle's
doesn't have a max
That's because the subtitle
And we put an n/a over in
to remind us that
But we still have
and that's no I-Frame playlist.
So how does the report change
The first part looks the
Now, in addition to the
there's an I-Frame
Now notice we're a little off
on our percent difference
But these are well
Remember, that's +/- 10%.
Now let's talk about these
Scaled average and multiplier.
Scaled average is the affective
of the I-Frame playlist.
Yeah, that's kind of a mouthful.
Remember that the measured,
average bit rate
at a 1 X playback speed.
But the whole point of I-Frames
at greater than 1 X speed.
Now the multiplier tells
at which we will hit
Higher rates are
because we will drop
to keep the actual displayed
What you should do with these
average data rate here, against
that has the same resolution.
These should be close in value,
or the I-Frame variant
Otherwise, Trick Play could
Now in this report, I've
That's because I added the
Now as I mentioned before,
this helps you find the
So let's look for this
Which is our lowest
Let's look for that in the json.
So here's an abbreviated
The top level of the
And we're interested
Which is an array
Now one of those dictionaries
And I want to note here
that these are not
Now this one with data ID 16,
that's the json variant entry
in the report.
That is the lowest
Now, I've skipped
There's much more information
Use your favorite tool for
or write yourself some
Now, these json's
It's not uncommon for them to
For our last example,
and we added multiple
So the top looks pretty similar.
Let's scroll down and
Now, rather than just
we've added two multi-channel
One is AC-3 that
That one's called the aud2.
And one is EC-3,
One we call aud3.
So let's go up and look
Now, notice that because AC-3
and neither are they
each one has its
That is, once we
we will default to variant #12.
Because that variant is the
that appears in the
Similarly, if we chose EC-3, we
Now notice there's
between the aud2
For example, variant
This is due to the different
The bitrate you'll see here
for the variant is the
the renditions.
Okay. That's it for my examples.
Where can you find some
Well, there are three
of the streaming page.
If you go to
there's a pointer to
And you could dig the
Or, you could just read
The first two will have
That's because these streams
and we deliberately
But that third variant
and should be almost perfect.
All right, it's time to wrap up.
Here are the only three things I
Obey the authoring spec.
validate your streams.
And include a test stream
For more information,
and use this session's
There's a lot of cool
in HTTP live streaming.
So I encourage you to
What's New in HTTP
Thank you, and have