[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi and welcome
AVCapturePhotoOutput,
This is a chock talk
Advances in iOS Photography.
I'm Brad Ford.
I'm an engineer on the core
In session 501, we focused on AV
specifically the
which is a new interface
This output supports Capturing
Wide Color Content, and
If you haven't watched
I recommend pausing here and
You'll get a lot more
In this session, we'll move
basics and discuss two important
for in Session 501.
Namely, Scene Monitoring,
and Resource Preparation
Lastly, we'll spend a few
but still very important topic,
Camera Privacy Policy
By way of minimal review,
the new AVCapturePhotoOutput
that addresses some
of AVCaptureStillImangeOutput's
AVCapturePhotoOutput uses a
There are clear delineations
between mutable and
It uses a separate object
to encapsulate per
called AVCapturePhotoSettings.
You pass it when making
It uses a delegate
for tracking the progress
This is called the
protocol.
All callbacks in the delegate
of
This is an immutable object
in which all photo
AVCapturePhotoOutput also
a subset of these capture
Scene monitoring
that informs the user what
currently active.
In this screenshot of Apple's
in a low-light situation.
The flash iconography at the
that the user is
meaning the flash
if the situation requires it.
Apple's Camera app is a client
which performs Scene Monitoring
to drive the flash
that you see in the top middle.
The presence of the yellow
that if they take a picture
AVCapturePhotoOutput
for two kinds of scenes.
The first is the flash.
All of Apple's current
as well as the 9.7-inch iPad
to illuminate dark scenes for
and a retina flash that
into a true tone flash,
to three times normal
up selfies in low light.
The second type of supported
Image Stabilization.
Still Image Stabilization is
that blends differently
in low-light situations.
It might not be totally obvious
a low-light feature, it's not
that your hands shake
It's just that the camera
to gather the same number of
to be very, very steady.
Still Image Stabilization
by capturing multiple images
and then fusing them together
to reduce noise and
So at first glance,
or Still Image Stabilization
like orthogonal features,
but they're actually
And this causes some
Looking at this graph, we see
for Flash Capture with
and without Still
I've shortened Still
to SIS for brevity.
The blue bar represents
at which the photo
if you've opted in for SIS.
The green bar represents
for flash if you've
Note that with SIS on,
without the flash
This is because SIS lowers the
so the flash is not needed.
If your current scene's
the answer to the question,
is this a flash scene
But if the light level is
on whether you're interested in
and the inverse is true also.
So what to do.
The AVCapturePhotoOutput
of capture you want
But if you're using
it needs to run continuously.
Is the current scene a SIS
In AVCapturePhotoOutput we've
with a specific API for
photoSettingsForSceneMonitoring.
And we've provided two key
that can asynchronously
when scene suitability
to Still Image Stabilization
You create an
specifically for Scene
which features you'd
like AVCapturePhotoOutput
Here I've set the flash
that I'm interested in
when it's available,
isAutoStillImageStabilization
So SIS should be considered too.
SIS tends to give better image
so if a scene falls into the
and flash, the photoOutput
Next, I assign this object
for SceneMonitoring property.
This property can be set
at any time including
AVCaptureSession running.
To be informed of
and Still Image Stabilization
I add key value observers for
and
Properties.
And I'm called back as
for those two properties.
Now let's talk about
photoSettingsforSceneMonitoring
and its default value is nil,
meaning no scenes
If you query
or isFlashScene without first
for Scene Monitoring, they will
Once you do configure photo
you can query or key value
properties and get
Be aware, though that
for Scene Monitoring
isFlashScene will still
Ditto
for AutoStillImageStabilization
My recommendations for
If your app doesn't display
of scene the user is
to enable Scene Monitoring.
But if you do, monitor
For example, if you intend
but not SIS, then monitor
to auto and auto SIS off.
Doing otherwise will
as your UI might report
that it's not a flash scene
fire when taking a picture.
That wraps up Scene Monitoring.
On to our next Beyond
Resource Preparation
To understand the need for
let's look at AVCaptureSession's
When you call AVCaptureSession
data begins flowing from all
various AVCapture outputs.
Most outputs receive and handle
such as the VideoPreviewLayer,
which continuously displays
Or VideoDataOutput
to your app via delegate
Streaming outputs such as these
render pipeline rebuild if you
You have to configure
of output before you
AVCapturePhotoOutput
since it only receives data from
When you request a photo
with settings and delegate,
the photo output delivers just
Unlike the streaming outputs,
the photo output has
It's perfectly positioned to
on demand without causing a
of the render pipeline.
It has the luxury of preparing
Resource preparation
And AVCapturePhotoOutput's
Taking an uncompressed 420
of the AVCapture device
Processed output such as EGRA
or JPEG requires
since there's a format
Flash captures require their
for delivering the
and strobe synchronized result.
Still Image Stabilization
for fusion.
RAW capture requires
RAW + JPEG requires
of resources big and small.
And bracketed capture
to return multiple
And of course, many of
and matched, requiring
With so many capture features
for the AVCapturePhotoOutput
to guess how many
And both over-preparing and
We liken an over-preparing to
of the year, just in
It's a lot of effort for us.
A lot of material invested.
A lot of uneaten cake
Video preview might come
Memory consumption might
Under-preparing is just
If we're not ready
with your requested feature
while allocating
Fortunately, we've
AVCapturePhotoOutput allows you
of captures you're
You do this by calling
passing an array of
with each one representing a
like it to prepare for.
You can optionally pass a
when preparation is complete.
The photo output also
preparedPhotoSettingsArray
so you can query the settings
The
function can do several things.
It prepares resources for
in your array of settings.
Also, it reclaims unneeded
And by passing an empty array,
It calls you back when all
And it returns an error if
This is all delivered via
preparedPhotoSettingsArray's
constructor for
which has JPEG set
and AutoStillImageStabilization
preparedPhotoSettingsArray
It persists across
or stopRunning, begin
and you can set it and forget it
if you always take the same
Another nice feature of
that it participates
in AVCaptureSession
deferred work semantics.
That is, if you call
and then change your
or removing inputs or outputs
and then set new
and then commit the
won't occur until the
You can atomically change
and prepare your photo output
for the new configuration
You can prepare before running
that your app is ready
as video preview starts running.
If you call
when the session is stopped,
it doesn't call your completion
Instead, the handler is called
which is after you call
If your session is stopped
of settings and then you change
with another set of settings,
your first completion
with prepared set to false.
This is effectively
of the first preparation.
We have three simple
on how you should
Firstly, prepare.
You can always issue a capture
but if the photo output isn't
of capture you want,
that first image back slowly.
Second, prepare before calling
Knowing the kinds of
in lets the session allocate
for you during startup.
Third, re-prepare only
You don't need to re-prepare
just when you change the types
like when your user toggles RAW
on or off in your app.
Not all AVCapturePhotoOutput
for on-demand resource
The first of these is
Some camera formats allow you
to capture a high resolution
than the format's sustainable
For instance, the front camera's
and 6s Plus supports
but can only stream
When the camera is
it can either deliver
or 5 megapixel stills depending
on whether your photo settings
But if the camera
for 5 megapixel stills upfront,
so AVCapturePhotoOutput
for the feature before
by setting
to true.
Once you've opted in,
or without high res
without causing an
Similarly, LivePhotoCapture
asset as well as a still image.
The movie contains
1.5 seconds before
So the capture render pipeline
to do this special
Lastly, live photos
and automatically
if large purposeful
such as dropping one's arm
down to put the device
If you wish to capture full
you must opt-out of autoTrimming
on your AVCaptureSession.
Our last topic of the day is
in iOS 10.
Let's review Apple's Privacy
Photos and videos on a user's
private and sensitive data.
Use of the camera or microphone
that must be granted
So beginning in iOS 7,
users were notified the first
or microphone and given an
This is a very good thing.
Transparency and trust are well
of tapping okay.
In iOS 10, we're requiring
in transparency by informing
to access sensitive data.
Sometimes your UI makes it
Your reason string should
For instance, here AVCam is
to use the camera to
That's a pretty explicit
about what it will
Likewise, apps linked against
string for using the microphone.
And lastly, the Photos Library.
You should be clear in your
to the Photos Library.
Are you using it for
In the latest version of
of possible privacy description
mic and photos, but for
In order to use any
you must provide
If you don't, your app
to the desired service.
The three specific keys
about for Capture are
NSMicrophone3UsageDescription,
and
Let's summarize what
AVCapturePhotoOutput
of scene monitoring behavior.
It also allows on-demand
and reclamation.
And Capture clients must provide
and photos use as of iOS 10.
For more information, visit
in iOS Photography
And if you're still at the show,
of these related
with photography,
Thanks for watching and
Enjoy the rest of the show.