[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Welcome everyone to Go
In this session, we
about all the new features that
I am Ben Harry, a
on the Game Technologies
And later, you'll be
Now we know people love
and share those recordings
ReplayKit gives our
with little effort required
To get started today, I am going
about the existing features
ReplayKit provides the ability
to record your app's
In addition, you may
By doing so, your users can
playing their games.
After a user trays a recording,
they may share the
from their game using
ReplayKit has a simple API, and
a small amount of
to bring these features
Moving along, ReplayKit will
with little impact on
and uses a minimal amount of
Here at Apple, user privacy
so we have implemented
For example, we present a user
so user's can give permission
Furthermore, recording
including notifications.
Therefore, when you receive
playing a game, that message
Finally, ReplayKit was
So this is a list of
that we offer with ReplayKit.
Now, I am going to take a
that have been added
First up, we are bringing
So now, you'll be able
and share it directly
The next new feature we've
Now, users will be able
in real-time to third
And for our third and final
to record the Face Time camera.
In addition, we've
to the microphone recording API.
So before I get into
I'm going to take a minute
of the ReplayKit architecture.
I want to show you how your app
with the operating system
So here we have your
Your application needs to
when it wants to
So ReplayKit provides an
You will tell this class
At this moment, a message is
The Replay Daemon will start
to a movie file.
When you tell the
to stop recording, the Replay
movie, and now we have
Now this movie needs to get
so your users can preview
To do so, we provide the
You present this view
so now your users
where they can preview,
and they can share the
As we just saw, we have
This is the class you
stop and to discard recordings.
You will also use it to
to record on the device.
There is a delegate property
and it will notify you if the
Also it will let you know of
The second class I brought up
You present this view
to give your users ability to
and to share that recording
We also have a delegate
and this delegate will let you
with the preview user interface.
So this is the reflected
and the classes you will use
on both iOS and tvOS,
to ReplayKit and Apple TV.
And to begin I'm going
So here I have a
Fox was developed
It was developed using SceneKit.
You may also recognize it
as sample code on our
The goal of this game
and collect these flowers
I'm going to make my
and collect the flowers.
There's three on the
You can optionally collect
but I'm just going to
I got two.
I know the third flower is on
on the topo of the rock.
So I'm over here, so
I'm going to bring
because I want to record this.
There is an obstacle
and I've been practicing
so I wanted to share this
that I can get through
So I'm going to start
and here is the consent
And I am going to
So now I'm recording.
So notice the recording
at the top of the screen.
This lets me know that our
Okay, so I made it
So all I have to do now
to do the final flower,
and ultimately finish
Okay so that's it.
I'm going to stop my recording.
Now, once I'm stopped, I have
or share the video I
to start off by previewing.
So we have a video playback,
and we have a timeline we can
I'm just going to
Notice here that recording
in the recording.
I'm going to show you
in just a few minutes.
So I have a video, I'm happy
So now I want to share it.
So I'm going to go over
And now we are presented
So I'm going to grab my phone.
I'm going to select my phone.
Anyway, when I do accept
and the file is transferred,
I do have the ability where
I can edit and trim the
and finally I can share it to
So that was how ReplayKit
I now want to take a few moments
from the demo, and then I'm
that corresponds with each
So first I'm going to begin.
I'm going to have
where I started my recording.
Then we have the gameplay where
on screen, back to the game
and finally when I stop the
to preview or share
So I'm going to walk
and show you the code that
We began or start our recording.
So when I press my
first I'm going to grab
of the RPScreeningRecorder.
And I simply am going to
Now once I'm recording,
I'm going to present
As I mentioned in the video,
the indicator was not
This is because ReplayKit will
main window.
Therefore, I'm going to
And then the indicator view.
The indicator view will be
This is because now you can make
So we have an indicator view,
I'm going to instantiate an
and simply add it as a sub view
to the window I created above.
Now the indicator
and we know we're recording.
When we are done recording, we
Again, I'm going to
of the RPScreenRecorder.
Now notice we return the
which is the RPPreviewController
I'm going to hide
And here it's important that
of the preview view controller,
to present in the next
and sharing the video.
Finally I'm going
So we saw that we have
but we have two interfaces,
one for previewing,
So at Apple TV, we have
When we want a preview, we
and then present
Similarly, to share, we
We are going to set the
present the view controller.
Now we will be presented
In both cases, when the user
we have a delegate method
Preview Controller did finish.
It's important when this
that you dismiss the
since your app was
Finally, when we are done
that we no longer need
to discard that recording.
Now ReplayKit will automatically
when a new recording begins.
This is because one recording
You could also explicitly
when you know that the preview
For example, maybe at
there could be no
to present a preview.
So now you can explicitly
by calling RPScreenRecorder's
Through these last few slides,
of code that is required
to bring these features
I encourage you all to add
and also to your iOS apps, if
So now, let me take a minute
to summarize ReplayKit
Now, with ReplayKit
you can record your app
Under Apple TV, the microphone
so you cannot provide voice
But you can allow users
and they can share their videos
As you saw, we have
In fact, it's the same
All these features
to be available new in tvOS 10.
So that was ReplayKit
So now it's time to move on to
which I personally am
So, at this time, please welcome
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Alright, thanks guys.
Hey, how is everyone doing?
My name is Edwin Iskandar.
I am a Software Engineer
on the Game Technologies
And like Ben, I'm super
about our next feature,
So with Live Broadcast,
to broadcast gameplay to
directly from their
So this is really exciting,
that this will be possible
or third party SDKs, will
to take advantage of their
camera and microphone to
in real-time.
And finally, we are going to
that all audio and video data
and the broadcast service.
Alright, so to illustrate how
with flair games to implement
and the flagship
So it's a really awesome game.
It's available in
And it has this unique
RPG and action elements.
Okay, now that we have a
we also need somewhere
So we've also been working with
that specializes
Alright, so now that
and a service, we're
So let's see this in action.
Alright so in Olympus Rising,
the Flair developers have
to start broadcasting.
To initiate a broadcast,
and are pesented with
that they have pre-installed
In this particular example,
the user has installed
so it appears on this list.
So at this point, the user
and they are presented
to set up the broadcast.
The user then goes ahead and
and once they're done,
on the start broadcast button,
which then presents a countdown,
so that the player can get
And now that they're live,
video and audio data is streamed
Spectators all around the world
from their device, and watch
Within the Mob Crush app,
spectators can also discuss
And even cooler, broadcasters
when this happens while
So it's just like in sports,
there is something
about watching an event live.
Now, this will be
and tvOS games as well.
Alright so now that we've
as a game developer, you're
to implement this
Here is the player
As you can see, there
Initiating the broadcast,
setting up the broadcast,
and stopping the broadcast,
in progress, and also uploading
to the back-end servers.
So this might look a little
but the good news for
of these steps are
and the broadcast service.
So let's take a look at the
So to initiate a
we use a new class
ViewController, and
to get an instance of it.
We then simply present it as you
which will then present
of broadcast services, and
to set up the broadcast.
Just before we do that, though,
we also set the
delegate method.
Because we want to be notified
At this point, the user
to broadcast to, sets
and once we you done setting up,
the activity view controller's
and this delegate method
of another new class,
which allows us to
But before we do that,
to dismiss the
since we are the ones
Start our in game
and when the countdown
we finally start the broadcast
on the new RPBroadcastController
And now we are live.
And since we're live
we need to clearly
So Olympus Rising
by animating the
Since the game has
they're reusing the button
in progress broadcast,
maximizing the available
Something to note is that the
during broadcasting and will
before you add this
So programmatically check
simply query is broadcasting
of the broadcast controller.
You can use the value of
or stop animating
To allow users to
the Flair developers have
that reveals a sub menu
When the player presses
we simply call finish
When broadcasting is
Alright, now that we
let's look at a few more
So since there are a lot of
it's possible that
So it is important to
And so let's take a look at how
To handle errors,
to the broadcast controller.
Once set, your delegate
with error method called
you should let the
and update any necessary UI.
So now another detail
when the user backgrounds
or the app is interrupted
like when receiving a
So when the application
ReplayKit will automatically
So in this particular example,
when the application is
to the foreground, we prompt
like to resume the broadcast.
If the user wants
the resume broadcast
simply call the finish
And that's it.
For the entire flow, the game
with two classes,
RPBroadcastActivity
to present broadcast services,
up a broadcast, and
pause, resume and
As you can see, it couldn't
into your games, and
because the benefits are huge.
There is really no better
increase player engagement
and even build a
So that covers game
but what about the
that players are streaming
Let's take a moment
about what those services
So for all the game
or watching online, I just
that the topics discussed
in the next section are
to implement in your games.
So let's go back to
We've seen that the
for initiating the
when to start and
We have also seen that the UI
for broadcast selection
of by ReplayKit's
So this leaves us with
Setting up the broadcast, and
to the back-up servers.
So to allow broadcast services
we're introducing a new pair
of app extensions
A UI extension, to allow the
and a non-UI extension
and uploading the
For those of you
they're target embedded in your
to extend your app so that
other apps.
They run in a separate
but can share data with
which can be handy
like authentication
So one thing to keep
is that extensions are limited
in resources compared
So try to refrain from doing
within them.
We made it incredibly
up these extensions
These are available as new
If created from this template,
the extensions will be
up in the broadcast
So let's take a look at
that a broadcast service
starting with the
UI extension has a few
first it's responsible for
and providing sign up if the
Ideally, this should all be
so that the user's
But is also perfectly
up to the parent application
to get back to the game.
So, during sign up
that the user be shown
for using the service, and be
or decline those
So as we saw earlier, UI
for allowing the user to
like adding a title to it,
to notify others
about to begin via social media.
Finally, its final
ReplayKit, and ultimately
that broadcast set
So now that we looked at the
over to the upload extension.
It is responsible for
and audio data, and
to the back-end servers.
So we are aware there are
of data processing and
So I won't be getting into any
this session.
Instead, if you are a broadcast
with us, so we can
This way we can implement
that delivers the best
So going back to our flow
at the broadcast
We have gone through the
And we've clearly broken
of the game, ReplayKit
and that was live broadcasting.
We really feel this is
that you players
and for developers it is
for your fans to experience your
but by watching them as well.
So before we go, I'd like to end
with a few new enhancements
around commentary for iOS.
Namely, support for the
and also a new capability
So first up, we've added
making it incredibly convenient
in picture video
Player reaction is
that special flavor to
So to enable this
the Flair developers have added
in their fly out menu.
Pressing this button enables
at the top left.
So let's look at the API
To toggle the camera on,
we simply set the
on RPScreenRecorder, this
and populates a new
CameraPreviewView, which
Since it is UI view, you can
to your game view, and
so that it does not
You can even attach a Adjust
and allows you to position
So looking at the code here,
we're simply setting the
to True during recording
Then we get a CameraPreviewView
to position it, and
as a sub view to your game view.
So now that we have video
to pair that with audio.
So microphone recording was
but now we are including
to mute it during
So we all know broadcasters
interesting to say,
but sometimes even
So Olympus Rising
by including a microphone
Implementing the action
to microphone toggle
The existing IsMicrophoneEnabled
on RPScreenRecorder can
to enable the microphone, and
Again this can all be
or recording session.
Alright so that concludes
and I really hope
With the powerful new broadcast
for Apple TV, we
and watch your games live
For more information,
session 601, and during the
out our other game
what's new in GameplayKit,
Okay, so that's it for me.
Thanks so much for attending
that you enjoy the rest
Thanks so much.
[ Applause ]