[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, and welcome
I'm Warren Moore from the GPU
by my colleague, Matt Collins,
who will be driving
I want to start off by
simple question: what is Metal?
You've heard us say that Metal
for GPUs, that it has a unified
and that it's built for
and is designed for
And all of this is true,
but Metal is a lot more
Metal is supported by additional
And they make it a lot more than
In particular, last year
which includes utilities
like interacting UIKit, and
as well as Metal Performance
to do common tasks such
and contain hand-tuned,
that you can drop right into
Metal is also tightly integrated
Xcode and Instruments.
When you have Shaders
they're actually compiled
including your app bundle to do
And the GPU Frame Debugger,
of your app at any given point,
Metal System Trace in
to get an ongoing view
and behavior of your Metal apps.
So two years ago, we introduced
we've brought Metal
So it really has broad
And it's also widely
It's supported on our desktop
from Apple, AMD,
and this includes all Apple
and all iOS devices since 2013,
So Metal gives your applications
and power of the GPU in
of our most popular products.
And Metal is also a foundational
It powers Core Graphics, Core
and Graphics Libraries
SceneKit, and Model I/O.
And it's also an
in key system applications
And Metal has been widely
of all sizes, from AAA
independent developers, and
and they've built
across all of our platforms.
These are just a few examples,
but I'd like to highlight
For instance, Fancy
to dramatically improve
and bring amazing visual effects
to their highly popular
And Metal has also been used
to build inspiring professional
like the upcoming version
And I'd like to show you just a
This is Affinity Photos
And they're building a fully
for the iPad Pro, allowing them
to achieve truly
And this year at WWDC, we
to help you start using Metal
to build amazing experiences
We have a lot of phenomenal
five sessions dedicated
Of course, this is the first
And during this session,
about some foundational
about doing 2D drawing and
texturing, and animation
In Part II of this session,
after this session, we'll talk
and go on and talk about
of synchronizing
and really taking your
with multi-threaded encoding.
Of course, we're also going to
And there's really a
that you probably saw teased
of Union yesterday.
I won't go through all
but if you're interested in
in your apps, you
out the What's New sessions.
And finally, we have
on advanced Shader optimization.
And this is really a hardcore
to get the absolute most
We'll talk specifically
and how you can use Metal to
and tune your Shader code.
Throughout the course
we'll build a sample project,
starting with just a simple
of graphics programming.
And then as I mentioned, we'll
And in Part II, we'll take
about updating object data
performing draw calls
Now of course, we have
about who you are.
We assume that you're
of graphics programming, ideally
So you're familiar
And also of course
in actually using Metal
and apps even more awesome
I assume that everybody here
That's why you're here, right?
So just to go through
We'll kick things off
that will sort of introduce
and why Metal is
Then we'll actually get right
and talk about creating
We'll go on to talk
into memory that's
And we'll talk about the Metal
We'll talk about creating
And then talk about issuing GPU
And then we'll finish up
to perform animation
Part II will take
and I've already mentioned
So let's just forward ahead.
Starting off with the
There are a few things that
Use and API that matches
Favor explicit over implicit.
And do expensive
Let's start with using an API
Metal is a thoroughly
And by that, I mean
and exposes the latest
and it matches very closely to
And being a comparatively
and has no historical cruft that
So there are no fancy
for low overhead operation.
It's baked in to how Metal
at the most fundamental level.
And fortunately,
across all -- across
When we say that we
over implicit operation, we
the responsibility to
over how commands are
as well as how you manage
And this puts on you, a
but with great responsibility
So, just to illustrate
"to do expensive work less
of three regimes of time
The time that your app is built,
the time that your app is
and so on, and then draw time,
the things that happen
So with a legacy API, like
like state validation every
You take the hit for
on the fly in the worst case.
And all this adds overhead
of encoding the actual work for
With Metal, we push some of this
So, as I alluded to earlier,
Shader compilation
at application build
And additionally, we allow
that you're going to be using
at load time, so you don't pay
that cost every time
Instead, the only work
when you're issuing your draw
So with that conceptual
let's talk about where
and that's, the Metal device.
So there's a Class MTL device,
and it's an abstract
And it functions as the root
meaning that you'll
like command queues, resources,
and other objects
It's very easy to
You'll just call
Now devices are persistent
to create one at the
and then hold onto reference
to it throughout your
It's just that easy.
So now let's talk a little
into a place where
so that you can issue
And in Metal, we'll store
So buffers are just allocations
in any format that you choose.
These might be vertex data,
And you write data
and then access them
and fragmentFunctions.
Let's take a look at what
So here is an example
that you might create, as
We have a vertexBuffer,
And an indexBuffer, containing
To get a little bit more
of this vertex type
that contains a position
as well as a color
You can just lay them out
Now let's talk about how
So the API for this
that you've already created.
And you simply call
to get a buffer of
that doesn't have any
Or you can call
and pass a pointer to data
And Metal will then
into the newly created
and it will be ready
You can also memcpy into
of the buffer if you choose.
So, since we're going to
as the first part of our demo,
let's talk about defining the
So, since we want to
and fragment shader
we'll actually provide these
And Metal's Clip
It differs from some APIs and
This is like the
It runs from negative 1
in Y, and zero to 1 in Z.
So this is the coordinate space
that we'll specify
So in code, it looks like this.
We create a Swift
and then we just
with a position and a color.
Now, we don't strictly
to do the simple of a used
and create an indexBuffer and
which correspond to of
and third vertices
And then we'll create a couple
So we'll create the vertexBuffer
which loads our vertex data
and we'll call a
and pass the index data and
So, now that we have
let's talk a little bit about
The Metal shading language is
and it's a unified language
meaning that you can
than just 3D graphics with it.
It really just lets you
So here's a block diagram of
And what we're really talking
and fragment processing stages.
Each of these has an associated
that's used to either process
that will wind up on screen.
Syntax-wise, it looks
And we're not actually going to
I just want to call
to these function qualifiers:
You'll notice that right out
unlike in say a regular
we actually have these
which stage this function
So we have a vertex
and a fragmentFunction
And I'll show you shortly how
with your pipeline so that
And we'll also look at the
for our 2D demo and
Now, I've mentioned a couple
to compile your Shaders
And the way that happens is,
if you have even a
in your Compile Sources
the Metal will automatically
Lib file, the default.Metallib
and copy it into your bundle
at the time your
with no further effort
So there's the insides
There's your default.Metallib.
So just to recap.
You can build Metal
Again, if you have a .Metal file
by Xcode using the
And then produce
up in your app bundle.
And the natural question you
how do you actually get
And the answer is that
Metal Library.
So Metal Library is a collection
of these compiled
produced by the compiler.
And there are multiple
You can go through the flow
which is to build
into your app bundle, and
You can also build .metallibs
with a command line
And you can also build directly
if you're for example,
through string concatenation.
So in code, it looks like this.
In order to load up
you simply call
on your existing Metal device.
And there's other API for
an offline compiled
And you can consult
So, you have a Metal Library.
What do you get from
You get a Metal function.
Now a Metal function
that represents a
And it's associated with a
Remember that we saw
the vertex or fragment stage.
And we also have an additional
kernel, that signifies a data
So here's that code snippet
that the function named
and the fragmentFunction
And I rehash this so that
for loading these
which looks like this.
We simply call
and pass a string that
of your function, and get
and then hold onto it.
Now, I'll show you how
to actually use all these
But that was just a
to the Metal Shading language.
So let's talk about building
But first, let's
So, with an API like OpenGL,
you're often setting
And then you issue draw calls.
And in between those, the
that the safety you've set, is
in the worst case, you
of recompiling Shaders
This is what we want to avoid.
So with Metal, it
You set a pre-validated
and maybe set a few other
and then issue your draw call.
Now what we're trying to do
of draw calls by again,
into the process.
So here are a few examples of
on your pipeline state object,
which we'll talk
First, let's state that you
when you're drawing.
You'll notice that in
the state that you'll set
includes the vertex
that will be used to draw.
And it also includes things
On the right hand side,
that you can set before
including the front face
So let's talk about how
that contain this
The chief object is the
It represents the
of the GPU pipeline, and
of validated state that you'll
Like devices,
RenderPipelineStates
that you'll want to keep
of your application,
of different functions, you can
asynchronously while
To actually create a
we don't create one directly.
Instead, we use an object
up all the parameters
to create this
Often in Metal, we'll
that really just bring together
that we need to create
And so for the
that's called a Render
You'll notice that it contains
and fragmentFunction,
And it also contains a
And attachments signify the type
into when we actually
Now in Metal, all rendering
but we don't need pointers to
Instead we just need you
that you'll be rendering into so
that we can optimize the
Additionally, if you're using
then you can also specify the
So once you've constructed a
you can pass it off
and get back a
Let's take a look
Here's a minimal configuration
You'll notice that we're
and fragmentFunction
and fragmentFunction objects
that we created earlier
And we're also configuring
of the primary color attachment
of our renderable and
This represents basically
ultimately be drawn to
And finally, once
that pipeline descriptor,
we can use the new
on the device to actually get
I want to emphasize once more
that PipelineStates
and you should create them
around as you do your
You can switch among them
to achieve different effects.
You'll generally have about
and fragmentFunctions.
So now that we've
to construct pre-validated
of your resources into memory,
let's talk about actually
including draw calls.
We'll go through this
We'll talk about interfacing
talk about -- a bit about the
and then get into render passes
how to present your
So in terms of interacting
we're going to use a utility
And MTKView is a
It inherits from
and from UIView on iOS and tvOS.
And it reduces the amount of
in order to get up
For example, it creates and
for you, which is a specialized
with the Windows server or
to get your content on screen.
It can also, by use of
manage the draw callback
by issuing periodic callbacks
in which you'll actually
And it also manages the textures
I want to emphasize
of what this does for
So, inside of the CA Metal Layer
there is a collection
And drawables wrap a texture
that will ultimately
And these are kept in an
across frames because they're
and they need to be
because they actually
to how things actually get
So we manage them for you and
that wraps up one of these
So here's how you can --
that you can configure
to determine how it
that you're going
In particular, you can set a
which color, the primary
You can specify the
which should match the color
on your pipeline state object,
as well as specifying a depth
And this last property is
This is where we
So, MTKView doesn't actually do
You can either subclass it,
or you can implement a
for doing the drawing.
And we'll talk through
So let's take a look at
to become an MTKView delegate.
It really boils down to
drawable sizeable
So in drawable sizeable
for responding to things
or the device rotating.
So for example, if your
on the window size, then
to respond to that instead
So the draw method will
in order for you to
that you want to have executed,
And we're not showing
of that method here, but this is
when we talk about
So you'll create a
with it, and then commit it.
We'll talk a lot more about that
of your hook for doing the
And we recommend using MTKView,
especially as you're getting
of a lot of things for you.
So let's talk about Metal's
This is the picture that
up over the next several slides.
And it's not important for you
to memorize everything
We're going to be
This is just sort
The objects that we're going to
So, Metals Command Submission
meaning that your
and submit commandBuffers
And you can think of a
of work to be executed
in contrast to what we're
which stores data.
Command buffers store work
And commandBuffer submission
meaning that when you
that you've constructed, you're
when it's ready to be executed.
We'll talk all about
Additionally, we'll talk
which are objects that are used
into work for the GPU.
It's important to realize
that these command encoders
of validation.
So all of the pre-validated
up in your pipeline,
we assume that that's valid
because we validated
And so there's no additional
or the driver at the point
that you're issuing
Additionally, Metal's Command
multi-threaded, which allows you
to construct multiple
and have your app decide
This allows you to scale to,
of draw calls per frame.
Adopting Metal Part II will
but I wanted to mention it
So let's talk a little bit more
The first thing we'll talk
And the Command Queue,
to a Metal class called Metal
that has been queued up
Like the device and
queues are persistent objects
up front and then keep a handle
You'll often only
And this is how thread safety
in the sense that you can create
into -- and use them
And the queue allows you
in a thread safe fashion,
to do your own locking.
It's really simple to
You simply call a new
and you'll get back a
Of course, a queue can't do much
into to, so let's
So I've already mentioned
And Command Buffers are the
by the GPU, and in
by a class called
So a Metal Command Buffer
to be executed by the GPU,
onto a Command Queue for
These, in contrast to almost
about thus far, are
meaning that you'll create
and then encode commands
and then let them
You won't reuse them.
You won't hold onto
They're just fire and forget.
To create a Command
up the Command Buffer
So we've talked a bit
and now let's actually
and commands into a
with a special class of
And there are several
including Render,
And these each allow you
And they all have this common
to encode work into
So for example, a Render
to set state and
A Compute Command Encoder
for the GPU to execute in a
rendering work.
That's your GP, GPU, and
And the Blit Command Encoder
between buffers and
We're going to look in detail
at the Render Command
And as I mentioned, it
of encoding commands.
And each Render Command
of a single pass into
So you'll issue some
and then you'll issue some
of Render target attachments,
that are going to be drawn into
So schematically,
about here is sort
You can see we have
of hanging off the frame buffer
And if we were doing multi pass
of the render targets in
for a subsequent pass.
But this is sort of the
So the again, the attachments
that we're going to be drawing
So in terms of actually creating
we use another type
called a RenderPassDescriptor.
So a RenderPassDescriptor
of attachments, each of which
action, a clear color,
and an associated Metal
And we'll talk a little bit more
in a couple of slides.
But the important
is that you'll be constructing
at the beginning of your frame,
with the textures that
So in contrast to the
that only needs to know the
of where the rubber hits the
to give us the textures that
So again, a RenderPassDescriptor
of render pass attachments,
depth, or stencil target,
and refers to a texture
And it also specifies
and store actions.
Let's talk in more depth about
So, at the beginning of a pass,
and your depth buffer and
And in order to actually
we'll need to clear them.
And we do this by setting
on the RenderPassDescriptor.
So we set a load action of clear
and that clears them to their
or clear value, as
Then we'll do some drawing,
which will actually
of our draw calls
And then the store
And the store action here is
The store action of
of rendering should
to memory and stored.
And in the case of the color
to present it potentially
In the case of the depth buffer,
when we're actually drawing and
about where the results of
So we can set a store action
to save some bandwidth.
This is an optimization
if you don't actually need
of rendering into
So to go in a little bit more
these determine how
at the start and
In addition to the clear
there's also a Load-Load
to load pixel contents
with the results
There's also "Don't Care."
For example, if you're going to
of a given target, then you
in the texture previously,
because you know
to actually be setting every
So that's another way
if you know that in
to be hitting every
Now, I could walk
to create a RenderPassDescriptor
and then create a Render Command
MTKView makes this
You saw earlier that we
with a couple of properties
that by now I hope you become
and the texture formats
So you can actually
for its current
and you'll get back a
that you can then go on to use
to create a Render
And this is how you do that.
You simply call Render Command
Now it's important to note here
that current
potentially a blocking call.
And the reason for that is
into the CA Metal Layers
which we won't talk about in
to obtain the drawable
that can be presented on screen.
And because that is
if there is not a drawable
if all of them are in flight,
So it' something to be aware of.
So we've talked about
and we've talked about
and Render Command Encoders.
So how do we actually get
First, we need to talk a little
So argument tables are mappings
from Metal resources
And each type of resource that
such as a buffer or a texture,
has its own separate
So you can see here
that we have the
and the texture argument table,
of buffers that are maps
in the argument table.
Now the number of slots
in any given argument table
the device.
So you should query for them.
Let's make that a
So, on the Render Command
called Set Over Text
that it has three parameters.
It takes a buffer, and
So this last parameter is
because it's our
So this is sort of the host
that are going to be
And there's a corresponding
which looks like this.
So this is in the
Inside your Shader file,
that each given parameter
that you want to access, has an
So, this is the first
Buffer Index Zero in
corresponds to the buffer
on our Render Command Encoder.
And we'll look at a little
when we actually talk
We've already created
but we actually need to tell
which pipeline state to use
So this is API for that.
We simple call
with the previously created
and that configures the pipeline
that we created earlier that
Now of course, the
has associated -- an associated
So let's take a look at the
that we're actually going
Back in Metal Shading
So, this is basically a
which means that we're not going
to be doing any fancy
It's really just going to
straight on through.
So, the first parameter to this
which is the buffer
And the second parameter is
with the vertex ID attribute,
to be populated by Metal
that we're currently
And the reason that's
because the vertexBuffer
and we can access it at random.
But what we actually want to do
in our vertex function
on one particular
So this tells us which
So, we create an instance
which represents all the
that we want to pass
So we create an instance of
to the position vector of the
And similarly for the color.
And this just passes that data
to the struct that will be
And then we return that
Now let's look at
It's even simpler.
So we take in the interpolated
in attribute, and that signifies
that this is the data that's
And we just extract
the color from the
and then pass it back on out.
And so, what's happened in
which were already specified
are being interpolated and
for each fragment
we simple return the
that was created for
So once we've specified
which contains our vertex
we can also set additional
that I mentioned earlier,
including the front
So if you want to specify a
order, than Metal's
then you can do that here.
It's a lot of configuration,
about to see some draw
So Metal has numerous functions
for drawing geometry including
but we'll just look at
Let's say that we want to draw
So, here we call
and we specify that the
because we want to
We pass an index count of
to draw a single triangle,
and then we also specify
We made our Swift array a
so we mirror that here.
And we also pass
that we created earlier
which vertices should be drawn,
and then we pass in
And this is actually
in a single triangle
We might also additionally
and issue other draw
of this first demo, this
So in order to conclude
we simple call it endEncoding
To recap all of that, you
a RenderPassDescriptor, at
Then you'll create a
with that Descriptor.
Set the RenderPipelineState.
Set any other necessary state.
Issue draw calls, and
So here's a recap of all the
Nothing new here.
Exactly what we've seen and
Create a Render Command
bind some buffers, and draw.
So you've rendered all
but how do you actually
It's pretty straightforward.
So, first color attachment
of your render pass is
that you've either gotten
from a CA Metal Layer
So in order to request that that
on screen, you can
on the commandBuffer, and
and that will be displayed
to the screen once all the
Then to finally actually
since we've been encoding
we need to signify
with the commandBuffer
Committing tells the driver
to be executed by the GPU.
So to recap that, we created
and since it's a
we hold onto reference to it.
Each frame we create a
or more rendering passes into it
Present the drawable
and then commit the
And now I'm going to hand
to walk us through the
&gt;&gt; Thanks Warren.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So here's the proof.
A 2D triangle, this is the Metal
by our awesome title,
Just a triangle, three colors
on the ends interpolated
Let's take a look at the code.
Now first I want to
to become a delegate of MTKView,
and Warren mentioned we have
So here we have MTKView,
And this is what is called
to changes in your window.
This sample is very simple so
We'll leave that up to you
And the other thing
We chose to put this
So, when our draw gets
Render's also quite simple.
I just wanted to show you.
When we take MTKView's
you just grab it out
and then you create the
and your encoder with it.
And I'd like to draw
"push debug group."
And this is how you talk
So when you do a frame
of your draws by whatever
So here, we have one
and then we pop the debug
and so this draw will show up
Let's take a look at the Shader.
Now Warren mentioned,
We have a vertex end
of the data we're putting
That's just a position
And we have the vertex
which is what we're passing
And you see here the
with this position attribute.
And this represents the
And every vertex Shader that you
must have one of these.
And as you saw, these
of familiar, they're
Vertices come in.
We have a pass through.
And you write them out.
And in the fragmentFunction, we
out of the rasterizer
and we read the color,
So that's the simple
I'll send it back
&gt;&gt; Thanks Matt.
So, we've shown how to
And 2D is cool, but you
Three-D. So let's talk a
and texturing in Metal.
In order to actually
alright well, we'll go through
We'll talk about how to
And we'll talk about animating
and then we'll talk a little
In order to move into 3D,
whereas we've been specifying
we now need to specify them
And then multiply them
by a suitable model
in order to move them
And we'll also add properties
as texture coordinates so
in our fragmentFunction,
and to determine how to
So, here's our extended vertex.
We have removed the color
in a normal vector as well as
And similarly to how we had
on a new buffer that will store
to reference from our various
in order to actually transform
Now, you'll notice
of this buffer is dashed, and
Because I don't want to create
to manage this tiny
This is only a couple
And it turns out that Metal
for binding very small buffers
So again, for small
less than about 4 kilobytes,
of vertex bytes and pass it --
And of course, tell
And Metal will create
that contains that data.
And again, you can actually
here, specifying it as 1,
because our vertices are
so we bind at Index 1 so that
inside of our functions.
So let's take a look at how
and respond to this.
Before that, we'll
to actually call setForTextBytes
So, we'll create
that again creates these --
contains these two matrices that
by the Model View Projection
which is the matrix that
from local space into iSpace.
We'll construct them using
comfortable with, and then
And finally use setVertexBytes,
to that structure and then
this implicit buffer that's
in our subsequent draw call.
Now, last year at
and awesome framework
and Model I/O contains a
But one of the great
that it also allows you
And because of MetalKit,
it actually has very tight
so that you can create
that can be rendered
So, instead of actually
by hand, I can for example,
of content creation
and load it with Model I/O.
Or in this case,
So let's take a look
So I want to generate
that represent this cube.
Well, in order to actually get
I'll create this thing
So MTKMeshBufferAllocator
between Model I/O and Metal.
By passing a device to
we allow Model I/O to create
and then hand them back to us.
So we create an MDLMesh
boxWithExtent, etcetera,
and this will create an
that contains the relevant data.
We then need to extract it
that are provided
And that looks like this.
So first, we generate
in the MDLMesh that we just
And then in order to extract
into the mesh and pull it out.
Similarly, for the indexBuffer.
And there are also a
that we've already
to supply to our draw call.
But the emphasis here is on
to use Model I/O to
and subsequently
that you can use
And now let's talk a
We have our vertex data.
We want to apply a
to add a little bit more detail.
Well, as you know, textures
in some pre-specified,
And they predominantly are
In Metal, it's no great surprise
with a descriptor object,
specifically a Metal
And texture descriptors
that brings together texture
and pixel format, and
to actually generate the
Let's take a look at that.
So we have these
on Metal Texture Descriptor,
for the descriptor that
supplying on the necessary
pixel format, and whether or
You can then ask
by calling newTexture
Now, this texture doesn't
in it, so you'll
like Replace Region or similar.
You can consult the docs for
yet another utility to make
And that's called
So this is a utility provided by
from a number of sources,
or from a file URL,
that you have already
in the form of an MS
And this generates and
of the appropriate size
to the image data
Now let's take a
So you can create
by simply passing
You'll get back a TextureLoader,
and you can subsequently fetch a
from your asset catalog.
And as long as you
then you can call
and hand it to data, and it will
You might also be acquainted
Now, Samplers and Metal are
They're not bound together.
And Samplers simply
to texture sampling.
So parameters such as
as well as level of detail.
And so we support
In order to get a Sampler
on in our Render Command
we'll create a Metal
and that looks like this.
So we create an empty
that has default properties,
and we specify whichever
Here, I'm specifying that we
in both axes, and
we want to use the
and when magnifying
So once we've created
we call newSamplerState,
and we get back a Metal
that we can subsequently use to
In the Render Command Encoder,
We create a texture so
of the Fragment Texture
And then we bind our
of the Sampler State Argument
And let's look at those
So the vertex function this
by the MVP Matrix that
out of -- a constant buffer.
It will then transform
from all the local
which is what we're obligated to
And it will also transform
from Models Local
so that we can do our lighting.
Here's what it looks
So notice that we've added
with Buffer 1, and like
this corresponds to
So we've created a struct type
in our metal shaving
to the constant struct that
that allows us to fetch out
in normal matrices.
And again, this is bound
So that corresponds to the
So, to actually move into Clip
into the vertexBuffer
Get up a position vector.
Multiply it by the MVP
to the outgoing struct.
Similarly, for the normal.
And also, we just copy
to the outgoing struct as well.
And all of these of
by the rasterizer.
So we just go ahead
The fragmentFunction is a
than previously.
We want to actually
so we'll include two terms of
and also sample from the texture
to apply the texture
It looks like this.
We're not going to talk
but the important
that we've added a parameter
that we've created and bound,
we've given it an access
which allows us to
It's sitting at Argument
The Sampler State that
at Argument Slot Zero for the
to actually read a
a filtered value
is call Sample, on the texture.
So Text2D.Sample, actually
as well as the texture
and gives us back
We'll also go ahead and do
but I won't talk
But it's just dependent upon the
and the lighting direction.
And we specified some constants
in our Shader file that
And that's pretty much it.
So we constructed the color
by multiplying through the value
by the lighting intensity,
to result in an animated
And I will now let Matt
&gt;&gt; Alright, let's take
Here's the Metal texture mesh.
You can see, it's a
Some simple lighting,
on a nice colored background.
Go ahead and admire
and now we'll take a
So you can see some new stuff
in our Shader compared
The first thing we take a look
This corresponds
that has a 4 X 4 Model View
normal matrix, and
for the appropriate transforms.
As Warren mentioned, we
Ambient light intensity,
And the diffused light
and the direction of
to actually compute
Our input and output structs
We've got a little
that we need to pass down now.
We have position.
We have the normal, which
and the texture coordinates
which we need to
And similarly, when we output
we need that same data again.
So let's take a look
Just as Warren said,
it's basically just a couple
and then a pass through for
And a quick look at
which is exactly what
Now let's see how
A little more going on now.
So we have a little
So we need to update a little
to rotate our cube by.
So here we have a
to update my time step
And that will change
Just like Warren said, we
like to send over to the GPU,
send a small structure over,
which was the two
And that's what we'll use
to compute the animated
Put the texture, the
Highly recommend you
to push your debug
exactly what you're looking
at a frame capture later on.
Present your drawable and
&gt;&gt; Cool. Thanks again, Matt.
So with these adopting Metal
to take advantage of the
of years now, teaching Metal,
and introducing awesome
that make Metal easy to use.
And so we hope that these --
this two-part session
You've seen that
and low overhead GPU programming
you've become acquainted
that are available inside of it.
Metal is a very closely --
is very much informed by how
and is you know, philosophically
as much expensive work
And so you've seen sort
that that informs
And the emphasis of course
that that entails,
the power that it
So you've seen how
and command submission can let
in a sense that if you know
and you know what it's
you can take the reins and
And of course, over the next
at WWDC this year,
that Metal has in store.
And then of course, it
and build awesome
So for more information on this
you can go to this
there are some related sessions.
Part II will be happening in
And tomorrow we have, What's
And the Advanced Metal
that I mentioned.
So thank you, and
[ Applause ]