[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone,
I hope you're all
and you've had some nice
We've got a great
It's going to be really fun.
I'm Matt Collins.
This is my colleague Jared
to talk Adopting Metal, Part 2.
This is Section 603.
So if you're in the wrong place,
So let's recap.
We have two Adopting
Hopefully you were here
for Warren's presentation a
about the fundamental concepts:
texturing, good stuff like that.
And in this presentation
to take it to the next level.
We're going to draw
We're going to talk about
large amounts of dynamic
and we'll cap it off with
Tomorrow we've got some
We'll talk about
We'll have the first session,
memoryless frame
about our improved tools
to really help you guys get
Part 2, we'll talk about
and function resource
and texture assets,
to Metal performance shaders.
And if you really
we'll have an awesome talk about
shader performance fundamentals,
more detailed about
It'll be great.
So if you're really interested
to make them to best they can
So this is Part 2 of Adopting
on what we learned in Part 1.
We figured out how to
So let's take a look at
to get the most out of Metal
We've got a demo that will draw
and we'll use that demo for
as we discuss and learn
We'll talk about the ideal
how to manage large chunks of
of synchronization between
like I said before, some
So hopefully you're familiar
because we won't be
So we expect that you understand
a Metal command buffer, how to
on that to go forward.
So let's start with
and see what we're
So right now we've
and they're all spinning
It's an interesting scene.
Metal allows us to issue
with very low overhead.
So here we have 10,000
You can see on the bottom
We're using a shadow map,
some nice anti-aliased lines
and of course all of our cubes.
So what goes into
As you can see, we've got
of these objects has its own
We need the position,
And this has to update
because we're animating them.
So this is a bunch of data
constantly have to reinform
We can also draw a few more
You can spin it around
that we're actually
So we have a draw call for cube
and we have to think about
about this data,
and how to communicate
So let's dive right in.
Thanks, Jared.
Managing Dynamic Data:
of data that's changing
And as you can imagine in
you also have a bunch of data
that every frame
So our draw basically
We want to go through all
in drawing and update them.
Then we want to encode
and then we have to submit
We have a lot of objects.
We started at 10,000
up to up to 100, 200,000.
Each of these objects has its
to figure out the best
Now in the past, you might've
You push updated data to
or something, you bind
some textures, and you draw.
And you push some more data up.
You bind shader,
You draw your next object.
In our scene we repeat
but we really want to get away
and try something new.
What if we could just
and have every command that
that was already there.
The GPU is a massively
and it does not like to wait.
So if all our data in already in
to it and it will go
and do all our rendering for us.
And each draw call we make then
that's already there.
In our sample, it's
We have one draw that
So the first draw call
of data, the second, the
But it doesn't have
and we can actually reuse data.
We have some data, like at
that we can reference
or we could have a draw call
of data in different places.
If you're familiar
it's a very similar idea.
All your data will be in place
So how do we do this in Metal?
In our application, we create
and this is our constant buffer.
It holds all the data that
We want to create this upfront,
and reuse it every time we draw.
We don't duplicate any data.
Again, any draw call can
so there's no need
Each draw call will reference
It'll do a little bit
which draw represents
And then you'll just
and everything will be in place.
Let's take a look at
Here's the code from the app.
You can think of us as
Like I mentioned before,
that will update here
that will change per object.
This is the unique rotation
So we need to put both
Now what do I mean
Well this is data
across every draw call we make.
For example, in our sample we
It's a 4 by 4 matrix,
if you're familiar
It represents the camera
This is not going to
so we only need one copy of it.
And we'd like to reuse
so we can create one copy
Let's start filling this out.
So here, we have
which is just a Metal
And with the Contents function,
Our app has a helper function,
and this returns that main pass
that has the view
the ViewProjection transform.
Excuse me.
And then we simply just
of our buffer and
So our buffer will
We'll have a MainPass with the
and we'll put it at the start
So now we have all this
And like we saw, we need to
so we need to start filling this
So then we have a set
and this is the unique data we
In our case, we have a single
which is the concatenation of
and we have the color.
So this is the set of data
So we'll walk through every
We'll keep track of the
We have our updateData
which will do our little
and then we'll update
This will pack our data tightly
and we'll fill it
Let's take a closer look at
It's quite simple.
Now, animation is kind of out
so I have a little helper
updateAnimation with
This could be whatever you
and indeed you should but
of animation you need.
But it my case it returns
which has the LocalToWorld
And just as I did before, I
So here's what that looks like.
I've got my frame data in place.
I have my other data, another
So all our data is in place
But are we missing anything?
Turns out that we are and I want
We have one constant buffer.
I mentioned I created one Metal
Now there's a problem with this.
The CPU and the GPU are actually
They can read and write the
So what happens when you have
of memory while something
Resource contention.
So it looks a little like this.
The CPU prepares a frame
The GPU starts working on this
The CPU doesn't know
so it decides I'm going
and it starts overwriting
And now our results
We don't actually know what
or writing to or what
So it's important
this is not handled
The CPU and GPU can
at the same time
You must synchronize
It's just like writing CPU
You have to ensure you're
And that brings us to
Let's start simple.
The easiest way to do this
after you've submitted
Your CPU draw function
submits the commands,
until it's ensured the
That way we know we
because the GPU will be
to generate our next frame.
This won't be fast
So we need some sort of
to let us know, hey, I'm done
Metal provides this in
We call them handlers
that are interesting,
and that executes when a command
to run on the GPU.
And for us, an even more
completion handler
when the GPU has finished
The command buffer is completely
at this point it's safe to
that we were using there.
So this is perfect.
We just need some way to
we're done, we can go forward.
Now how many of you are familiar
Anyone? Pretty good.
Quick background on semaphores.
They are synchronization
to control access to
and that fits us perfectly here.
We have one constant buffer
so we'll have a semaphore
and we'll create it
The count on a semaphore
we're trying to protect.
So we'll create our semaphore.
And again, this is something
that should be created
And the first thing
to draw is we wait
Now in Apple semaphore,
Some people call this taking.
Some people call it downing.
It doesn't really matter.
The idea is that you wait
to distant future,
which effectively means
Our thread will go to sleep
and wait for something to do.
When we're done,
in our completion handler we
That'll tell us that it's safe
We're completely done with
So this is sort of a naive
but it looks a little like this.
Frame 0 we'll write
And on the GPU, we'll
The CPU will wait.
When the GPU is done
it will send the completion
and create another
And that will process
So this works but,
we have all these
and GPU are actually
It doesn't seem like a good
What we'd like to do is overlap
That way we can actually
inherent in this
to somehow avoid
So we'd like our ideal
Frame 0 would be prepared on
While the GPU is processing
to work creating frame
So one thing to keep
that the CPU is actually getting
If you notice where
frame 0 is the only thing
So we're a little bit ahead
that in mind for a little later.
But first let's talk
in the demo and what we do here.
We'd like to overlap our CPU and
with one constant buffer
So our solution is to
So when we create a frame,
and then our CPU proceeds
to create the next frame while
While it's doing this, the GPU
that was produced before.
Now we don't have an
because we don't
So our pool has to have a limit.
On our application,
This is something that you
We can't tell you what to
of things that go into
how much memory you want to use.
So we recommend you experiment
For this example,
So here, you can see
We have three frames
but only one is finished
So we need to wait a little bit.
But by now, frame 0 is done,
from the pool and so on.
So let's look at this in code.
Here's synchronizing
We've already got a
for controlling access
In this case our limit is three
but it can be whatever
So here we create our
And instead of creating
we now create an array of them.
And lastly, we need an index
to represent the currently
for us to use.
We can walk through the
and the semaphore will control
So in our draw function,
on the semaphore, and if
we'll go to sleep.
Once we've taken the semaphore
for us to grab the
In our index, current
which one's available.
Then we fill out our frame as
do all our updates, add
and then we'll signal the
we're done with this frame.
You can go forward.
And the last thing we need
We'll add one.
We'll use modulo to wrap around.
And don't worry, we
about overwriting ourselves
because the semaphore
So constant buffers in the demo.
The demo has an array
and I've seen some
by marking them as,
from in frame number
to you in frame number 5.
But with this model you don't
The semaphore takes care of all
And if you can take the
that the last frame that
otherwise you'd still be asleep.
So now all our data is in
And we'd like to start
to get some stuff on the screen.
So here's the basic
We have two passes: One
and one pass that reads the
to split these into two
There's a good reason for this.
It lets us have two
that are independent and unique.
They don't depend on each other.
You encode the shadow pass.
You pass that to command
that you've already filled out
to render the shadow map.
And then you have a
that encodes the main pass.
You pass it to mainCommandBuffer
and it encodes all
When the encoding is all
on your two command
and then you've got your frame.
So what goes into actually
of our cubes?
We need a bunch of data and
We need some geometric
which is quite simple, you know,
eight vertices, maybe
And in our sample, we don't
or anything, just some very
So we could reuse that
across all of our cubes.
We mentioned the
We need one copy of that.
So we'll update it.
Stick it in place.
And then of course we
that LocalToWorld and
that we're animating.
So when we issue our draw calls,
we want to make sure we
So our encoder will
put them into our
draw call 0 will reference both
that we're interested in.
Draw call 1, similarly, will
and the object 1 data and so on.
This way everything's in place.
We issue our calls and the
Now we have a ton of
You know, in our demo,
and we want to issue these
So we'd like to avoid
We don't want to reset
Anything that's shared,
we'd like to set that once
So avoid redundant state updates
and avoid redundant
It's also worth keeping
and fragment stage argument
You can bind a buffer to
to the fragment stage
But if you have to bind
this can potentially double
setVertexBuffer,
This is one reason we didn't use
You can imagine we have
to make a copy of all that data
and once for the fragment stage.
That would quickly
But if we kept it all in one
we wouldn't have to
And the last guideline
out is using a new function,
setVertexBufferOffset/
This merely changes the pointer
So you can see here
they actually don't take a
They take an offset
This is because you must
to that specific point and
within it and that's
We have one constant buffer and
So we can set it
and then every time we draw,
and just point the
to the current spot
It looks a little
We bind this constant buffer
and then we call
with this offset.
Then we call it again
and again striding it forward.
We're not changing the buffer
We're just changing the
With these guidelines in mind,
our encoding is actually
We have a bunch of data
The per-frame constants
because we know we're
So we'll set that.
We'll set the constant buffer
to be in place for us to use the
We'll set the geometry
because we know they're shared
Then finally we can
through all the objects
We'll set the offset
for our current draw.
And then we'll actually
And here's the code from the
in the sample.
We'll start off by
that is our geometry and
which is our
We'll set the constant buffer
so we can use
In this case we're setting
and the fragment stages.
And then we'll set
Now you'll notice here that
to two separate indices
And Metal allows you to do
You could set the same
at a different offset if you'd
And then we dive
We need to track the
that we're not starting
of our constant buffer.
There's some frame
So the offset will be pushed
Then we'll call
and setFragmentBufferOffset
to the correct data that
We'll issue the draw call
and then we'll set the offset
data struct at a time.
So our draws are in place.
This is still very linear.
And I promised you
and Warren mentioned that, hey,
of stuff in parallel in Metal.
So how would you do this?
An ideal frame might
Our render threat is chugging
I need to render a
to render a main pass.
It'd be great if I could
I've got multiple CPUs.
So what if I dispatch this
then I rejoin back
and the render thread
to do a bunch of work.
This would look great.
How many of you have used GCD?
This is a great fit for
If you're not familiar,
Grand Central Dispatch is
This is an API that
and these queues manage
on your machine.
There are two types of
There's a serial queue.
When you dispatch work through a
that all that work
But what's more interesting
When you dispatch work to the
at your system and
to schedule this for you.
And that's perfect.
We have two jobs we
So if we created this one queue
it would do that for us.
This is another object you
So here's some code to create
You should always a
I've used the very
but you might want to
So we made some modifications
We still create the command
But since we were smart enough
and separate our
into two unique things,
to do other than
So dispatchQueue.async
to dispatch work
This is an asynchronous call.
It'll push the work on and
So here we dispatch
and then we dispatch
We'll want to commit
so we call dispatch barrier
that all the work is done by
And then finally we've rejoined
Now the ordering
The shadow map has to be done
So we have to commit the
and then the main
There's something else
How many of you are familiar
Great. How many of you
where closures captures self
and you thought you were
You can be honest.
It's happened to all of us.
I just wanted to call this out.
Closures capture self.
So if you're referencing a
within them and you're not
it's still actually going
So if you want to
to reference the correct
to capture it outside and
in a second.
These two things don't
So in the first one where
you can see the constant buffer
on self.constantBufferSlot.
I don't actually know what that
This is really asynchronous
So by the time my dispatch
this could've changed
It may be right but
I can't guarantee it.
So keep that in mind and
Instead, we'd like to
to the constant buffer
So here we just say
and grab it out of the array.
But then when we
we reference the specific one
That makes sure we know exactly
So this is some multithreading
The actual code in the
We capture the constant buffer.
And when we use it, we make sure
the one that we've
to know that we're using
Now I had mentioned
and how this was important.
When you create a command buffer
that this executes on
by the order you commit it in.
So if I commit the shadow
and the main command buffer
that the shadow one will happen
by the main command buffer.
Sometimes we refer to this
as implicit command
But you can be a little
Metal provides an
that enforces command
If you have a set of command
and you're guaranteed
in that order regardless
or when you commit them.
This is something really
to commit command buffers from
and you don't have
The runtime will ensure you're
So let's see how to
A couple new additions here.
Now when we create
we immediately enqueue
Again, the order
to enqueue shadowCommandBuffer
and then mainCommandBuffer
But now when we dispatch,
from within our other thread.
Again, the runtime is going
So we don't actually
This actually lets us remove
because we have no
and commit the command buffers.
They're already committed
But I seem to have
that synchronization stuff
and we still need it
to be overriding ourselves
So can we apply these same
to this sort of multithreaded
It turns out we can and it's
We bring back our
and our array of
And again, don't forget to grab
At the start, we'll wait
if nothing's available.
We've enforced our ordering with
Now we know
that mainCommandBuffer is
in our frame.
And we know that we want to
So we should add our completion
and you could do this
So the mainCommandBuffer is
We add the completion handler
and we commit it from
just like we did before.
Now you may notice here that
and a second ago I just told
So what's going on?
Well it turns out a semaphore
and we do actually want to
as all of our other threads.
So we want the value
at the time the thread
So in this case, we
something to keep aware of.
And here's the recipe
At the start of our
we wait on the semaphore.
We select the current
We write the data into
that represents all
We encode the commands
We can do the single-threaded,
multithreaded, however
We add a completion handler
and we use it to signal the
when we're done and we
And the GPU takes all this
and starts chugging
So let's look at the demo
So here you can see
this is single-threaded
and you can see how many
And the top right, you can
to encode a frame.
So here we've got 5 milliseconds
of draws up and see that
and more as we draw things.
Now this is single-threaded
And when you think about it,
which means we have to issue
and then we're drawing the
to issue another 40,000
But again, we can
so we've added a parallel
And you can see how it's
Now take a look at
You can fly around a little bit.
So here we have 40,000
They're all being updated.
We're using GCD to encode a
We have two command buffers:
on the ground and one to render
The lighting is quite
which is basically
about earlier, the N.L lighting.
And that's our demo.
This will be available
for you guys to take a look at.
Hopefully you can rip it
and the thoughts in it and
So what did we talk about today?
When you walked in
to Warren's session earlier
about graphics or had done
but we took you through
The conceptual overview
around it is to use an API
and close to the driver.
We learned about the Metal
in Metal that everything
We talked a bit about
and the different resource
the Metal shading language,
to write programs on the GPU.
We talked about building
prevalidated objects that
vertex and fragment
and a bunch of other
to save you time at runtime.
Then we went into
creating a Metal queue, creating
and creating encoders to
and then issuing that work and
We walked you through
and using set vertex bytes
to do your animation in.
Then when the small bits
we talked about managing
and using one big constant
in multiple places to get some
We talked about CPU-GPU
of making sure your CPU and your
and playing nicely.
And then lastly, we
about multithreaded encoding,
to encode multiple
on your queues at the same time.
And that's adopting Metal.
Hopefully you enjoyed the talk
to your apps and make
than they already are.
If you'd like some more
out this website,
We have a few more
that I recommend
At 11:00 o'clock, we
Part 1 and then a
we have What's New
That'll tell us everything
of Metal, awesome
to your applications
And then for you hardcore
we have Advanced Metal
So if you want to know
out of your shaders, I recommend
It's really great.
Thanks for coming
Welcome to WWDC.
Have a good rest of the week.
Thanks again.