[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Morning, everyone.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; My name is Aaftab Munshi.
And my colleagues and I
with you the new
in macOS Sierra and iOS 10.
But let's begin by highlighting
on Metal this year at WWDC.
So yesterday we had two
about adopting Metal
And today we have
So this session and
that cover the new features in
by another session
about optimizing
All right.
So let's look at the features
So in the second session the
about are function or shader
to write to resources such
from your fragment
wide color using wide color
and texture assets, and some
to Metal performance shaders,
and [inaudible] networks
In this session we're
of the improvements we
which we think you guys
We've also made resource heaps
and resource allocations
and given you more control.
So we'll talk about
and memoryless render targets.
And I'm going to be
So let's begin.
All right.
So the first thing, let's spend
to understand why we
So we are seeing applications
and more realistic
So what that means is in
we need to be able to
of geometry to the GPU.
That's where we're going
That means lots and lots
to be processed, which
in memory bandwidth.
It would be really nice
if instead we could just
that we want to send to the GPU
call it a core smash, and
high-resolution model.
So in fact, that's
Tessellation is a technique
and refine the details
We have two important
The first is that the
the triangles that are
in graphics memory.
We don't want to pay
And the second is a
to be programmable.
So let's look at an example.
So here is a screenshot
which is a benchmark
And one of the key features
So here's a screenshot
of the car that's being
You can see those rims.
They're very polygonal.
You wouldn't drive a car
Even the body panels
And the reason for that is this
being sent.
So you can see not a lot of
it's exactly what we want.
What tessellation does is
and produces something
I think this is really cool.
So if you look at
you can see the GPUs
now we're rendering lots
And that's the power
All right.
So let's look at how
So just like we did
we wanted to take a clean
We wanted to design
even though there
that do support tessellation
we wanted something that
you know, easy to use,
to leave any performance
And we think we have achieved
after this presentation.
So tessellation is available
with the A9 processor.
All right.
So let's -- the things I'm
how does the Metal
like for tessellation?
How do I render my
And then how do I adopt
So let's begin.
So today when you send
with Metal, you're sending
With tessellation, you're
And put simply, a patch is
that is made up of
What does that mean?
You may have heard of things
like Bezier patches
So you describe a patch by
So in this figure you
So you have 16 control-points
And what tessellation does put
okay, how many triangles do
So you may decide,
I don't really want
I don't care how it looks."
So you may decide just four
and you'll get a polygonal look.
Or you decide, "Hey, I
and smooth."
That would take a
But you have that control.
So let's start.
So the first stage in
when we're doing
tessellation kernel.
And what it does is
we talked about the patch with
and decides, okay, how much
How many triangles do I want
This information is
as tessellation factors.
And I'll talk a little bit
about what these factors
And you can also generate
if you need it in a later stage.
The key thing this is
that means you're writing code.
So once you've written
factors, the next stage
So this is a fixed
So no code to write.
But you do net knobs
So it takes those
and breaks the patch
And the key thing the
that it does not store
that triangle list it
In addition to the triangle
for each vertex in the triangle
call a parametric coordinate
And it uses this along
to compute the actual
Okay? All right.
So the tessellator
Today in Metal when you
you send triangles to the GPU.
What is the first thing
that happens is a vertex
Well, here the tessellator's
So if you think logically,
the next stage would be a
We just call it the
because it's operating
that are generated
And so it's going to execute for
that the tessellator
to output transform positions.
So if you're familiar
it's this shader plays
as the domain shader
All right.
And then the rest of the
We have the rasterizer and
So you may ask, "Well, so I need
to generate the tessellation
Well, can I use the
Of course you can.
In fact, you don't even
to generate these factors;
and you can just load
that to the tessellator.
So you have a lot of control.
But if you are generating these
that you use a compute kernel.
Because guess what?
That allows us to run
with other draw commands.
So netting you a performance win
and I think you guys
Well, actually let's
You don't even need to run
Because guess what?
If you have computed the
let's say you decide,
to the camera get much
objects further away
So once I've computed
on how the object is moving,
and the tessellator takes that.
So really, the pipeline
We have four stages.
So let's compare it with
without tessellation.
So without tessellation
we have vertex shade,
and the fragment stage.
With tessellation we added a
It's fixed function so you
And the vertex shader became the
We think this is really
I hope you agree.
All right.
So how do I render my
There are four things
Okay. Let's look at
or post-tess vertex shader;
from the regular vertex shader?
How do I pass my patch inputs?
And I told you that the
So let's look at
and then draw patches.
So, well, meet the new shader,
So in fact, you declare a
with a vertex qualifier.
But in addition to that, you
which says, "Hey, it's
There are two kinds of patches
And you see the number
That number tells you how many
working on.
So if you had a regular
you would have passed
Now you pass a patchID as input.
Remember I told you the
parametric UV coordinate?
Well, that's what this
And then if you had a
you would have passed
the patch input we
Everything else you
and you're generating a
And that's actually going
because the next stage with
or without tessellation
All right.
So let's look at patch inputs.
So if you had a regular
you would have described
as a struct, okay,
And if you had decoupled the
and the buffers where the
from do not match the
then you would have used
to describe the layout.
Well, for patches
One is the per-patch input.
And remember, I told there are
So we need to specify
But it looks identical
So you use a MTLVertexDescriptor
of the patch input
And as I showed you the slide
as a stage in as well.
And you use the attribute index
in the shader with the
in your MTLVertexDescriptor.
Since there can be more than one
to declare it using
And I'll talk about
So let's look at an example.
So here I have my
It has two elements.
So I'm using attributes
And my per-patch data, which
So we combine these
and this is my patch
So notice that control templated
underscore point.
So that's what tells the
this is referring to
Okay? And remember I told
or whatever the number is?
That also tells the Metal
control-points there are.
So now we have all information
And so we just pass
It's pretty simple, I think.
All right.
So okay, how do I
So there are properties
in the
can set.
A few examples are you can tell
want to use to generate
it's called the partitioning
You can also specify a
And we think this is
because it allows you to control
that the GPU will generate
Remember, the tessellator
So you need to specify the
So use the
to do that.
Now, these factors,
to subdivide the patches along
So we have two kinds of patches.
If it's a triangular patch,
there are three edges
If it's a quad, then you have
So you specify these as half
that you pass in.
And then drawing.
So today when you're
you're sending triangles
you're either going
or drawIndexPrimitives.
You the specify the start
And if your vertex
you will pass an index buffer.
Well, to draw patches,
or drawIndexedPatches.
You specify the start patch,
And if you're control-point
you specify an index buffer.
So it's just a one-to-one
And then there is the
And what these are is
where the start patch
and other information when
but instead you pass a buffer.
And that gets filled out
by a command that's running on
for drawPrimitives as well.
So really, if you don't know
then drawPatches just
Okay? So we think this
All right?
So hold on.
So I've shown you what
and how to use it.
As many of you may
or already using tessellation in
or OpenGL, you will notice
little different.
Don't worry.
We've designed Metal
so it's incredibly
to move your existing
As an example, for the past
with Unity.
And in an incredibly short
to integrate Metal
And here's what they
So we're really excited that
Metal Compute and the ability
in Unity's coming
It's incredibly exciting.
And we've also been
to efficiently integrate Metal
And Epic is planning to
in UE4 later this year, okay?
So we have UE4, we have Unity
Well, let me show you
in these game engines
by demonstrating two commonly
adaptive tessellation
All right.
So here we have a
by a few Apple engineers
So let's turn tessellation
and get wire frame mode.
You can see there are not a lot
of triangles being
This is great.
This is exactly what we want.
We want to keep the amount of
to be as little as possible.
Let's turn tessellation
You can see now the GPU is
And adaptive tessellation
to control the geometric
So in this example we've decided
to the camera need more detail.
So let's draw them with
versus objects further
So the regions in blue represent
of tessellation, and the region
with the highest
I can show you as I move
I can use that to increase
and you can see objects
Okay? Well, let's turn
And if you run -- as we
you can see there's a
If I turn tessellation off, all
Turn tessellation on,
So this is an example of
to really create rich visual
And I wanted to thank
for making this happen.
So the next demo is displacement
So here we have a
Well, let's look at how
to render the sphere.
Not a lot, right?
There are about 3,000 triangles.
And what displacement
that allows you to
to create incredible detail.
And it does that
using a displacement
So you look up, you know, from
and then use that to
Or you may actually do this
But displacement mapping
you're drawing lots and
really small triangles.
Otherwise it doesn't work.
It creates artifacts,
But that's fine, you know?
We can use tessellation.
That's what it's here for.
Because we still want
smaller triangles to the GPU
and use tessellation
So let's turn wire
and let's turn displacement
As you can see now incredible
If I turn wire frame mode on,
you can see we're generating
and they are really,
In fact, let's actually
so you can see the
and let's zoom in to see detail.
You can see self-shadowing
And the reason self-shadowing
because we're actually
unlike a technique many
with called bump mapping
which just creates an
So this is another
with tessellation to
in your application
And hey, thank you to
[ Applause ]
All right.
So
Metal Tessellation
to accelerate digital
As an example OpenSubdiv is an
by Pixar.
And it implements
subdivision surfaces.
Actually, it has been
of third-party digital
such as Maya from Autodesk.
And OpenSubdiv uses tessellation
to render these subdivision
Well, we -- Apple -- have
into OpenSubdiv.
And I'm really excited to
to release these changes
to the OpenSubdiv open source
Okay. I mean, here's
As you can see, Pixar's
to see a native Metal
of OpenSubdiv in iOS and macOS.
All right.
So now you may be asking,
How do I move my existing
Well, let me show you how.
So we'll take DirectX
but the same rules
So here is what the DirectX
like with tessellation.
We have three new stages --
They're called the hull
And then we have this
Right? So, well, okay.
How do I move this to Metal?
Notice where the
It sits right after
Does it remind you of any
in the Metal pipeline?
Yeah, I think so.
Yeah, post-tessellation
Because guess what?
The domain shader
with tessellation really
And just like you can
or GLSL vertex functions
you can move these domain
to the post-tessellation
The tessellator is exactly
So really, we have this
the vertex and hull shader.
And we got to make
Okay. Let's look at
So let's look at some --
that means there's probably
at runtime by the application.
And that means -- because
to be decoupled.
So that means I need
But I don't do stage
Right? Well, now you can.
We've added support for it.
So just like in a vertex
in to say this is my vertex
in to say this my
And you can specify
in a MTLStage
It behaves identically.
It's very similar to
Some of the things you
because this is for
And then two things to observe.
With tessellation
the vertex shader executes on
And the hull shader has
One that executes on a
that executes on a patch.
The per-patch hull function is
tessellation factors.
All right.
So the best thing to do?
Translate all these three
And then we'll write
that will call these functions.
But don't worry, we're not
The Metal compiler
Okay? So let's look
So each thread basically
to call the control-point
and for the hull, right?
So let's say there
So the first thread
and control-point hull function,
second thread does the
Right? And any intermittent data
to share, they'll put that
which is this local memory
which is high-performance,
So we're not going
And then if there were
there will be 16 threads
Only one of them need to execute
That means you typically
and then you will execute --
only one of the thread will
You have a conditional
is my thread in thread
Then call this thing."
And this is the function
that will output the
to graphics memory.
If you had any additional
to output, you could do so.
And if you really, really,
to output the control-point
But we find in most case the
passed through.
It's the nature of
and these are the existing API's
which requires you
But you're just passing them
You already have them
All right.
Let me close.
So I hope I have shown you
that Metal Tessellation
We designed it from the
I've shown you how easy it is
to adapt your existing
It's available on iOS and macOS.
So now it's your turn.
Show us, you know,
and create some amazing visuals
that you can render
So I want to thank
I'm going to call my colleague,
to you about resource heaps
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thank you, Aaftab.
For the next part of
to introduce two new Metal
and tvOS - resource heaps and
These features enable
of your resource
and memory efficiency.
I'll introduce resource
followed by memoryless
So resource heaps are a
management option in Metal.
Now, you can already create
so why do we need another way?
Well, creating resources
with a device is
and many developers
On the other hand, as many
of your Metal apps
and complex scenes, you
over your Metal resources
and memory efficiency.
That's why we are
Resource heaps enable fast
through resource sub-allocation.
The flexibility of resource
by allowing multiple
And finally, the
of resource heaps is made
over tracking resource
with explicit command
Now, let's dive into each one
with resource sub-allocation.
Before talking about the
let's first discuss why
is expensive.
Creating an individual resource
with a Metal device
Allocating the memory; preparing
clearing the memory for
creating the Metal object.
Each one of these steps
of the time is spent
But there are situations when
on your performance-critical
without introducing
Texture streaming is one example
or perhaps you have an image
to generate a number
of temporary textures
The cost of binding resources
to command encoders can also
Metal must track each
to a command encoder
that the GPU can
And for complex scenes, this
Resource sub-allocation
of these performance issues.
Remember that the expensive
in the memory operations.
With resource heaps you can
ahead of time outside
Resource heaps address the
to sub-allocate many logical
By sub-allocating multiple
Metal tracks one memory
of one per individual resource.
This significantly reduces
Now, let's compare
between the Metal device and
When you create a resource with
and prepare a block of memory
and then create the
So for four resources,
or prepare four blocks
Now, compare that
When you use a MTLHeap
you first create the heap
Memory will allocate and
of the requested size.
And if you do this ahead of time
the expensive part of
Now, to create four
Metal only needs to reserve
and create the resource
This is much faster.
Now let's see what
to release some resources.
When a device-based
the Metal object is destroyed,
but the device will also free
On the other hand, when
only the object is destroyed.
The memory is still
So creating a new resource
on the device will incur another
whereas the heap can quickly
to another resource.
Let me show you how easy it is
to sub-allocate Metal
So like many Metal objects,
the Metal resource heap has a
So let's create a heap
to the amount of
With the heap descriptor
to create us a heap object.
Remember, this is the slower
of time, like when
or at content loading time.
With the constructed heap,
we can call its resource
which should look very
and arguments are the same
So before moving on
like to share some
for using resource heaps
Now, the most important tip
to create resources on your
Creating resources using
for your game loop;
Allocating resources of varying
of a heap's memory
if the resources have
So use multiple heaps and
to limit the effects
Now, you may also
to choose an appropriate
Well, Metal provides two new
to query the size and alignment
Use these queries to help
that you need.
Okay. Let's move on
of resource heaps --
Resource aliasing allows
to occupy the same memory,
therefore reducing the
of the resources.
Dynamic resources have contents
and include things like your
or temporary textures
Here we have a heap containing
Compare that to this heap
resources but now
Now, you can obviously see
that the aliasing resources can
Let's apply resource
The shadow map passes render
one for each light in the scene.
So here in our heap we have
And in the main pass during
will sample the shadow
if each object is in shadow.
Now, after the main
for the shadow maps are
They will be regenerated
So after the main pass ends, we
that can consist of a number
each executing a specific
These filters will store
to pass filter results to
Now, the key takeaway
for the shadow maps and the
never used at the same time.
So why not share the memory?
So let me show you how to create
with Swift.
Now, the first section
First we ask the device
and we create our
Okay. Now we see a new
By calling makeAliasable
on a heap resource you are
that resource's memory
The shadow maps are still
to be reassigned by the
So now when we create the
on the same heap, they
as the shadow maps.
So now let's talk about
for resource aliasing.
To maximize memory reuse
for dynamic resources call
in the same sequence that their
That will allow you to
that will allow you to
when the resource contents
And you want to keep dynamic
and static resources
Static resources are generally
up preventing dynamic
with each other due
to fragmentation of
Next I'm going to talk about how
to your heap resources.
So, so far we have discussed
with sub-allocation and
with resource aliasing.
But remember that resource
because you control
of heap resources.
This is something
with device resources.
But unlike device
when a command modifies the
like when a render pass stores
Metal also doesn't know when
of the heap's memory from
But for correctness,
when a command is
so that other commands can
This is especially important
because the GPU can execute
So to synchronize
your application will
to communicate resource
Let's take a closer look
So a GPU fence is the timestamp.
It is a reference point in
Now, you can encode
to synchronize commands.
A command can update a fence
when the command is finished.
And a command can wait
until the GPU has reached
before executing.
Okay. Let's bring back
and I will show you
to synchronize command access
So here again is the example
but now we have five
of the render stages, render
and fragment processing steps.
So we have a shadow
and finally a post-processing
that we will execute
So Metal commands are submitted
in serial order to
So maybe it's not quite clear
yet why we need any
But GPUs are very parallel
on multiple commands
GPUs in our iOS and tvOS
fragment, and compute
to maximize GPU utilization.
The GPU can even be working
on multiple frames
All right.
So maybe now you spot a problem.
Look at these two commands
They are both updating
and heap resources
We have to use a
So first let's bring in a fence.
The post-process command
so that the shadow commands
wait on the fence.
Right? So now the two
at the same time anymore.
So I'm going to show you how
and fence wait with Swift.
First, we create a
This is a new method
Next, let's encode the
at the end of the first frame.
We first create a
and encode the dispatches.
But before we end the encoder,
so that subsequent
until this command has
So in the next frame we would
So we create a
in commandBufB, which
for the next frame.
But before drawing the scene,
to wait until the
on the GPU.
Now, notice this time
There's a second argument
Render commands execute in two
So Metal allows you to specify
to wait for the fence.
In our example only the
to access the heap resources, so
Finally, we can render
because we know that this
after the previous frame's
Okay. Let me talk about
for command synchronization.
So you know that if you use
to synchronize command access.
But you are given this control
because you know you
about how your resources
and your application will
than if Metal were to
For example, textures
and never modified don't
And as another example,
resources that are used
with a single fence.
So let me summarize the main
Create resources faster
Use your memory budget
with resource aliasing.
And synchronize your
across GPU commands
Okay. Now I'd like to introduce
in iOS and tvOS:
Now, this sounds
but I will show you how almost
feature to save a
with a single line of code.
So memoryless render
that do not allocate any system
Without any memory backing
what remains is the
such as the texture's dimensions
Now obviously this is
but when can you use a
You can use them for render pass
Most Metal apps will have
with a store action of don't
And the textures used for those
be memoryless.
To make a memoryless
you can simply create the
with an additional
MTLStorageModeMemoryless.
That's it.
This feature is supported
because it relies
on the tile-based
of A7 and later GPUs.
Let me show you how
Here on your right we have
a color attachment and
Now, A7 and later GPUs
at a time, taking advantage
at the heart of the GPU.
The GPU tile storage contains
of your depth, stencil,
And this tile storage
from the texture backing
Now, in Metal your load and
to initialize the GPU
to copy the results from
to system memory.
If an attachment is not loaded
to memory, you can
for that attachment memoryless
to eliminate the
Next, I'll describe some
where you can apply this
Depth attachments
to enable depth testing
But the A7 and later GPUs
in GPU tile storage
Depth testing does not
So if you don't store the depth
make the texture memoryless
Let me show you another
When executing multisample
the A7 and later GPUs
in GPU tile storage.
The MSAA color attachment
if you choose to store the
But most apps will choose the
which results directly
to the resolve color
So in that case make the
texture memoryless and this
As you can see, the savings
for adopting this
By making a 1080p depth
your app will save
If you are rendering to
of a 12.9-inch iPad Pro,
the savings for the depth
And the savings for making a
target memoryless are even
So use memoryless render
of your application's
Use the savings to lower the
Or better yet, use the
and unique content to your game.
Okay. I'd like to invite
about the improvements
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, James.
So outside the great additions
to the Metal API we did
to Metal Developer Tools
First we'll talk about
Than we'll introduce a new
And we have some very
to GPU Frame Debugger.
So what is Metal System Trace?
In the [inaudible] Metal session
you Metal working on
Metal System Trace is
for visualizing just that,
helping you understand
of your Metal applications
through the whole graphic
to the GPU, and then
Last year at WWDC we
for iOS platform.
I highly recommend checking
for a great overview
Later in the fall we
And today we're happy to
for macOS to help you squeeze
on all Metal platforms.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; We improved Metal System
extending the events
[Inaudible] events,
we visualized expensive resource
from system memory
Like in this case where we
which is causing a
Metal System Trace also
which make it easier for you
to understand command encoded
On macOS we support tracing
which is unbelievable
where you're distributing
And on iOS we now
so that you can diagnose when
by rotating or scaling
You can now use a wider range
of instruments alongside
such as Time Profiler,
Allocations, and many more.
Even different views
which will show you
These will help you to correlate
deepening the understanding
of how the system is
and allowing you
such as GPU starvation
to a [inaudible] operation.
Metal System Trace
So we made it easier for you
With the new workload
on any command encoder
as it works through
And with with support
you can quickly move your
Finally, I want to introduce
And what Performance
with a comprehensive list of
in your trace from analyzing it.
From display surface
to unexpected shader
or high GPU execution times,
for you the events which
which you can navigate
from the Performance
All these new additions
to tune your Metal
as you want them to be.
And now for a demonstration
of our awesome GPU
let me hand over to
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jose.
I have a number of great
So let's dive right in.
I have my app running here,
cruising over beautiful terrain
Wouldn't it be great to see
to see triangles individually?
The good news is our newest
gives you ability to modify
from the debug bar while
We have a number of different
including wire frame mode.
Let's switch to wire frame mode
to see how tessellated
Visualizing each
to tune your tessellation
between performance
Normally you'd have to go back
and change your code,
But with GPU Overrides,
with your tessellation scaling
Let's set scaling to 25%.
Now we have far less
of the interesting details.
Let's try 75%.
I think this looks better.
Let's see it without
Okay. I like this one.
Now, we have less triangles
but still have all
And with the performance gains,
I can add more cool
So as seen here, GPU Overrides
with initial diagnosis
and performance problems
Next, let's capture the frame
that will greatly improve
The frame capture is
for the terrain resources to
Let's switch to all GPU
where you can see all
So we have all of
And going over everything
to find terrain resources
This is where the new
You can filter by any properties
type, size, or details.
Since I labeled all
I'll just filter by terrain.
And right here I have
for rendering the terrain.
Now that I found the terrain
like to do is to see where
With a simple drag and drop I
to show me all the
to terrain patches
In this case, I see where it
and where it says [inaudible]
This filter is really powerful.
I can also use any
of the bound resources
For example, if you
you'll see all the draw calls
with SRGB pixel format.
This is a natural
around your frame quickly.
Next, let's move
to see how we are using these
In bound mode your
under different sections
of the Metal pipeline
in so you know exactly
Looking at the vertex stage,
terrain patches is a buffer
with different offsets.
Let's use our only buffer
All the vertex data
with the layout except
with patches.
So this is using the
as your post-vertex function.
And we have a color data here.
It recognizes the word color
of the value right in there.
Since this is a large buffer
of data, I have added
with the new [inaudible] API,
to find what you
With the layout menu,
to any other available layout
Looking at individual
What is even better is the
which lets you see
as your vertex shader sees it.
Input attributes collects all
tessellation factor buffers,
then provides you a single view
In this case we are rendering
and I can see what data belongs
So that was a quick look at some
of our newest GPU Frame
Let's switch back to
[ Applause ]
So you've just seen some
of our newest GPU Frame
I would like to tell
With the new Extended Validation
perform even deeper
providing recommendations
usage or storage mode
You can enable this mode from
And the new support
for stand-alone Metal Library
libraries to be shared
or include multiple of
like any other framework
So we talked about features
that will greatly improve
Now let's summarize what we have
We have seen the great additions
resource heaps and
then we showed you improved
and GPU Frame Debugger.
Be sure to stick around
where I will talk about
and function resource
and texture assets,
to Metal performance shaders.
For more information
please check the link online.
You can catch the
to documentation
We had great sessions yesterday,
And this afternoon we have
then Advanced Metal Shader
Thanks for coming,
[ Applause ]