[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
This is Part 2 of our
My name is Charles Brissart,
and together with my colleague,
I will be telling you about
But first, let's take a look
at the other Metal
The first two sessions I call
of the basic concepts
as some more advanced
The What's New in Metal session
Finally, the Advanced Shadow
you how to get the best
So this morning you were
resource heaps, memoryless
as some improvement
This afternoon we'll tell you
function resource read-writes,
as well as some addition to
So let's get started with
It is a common pattern
to define a few complex
and then use those master
of specialized simple functions.
The idea is that the
to avoid duplicating card while
simpler on those as a result
So let's take an example.
If we are trying to write a
write a master function
of any material that
But then, if you are trying
a simple shiny material,
you would probably
but you will need a
If you implement a
on the other hand you will
on also the specular highlights.
Our transition material will
but probably no reflection
or may be no specular
You get the idea.
So this is typically implemented
The master function is
for the macro to create
This can be done at runtime,
You can also try to
of the precompiled function, but
but this requires
because you can have
or maybe you don't know
Another approach is to
Runtime constants avoid the need
However, you need to
of the constant at runtime.
That will impact the
So we are proposing a new way
to create specialized
function constants.
So function constants
that are defined directly in
and can be compiled into IR
Then at runtime you can provide
to create a specialized
The advantage of
that you can compile the
and store it in the Metal lib.
The storage requirement is small
because you only store
And since we run a
when we create the
you still get the
So let's look at an example.
This is what a master
like using a preprocessor macro.
Of course, this is
A real one would be
As you can see, different parts
if statements so that
that section of the code.
Here is what it would look
As you can see at the top,
of constants, and then
To define the constants, you use
by the type, in this case
of the constant and the
The function constant attribute
of the constant is not going
but will be provided at runtime
when we create the
You should also note that
That index can be used
to identify the constant when we
at runtime.
You can then use the
like your normal constant.
Here we have a simple if
to conditionalize
So once you've created your
and stored it in a Metal lib,
you need to at runtime
So you need to provide the
To do that, we use an MTL
that will solve the values
Once we created the object,
of a constant either by
Once we have created an object,
we can then create the
by simply coding the
and constant values on the
of the master function as well
This will return a regular MTL
to create compute pipeline
on the type of the function.
So to better understand
let's look at the
So at build time, you use the
and compile it and
At runtime you load
and create a new function using
to specialize the function.
At this point, we
to eliminate any code
and then we have an interior
to create a render pipeline
You can declare constants
that is [inaudible]
half, int, uint, and so on.
Here we are defining
You can also create intermediate
of function constants.
Here we're defining
that has the opposite value
Here we are calculating a
of the value function constant.
We can also have
Optional constants are constants
to always provide the value when
This is exactly the same
in your code when using
To do this, you use the if
in that will return true if
and false if otherwise.
You can also use
or eliminate arguments
This is useful to avoid, to
to bind a buffer or texture
if you know it's not
It's also useful to replace
and we'll talk about --
we'll talk more about this
So here we have an example.
This is a vertex function that
of the value of the
The first argument of the
that will exist depending
on whether the doSkinning
We use the function
that argument as being optional.
In the code, you still need to
to protect the code
So here we use doSkinning
and then we can use the
You can as well use function
from the stage in struct.
Here, we have two
The first color argument
for attributes, that
The second lowp color is a
but is overriding the
So you can have either
These are used to
of the color attributes
There are some limitations with
you cannot really change the
and that can be a problem
to have different constants for
But you can work around that
but adding multiple arguments
So in this example, we
that are using buffer index 1.
They are controlled
use ConstantA and ConstantB.
So these are used to
Note that we have -- we use
that is the opposite
to make sure only one
of the arguments will
So in summary, you can
to create specialized
It avoids front end compilation,
and it only uses fast
to eliminate unused code.
The storage is compact
to store the master
You don't have to
It can only ship the IR.
And finally, the unused
which gives you the
So let's now talk about
So we're introducing
function buffered read-writes
and function texture
Function buffered read-writes
to a buffer from any function
to use atomic operations
from any function type.
As you guessed, function texture
to read and write to texture
Function buffer read-writes
with a 9 processor and macOS.
Function texture read-writes
So let's talk about function
So what's new here?
What's new is the
from fragment function as well
in the text and fragment
These can be used to
as order-independent
of lights that affect
or simply to debug your shaders.
So let's look at
Let's say we want to
of the visible fragments
It could look like this.
So we have a fragment function
to which we pass
The output buffer is
to store the position
Then we have a counter, so
after [inaudible] that we
into the buffer,
to which we want to write.
We can then use an atomic
of fragments with that
to get an index in the buffer.
And then we can write into
of the fragments.
So this looks pretty good,
The depth and stencil
to buffer is actually
after the fragment shader.
So this is a problem
to still perform the
which is not what we want.
We only want the
It's also something to be aware
of because it will
That means we don't have any
so we are going to
when we probably
Fortunately we have a new
fragment test that can be
and stencil test to appear
As a result, if the depth test
of the fragment shader and
So this is what we need here,
with the early fragment test
to only execute the function
Now let's talk about
So what's new is the ability to
and fragment functions as well
to a texture from
This can be used, for
when implementing post
by using the same texture
So writing to texture
You just define your texture
and then you can
Read-write texture, a texture
that you can both read
Only a limited number of formats
To use the read-write texture
qualifier of read-write, and
and write to it in your shader.
However, you have to be careful
if you want to read the results,
if you want to read the same
In this case, you need
The texture fence will ensure
that the writes have
so that you can read
Here, we write to a given pixel,
to make sure we can
and then we can finally
We should also be
because they only apply
which means that if you have
to a texture and the
to read the value that was
even after a texture
What will work is if each thread
that it was writing
that are written
So one note about reading,
to buffers and textures.
With vertex and fragment
you have to be careful.
In this example, fragment
is writing to a buffer
and a vertex function is
However, this is
because of having the
To fix this, we need to use
The fragment function
in the first
texture -- the vertex function
in the second
read the result and
You should note that
this is not necessary.
It can be done the same
So in summary, we
function buffer read-writes and
You can use early fragment
and stencil test is done
of the fragment shader.
You should use a texture fence
from a read-write texture
And finally, when using vertex
to buffers, you need
to use a different
when you want to
So with this, I will hand the
to you about wide color.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Charles.
Thank you.
As Charles mentioned,
I work as an engineer in Apple's
and I'd like to start
about color management,
that all developers are
So if you are an
either a texture artist
or a photographer editing
you would have a particular
and you'd choose
And you'd want consistency
on which your content is viewed.
Now it's our responsibility
and software engineers to
If you're using a high level
SpriteKit, or Core Graphics,
for you, and you
as app developers don't
Metal, however, is a
This offers increased
but also places some of this
So why now?
You've been able to
with different color spaces
with Apple devices
Well, late last year, Apple
with a display capable
in the P3 color space.
And in April, we introduced
which also has a P3 display.
So what is the P3 color space?
Well, this is a chromaticity
and conceptually this
in the visual spectrum, in
that the normal human
Of that, within this
that a standard sRGB
The P3 display is able
of a much broader variety.
So here's how it works on macOS.
We want you to be able to
and as I mentioned, high level
this job of color
by performing an operation
where your color and one
of the display color space
on the display regardless
that you're working
Now, Metal views by default
This color match
and this generally offers
So by default, you're
of the display, and therefore,
the display will interpret
Now, this means that sRGB
as P3 colors, and rendering will
So if this is your application
and this is the display, well,
these colors become
So why does this happen?
Well, let's go back to
This is the most green
in the sRGB color space,
you'd represent this as
1.0 in the green channel
Well, the P3 Display
and interprets it,
and it basically thinks
So you're getting the most
which happens to be a
Now, for content creation
that you get this right because
consideration to
For games, the effect is more
and artists are looking for this
they're going to be disappointed
and happy when you
Also, this problem can get worse
as the industry moves towards
So, the solution is
You enable color management
by setting the color space
probably the sRGB color space.
This causes the OS to
of its window server's
So if here's your
here's your application
and here's the display,
the window server takes your
and performs the color match
Now, all right, so now
What if you want to
You want to purposefully render
gamut display is only
Well, first of all, you
You need your artist to
and for that we recommend
color space.
This allows existing assets that
to continue working
and your shader pipelines don't
However, your artists can
that will provide much
So what exactly is the
Well here's the sRGB
Extended range sRGB
in all directions, meaning
in your shader represent
on a wider than sRGB
So I mentioned values
This means that you will need to
to express such values, and for
couple of formats.
You can use the BC6H
It's a compressed format
as well as the pack float
For your render targets, you
or the RGBA half-float
to specify these
Color management on
You always render in
even when targeting
Colors are automatically matched
And if you want to use wide
of some new pixel formats
that are natively
There's no compositing
They can be gamma encoded,
and allowing you to do linear
and they're efficient for
All right.
Here are the bit layouts
So, there are -- there
with 10 bits per channel
Now, this, the values
can express values
Values from 0 to 384 represent
the next 510 values, represent
and those greater than
intense values.
Now, note here that the RGBA
and therefore uses twice
as much bandwidth
So, in general, we recommend
in the CAMetal Layer if
All right, so you've made
to create some wide
How can you do this?
Well, you have an artist --
author using image
which supports the P3 color
You can save that image as
or JPEG using the
Now, once you've got this image,
how do you create
Well, you've got
The first is you can create your
and from that 16-bit per channel
using the extended sRGB floating
the ImageIO or vImage
And then from that on
of those floating point pixel
and on iOS you'd convert to one
of those extended range pixel
All right, so that's option one
if you really want
of how your textures are built.
The next option is
for textures in asset
With that, will automatically
textures for devices
and I'll talk a little bit more
about asset catalogues
So for a while now you've been
into an asset catalogue
Last year, we introduced app
a specialized version
for various devices based
such as the amount of memory,
or the type of device, whether
or watch or even
And when your app was
and install only the single
for that device with the
The asset was compressed over
saving a lot of storage
and there were numerous APIs,
which offer efficient
So now we've added texture
So what does this offer?
Well, storage for mipmap levels.
Textures are more
You can perform offline mipmap
will automatically color
So if it's a wide gamut texture
will perform a color
or extended range
And I think the most important
that we can choose the
for every device on
So on newer devices that support
we can use that format.
On older devices which
we can choose either
or some other compressed format.
Additionally, we can
for devices with a P3 Display.
So here's the basic workflow.
You create texture
You assign a name to the
You'll add an image and
that texture will be used,
or some other type of data like
Then, you'll -- can
Xcode will build this texture
and deliver it to
Now, you can create these
or programmatically.
Once your texture is on the
to MetalKit, and MetalKit
a Metal texture,
So I'd like to walk you
to introduce some of
So, you'll first select
in your projects
and then hit this plus button
Now, here's where you can create
There are image sets, icon
as well as texture and
So once you've created
you need to name it.
Now, your naming
If you have a number of textures
one for each object, you can
and stuff your base texture
and your hierarchy can be
You add your image, and then
Now there are three
Color, in color NonPremultiplied
match operation.
The NonPremultiplied option
by your R, B, and G --
RGB channels before
The data option here will
height maps, roughness maps,
Now, this is all you need to do.
Xcode will go off and
of this texture, and it
pixel format.
You can, however, have
You can select any number
which will open up
that you can select
You can add different
You probably wouldn't
but may be a different
So on a device with
you can use a bigger
with a smaller memory, you would
And then you can specify how
The all option will
down to the 1 by 1 level and the
some more explicit control,
to use a max level and
to have different
And finally, you can override
of pixel formats.
Now I mentioned that you can
texture sets.
You don't really want to
if you've got thousands
So there's a pretty
and within that directory
of JSON files.
Now these files and directory
on the asset catalogue
So you can create your own
to set up your texture set.
So once you've got this
how do you make use of it?
Well, you create a MetalKit
Metal device, and then
with its hierarchy
and MetalKit will go off
You can supply a couple
such as scale factor if
of the texture for different
if the asset catalogue is
in something other
There are also a couple
of options here that
So I'd really like you to
and set your apps apart
by creating content
Asset catalogues can help
As well, they provide a
which you can make use of,
such as optimal pixel
I'd like to have my colleague
about some exciting improvements
to the Metal Performance
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. Good afternoon.
Thank you, Dan, for
As Dan said, my name is Anna.
I'm an engineer on
So let's talk about
to the Metal Performance
We introduced the Metal
last year in the What's
If you haven't seen
you should definitely
But just to give
the Metal Performance Shaders
of optimized high performance
for the GPU in Metal .
The algorithms are
and they have been available
and now the A9 processors.
The framework is designed
into your Metal applications
It should be as simple as
So last year, we talked
of supported image operations,
for lots of details
But this year, we've added
We've added wide color
to convert your Metal textures
You can convert between
C3 and any color
We've also added Gaussian
to create multiscaler
on the GPU to enable
They can also be used for
image blending, and
And finally, we've added
or CNNs, which are used
to accelerate deep
This is going to be the
So let's just dive right in.
First of all, what
Deep learning is a field of
to answer this question.
Can a machine do the same
Well, what types of
Each one of you has an
You probably took a
and all of us are constantly
on the Web every day, on
When you see an image, you
on it.
You can detect faces.
If you know these
You can annotate this image.
And this works well
but what if you have more
Think about all of the images
No human can hand
So deep learning is a technique
for solving these
It can be used for sifting
and for answering questions
And "Where was it taken?"
But I'm using image-based
because they are visual.
So they are a great fit for
but I just want to mention
that deep learning
for other types of data.
For example, other types
to do speech recognition
to create the sense of touch.
Deep learning algorithms
The first one is
So let's talk about it,
So image that you
to categorize images
This is an image of a cat.
This is an image of a dog.
This is the image of a rabbit.
This is a labor intensive task
of images, hand-labeled
for each one of these
So for example, if you
to recognize cats, you need to
of cats all labeled, and
and all the other animals
to be able to recognize.
This is a one-time
It's usually done offline,
of training packages
The result of the training
So I will not talk
but we will get back
The trained parameters are
which is the inference phase.
This is the phase where
with a new image that has
to classify in real-time.
So in this example, the system
as an image of a cat.
We provide GPU acceleration
Specifically, we give
to build your inference
So let's now talk about what
networks and what are these
The convolutional
are biologically
to resemble the visual cortex.
When our brain processes visual
of neurons that receive
in the visual cortex are
or blobs of color, while
down the visual pipeline respond
like faces or kinds of animals.
So in a very similar way,
the convolutional neural
into layers of neurons
to recognize increasingly
So the first layers are trained
like edges and blobs of color,
while the subsequent
to recognize higher
So for example, if we
then will have layers that will
eyes, cheeks, and then
and then finally faces.
And then the final few layers
information to produce the
such as the probability that
And I keep mentioning features.
Think of a feature as a
for that feature,
and if that information is
If that feature is found, this
to the subsequent layers.
And, of course, we need to
So if we're doing face
for just noses is
We also need to look for other
eyes, and then combinations
So we need many of
So now that I've covered
let's talk about the
The first building
We want you to use MPS images
which we added specifically to
They provide and optimize layout
and intermediate results.
Think of MPS temporary images
which we want you to
with a transient lifetime.
MPS temporary images are built
which were described in the
They address some of
and they avoid expensive
and deallocation of
So the goal is to save
and to help you manage
We also provide a collection
to create your inference
But you may be thinking
which building blocks
to build my own inference
So the answer is
The trained parameters, I
when we talked about
The trained parameters give
to build your inference
They tell you how many
what kind they will be, in
and you also get all those
So we take care of everything
that the networks you build
the best possible
All you have to do
into this optimized
and to call library
that make up your network.
So now let's discuss all these
but let's do it in a context
So in this demo, I have a system
that has been trained
And what we'll have is
in real-time the system will
or not.
So I will first smile,
and you will see the
[ Laughter ]
All right.
So that [inaudible] my demo.
[ Applause ]
Okay. So now let's take a
that I needed to build
So the first building
about is the convolution layer.
It's the core building block of
and its goal is to
And it's called a
because it performs a
So let's recall how
You have your input and your
by 5 pixel filter
And in order to compute
in your output, you need
to convolve the filter
Pretty easy.
The convolution layer
of regular convolution.
It allows you to have
The different filters are
resulting in different
So if you have 16 filters.
That means you have
So in order to get the value of
of the output, you need
and convolve it with the input.
And in order to get the value of
of the output, you need
and convolve it with your input.
Of course, in our examples,
mild detection we are
So that means that your input
channels, and just because
networks work, you need
where you have one set
And then you apply
to separate input channels
to get a single output value.
So this is how you
of these convolution
You first create a descriptor
as the width and height of the
and then the number of
And then you create
from this descriptor and
for the feature filters,
from the trained parameters.
The next layer we are going to
The function of the
to progressively reduce the
which reduces the
for the subsequent layers.
And it's common to
in between successive
Another function of the
or condense information
and it would provide two pooling
So in this example, we take a 2
We take the maximum value
And this is the API
in the Metal Performance
of these pooling layers.
It's common to use
with a filter size of 2 by 2.
The fully connected layer is
in the input is connected to
But think about it as a special
where the filter size is
So in this example, we have
as the input, and
to get a single output value.
So in this architecture,
and pooling layers operate
while the fully connected
to aggregate information
It's usually one of the
and this is where your final
and you create -- you generate
such as the probability that
And this is how you
of these fully connected layers
in the Metal Performance
You create a convolution
because this is a special
and then you create a
from this descriptor.
We'll also provide
which I'm not going to cover
but they are described
We provide the neural
in conjunction with
and we also provide the soft
So now that we've
let's talk about your data.
I mentioned that you
So what are they really?
Most of you are already
So this is a 2D Metal
where every channel corresponds
And I mentioned in my
to create images with
for example, 32 channels.
If we have 32 feature filters,
we need to create
an output image that
So how do we do this?
So an MPS image is really
with multiple slices.
And when you're creating
all you really should
that you are creating an image
But sometimes you may need to
to the CPU, or you may want
to use an existing Metal 2D
So for those cases,
that we use a special
So every pixel in a slice
of the structure contains
So a 32-channel image would
And this is the API you
of the MPS images
You first create a descriptor
as the channel for data format
and the number of channels.
And then you create an MPS image
from this descriptor,
Of course, if you have
then you should batch them
and we provide a simple
So in this example, we create
Okay, so now that we've
we've covered data, and
at the actual network you need
So we start with our
to use the trained parameters
to help us build this network.
So the trained parameters
in this network is going
which takes a three-channel
and outputs a 16-channel image.
The trained parameters also give
for this layer, and these
the visualization of
after the filters have
The next layer is
which reduces the spatial
of the convolution layer by a
The trained parameters tell us
that the next layer is
which takes a 16-channel
and outputs a 16-channel image,
in size by the next
and so on until we
As you can see, this
of convolution layers
and the last two layers are
which generate the final
So now that we know what this
and this is very common for a
for inference, so now
to create it in our framework.
So the first step is
Once again, the trained
to have four convolution layers
that the code had to create
but as you can see, I'm
that I've showed you before.
Then we need to create
We just need one because
to be using the max operation
And we also need to create
and once again I'm only
for one for simplicity.
And now, we need to take
In this particular
that we have an existing Metal
that you would like to use
and this is the API that you
from existing Metal textures.
And so the last step is
into an existing command
by the trained parameters.
So we have our input and our
that we need one more
We need to store the output
So let's use MPS
This is how you would create
As you can see, this
to the way you would
And now we immediately use it
And the temporary image
as the command buffer
And then we continue.
We create another temporary
of the second layer, and so
That's it.
And just to tie it
the order in which you encode
diagram that I showed
so starting from the input
So now we worked through
Let's look at a more
We've ported the
from tensor flow to run
Shaders framework.
This is a very commonly
for object detection, and
for this network.
As you can see, this
that the previous
It has over 100 layers.
But just to remind you,
to call some library functions
And now first, let's take a
So here I have a collection of
and as soon as I
we will run the inference
and it will report
for what it thinks
So the top guess is
Then this is a pickup
So that looks pretty good
let's do a real live demo
And we'll take a picture
and let's use this
[ Applause ]
So what I wanted to show
that even a large network
in real-time using the Metal
but this is not all.
I also want to talk about
from using MPS temporary
So in the first version of
to store intermediate
up needing 74 MPS
over 80 megabytes for
And of course, you don't
You can come up with your
to reuse these images, but
in your code, and we want to
as easy for you to
So in the second
we replaced all the MPS images
and this gave us
The first one is reduced
and energy, but also creating
in just 5 underlying memory
over 20 megabytes and this
That's pretty huge.
So what I showed you with
that the Metal Performance
complete support for building
for inference, and it's
So please, use the
to build some cool apps.
So this is the end of
and if you haven't seen the
out the video so you can learn
as tessellation, resource heaps,
and improvements to our tools.
In this session, we talked
and function resource
and texture assets,
to the Metal performance
on convolutional
For more information about this
You can catch the
to related documentation
And here's some information
You could always
of the past Metal
but you can also catch
optimization talk later today,
of this talk has
Tomorrow, you have an
with White Color talk
and Accelerate talk
to create neural networks
for the CPU using the
So thank you very
and I hope you have
[ Applause ]