[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, hello everyone.
My name is Fiona and this
And I work on the iOS GPU
to make your shaders run
and to make them run as
And I'm here to talk
Advanced Metal Shader
and Polishing your
Our compiler is based on LVM.
And we work with the
to make LVM more suitable
Here's a quick overview of
in case you missed them,
and don't worry you can
Yesterday we had part one
and earlier today we had part
in Metal, because there's quite
And of course here's
the one you're watching
So in this presentation we're
of things you can do to
to make your code faster.
And some of this stuff is
and later GPUs including
that has never been
And some of it will
And we'll be noting that with
for slides that are
And additionally, we'll be
That is things that may not
of micro optimizations
but if you run into these,
so much performance, nothing is
So it's always worth making
And those will be marked
with the triangle icon,
Before we go on, this
This is the last step.
There's no point to doing
until you've done the
like watching the
from optimizing your
of your engine and so forth.
Optimizing your later shader
you do.
And, this presentation
for experienced shader authors.
Perhaps you've worked on Metal
to get more into optimizing your
to Metal, but you've done a
on other platforms and
to optimize better
this is the presentation
So you may have seen this
of the previous Metal talks.
And we will be focusing
on the programmable
as you can see there,
So first, Alex is going to go
over some shader
and higher level issues.
After which, I'll return
down and dirty shader
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Fiona.
Let me start by explaining
of shader performance
These are the things that
that you have right
into source level optimizations.
Usually the impact of the kind
of changes you'll
or potentially hide other
that you make elsewhere.
So I'm going to talk
Address space selection
buffer preloading, dealing
with fragment function
and how to optimize
So, let's start with
So since this functionality
in all shading languages,
So, GPUs have multiple paths
And these paths are optimized
and they have different
In Metal, we expose control
to the developer by requiring
arguments and pointers
with which address
So a couple of the address
to getting information
The first of which is
This is an address space with
You can read and write data
you can pass as much data as
that you specify at the API
alignment requirements.
On the other end of things, you
As the name implies, this is
but there are a couple of
There are limits on how
through this address space, and
that you specify at the API
alignment requirements.
However, this is the address
with a lot of data reuse.
So you want to take advantage
of this address space
Figuring out whether or not the
sense for your buffer
of asking yourself
The first question is, do I
And if you have a potentially
this is usually a
to be using the device
Additionally, you want to
in your buffer is being read.
And if these items can
this is usually a sign
into the constant address space.
So let's put this into practice
from some vertex shaders.
First, you have regular,
So as you can see, each vertex
And each vertex is the only one
So there's essentially
This is the kind of thing
in the device address space.
Next, you have projection
Now, typically what you have
of these objects, and they're
So with this kind of complete
to be in the constant
Let's mix things up a little bit
and take a look at
So hopefully in this case
of bones that you're handling.
But if you look at each
by every vertex that
and that also is a potential
And so this really ought to be
on the constant address
Finally, let's look
As you can see all vertices
in the instance will read
but on the other hand you have
of instances, so this
in the device address
For an example of why address
for performance, let's move
on to our next topic,
So Fiona will spend some
to actually optimize loads and
but for many cases the best
to actually off load this
So we can do this
context buffers and
But this relies on knowing
in your shaders and what address
So let's start with
So the idea here is
through the constant
what we can actually do is
into special constant
for the ALU to access.
So we can do this as long
as we know exactly
If your offsets are
this is straightforward.
But if your offsets aren't known
until run time then we need a
about how much data
So indicating this
to the compiler is usually
First, you need to make
in the constant address space.
And additionally
that your accesses are
The best way to do this
by reference rather than
If you're passing only a
this is straightforward, you
to references and change
This is a little different
that you know is bounded.
So what you do in this case is
and pass that struct
than passing the
So we can put this into
at a forward lighting
So as you can see in sort
of the original version what we
that are passed as
And this doesn't expose the
So we can do better than this.
Instead if we note the number
of lights is bonded what we can
and the count together into
And we can pass that struct
as a reference like this.
And so that gets us
Let's look at another example
of how this can affect
So, there are many ways to
but what we find is that the
that you make can have a big
that you achieve in practice.
One pattern that's common
to accumulate the
And what you can see form the
is that it can potentially read
and that means that your
Now, on the other hand if you're
such that each light is handled
in its own draw call
that each light only needs
and it's shader and that
in the constant address space
and take advantage
In practice we see
that this is a significant
Now let's talk about
The idea of vertex
to reuse the same dedicated
for a fix function
And we can do this for regular
that you access your
like fix function
So what that means
to be indexing using the
Now we can handle a couple
to the vertex or instance IDs
and that's with or
or instance offsets you might
Of course the easiest way to
to use the Metal vertex
wherever possible.
But if you are writing
we strongly suggest that
so that vertexes fetch linearly
Note that this doesn't preclude
like if you were rendering quads
to all vertices in the quad,
like indexing by vertex
because this just
So now let's move on to a couple
In iOS 10 we introduced the
from within your
And this has interesting
for hidden surface removal.
So prior to this you might have
that a fragment wouldn't
as an opaque fragment
So this is no longer
if your fragment function
because those resource
So instead your behavior
on what's come before.
And specifically what
or not you've enabled
on your fragment function.
If you have enabled
once it's rasterized as long
as it also passes the early
If you haven't specified
then your fragment
as long as it's rasterized.
So from a perspective of
what you want to do is
wherever possible.
But there are a couple
that you can do to improve
And most of these boil
You want to draw these objects,
the objects where the fragment
after opaque objects.
And if you're using these
and stencil buffers,
that you sort these
Note that this guidance
if you've been dealing
that do discard or modify
Now let's talk about
Since the defining
that you can structure your
Let's talk about what factors
on iOS.
First we have computer
So on A8 and later GPUs
that it takes to launch a
So if you don't do enough work
from within a single compute
it leaves the hardware
and leave performance
And a good way to deal with
for writing computer
to actually process multiple
in a single compute threat.
And in particular a pattern
to reuse values not
through thread group memory, but
for one work item when you're
in the same compute thread.
And it's best to illustrate
So this is a syllable
of the most straightforward
it reads as a three-
and produces one output pixel.
So if instead we
of processing multiple
in a single compute thread,
we get something
Notice now that we're striding
So processing the first pixel
We read the 3 by 3 region.
We apply the filter and
But now let's look at
So stents are striding by
to make sure that there is
And now we read its data.
Note here that a 2 by 3 region
of what this pixel
by the previous pixel.
So we don't need
we can reuse those old values.
All we need to load now is the 1
by 3 region that's
After which, we can apply
Note that as a result we're
instead of the old 9, but
So this is a significant
of texture reads per pixel.
Of course this pattern doesn't
Sometimes you do still
through thread group memory.
And in that case, when you're
in a thread group, an important
that you want to use the barrier
for the threads that
In particular, if your thread
the regular thread
in Metal is unnecessary.
What you can use instead is the
introduced in iOS 10.
And what we find is actually
to fit within a single SIMD
and using SIMD group barrier
to use a larger thread
that additional reuse,
but having to use thread
So that wraps things up
make sure you're using the
for each of your buffer
to the guidelines
Structure your data
to take maximal advantage
and vertex buffer preloading.
Make sure you're using early
as many fragments as possible
when you're doing
Put enough work in
so you're not being limited
by your compute thread
And use the smallest barrier
to synchronize between
And with that I'd like to pass
into tuning shader code.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Alex.
So, before jumping into the
over some general
and the bottlenecks
And all of you may be
but I figure I should
So with GPUs typically you
And it's fairly common for
by one of those resources.
And so for example if
by memory bandwidth,
in your shader will often
performance improvement.
And while it is important to
and focus on them to
there is actually still
that aren't bottlenecks.
For example, in that example
at memory usage, but then
to be more efficient, you
if you are not improving
And of course being on mobile,
saving power is always
So it's not something to ignore,
just because your frame rate
So there's four typical
in mind in shaders here.
The first is fairly
The amount of math
The second is memory bandwidth,
the amount of data that the GPU
The other two are
The first one is
Which represents the
that can be performed.
And this can come up in the case
where you have smaller
or you're using a lot of thread
And the last one, which I'll
about later is latency
You may have heard about that,
but I will save that
So to try to alleviate
and improve overall shader
we're going to look
of optimization opportunity
And the first one is data types.
And the first thing to consider
when optimizing your shader
And the most important
when you're choosing
and later GPUs have
which means that for example if
that's twice the register
potentially twice the
it's just twice as much stuff.
So, accordingly you
you will get faster performance,
by using smaller data types.
Use half and short for
Energy wise, half is
And float is cheaper
but even among integers,
than bigger ones.
And the most effective thing
to use half for texture reads
of the time you really do
And note I do not mean
I mean the data types you're
of a texture sample
And one aspect of A8 in later
and makes using smaller
than on some other GPUs is
that data type conversions
even between float and half,
to worry, oh am I introducing
by trying to use half here?
Is this going to cost too much?
Is it worth it or not?
No it's probably fast because
so you can use half wherever
about that part of it.
The one thing to keep
that half-precision numerics
and limitations are
And a common bug
for example is people will
but that is actually infinity.
Because that's bigger
And so by being aware of
you'll better be able to
and shouldn't use half.
And less likely to encounter
So one example application
for using smaller integer
And as those of you who worked
thread IDs are used
And so making them smaller
performance of arithmetic, and
And so local thread IDs, there's
for them as in this case,
because local thread IDs can't
For global thread IDs, usually
because most of the
that many global tread IDs.
Of course it depends
But in most cases, you won't
so it is said you can do this.
And this is going to be lower
because all of the arithmetic
going to be faster.
So I highly recommend
Additionally, keep in mind
which of course includes
of an operation is defined by
For example, if you're
that's a float operation not a
So accordingly, make sure
when not necessary, because
to be a half operation, it
into a float operation.
Because by the language
that's actually a float
of the inputs is float.
And so you probably
This will actually
This will actually be faster.
This is probably what you mean.
So be careful not
to inadvertently introduce
into your code when
And while I did mention that
there's one exception to
Remember as I said that
and later GPUs is
And so char is not going to
or anything like that
and furthermore there's no
So it sort of has
It's not overly expensive if you
But it may result in
So don't unnecessarily
that don't actually need it.
So next we have arithmetic
and pretty much everything
in this category
The first thing you can do
whenever possible.
They're optimized
for a variety of functions.
They're already optimized
It's generally better than
And in particular,
that are usually
And this is because GPUs
Operations that can be
and output of instructions.
And for A8 and later GPUs
absolute value, and
these three operations in green.
So, there's no point to trying
up your code by avoiding
they're almost always free.
And because they're free,
There's no way to
A8 and later GPUs, like a lot
of others nowadays,
And while shaders are
the compiler is going to split
Of course, there's no downside
I mean often it's clearer,
often it fits what you're trying
than writing scaler code
and the code you're
So there's no point in
that doesn't really fit a vector
to end up the same
and you're kind of
However, as a side
into more detail a lot later,
do have vector load in store
vector arithmetic.
So this only applies
Instruction Level Parallelism
of you may have used
especially if you've
But on A8 and later GPUs this
to try to optimize for
against registry usage,
and registry usage
So a common pattern you may
where you have multiple
to better deal with
But on A8 and later GPUs this
You'd be better off just
Of course this applies to
than the artificial
Just write what you mean, don't
to get more ILP out of it.
It's probably not going to
you just might get worse code.
So one fairly nice feature
that they have very
that is the ternary operator.
And historically it's
to use clever tricks,
to perform select
to avoid those branches
But on modern GPUs this is
and especially on A8 later GPUs
through this cleverness.
It's not going to figure
And really, this is really ugly.
You could just have
And this is going to be faster,
to show what you mean.
Like before, being overly clever
trying to do and
Now, this is a potential
hopefully this won't
On modern GPUs most of them
or modulus instructions,
So avoid divisional
that are not literal
the new feature mentioned in
So in this example, what we
where the denominator
that will be very, very slow.
Think hundreds of clock seconds.
But these other two examples,
Those are fine.
So don't feel like you
So, finally the topic
So in Metal, fast-math
And this is because compiler
critical to performance
They can give off in 50%
over having fast-math off.
So it's no wonder
And so what exactly do
Well, the first is that some
of the Metal built-in functions
guarantees between
And so in some of them they will
in fast-math mode to
The compiler may increase
of your operations like
add instructions.
It will not decrease the
So for example if you write a
operation that is at
Not a math operation.
So if you want to write half
that, the compiler will
because it's not allowed to.
It can't your precision
We do ignore strict if not
and sign zero semantics,
because without that
that x times zero
But we will not introduce a new
because in practice
to annoy developers,
and we don't want to do that.
And the compiler will perform
but it will not do
And really this just comes
and makes it faster versus
And we don't want to break code.
So if you absolutely cannot use
there are some ways to recover
Metal has a fused multiply-add
Which allows you to
multiply-add instructions.
And of course if
the compiler is not even
it cannot change one bit of
So if you want to use
and fast-math is
to have to use the built-in.
And that will regain
not all of it, but
So, on our third
Predicated GP control flow
of you may already
But here's a quick review
Control flow that is
that is every thread is
is generally fast.
And this is true even if
So if your program doesn't
to be uniform when it runs,
And similarly, the
different lanes doing different
it potentially may
of the different paths
which only takes
And as a result it does more
that inefficient control
of the bottlenecks, because it
doing more stuff, whatever
So, the one suggestion I'll make
to avoid switch fall-throughs.
And these are fairly
But on GPUs they can potentially
because the compiler has to do
to make them fit within the
And often this will involve
of nasty things you probably
So if you can find a nice way to
in your code, you'll
So now we're on to
Memory access.
And we'll start with
that people most
and that is dynamically indexed
Now that's quite a mouthful,
but a lot of you probably
that looks vaguely like this.
You have an array that consist
in runtime and vary between each
And you index it to the
that is also a variable.
That is a dynamically indexed
Now before we go on, I'm
for grabs at the idea that
I'm going to explain why.
So, on CPUs typically you
maybe a dozen threads, and you
between those threads.
So every thread can have
of stack space before they
to head off to main memory.
On a GPU you often have tens of
And they're all sharing
So when it comes down to
very little space
It's just not meant for that,
as a general rule,
if you're using the
It's so slow that almost
been better.
And an example for a real
of the program it needed
for vectors, so it
an array of two float
between them using
And that caused a
in this program even though it's
It can be pretty significant.
And of course every time we
going to try harder and harder
to avoid generating these stack
Now I'll show you two
This other one, you can
not variables.
It's not a non-constant
because the values don't vary
to be duplicated per thread.
So that's okay.
And this one is also okay.
Wait, why?
It's still a dynamically indexed
But it's only done dynamically
And the compiler is going
In fact, your compiler
that is accessing the stack to
So in this case after it's
dynamically indexed,
And this is worth mentioning,
because this is a fairly
of graphics code and I don't
that when it's probably fine.
So now that we've gone
to not do certain types
let's go on to making
that we do actually fast.
Now while A8 and later
as I went over earlier, they
And one big vector loading
than multiple smaller ones
And this typically effects the
because if you're running
through a loads,
And, so as of iOS 10, one of
is we will try to vectorize
to neighboring memory
because again it can give
But nevertheless, this is one
with the compiler
and I'll give an example.
So as you can see here,
that does some arithmetic and
but on each iteration,
Now we would want that
because one is better than two.
And the compiler wants that too.
It wants to try to vectorize
and C aren't next to
so there's nothing it can do.
The compiler's not allowed
so we've got two loads.
There's two solutions to this.
Number one, of course,
now it's a vector
One load, a set of
Also, as of iOS 10, this
because here, we've
to put the values
so the compiler can
when it's doing it.
And this is an example again
you've allowed the compiler to
because you understand
You understand how the
to make the compiler happy
and make it able to
So, another thing to keep in
that A8 and later GPUs
for device memory addressing,
The offset for accessing
within a signed integer.
Smaller types like short
in fact they're highly
because those do also fit
However, of course uint does
out of range of signed integer.
And so if the compiler
where the offset is a
that it will safely fit
it has to manually
rather than letting the
And that can waste power,
it can waste ALU
It's not good.
So, change your offset to
And of course taking advantage
to this will typically
So now on to our final
over earlier, latency
So one of the core
of modern GPUs is
by using large scale
So when they're waiting for
like a texture read,
and run another thread instead
of sitting there doing
And this is fairly important
because texture reads typically
to complete on average.
And so the more latency
the more threads you need
and how many threads
Well it's limited by the fact
of resources that are shared
between threads in
So clearly depending on
you have a limitation on
And the two things that
of registers and
So if you use more
now you can't have
Simple enough.
And if you use more thread group
into the same problem,
more thread your memory per
And you can actually check out
by using MTLComputePipeLineState
maxTotalThreadsPerThreadgroup,
which will tell you what
of your shader is based
and the thread group
And so when we say a
it means you have
to hide the latency of a shader.
And there's two things
you can either reduce the
your save registers
that is preventing you
So, since it's kind of
in a very large complex shader.
I'll go over a little bit
that will hopefully give you
to think about latency
of mentally model
So, here's an example
We have a texture sample,
of that texture sample
and then we do another texture
We have to wait twice.
Because we have to wait once
And we have to wait again
from the second texture sample.
So that's two serial
for a total of twice
Now here's an example
It looks a lot like the other,
except we're not using
But typically, we can't
The if statement acts an
So, we automatically have
to wait here anyways even though
So we still get twice
As you noticed the GPU
about your data dependencies.
It only cares about what the
and so the second one will
as the first one, even
dependency there.
And then finally
where you just have two
and they can both
and then we can have
So it's 1 x instead
So, what are you going to
So in many real world
to tradeoff between
And a common example of this
where based on one texture read
to do anything in this shader,
And that can be very useful.
Because now all that work
where you don't need
you're saving all that work.
That's great.
But now you're increasing
by reducing the amount
But you're also increasing
to do the first texture read,
then do your early
and then do whatever other
And well is it faster?
Is it not?
Often you just have to test.
Because which is faster
on your shader, but it's
of that often is a real
to experiment to
Now, while there isn't
there is one particular
and later GPUs and that is
at least two texture
to get full ability
One is not enough.
If you have to do
But if you have some choice
in how you arrange your
if you allow it to do
you may get better performance.
So, in summary.
Make sure you pick the correct
layouts and so forth, because
to hurt so much that often
in the presentation will matter.
Work with the compiler.
Write what you mean.
Don't try to be too clever,
or the compiler won't know what
and won't be able to do its job.
Plus, it's easier to
Keep an eye out for
not just the
They're often not as obvious,
up as often, but when
And they will hurt so
of micro-optimizations
And feel free to experiment.
There's a number of rule
where there's simply
And try them both,
So, if you want more
The video of the talk
Here are the other session if
the videos will be online.
Thank you.