[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, hello
to Controlling Game
I'm JJ Cwik, Game
Now when we introduce Apple
about the 10 foot experience.
We talked about it being a
one that's ideally suited
And the fact of the matter is
that people just love playing
and Apple TV is great for that.
It gives you the tools you need
to create really
And I'm really happy to talk to
MFi game controllers and how
to best integrate
Now before I start
here's what's new in tvOS 10.
As you heard on Monday, games
that cannot be supported
by the Siri Remote can
requirement that they
Now we've also included
to four MFi game controllers.
This is going to be great
And as you also heard on Monday,
that can be used to control
as a game input device.
Now I'll talk about all
of the talk, so let's
Now apps on tvOS
from the focus engine or
from touches and gestures.
But there's also a third
to read inputs directly
and game controllers with the
Now let me give you
of the Game Controller
who may not be familiar with it.
The Game Controller framework
to expose third-party game
These compatible game
MFi controllers.
Now the framework has
to also include support
The Game Controller framework
that allows you to
and use the same
of the controller vendors.
It standardizes detection
It seamlessly handles
and disconnect while
And it allows you to
to read inputs off of the
or an event-driven model.
And it's also available
And so even though this talk
of the code and concepts
So now that you have
of the framework I'd like to
There is a core class
in the Game Controller
This represents physical
and it's the same class
and MFi game controllers.
Now the first thing you're
in your app is to get a list
of all the currently
And to do this you use the
on GCController.
This returns you a list of the
as an array of GCController
or an empty array if none exist.
It's also common for controllers
as your app is running and to be
for the GCCcontrollerDidConnect
and GCControllerDidDisconnect
A great place to do this is
in your application Did
So now we know which controllers
like to shift focus and
Now the Siri Remote is
as a game controller using
that I just mentioned.
And in the Game Controller
of profiles and profiles grouped
and the Siri Remote
The first is called
This is what you use to
and the buttons on
The second profile that the
GCMotion and this is what you
and accelerometer
Now note that this is different
to on iOS where motion comes
through the CoreMotion
On tvOS motion comes through
So let's look at each of
First, the GCMicroGamepad.
Now the touch surface on
to your game as a
And you can query its value
as an XY coordinate pair or
as four buttons up,
The GCMicroGamepad profile
and this corresponds
This is ideally suited for the
especially when the
in portrait orientation.
And the profile also has
as a secondary action
and it becomes really natural
on its side and held in
to have a thumb on
and another thumb
Now note that there's also a
I'll be talking about
And the remainder of the buttons
on the remote are
Here's a code example
to read inputs off
Here we see we have a controller
and from that we can read
That stores the button A
and from there we just
to determine whether or not
Now we also support
So if you want to be notified
when the buttons are
to poll you can do that.
These are called the
and this block of code that
button changes state.
Notice of this is called twice
for traditional button
and another time on button up.
So those are the buttons.
Let's look at the DPAD now.
The DPAD as I mentioned
as four buttons up,
And interestingly, has
as two axes, xAxis and yAxis.
So let's look at those.
Here you can see there's a DPAD
and it has xAxis and
From there we read
which returns a float normalized
normalized between
Now as you'd expect, we also
And note in this case our
or we're supplying a
on the DPAD itself not
This is because we want to
of those two axes changes.
Now there's some interesting
that I'd like to talk
And the first one is
Now what this is is it really
of your x and yAxis
Now you might be wondering
at the center and the answer is
A lot of times a player doesn't
with the precise location
on the touch surface,
to put their thumb
to where they initially
And that's what DPAD
as a game developer is to tap
So initial touch downs
on the touch surface
and then further movement from
to your game relative
Let me explain with an example.
So here's our touch surface
and I place my thumb
Notice it's not at the
but with DPAD windowing
for our x and yAxis
Also note there's an imaginary
of that centered
Now watch what happens
across the touch surface.
The values reported to your
and in proportion to
Now as I continue
across the touch surface
and the axis along with it.
Now we have established a new
across the touch surface
to your game relative
So that's DPAD windowing.
If you want to receive absolute
opt into this with the
property, set this to true
at the physical midpoint
Then as I place my
across the touch surface all
to the physical midpoint
So that's DPAD windowing.
Next up rotation.
So the DPAD values
in portrait orientation
to the right and Y is going up.
However, this might cause a
to play in landscape
In this case, your game would
so that it's proper
But then what happens if
in the other direction,
to transpose those values
And how would you even do
to force the player to play
in a particular orientation
to start reading
and track the orientation
And this isn't something
So we've provided a property
Now by default this
But if you set it to true,
to your game will
to whatever orientation the
So when this is true
in portrait orientation
to the right and Y is going up.
And in landscape left X is going
And in landscape right
to the right and Y is going up.
So if your game wants
in landscape orientation
so you don't have to worry
or rotating DPAD
So that's rotation.
Next up motion.
As I mentioned earlier,
that the Siri Remote
Now as the user moves the
in user acceleration
by the GCMotion profile
Note that these values are
to your game.
So if you have a tvOS game
and you're doing motion
that so that you don't
into your game.
Also, this is fused motion data
that the accelerometer and the
and correct each other.
So just like on your
from the accelerometer
in the gyroscope and
to smooth the values coming
They reinforce each other.
But really, vigorous
so for this reason we recommend
in your game that
to vigorously shake the remote.
Because this causes data
until the sensors have
Next up I want to talk
Now all controllers
in the Game Controller
It's the same Menu button
on the Siri Remote and
Now in an app on tvOS when
recommended behavior changes
Sometimes pressing the Menu
and return you back to
That's typically done in
At other times pressing the Menu
in your apps menu hierarchy
and this is typically
Lastly, pressing the Menu
or resumes your active gameplay.
Now nongame apps
in UIKit get the first two
without any additional
to their custom UI have to do
to indicate to the
Let me explain.
So in UIKit when the
for UIKit apps it pops the child
This returns you back to your
Now you can do this successively
with each Menu button press
controllers off the
at some point you have
your root view controller
Now when there's only
on the stack the next Menu
and bounces you back to
Most games by comparison
they typically have custom
in UIKit.
And they also typically
between the different
that also aren't
And so for this reason
with only having
the root view controller,
for the entire duration
But by the rule that we just saw
because there's only one
at all points of your game
by default pressing the Menu
to the Apple TV Home Screen.
So you're going to need some
when you want Menu button
to the Apple TV Home
Enter GCEventViewController.
This is a special view
or rather for game
that have a single-view
So if your game is one of these
as your root view controller.
Now this view controller
controllerUserInteractionEnabled
that you have for controlling
to the home screen for
When this value is false this
traps the Menu button presses
up the responder chain,
effectively keeping
Incidentally, this is also
where your controller
and I'll get to that
Now when this value is set
to true Menu button events
up the responder chain as
to be minimized and
to the Apple TV Home Screen.
So your job as a game
of
as a user goes back and forth
between different
Let me show you with
So here we are at the
and we launch our app.
Some games have a splash screen
or some other introductory
and many games will
on an in-game main
And for both of these
that when they press the Menu
to the Apple TV Home
Therefore,
set
to true.
Now when the user progresses
say active gameplay
the user's expectations is
that Menu button presses
to the Apple TV Home Screen.
So in these cases set
to false.
And if a user transitions back
to the in-game main
to set this back to true again.
So that covers our first
to the Apple TV Home
And we still have the
We need to worry about going
and resuming active gameplay.
Basically all the dark
And the good news is that
in the controllerPausedHandler.
The controllerPausedHandler is
to the controller or for
and this is code that runs
pressed and you're not
to the Apple TV Home Screen.
And it's a simple matter within
if you're in a submenu go back
to the previous level
If you're in active gameplay
And that's it now
up to properly handle Menu
of where you are in your game.
So now let's talk about
Some games can really take
of controls offered by
and these are optional
that players may have.
Now by extended what
to is the control
that you're probably
It features a DPAD on the left,
B, X, Y in these
the diamond pattern
On the front of the controller
and on top we have two
Now all of these buttons
so far are pressure-sensitive
We also have a Menu button,
and we have four
Now just like the Siri Remote
extended game controllers
GCExtendedGamepad profile.
And you'll notice on the left
the properties.
Also notice the data types
and GCControllerButtonInput.
These are the same
to on the Siri Remote.
Now one thing I'd like to
and the buttons and
on this table actually
So even those buttons and inputs
that are typically
in other controllers that
like the DPAD and
and shoulder buttons they're
and so they can be read in an
So let's look at code that shows
Here we have the A button and
to access the digital state
of the button whether
So if your game only concerns
with whether or not a button is
to use.
However, if you care about
that's when you'd use
And this is great to add more
Maybe you're creating a
to allow players to vary
from a soft gentle pass to a
that by reading how hard
with the value property.
We also offer event
Now notice there's a
which corresponds to
This is for Boolean
or digital state changes.
And there's a value changed
to the value or sorry, a value
with the value property.
Now the value change
in a typical button press
down through its travel
And for those of you looking
to use polling or event
and fast rules, but
for reading those
over a longer period of time.
Like maybe the accelerator
to the trigger of a button
of the game controller.
And event callbacks
when you're concerned about
So maybe you have
and a player swings
to activate the swing sword
is pressed.
Event callbacks are
So by this point you
of the mechanics of
from the Siri Remote
and you're probably
about which control types
Will it support just
or will it support the Siri
Or as you heard on Monday,
games that have advanced
that can't be supported
by the Siri Remote can require
Now how you specify
which controller types your
In your target settings
and in there you'll find the
Enable this capability
of controllers your
Interacting with this GUI
in your info.plist
And this is important for
that link the Game Controller
or rather these keys are going
by all games that link the
And where this really
because your users are going
if your game has game
or game controllers as required.
Additionally, the user may
to download a game
when they haven't
to that Apple TV before.
Now note that this
because it's very
that requires game
and find no game
And this is a case that you
It's very possible that maybe
on their game controller.
So in this situation
that no game controllers
and to connect a
Otherwise, the user may be
seemingly not controllable.
Now there's one other
with notifying the user in
on controller disconnections.
This is because the controller
or rather the controllers
check, but then somewhere
down the line while
of the game controllers
And if this is the
that was available then at this
since it requires
and again a place
For more information,
session 802 for more information
So let's talk about
the Apple TV Remote app.
As you heard on Monday, this
in beta form on
This app allows you to
and it features a large
of the screen and on-screen
as well on the Siri Remote.
And importantly for our
as a game input device.
And the way that's done
by the Game Controller
in a very familiar manner.
It's effectively an
So it shows up as a
and it supports the
and GCMotion profiles
In fact, it's indistinguishable
in the Game Controller
So the code you write for the
Now by default these
so if you have a Siri Remote and
as one game controller
in your controllers array.
This means that button inputs
to your game as if they
and the same thing
Now for motion we didn't want
overwriting and fighting with
so we take motion from
from one remote at a time.
And the remote we take
that last received intentional
on the touch surface or
Now if you want you can opt-in
and have them show up
in your controllers array.
To do this, go to
and add the Boolean key
set this to yes and
and Apple TV Remote
up as distinct controller
Now I want to talk to you
of the Apple TV Remote app
This is a mode that users can
in any game that links the
Now this app is in landscape
the DPAD values are rotated
by 90 degrees before they
So your app doesn't
to take advantage of this mode.
However, just note that if
values by 90 degrees
to be doing a double rotation.
So our recommendation is if
to allow players to play
with the Siri Remote
on the Apple TV Remote app
like we saw previously
to handle the orientation
Now one more thing to note,
the Apple TV Remote app's Game
touch surface from the A button.
This is different
where clicking the touch surface
Now mechanically this doesn't
can still simultaneously
and your game code
for simultaneous input on both.
But the key point is if you
that all A button presses will
this won't work in the same
for the Apple TV Remote app.
And lastly, I'd like to talk to
We get asked all the time how
TV support.
And the answer is one Siri
up to four MFi game controllers
Now we typically get
of multiplayer gaming and
to four MFi game controllers
to be great for multiplayer
But something that may not
that this is very important for
Let me explain.
When your app launches you're
to find only one Siri Remote
to find a game controller
or maybe you'll find one of each
or maybe you'll find
multiple game controllers,
You get the picture right?
So the key point here is on
to receive inputs from
for single-player games.
And importantly, you
which controller the
So you can't just assume
that the controller's
that the player wants to use.
So how should we handle this?
Well the key realization here is
that players can switch
Maybe they launched your app,
traverse through your
into gameplay all with the
to the MFi game controller
to actually start
And games that allow players
between different
to prompt the user with
or without requiring the
and reenter gameplay
with a different controller will
user experience.
So how should we do this?
Well one way to go about
from all controllers
for your single-player game.
So if you have a character
from the DPAD allow all
allow their DPADs to control
Similarly with buttons, if
if your character jumps
by pressing the A button
on all the connected controllers
And if a controller
of your gameplay you can
that controller too
to control your character.
Now this is working
to give the player a system here
to switch back and forth
And this is effectively a
where we're taking the
and game controllers
into our single-player
But there's one edge case
about and that's motion.
So let me explain
If you have a game
to control the attitude of
with the Siri Remote
that controlling the
if the player is playing
And that's perfectly fine
The key concern here though is
that controls the airplane
to be overwritten by any motion
from the Siri Remote when
So in this case the code in your
of the airplane should
that information from
So then back to our example
with my Siri Remote if I pick
up my game controller any
on that game controller whether
or triggers or buttons will
from the Siri Remote and
to control the attitude of
If I then pick up my Siri
namely swipes across
or X button presses will at
to motion coming from the Siri
In using this we have a control
for players and allows
as seamlessly as possible.
Now I'd like to end
that maybe these techniques
that I've shown you here can
or maybe they're a good starting
and customize them to suit
But in any case, I really
to go beyond the mere mechanics
and disconnecting and
and really thoughtfully
to integrate game
Because when you get
of the player game
and it really allows them
and enjoy the game experiences
that you've worked
And that's what games
So we've talked about
To summarize, we talked
about the Siri Remote how it
profile in the GCMotion profile.
I talked about DPAD
I also talked about
on Apple TV the expected
on the context of your app.
And how you can use the
and control or pause handlers
I also talked about
that these use the
that they introduce
and that they can
as a controller for your game.
I also talked about
and how that's an emulated Siri
of the Game Controller
And I talked about
of the Apple TV Remote app
so that your game
for the Apple TV Remote app.
And lastly, I finished
about multiple controllers
for multiplayer gaming, but it's
for single-player gaming.
Namely, allowing your players to
as you can for your game.
Here's the URL for this session.
You can find the
and code samples here.
This is session 607.
Related sessions include
and Designing for tvOS.
There's also a tvOS lab
Thank you so much
and have a wonderful