[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
My name's Bruno Sommer.
I'm a game technologies
and this is What's
So last year, we
Apple's high-level
and what GameplayKit
of common architectural
and algorithms that enables our
and compelling gameplay
We want you guys to think about
for great gameplay, so
of game you're making, whether
or a city builder, there's
in GameplayKit to make
and to make your gameplay
So last year when we
it was made up of
things like entities and
and our game quality
This year, we're making
agents, and game AI, and we're
systems to GameplayKit.
We have a really powerful
that's going to let you get
out of runtime queries
You must have a really rich
that's going to let you
runtime content.
And this year, we've also
into our Xcode Game
of the workflows previously
now you can do right in
no recompile necessary.
So we have a lot to
I'm going to jump right in
So last year, we introduced
These are our graph type
of impassable obstacles
And under the hood, we use
to map the passable area
Now, this method
It results in really good
for larger game worlds and game
of obstacles, these can
intensively to calculate
and really memory
So this year, we're providing
We're introducing GKMeshGraph.
Now, this is very similar
Again, we're dealing with a set
of impassable obstacles
But now instead of
to calculate the passable
we're actually going to
We're going to make a
such that every passable point
in your game world
and only one triangle.
So this new triangulation
in really good quality paths
of being really fast
and really low overhead
especially for really
In addition, you have
with where nodes get
You can place them at triangle
and on triangle edges and
Let's look at a quick
of what using a mesh graph
and this is going to look
that have used our
They're solving the same
So here at the top, I'm going to
I'm going to pass in
Recall that this buffer
of your agents that are
in your world.
We're going to artificially
of your obstacles under the hood
to compensate for
Here we're also going
(0, 0) and (1000, 1000).
This is the span
that this mesh graph
Next, I'm going to set
on my mesh graph.
This is that flexibility
that I was talking
Here we're going to specify
at triangle vertices
And lastly, we're
of obstacles into
We have a set of obstacles
Then we're going to
This actually commits those
run the underlying
and then we're good to go.
This graph is ready for use
So in addition to
this year we're introducing
to pathfinding.
A number of our graphs
their nodes.
That's our grid graphs,
our obstacle graphs,
Now at initialization time,
you can optionally specify
to instantiate instead.
And this is really useful if you
or logic to your nodes, which
on the game you're
We call the appropriate init()
when we would've generated
And all these graph classes
and Swift generics, so
when you query your
So that's what's new in
Let's go ahead and move on
A little bit of a refresher on
They are autonomously moving
of goals and behaviors,
of realistic physical
things like velocity, mass,
obstacle avoidance,
On the right here, you see
at your disposal to achieve
for in your game.
And this is things like
or wandering and fleeing.
So previously, agents
This year, we're
that we're bringing
The class is GKAgent3D and the
to its 2D variant.
The key differences are that
and rotation is of course
And all the same goals and
So a couple things to note
GKPath has been changed to
with regards to our
And with regards to obstacles
those, if you're going to
they still live on
so you need to pick a plane
So in addition to bringing
this year we're introducing
We have a new class
subclass of GKBehavior,
of weighted behaviors.
This is really similar
between behaviors
Behaviors are a weighted
So these are fully nestable,
so now you can do really
behaviors in your game, and
to maintain, especially
with a large number of
Let's take a look at
of these composite
At the top here, I'm going
by combine an align, a
Next, I have some obstacles
that I'd like my agents
to make an avoidance behavior
and an avoidEnemies goal.
Then I'm going to combine
into our new composite behavior,
effectively combining
And lastly, I'm going
I'm going to set my
as the agent's behavior,
The next time we
it's going to correctly
to achieve both of those
So that's what's new
Let's move on and talk about our
So a little bit of background
on why spatial partitioning
A lot of times when we're going
we ask a lot of spatial
things like, how many
Or where are all the
Or what projectiles will
Now, especially for larger
with a large number of game
of questions can be expensive.
In gameplay programming, we
of spatial queries using a form
of caching called
So a little bit of an overview
with our spatial
This is a set of tree-like
to cache your game
You add objects to these
and they get grouped
and buckets under the hood.
And then future queries
implicitly faster.
This year, we're introducing
for you spatial partitioning
We have R-trees,
Let's dive a little deeper
Let's talk about R-trees.
Now, what an R-tree is,
that has a number of
Whenever you add an object
into one of those buckets.
Now, all these buckets have
with them that is the sum
of the children that
Now, R-trees have a special rule
that when these buckets grow
and this is a user-configurable
of just how large
And we have a number of
to decide how these
We can simply have them or we
and quadratic distance
of the resulting buckets.
I'm going to give you
of what building a
Let's say I have a space game
with some spaceships
I'm going to add a
It gets fitted to a bucket
and it's just simply the
And then I'm going to add a
and you notice it grows larger
I've specified a rule in
that these buckets need to
than three objects, so
and add a fourth
We've grown too larger.
Now we need to split.
And we're just going to do a
and we end up with
Again, I'll add a couple objects
We've grown too large.
We need to split.
And again, we'll do a
up with two resulting buckets.
That's the gist of how
So let's move on and talk
I'm going to address
because they're solving the same
in 2D and octrees live in 3D.
The interface is identical.
These are tree-like data
of levels and hierarchies,
space is subdivided evenly.
Here on the right, I have
And you see in the upper
that quadrant once, and then
in that new subdivided
I've subdivided again.
So quadtrees and octrees have
with them, and that controls
grow and just how small
Now, when you add an object
it gets placed into the smallest
And a small note on
this is really related, this
to the performance gains
out of these data structures,
or a max cell size that
Typically, this is
of the smaller game
Again, I'll give you a visual
Same examples, spaceship
I'll insert a spaceship
Gets placed into the lower
I'll add some bigger
they live one level up.
Take special note of that
You see it sort of straddles
It's actually going
up because it doesn't fit neatly
And lastly, I'll add
and you see that they
So that's the gist of what's
when you use a quadtree
Let's look at a code example
So at the top here, I'm
I'm going to pass in a
in my game world that I want
Here we're going to cover the
1000) in my game world.
I'm mostly going to specify
No cell in this quadtree's going
So I also have some
I'm going to go ahead and
Notice here that all these
with a quad of their own.
This is where that enemy
and where it's going to
And lastly, I'm going to
I'm going to ask my quadtree
that are between (0, 0) and
and therefore in my game world.
And it just so happens that
and I'm going to get all three
So that's spatial
Let's move on and talk about our
So a little bit of background
on why procedural generation
I'm sure we're all familiar
This is things that we
or before the game even
like artist design, or
or artist developed
And these are great assets.
They really work
But for other types of
you run into problems because
They don't change at
So especially if I'm
every time I play my
I can't really use these
So what I'm looking for
and this is things like
procedurally generated
So we're looking to make this
What we're really looking for is
A lot of these random elements
in nature, things like worlds
So we need a source
that makes sense spatially,
that actually has an underlying
Now, you might say
I can just use a random
I can pull some values
make my random content,
Anyone that's ever tried to do
that very quickly runs
Outputs of RNGs tend to
It's difficult to have
between subsequent calls
and it's also very
Every time I randomly
I want it to appear the same
So we're looking for this
One such source of
Now, what noise is, it's a
and gives output values,
but there's some rules
For small changes in input, I
and for large changes
but still spatially
There's some underlying
And noise functions
for the whole range of inputs.
It continues infinitely,
Given the same input, I
So once we have this noise
at intervals that are relevant
of content I'm trying to make.
So if I'm trying to
this might be coordinates or
Or if I'm trying to
this might be texels
So a little overview
with our procedural
and our noise system in general.
You have a number of noise
to sample and make meaningful
and this is things
things like Perlin
and also geometric noise
and spheres, ridges and
of constant noise like
or the constant noise function.
So you can then combine noise
and perform a number of
And these are things like
or translating, scaling,
So once we've combined
into a noise object, we
of that underlying noise
in a noise map, get our samples,
So let's dig a little deeper.
Let's talk about
Now, all of our noise
between negative 1 and 1.
We'll talk a little bit
And they all have parameters
to tweak their various
that underlying noise
and coherent noises like Perlin
with a GKRandomSource and they
on them to tweak their
And for our more geometric noise
to alter their shapes, so the
or the frequency of
So once we have some
we can then combine them
Now, this has all the functions
and modify our noise sources,
and logical operations
So if I'm trying to combine
multiply, min or max,
to transform a single noise map,
or I can modify it by
clamping, inverting.
So once we have our
we can them sample a
that underlying noise
You specify an origin
This is the region of
that we're sampling.
And you also specify
How many times do we sample that
What's my fidelity at
So then once we have
we can then get the value
on that noise map, and again,
like I mentioned before.
And at runtime, you can
as needed if your
So I realize that this
I think the best way
with a visual example.
Let's say I wanted to randomly
and I want to model it
I want it to have
Deserts, forests, arctic
One, this is one method you
Here I've generated
and the one on the left I'm
At any point in my game world,
and determine how wet or
And on the right, I have what
At any point in my game world,
and decide how hot or
So some things to note here,
On the moisture map, you
on the right.
That's that black smudge.
And a very wet area on the left.
And again, these
to that output I
Here black is my negative 1's
and white is more
And on the right, notice I
at the top.
That's that black smudge again.
And a very warm sort of
So I'm going to specify
on how I actually combine these
in some meaningful
Here I just have
On the vertical axis,
and on the horizontal
So I can use these rules
of those two maps,
that has a really
but really low moisture,
up with something like a desert.
Or if I have something with
and really high moisture,
up with something
And so there, and sort of
I have tundras and arctic zones.
And then in the middle,
like the more temperate
savannahs, and grasslands.
So using those two maps I made
and combining them
I get something like this.
You see it has a nice,
and some things to note.
On the right, you see we have
of bleeds into some grasslands
and then bleeds into
That corresponds with that
and that really warm spot
And sort of on the upper left,
you see we have a really big
Then on the upper right
we have some small
with really high temperatures
So this is just a really
of the cool stuff you can do
Here we just used two simple
with some really simple rules,
and got some pretty
Now, I'd like to call my
up to tell you about
Michael?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Bruno.
Hey, everyone.
I'm Michael Brennan.
I'm a game technologies
and I'm really excited to share
with you today what
to GameplayKit this
Last year with GameplayKit,
we introduced the
This is a great AI solution
that guarantees an optimal
It guarantees this by
of that state space combined
with the scoring function you
in the game to give you the best
to make at a certain point.
The exhaustive nature
of the Minmax strategist does
to use for games with larger
Games like Go or
That's why this year
with you the Monte
Monte Carlo strategist
of the state space combined
of that state space
for you opponent to make.
It does this by first selecting
versus exploitation to choose
out new games from that move
until it reaches
either a win or a
which then propagates
It doesn't guarantee the optimal
but it does converge
Monte Carlo strategist is fast.
It guarantees a good
with incredibly large state
And given that it only
something your games
it's very simple to
And it is approximately
that optimal move Minmax would
and it will converge on
Let's go over some of the
to incorporate this
With GKMonteCarloStrategist,
This is the amount
that four steps we
And you need to provide
Now, this is a value between 0
on selecting a move you want
or whether you want it to
and found to be very winning.
And you need to provide
This is something
with if you've used
Now let's look at a
So here we've got our
which we're going to
and our Monte Carlo strategist,
and hold a reference to.
We're first going to set the
model to point to our
we're going to give it a budget.
We're going to say around 100.
This means it'll do
the simulating [inaudible]
And then we're going to set
This means we want it
And then we're just simply
for our active player in that
and apply it back
It's just that easy.
This year, I'm excited to tell
to make your own
We implemented a new
and you simply conform to
game model update,
and implementing find best move
like you would any other
So that was what we were
Now let's talk about something
There are many ways to
many of which GameplayKit
Your enemies need to be able
to make decisions considering
and they need to be able to
As you can see here, we have
Just in this simple game, your
where you are, where every other
who owns the buttons at
whether they're jumping,
where they are in the level.
It's quite a lot of
Decision trees are a simple
They're a tree-like data
to visualize and debug, and
or learned.
GKDecisionTree gives
for determining your action.
It's completely serializable and
to make nodes that will
with certain weights
if a certain branch is a
or by satisfying
It's extremely flexible,
Let's go over a brief
So as you can see here,
We're going to initialize
asking if we're near the button.
And then we're going
to that root node for later.
After that, we're simply
of that root node -- one for
that button, in which
and one if we're not
in which case we're
And we're going to
to that wander node as well.
With that wander node,
we're going to create
one with a weight of 9 we're
and one with a weight of 1
Now, this is additive,
which means that for the left
of 9, that means it
that there's a total
and the right move has a
Then we're simply going to pack
and pass it into
on the tree to get our action.
Decision trees can
You simply supply
and it will find the
in that data and
to that decision-making
As you can see here
we have a top row
That's the attributes.
And the interior
That's what various points of
And on the right-hand side, we
That's simply what we did
at those various
You pass this into the
and it will fit a decision tree
to that gameplay
Let's look at what this
So here we have my
to turquoise colored player,
playing against the
that handmade decision
As you can see, it's missing
that we're doing that
Let's look at a different
Here you'll see it
like how we were
Like I said, you just simply
pass it in, and you can model
So that's what we're
to game AI for GameplayKit.
It's awesome and I'm
and now I'd like to invite to
to tell you more
about GameplayKit
Sri?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Michael.
Hello, everyone.
My name is Sri Nair, and I'm a
at Apple.
So when we introduced
it was exclusively
You had to create the
and tweak the properties and
And that can be inefficient
so I'm happy to say that we
by introducing a more
for GameplayKit by
with Xcode and SpriteKit Editor.
As you know, editor integration
on your game features
They also help to separate
from the design workflow.
So here are the four main
to help accelerate your
Number one, entity
Number two, navigation
Number three, scene
And number four, state
Let's dive deeper into
What's the component editor?
Let's recall that an entity
and component system
where a game object is
and their behavior is
and independent components.
And this provides for
and usability of code.
And they also tend to be easier
So now with the component
and components to your
and tweak the properties all
for an editor-based,
The editor is closely
and supports auto-discovery
of component classes
For example, let's say you
that's derived from GKComponent,
and annotated with the newly
for them to show up in the UI.
And the component editor will
components that you have
and now you can simply select
and assign to the nodes.
Once you add the component, the
with the corresponding
and now you can adjust
and preview the changes right
to quit the editor or recompile
to a much faster iteration.
And all of these updates
and under the SKS file.
And all the unchanged
setting code.
The GKEntity to the
under the hood through
And the UI supports all
such as float, int,
and that's component editor.
Now, let's move on to the
As Bruno mentioned earlier,
as GKGraphs are used
to find an optimal way
from point A to point B.
And with the navigation
now you can create GKGraphs
You can add or edit
between them just by clicking
And these GKGraphs are
that you can later retrieve in
I also want to mention a highly
to SpriteKit Editor
for GameplayKit development as
It outlines the scene elements,
Most standard operations are
rearrange, delete, et cetera.
The navigation graphs you add
in the scene outline view.
It also can be used
and changing the visibility.
It also comes with
for more selection-specific
Quite handy.
And last but not least,
So just to refresh,
we introduced GKStateMachine
to represent some kind of
And it has many applications in
UI, level sequencing, et cetera.
And up until this
of previewing what these
It was quite hard to
between the states,
or what state it is in
we are integrating a state
into Xcode Debugger's
This allows you to put break
to see the state machine and
and it pops up a
of for your current
And it shows the states,
and the current state
Here are a few more
as seen in quick look.
And with that, I would like to
workflow of GameplayKit.
[ Applause ]
So here I have a, we're going
where a player picks up
and throws at an enemy
and enemy can do the same.
So we have a basic scene here.
As you can see in the
we have a background and a
So first, we will try to add,
it's a pretty basic,
It's very static scene, so we'll
to the player using
So for that, I have added a few
at the movement component
as a few properties that helps
friction, acceleration,
And you have annotated
so that you can treat those
Similarly, I have a
and we will assign these to the
and looking in the
So on the inspector area
I have the newly
Now, I can select the player
to add these components
So we'll go ahead and add
and the movement component.
And we'll see what
So I would expect
to move with the keyboard.
That's great, so can
And except you can, you'll
at the boundaries because I
to the player yet, but I do have
which essentially adds the
So I will go ahead and
And while we are at it, I will
that I added which allows you
So let's see what
Yay, now I can pick
and he's stopped
That's awesome.
We'll go ahead and do the same
I had a game object, enemy
but I had set it to invisible,
in the scene outline view.
And go ahead and assign the
So in this case, the difference
so that it picks up the game AI
and similarly, movement
as well as the fight component.
And with that, I would
up the balloons and,
That was quite easy for
to make the gameplay a
by dropping some balloons into
So I have a drawn object that I
and go ahead and add
which basically does the
as follow a certain path.
So I want to add a
and that's as simple as
and typing in "nav graph."
Now, you can just simply drag
and drop the nav
So we'll just make the
to demonstrate the feature.
So here's the navigation
And while we are at it, we'll
We'll set the health to be 2
speed up a little,
to the player a little bit,
you got some advantage.
And enemy will get
And let's see what we have.
You know, you can see that the
that I can pick up and throw.
He got me and I got him
Yay. All right.
I'm sure my son will have a lot
of fun playing this
That pretty much demonstrates
for GameplayKit.
Let's switch back to the slides.
So to recap the session,
we have introduced
and useful features
In the beginning, Bruno talked
about the next spatial
for efficient spatial
The new procedural
for using various
to create more dynamic
as well as improvements
such as pathfinding and agents.
And Michael talked about
with gameplay strategists
And I finally covered the newly
of GameplayKit for
I hope you find these features
to see what you come
And here is the URL for this
Number 608 is the
And here are a few sessions
that you might be
What's New in SpriteKit,
Game Center, and Game
Thank you for coming,
and we hope you enjoy the
[ Applause ]