[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Good morning and welcome to
My name is Amaury and
to present you how we brought
with state of the art graphics.
So we have a lot to cover today.
So I will start with a quick
into this new rendering
Next Jean-Baptiste and
to present a cool demo,
and present all the new features
such as great new
And finally, Nick will join us
So in a nutshell.
As you know, SceneKit
under the GameKit umbrella
It plays nicely with
on top of Metal [inaudible].
And use SceneKit in any
to disperse with the
And when you start to think
in a great deal of places.
For instance, we just
where SceneKit makes scenes
in the first steps in
In Xcode we use SceneKit
and extremely useful interface
that helps you develop
In iBooks and iBooks Author
with enhanced illustrations
And of course SceneKit
Last, but not least, thank you.
You guys found of so use cases
You published thousands
to the Store.
So thank you.
[ Applause ]
Now, as you know, SceneKit
with the system.
It works seamlessly with
and it takes the
where it's been available
And sense we last talked at
on tvOS.
All we had to do for the
to add two ports for game
to be played on the big screen.
So it's absolutely fantastic
and code can run on
And this year we
with SceneKit coming to watchOS.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So SceneKit on watchOS is a
to think about new
to present content
Now, as you might imagine,
about the [inaudible]
And we won't have time
But we have a [inaudible]
for Apple Watch," on Friday,
about what's available, how to
and other technologies.
And if you are new to SceneKit
you can always go online to
where we explained basic,
but also really advanced,
Okay. So now let's dive into
Well, this year SceneKit puts
in the hands of everyone.
It means that developers,
get to have stunning graphics
It's the biggest leap forward in
since its introduction.
We rely on the latest
and leverage modern technologies
and physically based shading.
Now, physically based
[inaudible] requirements.
So we start with
So what you see here is a smooth
to one and, as you can see,
That is until you comprise
in an eight disk optic
And, as you can see,
And that's new because our eye
in the dark effluence.
Now by applying gamma encoding
to these darker turns.
So, for instance,
which shows the difference
between storing pixel
or using gamma encoding.
Now the thing is that when
lighting information
and equations are
So in a non-linear pipeline
that [inaudible] that is rich
with gamma encoded
and then it's processed
and the resulting
to a texture or framebuffer.
And, as you might imagine,
For the final image to be
to happen in enough space.
So, as an illustration,
with lighting occurring
And here is the same scene
And if you compare them, you
and edges appear harsher
Now linear rendering
for physically based rendering
of the SceneKit lighting model
because it just makes
Now, as you know, color is a
at WWDC so in addition to
management automatically.
So what does that mean?
It means that the color
to a texture will
Any operation that happens
from disk to the moment
so that it can be
we will respect the
So a SceneKit-based application
of the color accuracy
of a professional
Now, as you know, [inaudible]
to be stored as colors.
And SceneKit knows that
and so it won't color
Now to help you with that
in Xcode 8 asset catalogs
In a texture set one can specify
data or raw data and then Xcode
images to CPU and GPU
But to learn more about
after lunch, "Working
where the Metal team gets
Now, in addition to textures,
color management also
So color components are no
And so if you are creating
it's now really important that
So here is an illustration
one Display P3 and
that were created using
When working with color
to the color space
Above the menu we let you choose
including device
such as [inaudible]
And there's also a handy
as [inaudible] rather
so that they can be
And speaking of which,
shader modifiers are a
that will allow you to
Now, as I said, this year
So you must be sure
to the linear extended sRGB
components are used
Now a few notes about
Linear rendering and color
enabled whenever you link your
There's no performance
but they will dramatically
of [inaudible] scenes.
So, for instance,
which did not use
And here's what happens
Now, of course, textures,
and shadow modifiers
with linear rendering in mind.
But if you want to deploy your
of the system, or want to
in color management
we have found a way to do that.
You can [inaudible]
in your apps Info.plist file.
And then there is
So, as you know, with
such as extended sRGB
and they are really important
when working for
The new iPad Pro and iMac
with Retina Display
that SceneKit can
All you have to do is to
so textures or colors,
and SceneKit will enter
Now wide gamut textures
and framebuffer will require
and that will lead to an
So may you experience
we offer a way to upload again
Now let me mention the color
that we built in collaboration
with the Cocoa and
It's a synching-based
to see the out of
and it's also really useful
because on the wide gamut
to see what this display brings
because you can simulate
So to learn now about working
to convert color components
again we have a great
And so that works for accurate
of physically based rendering.
Now what is physically
Well, [inaudible] scenes
And that is definitely true.
But shading is what
So all you see here
to be a soup of polygons.
And shading is a process
for each detail on the screen.
So all the highlights,
it comes from shading.
Shading is that magical
that can bring a scene to life.
Now how does it work?
Well, first there is light
And when light hits an object it
to properties of the surface
to find your eye or a
Now this interaction between
that is really complex.
And over the years many
developed to try to
Physically based rendering is an
that relies on such mathematical
into account the physical
But, as you know, SceneKit is
to allow anyone to benefit
So we will expose a
so that you can use
that artists love.
So at the end of this session
from this rendering,
to a physically based one.
Okay. So in SceneKit we
rendering from two angles.
First, physically based
physically based lights.
So first, physically
Here is a description of
with normally indicating its
And when light hits that point,
diffuse reflection and
Now diffuse reflection
that goes underneath the surface
and in so many directions
The color of the diffuse
or the base color of the object.
So when designing the interface
in SceneKit we will want
Now specular reflection
Specular reflection
that bounces off the
of the color of the
So here is what we
It's a collection of six spaces
around the location in 3D space.
And when we place a
in such an environment we will
Now let's take a more realistic
As you can see, it's
At the center is the reflection
to the edge it gets brighter.
And actually for raising
Now not all materials have
What you see on the
which represents the
of the incident angle
And you will see that these
constant from zero to 45 degrees
and actually we can
to reconstruct the whole curve.
Now gold is an interesting
because it has different
green, and blue components.
The one last thing to note here
and gold, have high reflectivity
or dielectrics have low
And this difference
in reflectivity is
for the final look
So in SceneKit we want
which will indicate which
and which part is not.
So in addition to reflectivity
to different type
also note that metals will
surface where dielectric
So the visual effect of this is
that metals have a wide
and no diffuse reflection and
of diffusion and specular
only at raising angles.
So in SceneKit we will reuse
to store the reflectivity
and the albedo of dielectrics.
And for the reflectivity values
of dieletrics we just use
So we just reuse the
that we brought from
Now one last aspect
about is the surface roughness.
So, as you know, no
As a microscopic level
and cracks that will affect
So the rougher the
the blurrier the reflection
of light are no longer aligned.
So again in SceneKit we would
which will indicate which
and which part is smooth.
And this one is a
So we just saw how we can divide
and each of them has a
from [inaudible]
Now creating a physically
in SceneKit is straightforward.
You first create a material,
to the new physically
and finally you provide
So let's take an example.
We start with a mine cart
We will then add
So, for instance,
Coal is rough so there
And finally we will
So, for instance, take a
Let's take another example.
We have a fire truck.
Again, we start with
Now we will add a metalness map.
And finally a roughness map.
So for instance,
Now one thing I would
For the metalness, roughness,
please use grayscale images.
Having different channels
and blue would just
And even more if you
Now, furthermore, if you
over the whole surface, you
or even better, for these
[inaudible] numbers.
So we just saw how we can
and high-level API to create
Here is the same object
and on one axis we changed
and on the other axis we
Now remember how we said that
based rendering.
Let's now have a look at
Well, in SceneKit lights can
I will start with image
then cover light probes,
So image based lighting.
As I said, you can use a cube
around a location in 3D space.
So when shading a point
on the surface we can
above the end point
and the right lighting
that is [inaudible]
So for instance,
which is lit only using
There is no light in that scene.
And you can see how changing
to cube map dramatically
Using image based
in your scene will
and will work nicely together.
By using image based lighting
in SceneKit is really
We added a lighting environment
And you can simply set a
And what's great is
with the background property.
So for instance, if you take an
to the background and
you will be able to display
Now cube map, it can show
and the aesthetic.
So when shading a point on
that this environment is not
or there's another
And that can be taken
with image based lighting.
So it does not work very
Luckily we have a solution
Light probes are local lights
and they capture the local
So when shading a point
on a surface we can find the
and interpolate lighting
So as I said, light probes,
and so they can account
And they are implemented
that they are really
You can have dozens of
And we actually recommend that.
Because the more
the finer the [inaudible]
and the better local lighting
So creating a light
You create the light and
That can be done
or within the Xcode
Now just like cube maps,
light probes capture
And this information
into the probe easily using the
So we just saw how using IBL
or light probes you can have
But of course if you want direct
to all the other kind of lights.
So omnidirectional, directional,
with physically based rendering.
And actually we have [inaudible]
so that you can be
For instance, we added
A light's intensity is expressed
of watt 1000 which
of magnitude of a light bulb.
We also added a light's
in Kelvin and from which
And one great new feature,
of lights, IES lights.
So IES lights, or
can account for any
So while the spot light
or omnidirectional light has a
curve, IES lights can better
of a theater world light.
And, for instance, it can
It can account for shadows.
For example, due to
Now creating photometric lights
Again, you create the light.
Then you change its type.
And finally you provide the
which can, for instance,
from the website
So as a quick recap, we
to create a physically
and all these properties derive
on the surface so they are
and how we can work with
of physically based material.
So with that please
and Sebastien for great demos.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So thank you, Amaury,
of the new rendering
So let's see them in
So, as you will see,
that has been presented
by Amaury is actually
in the [inaudible].
You will be able
and see the result in real time.
So I have a very simple
with just one light
I go to the Materials inspector.
As you can see we have just
One for the body and one for
So I'm going to select
We are continue using the Blinn
to the physically
Now I've set the two
And, as you can see,
because we don't see the
So we can go to the Scene
to set the lighting
So for that I will use the cube
of a parking as the
So. Shortly I'm focusing on
of the physically
So let's now move to
The roughness is indicate
So you will see that the
the blurrier the
So if I move the value of
I have a blurry reflection.
And then almost no reflection
So if I move back to zero, I
as you can see, everything is,
the whole environment is
So now I'm using just
for the roughness.
And I would like to be able
for each part of the object.
For that I just have
So let's use a roughness
And a roughness map
So we have the same kind of
So we want to be able
of the object is
So for that we [inaudible].
So let's set the metalness
A different map.
So, as you can see,
of the object is nonmetallic
is completely metallic.
The final touch is
And we will be done.
So that's it.
So we have a full [inaudible]
I can now switch
and change the cube map.
For example, this cube map
of the lighting environment
I can set it in the background.
So that's it.
So, as you've seen,
to use the new SceneKit
And, you know, now to
of rendering in action we've
to show you now while
&gt;&gt; Hello.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So I'm delighted to present
for this year.
Bub. Bub is a badger.
He rides in the mining cart.
And he tries to catch gems
So everything you
with the new SceneKit's
All the materials
All the lights, too.
We also used the usual
such as action, animations, and
It's a Swift application that
It's fully built with Swift,
We placed light probes
into account the
And pay attention to the
in the caves or in the tunnels.
We have also added new
which you can see when Bub
like this.
We have a new HGI camera
and when there is a bright light
We also use IDL's for
Again some new, some,
You can also see bloom when
And all the materials, as
so we have free reflections
and for all the bonuses,
Once again, you will
It's tone mapping
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, let's go to the slides now.
I will tell you a bit
And the first thing
to tell you this year is that as
Yes. Thank you.
[ Applause ]
You can download the code on
from the developer
inspect the scene code,
And it's 700 lines
We think it's pretty
and we hope you really like
of things from the demo.
So this year we had to
we discussed it with
And we produced some
into account the
And once we agreed
and the workflow the artists
And as it's an interactive
to be able to ingest the
and to start programming
without waiting for
So we have a custom
that uses the full
in a common line application.
To involve the tools from the
to meters and they also place
in the scene because there
and we don't want, we
in by hand each time
We have used image
So we have a cube map
another cube map for the
We used the lighting environment
And it's, as you've seen,
We have also used light probes.
You can see these light probes
and we've highlighted them.
You see that only
of view there are
so you can imagine how many
So the custom tools placed them
in the environment
You can also do it by hand
the more light probes you
It's essential for the inside
to the view in the outside
to detect small changes
We have added light
because it overrides
the lighting environment, which
as the light is very
so we have the probes and the
and the mood of this
Of course we use
to add details to the models.
We also use baked
for a very much better
We have one big point
It's very high in the sky
to create dynamic shadows and
As I said, all the
in the demo are 100%
So we get the nice water palms
as well as the crystals.
Talking about crystals,
that we built.
It has no texture map so
It's fully metallic and
And just a diffuse color.
So it's a very nice
that reflects the
On the other side of the
which is one object
and nonmetallic parts.
We used, of course,
texture maps to create that.
And, as you see, we
on the normal map to add detail.
So basically the demo used
of SceneKit.
Physically based shading,
for materials, lights.
We used Xcode integration
and also new custom tools
And we think it's
for this year's capabilities
for you to learn new things.
And we hope you will
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, as you've seen, we've
with materials and
But we also had to change how
that we have great
we also needed a
And now that we have light
to have an HDR camera
because the usual camera used
which is 8-bits per components.
Now we have float per components
very unbright light such as a
for example, the sun which
So this creates a very high
to remap to the dynamic
And for that we used
Tone mapping is the action of
to a smaller capability device.
So we need to enable
It's not automatically
You can set that in
And you can configure
You can change the gray
and the range you
And you can also frost
So, for example, you can have
but you can create a low key
or overexpose it, well, but
It's very simple.
We have added also very
to the new HDR camera.
The first one is bloom.
Bloom is a way to simulate being
from the scene and reflections.
And it will be created
on the light on the
So you can see in this example
and we can see how it looks
on the roof of the tower.
I think it's a very nice way
on the surrounding pixels.
And it adds a very nice
Next we have added motion blur
So it smoothens the
And the thing is when
to the whole scene
so sometimes we don't
For example, we wanted
to be sharp and crisp.
So we have a new
to exclude some objects
and the result gives you a nice,
We have added a couple
from real life camera
The first one is vignetting.
Vignetting is a way to, is an
that creates shades on
So you can change it from
And you can also
to change the filtering going
to the border of the image.
Another aberration we have
color fringe.
Color fringe is a defraction
in real lenses, in the
So it creates a magenta
of the lights in the rendering.
And we go from this
This is a very exaggerated one.
You can go more subtle
We have also added a very
of your scene with
So you can change
go for an almost
or overblow the colors
And you can also change
So you can have the normal
or oversaturated image,
And the last one we have, it's
It's color grading.
Color grading enables us to
of the scene to completely
So we use a strip
to create the 3D color cube
to remap the original
For example, in this case would
on the upper side
So we get this looking like
And it's very simple to use
It's a very nice look.
So that's all we have
We think it's a very
We can't wait to see
We got brand new effects that
you don't have to
for example, bloom
You can use all at
Of course it has a cost but you
image and very cool
So now I hand over
about Model I/O improvements
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Hi, everybody.
So I'd just like to start
out by covering a little
and output of models
So this year SceneKit
in their native authored
not necessarily just triangles
of quadrilaterals or
that the authors originally
SceneKit, if necessary, will
for you in order to
And the thing is if you want
to use our new tessellation
to have accurate
So you'll need to opt-in,
using the preserved
That flag corresponds to
and you bring in the
It will preserve holes, and
that are important
for an accurate rendition
Now this year we have improved
to the new system and
You can see in this example here
that previously we would
and when you do the tessellation
to smoothly subdivide comes
Now if you bring it in
you can see that the quads go
and it looks very nice.
So this kind of facility
for having lightweight objects
to your scene, and
Now the other aspect of
to emphasize is that last year
materials and things
They bridge naturally onto
So if you have a high
in Model I/O, it
and without losing
So on to Model I/O.
Yeah. Quick refresher.
As it says on the [inaudible],
of models onto our
Need this so obviously to
where you've created
between frameworks,
and MetalKit, and so on.
And we provide support for a
Now file formats are the
from your art program
And historically the formats
that we had have been
For example, they might
Or they just might
Now really exciting thing that
we're bringing to you, is in
at Pixar we're introducing
for Universal Scene Description.
Now Universal Scene Description
And the thing that's really
about it is it's not only
that can be either easy to
for loading in binary
but it also includes a
That really distinguishes it
from any other format
It embodies years of practical
Pixar uses this for their films.
And "Finding Dory,"
is rendered entirely
Now USD has data types that
And it introduces, once
as an open format,
to enable concurrent workflows.
Now concurrent workflows is
Here is a representation
in Universal Scene Description
We have a shot layer, the
from components,
The characters themselves might
Now you can see there's
of a shot layer there.
That's because not only can you
of these things composed,
And so the scene description
like take three, maybe
in a little bit faster
And you can have all of
in one file and for review.
Now another really unique aspect
to Universal Scene Description
it's the only open
that allows the specification
in variations of objects.
Now, you can imagine that
of a situation where you
and they all want to go
and there's like books.
Now in a traditional
to find yourself creating
slaving out millions and
for every little book, and then
and getting it out for
Now that is tedious.
In games you have things
maybe they all differ in
And you might have to
Now Universal Scene Description
in a single file
So the class represented
So the file can represent
interpretations of books.
Like you obviously
and a tall one, and a thick one.
And when you instantiate
into the bookcase you can tell
"I want this book and I want it
And it will provide the
to instantiate that
or your shot, or whatever.
The variations that you can have
in a single file can
In this case I'm changing
So previously I had
I can make them whatever
And the magic of that is I place
for the purposes of rendering,
on the shelf in this place?"
it will work out,
about scene composition that
the way that it should
Now beyond that you can
in a single file,
So what I'm showing here is
like say for a wearable device,
The same file can have one
in the highest rendering
Now we've integrated Universal
of our systems and frameworks.
So at a very nuts
If you import a Universal
into Model I/O -- I don't expect
you're going to be
of familiar Model I/O objects
that were in the Universal
represented so that you can
in Model I/O, such as
and evaluating them
However, beyond that, let's say
and your art team just gave
You can just open that window
that you just got and Finder
so you can see what's there.
And Quick Look works
So you can select one of these
and it'll pop up and
Now, of course Quick Look
If you want to hold
or maybe your USD file has
in it that you want to inspect
that up in preview and Universal
great there.
And if you're bringing
into Xcode, it imports via
with an exact representation
so that you can inspect it
you can look at the properties,
you can move things
You make edit scenes,
And then you can send it back
you know, I've got
Can you, do you know the rep?"
So finally, it's
And so friends at Pixar supplied
up with Mr. Ray from
And this is just stock
with the new physically
that you just heard all about.
And we're just playing the
of animation, and it
So plugins are the thing that
to incorporate Universal Scene
So that will enable the motion
your content creation programs,
Now the plugins, and the
and all availability,
are available on the openusd.org
to go visit to find out
in your pipelines and processes.
So that's Universal
[ Applause ]
So a quick summary.
SceneKit is available
on every platform.
It's kind of an amazing thing.
We have physically based
of the art looks and state
just a beautiful look.
And HDR cameras and
over how things are represented
and how they look,
And we've got support for
which we're really happy to
to make a big difference
in coming days and months.
More information on this
is available on the site.
There's related sessions:
Wide Color, Game
that you can attend
And thank you very much.
[ Applause ]