[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
And welcome to What's
I'm Ross. I'm an engineer here
in the Games Technology
And I'm really excited
to show you what we've been
Before we jump into talking
about the new features
I'd like to take a moment to
for anyone who may not
So, SpriteKit is our 2D
It's designed to be highly
to use while still
So, there are as few barriers
and the great games
It's supported across all of our
tvOS and this year
that is available
Any app, I know,
[ Applause ]
Any App that uses SpriteKit
to the latest version of
without needing to be
so you're always up-to-date.
And it's naturally integrated
all these great features,
But the framework is only
The other half is our Xcode
which lets you preview your
and lay them out visually.
It offers timeline-based
to bring life to
with our robust particle editor.
It's fully integrated
so you can leverage
and on-demand resources
to jump through any hoops.
And this year we're
and GameplayKit integration,
about a little later on.
And finally, SpriteKit is fully
that support it,
to its great performance
without having to do anything.
So, this year we're continuing
that make it easier
to make great games
So, without further ado,
Now, normally with
we'd put the tools
But today we're going to turn
And that's because the
to getting the most
And this year we've got some
So, let's start with
Knowing what's in your
to one another is
for effective scene management.
In Xcode 7, this
through the Jump Bar.
The Jump Bar is designed to
in your workspace easier but
it also has all the
And this is great for
but it would be nice if we
at the same time.
So, now in Xcode 8 you can,
It's a new panel that allows
in your scene and
relationship simultaneously.
In addition to being
you can also rename them and
You can also change their
of the nodes by dragging
much like you reorder
Drag a child onto another
drag a node onto another node
or drag a child out
to break that relationship.
We also have the ability
Locked nodes can't be modified
And that can make navigating
when you have a lot of notes and
And the same with hiding.
It's great for when you
and you want to access some
So, all these features make the
and it's making, makes managing
So, next I'd like to talk a
to integrate the GameplayKit
So, last year we
a brand-new framework that
for problems that are commonly
One of the features included
and components, which is a
on modularity and reusability.
Components encapsulate behavior
or entities to change
And you do this without
for every object in your scene.
Now, we're not going
about how these work but it's
as code building blocks that
to create objects that
Typically, you might have a
for objects that can be damaged.
Or a component that has
that can collide
Or a component that
to be a player controlled
Components are really
to control how your
And now we're bringing
into the SpriteKit editor.
You can assign components that
from within your scene
and components panel
Additionally, you can
on the custom components
and those will then
and you can tweak
The best part about all this is
if you're already using
and components, we're now
and you can do all of your
from the editor.
Another great feature
that GameplayKit
Pathfinding is all about finding
to point B and it does this
by operating what's
Navigation graphs
of nodes joined together
And they describe how an object
without colliding
And now we've integrated
into the SpriteKit editor.
So, you can create and edit
You can add and remove
and make connections
by clicking in the editor.
And you can leverage the
Creating the graph this
and easily define how entities
making pathfinding a breeze.
So, now let's talk a little bit
yeah I know, it's
[ Applause ]
Now to talk a little
that helps you get the most
of your game, the FPS
You may have used the
As you're running your App,
of real-time performance
including your frame
and CPU/GPU frame time.
And this is really helpful
but further granularity
Now in Xcode 8, you get,
of your SpriteKit apps time,
frame time for both
Additionally, it breaks down
to see how much time is
running the update loop,
of physics and idle time.
This information can be
where you need to focus your
The FPS performance
to help you improve your
It's available for use with
So, we've covered some great
and now I'd like to change
about a new feature that's
and the framework, tile maps.
So, for anyone who
with what tile maps are,
of evenly spaced images.
And they're great for piecing
of small, repeating
Think of tiles as, tile
and tiles as the pieces.
Individually they don't look
and you can easily create
So, before we get into the
let's talk a little bit about
Building scenes from small
common when creating games.
And without tile maps,
you'd have to manually place
And this totally works.
And using a set of
for keeping memory overhead low.
They can also be rearranged
to how the scene looks.
However, copy pasting
and manually aligning each
tedious and time-consuming.
It can also cause your scene to
which quickly makes things
So instead you could use large,
more detailed images
A sample game released
DemoBots, used this approach.
So, let's say one large image
in your scene is
and that definitely keeps
But if you want to
you need to make modifications
Plus, large images
and if you want more
you'll need additional
which in turn further
So, tile maps gives you the
They're easy to manage, as each
in your scene.
They can be quickly modified.
Say for instance I want
to change the sand
All I have to do is
to change the type
And by using a set of smaller
to have large, detailed scenes
Tile maps are also
of different games
You can use them
side scrolling platformers,
hex-based board games.
Tile maps are incredibly
So, as you've seen, tile maps
of just telling you that how
into a demo so I can show you.
So, here we are in
and we've already got a
So, let's go ahead
And so the quickest way to start
double-click on it.
And that brings up our
at the top of the screen here.
And by default, we have
which allows us to
And so the paint, all we
and we start placing
If you want to change what type
all we have to do is click on
and that shows us all the
for placement.
So, here let's place edge
and a couple more edge tiles.
And we can see how
piece together your
But individually placing
bit tedious.
So, I'm going to show you
So, here we're just going
to a place a new tile
And by default on our tile
in the inspector enabled
And what this does is when I
to select my tiles, you'll see
for placement, we now have these
into different types of terrain,
So, I'll go ahead
And now when we go to place
and place the center
to all the edge tiles
And this is really
and easily creating your scenes.
Now, instead of having to
and corner tile, we can just
up each of the tiles that we
to go through any extra
That makes painting
[ Applause ]
So, let's take a look at how
So, the tile sets arrive
And as you see here, you can
that we have, like grass,
And you can see that
so that you can see how they're
So, let's put a new
So, all we have to do to set
with our automapping is to
into their corresponding
You can see that we
that vaguely what the tile's
So, we'll just grab some tiles
And we just drag-and-drop
and super easy to set
So there. Let's give it a name.
We'll call this one garden.
And that's it.
So now we can go into a scene.
We'll create a tile map here.
We'll start editing it.
And you'll see our garden
So, I just grab that
And you can see how easy it is
that already works
You don't have to
But there's a little
with the tile groups as well.
So, I'll go back to our tile,
that I premade over here.
And at first glance
But then when I start clicking
you can see that we have a bunch
of variants available
And this is the same for each
So, when we paint this
it will randomly select one of
So, you can have a lot more
Additionally, you can
of the styles, these variants.
See here, the red
have a placement weight of 3.
White flowers have a
And the blue have a
So, the red flowers
than the white flowers and more
So, now let's go
We'll create another tile map
and we'll assign our
Now, when we start
you can see our variants
So, you can see the tiles sets
to achieve a lot of different
of work which is super useful.
So, another thing we can do with
So, here in the tile
it appears as if there's
But if I grab it here,
you'll see that's actually 2
And so you see we can layer
to make it make it appear
as if we have more
than we actually have.
So, it looks like these
to transition to
So, they actually have
So, when we move
they just naturally
And so we move it on
to achieve the same effect.
Now looks as if they're
So, this allows you to
out of your art assets.
If you just have them
on the edges, you can
any way you can conceive
to get a lot more flexibility
So, another thing that we can do
with our tile sets is
So, here we have a nice tile set
We'll press the animate button
and if you look closely
on the water tiles
So, now let's take a look at the
Set the water.
You can see, preview
from our tile set editor.
And I can select
and you can see we just have, so
that are in our animation.
Now, we give it a time per
Now, this is basically
with textures app should works.
And it's just that easy
Which is a really great way of
But in additional to frame
we can also animate the
So, the tile maps
So, you can do everything
So of course you can
You can scale them.
You can rotate them.
I note that you can still
while they're like this although
when you're at some weird angles
But because SK nodes, the
we can run actions on them.
So, here you see I have a bunch
up on my tile map by moving
So, we just animate this thing.
We can see yeah, we
and then we put it back.
And so you see that
of bringing animation
which can be really useful.
In fact, we can leverage this
to create some interesting
So, in this scene, I've got
up in our tile map here.
Don't want to do that yet.
And if I position the camera
we're simply moving these tile
and this achieves the
an effect that we call
And all I'm doing here is simply
at one rate of speed, the middle
and the background layer
And that achieves the
And it's just incredibly easy.
So, in addition to having simple
we also have support
and isometric tiles as well.
So, you have lots of flexibility
that you can achieve
So, speaking of which,
at a game sample right now.
So, here we've got a little
A little guy that
And you can see that I got
on in the background.
And you'll note that I'm
And I achieve this by
that we can put on
Here, I'll show you
Select one of the variants here.
And you can see that we have
And I just have a
which is a Boolean,
So, in code, I'm going
in our platform demo
for all of these edge tiles.
And whenever I find one,
to allow the player
And since it is just in our tile
over this large wall here.
When I run the game, you'll see
that my guy can't actually jump
And he really wants to
over there looks
I really want to
So, since we're just generating
and our user data, all we
and erase these tiles and
The tiles are now gone and we
And we didn't have to
We just used the
from the tile map
It's that simple.
[ Applause ]
And now as a reward, I
Yay.
So, that's how our tile
So, now that we've shown you
let's take a look at the
And if you're creating tile
you're not going to need to
But it's good to get an
So, tile maps are implemented
which as mentioned in the
It holds all the information
about the tiles you've
But to be able to place tiles,
And the tile set is defined
It contains all the tile
Additionally, it also defines
and they can either be
isometric tiles or
The tile groups are defined
And as we saw on the demo,
of related tiles,
of terrain like grass or water.
The tile group also
that define how the
in the group should
And those rules are defined
That also holds all the
with the pattern it describes.
And finally, each
through an SKTileDefinition
which defines the
Each one has at least one image
they can be animated
to help bring life
Additionally, the tiles can
allowing you to get more
Now, let's take a
so you can see how
and modify a tile
The first step is to get the
Now, you can create
but it's a very involved
that you create them
Getting one you've
Just call this convenience
of the tile set that
Then, to create a new tile
with the tile set we want to
and rows in the map along
If you want to start
we're going to need
So, here we're just grabbing
in the tile set.
Once we have a tile map and a
we can start setting
Here we're setting
on the tile at column 4, row 7.
We can also operate on
Here we are filling every tile
So, if you're creating
through the SpriteKit editor,
of the API we just covered.
But unless you're
for entirely static backgrounds,
to be able to query them.
There are a bunch of
Say for instance you want to
over a particular tile
and inject some custom
on the tile definition.
You can do this by first
and a tile maps frame
Then, you'd use the
to get the column
that contains that position.
Next, you query the tile
in that column and row.
And finally, now that you've
you can check the user
that you're interested in.
And then act on that data
And the demo we just showed,
to this to detect
on the big red button.
When they are over a tile
with a button custom
we trigger the fireworks.
It's all a lot to take in,
so let's quickly recap the
By creating scenes from a set
tile maps help you get more
Overall, you'll need
and it also brings the benefit
They support animation, both in
and actions at the node level.
Tile maps are designed to be
which further increases the
and enables effects
They're extremely
of different art styles
Large tile maps are
into smaller chunks
that are currently
which provides a big
Additionally, if all the tile
in the same Asset
each chunk will batch all the
with a single draw call.
Tile maps also come in
standard square grids, isometric
On the tool side, editing
Just point and click to
Automapping does all the hard
to individually place
And you can of course
to do the detail work by hand.
Finally, creating new tile
Just drag-and-drop the
into their corresponding
and you're good to go.
So, that covers tile sets.
Now I'd like to invite
up to talk to you about the rest
of the awesome features
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ross.
All right, some cool
So, hello.
My name is Clement.
I'm a software engineer
in the Game Technologies Team.
And guess what?
We actually have
so let's see what else
And the first up is
So, currently you have many ways
You can apply a scale to make
You can apply a rotation to
Or if you like to
you can also write
such as this low
that you can see right there.
This year we're very happy
of transformation called
Warp Transformation allows you
to define a custom distortion
So, for example if we
it's basically 8 points
in green is our source position,
Then I get a second grid here
but it's going to
So, what you see here is
and as you can see,
around to create a distortion.
So now if I apply like
of earlier, this is what I get.
As you can see, we get a nice
and smooth distortion
And the distortion is going
between the source and
So, let me show you some
with Warp Transformation.
And my first example
So, what I'm doing here is just
center to create a
Next, I had a stretch effect.
I am pulling the
and making it wiggle
It can look a bit funny.
And the next big thing here
So, usually in 2D games
to make static frames
And it's a pretty long
to iterate a new
And Warp Transformation,
as just moving points around.
And if you have any
such as a keyframe-based
you can just provide multiple
to be done at one time.
You no longer need
So, now let me explain you
Warp Transformation.
So again, if we have a 2 by 2
of points from 0 to
This point, this point,
in this grid are quad
So, now from the computer
what we have here is a list
and texture coordinates are
And then you just set the GPU
So, this is fine and we
but initially what happens if I
and I limit it to one quad
by 1 grid, so, come on.
Show me some distortion.
All right, go for it.
Yeah, it doesn't
And the reason why is because
so only one triangle
So, what can we do about this?
Well, we could make
and upload more quads.
But then it's kind
because you have more
Especially because
It's almost as if
move pixels around, right?
So, no. As you have guessed,
So, in SpriteKit,
Again, 2 by 2 grid.
We, so you only have
and as you do the distortion
of the points moving
There we go.
So, we do automatic quad
And this is great because it
between a high level of details
and minimal quads
And again, you only
So, here, as I move the
you can see that I'm going
of distortion is a bit high.
So we you do subdivision.
But at the bottom right, it's
so we only subdivide twice.
And because we want to
we actually allow you to
of subdivision.
So, if I take my
and I make it a bit distorted
you might see some
some artifacts throwing up,
So, if I go with
you might see artifacts.
But if you go up
we clearly lose all
and have this nice smooth line
So again, this is perfect
to tune your visuals
Because of course, the
the best for performance.
All right, this is cool but
Okay, so first thing.
Remember, we have a grid layout.
So, 8 points labeled
I'm going to provide a
a list of definition position,
I can just create my
by providing the column, the
source positions, and then
And we have the distortion.
And optionally you can
to whatever you want
And because it is SpriteKit,
of new SK actions
So, making a transformation
as just saying SKActionWarp
Or, if you have something
such as a keyframe-based
you can provide a list of
All right.
So, okay, let's do
to show you Warp
Alright. So, I'm actually going
to be using the same demo is
to go on the left
where all the cool stuff is.
All right, so we
let's go explore for a bit.
Oh, look at that.
All right, so what we have
We have one animation that
to right and one that makes your
a bigger size to smaller size.
And we also added
to make things rotate
It just makes your scene much
Okay, so let's keep
Okay, oh, look at this,
Well, what's the best way
I think it's just to
There ago.
So, what I did here is just
and then the collision
I'm just running in SKAction
All right, so that's
Let's go back to the slides.
So, Warp Transformations
and enable a broad range of
So I really hope you're going to
And next let's talk
about per-node attributes
Shaders are awesome.
I really love shaders.
And there is a best way for you
to make exact digital
In SpriteKit, we support custom
with SKShader class which is
which you apply to your nodes.
It comes with a few built-in
the texture, texture
And if you have any
you can also specify
for your special variables.
All right, so what about we
Okay, so I really
So, what about some platforms.
Here we go, that's pretty good.
Okay, I want something
Oh yeah, that's awesome.
I love this guy,
Right? You know what, I'm going
So let's put some
and danger, just like that.
Right, that's better.
Unfortunately our bunny's
and because I want I don't
I'm going to have the
and the health bar,
And guess what?
The health bar is
You see it coming, right?
Okay. So, how would I go
making a health bar
So I add a Sprite
I have a shader to
such as the blinking
and how filled in it is.
So, here our bunny
so it's only filled halfway.
And to control these visuals,
I have a uniform
It's going to be a flood
from one being full-life
to not full-life.
Okay. But because games
when you have multiple players,
We can have up to three players.
To, that means at any time
full-life, someone
and someone who's pretty
Okay, so again, In
I have my Sprite, my
But now how would I go
with multiple players?
Well, I have to do this.
Yeah, I have to duplicate
but that just doesn't
Why do we have to do that?
That's just bad.
And it's bad because, while
And it's going to break
meaning more draw calls.
And it's just too
Well, if you wanted to
I have only one shader and
And, well, starting this
that using attributes.
With custom attributes, you
attach it to your shader, and
on the nodes themself.
So, here I have a custom
and I just set the health
It's super simple.
In Swift, this is
I'm creating my attribute
I give it a name, so here,
I attach it to my shader.
Because my shader only
I'm giving a list
Lastly I can directly set
So, here play one has only
so I'm just doing set attribute
So, this is very convenient
with per-node customization
All right.
So, now let's talk about a
And the first one being focus
So, for those of you who've
for Apple TV, you already know
But for those of you who do not,
let me just recap what
Last year we introduced
tvOS and its brand-new
as the Siri remote
So, now one of the major
and Apple TV is interaction.
So, on iPhone the user's
on the phone by touching
On Apple TV on the other hand,
the user will always have
between him and the interface.
And we actually call
focus-based interaction.
So, let me show you what happens
in the main menu of the
So, as you can see, we only
and scrolling ware is
and react your fingertip
So, in fact, this
And it's so important
and our frameworks using
So it means that if you happen
you don't need to re-create
All you have to do is
say which one are focusable,
It's very simple to use
and provides a consistent user
in the main menu of Apple
And as a bonus, we support
game controllers and many
and many, many more.
If you want to learn more about
there is a session this week
and you can find many
All right, so the
that we have SpriteKit
So, that's pretty great.
Yeah, thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, this is actually
of user interface in your
or you could have subbuilder
such as a chess game
And the cool thing here is
What you can see
It's a sample code app
to be for iOS and macOS.
We did a port to tvOS and
to remove all this code for the
It was just so much
Speaking of DemoBot,
about creating this menu
and focus interaction.
The first thing you
that UIKit introduces new
which conforms to the
This extends the focus
So, as you have guessed,
now SKNode is actually
So, the first thing you need
So, here for my menu element,
I'm going to use
I'm going to use a SpriteNode.
So first, make a subclass.
Second, you need to override
to true so that your
Next you have to obtain your
and to do that, you just have
to set the
to true.
And the last thing you need
to do is override the data
which is going to give you
So, you can override this
or any node that actually
So, here the context subject
the previously focused item,
for a menu element and
I can just run some SKAction.
So, this is how it
As I finish the game, I am
and I can just use my Siri
or game controller, it
And I have the same
in the main menu on Apple TV.
Again, very simple,
We recommend highly
All right, a pretty
SpriteKit on Apple Watch.
So, as you have seen,
we brought some frameworks
And yeah, SpriteKit
So, that means that now you can
using this high-performance
And of course we bring
such as particles,
and all the editors
so you can use the scene editor.
You can use the particle editor.
We have all the editing tools
that Ross just told it out.
All of this is just working.
So, a typical SpriteKit
I have an SKView and then
which itself contains
Such as the SpriteNode,
On Apple Watch, though,
Instead, you present
WatchKit interface.
And in fact it's going to be
So, instead of using an SKView,
I will be using a
It looks pretty much it.
All right, so let's see how we
on iOS to make it a
So, that's some code,
that's some sample
So, pretty typical,
I'm doing some set up on
All right.
So, what I have to do now
new, target, select
So here I'm going to use a game
Click next.
Give it the best name
to call it Apple Watch Game.
And then click next.
And you're done.
No, seriously, you're done.
Xcode is going to create
such as the storyboard and the
And if you take a look at the
up everything for you already.
So, this guy is actually
as you can see at the top here.
And you're just ready to go.
You have your WKInterfaceScene
and you have the same
So, it's very simple.
All right, so some compatibility
There's no SKAudioNode
but of course you can
SKAction playSoundFileNamed.
There's no SKVidioNode
WKInterfaceMovie instead.
And lastly if you're doing a
you can still do them but
So, we're really excited
with Apple Watch in SpriteKit.
It's going to enable you to
and fun apps with the platform.
All right.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, since we have more and more
about a few best
The first one being
Use Asset Catalog.
It's great.
It works very well with
of cool features for your game
to make things simple
The first thing being
In Asset Catalog, you
which is a fundamental piece
where you have multiple textures
which reduces the number of
Next we have support for
you know, 1x, 2x, 3x, which is
such as the iPad,
And again, you don't need to
is this that platform
No, you just call your
We do rest for you.
We have support for
which is fundamental for tvOS.
And lastly we do app slicing,
meaning that if you
that are specific platform,
for the bundle and
into the runtime binaries
which gives you a
and a small download
So yeah, Asset Catalog
Next, about performance
So, a big change in
that we do not render
Now, we only render when
So, if something change, we
but if nothing changed, we
So, if you're using
such as the performance gauge,
you might see the
And it's actually a good
that you are not
If you need to control
you we also have a couple
The first one being
on SKView.
At any time, you can
to whatever you want, which can
if you have the menu and you
And when you come back to your
or 30 FPS based on
The second one is a
It's a delegate in SKView
which is giving you
with the absolute
So, this method is going
and you can decide based
or no you want to
So, this gives you a
of the rendering for your game.
All right.
And that's it.
So, what's new in SpriteKit?
A lot this year.
The first being the scene
to manipulate your
The GameplayKit integration.
If you're already using
now you can just set them on
FPS high performance gauge which
of your scene performance,
Tile maps for complex yet
Warp Transformation to
and complex animation using
Per-node attributes
if you're using per-node
of shaders, very convenient.
And of course focus interaction
on Apple Watch, which is
If you want to learn more,
you can go to the
We have a lot of sessions
of them are already done.
But you can still see
on the website we I
And tomorrow you can go to
as well as Game Technologies
to learn more about these
All right.
[ Applause ]