[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
Thank you for coming.
My name is Megan Gardner.
I am a Software Engineer
and today we're going
about what's new in Game Center.
So if you don't know what
Game Center is Apple's
It allows you, as developers,
which your users can
also define achievements
We also have challenges which
and achievements to add
to your single player games.
We also have two
both real-time and turn-based.
And we ship all of these
and this year we are
So what's new?
We've got a few new
First is we have a great new way
Next we have big news
if you haven't figured
We have a brand new API for
that we're really excited about.
And we're also announcing
Now we don't have time
in this session, but if that's
I really suggest that you
for Apple Watch" later this
So let's talk
about message-based
Now you can play with
Currently our multiplayer
for Game Center pretty
This is our
and this is what most of you are
This is a built-in
It allows your users to be able
to invite their Game
as do play now which
Some of you have
which is our programmatic
to do your own UI and
But if you've been using
it now looks like this.
This is our new integrated
You'll notice some differences.
There's no bubbles but that's
It now integrates
which will allow your users
to anyone in their
to play a game with them.
So let's see what
This is the Multiplayer View
You can click Play Now
and automatch will work
However, we're more interested
when we click Invite Friends.
So that will bring in this
You can see we have this
that we've got.
We've got the little Doodle
I added a little bit of text
about what this link is
And this is all based on
of your users will
into iCloud for this to work.
You can then start
This will autocomplete to
in a email address or phone
or anyone that you just met.
Or you can click on that
to bring in the Contacts.
So these are all my Contacts
that I have Messages
You'll also see that there's
That is where your Game Center
as well as anyone that your
on Game Center.
And Nearby also functions the
in that it will be looking
that are also playing this game.
So I'm going to click on Alisha,
invite my friend,
And then we'll click Add
in into that To field.
You can then, this functions
This is basically Messages UI
so you're users can
and then it's going to
If I clicked on a Game Center
to show up in gray and
Center notification.
They're not going
of weird Game Center iMessage.
It will come in as
So if we click on that Send
to Alisha and this is
like on Alisha's screen.
She can then tap the link
and that will take her
and start connecting
if she had tapped
And the same functionality
if she did not have Doodle
to the store where she can
like she would be able
Now I said that there's
in order to implement this.
We have just replaced
so if you have been using
then you've got this just
As soon as iOS 10 is shipped
to do this and invite
They will no longer be limited
However, we have one thing
if you would like, which
So you'll notice right here it's
If you would like to change
that you feel more appropriately
or more appropriately indicates
or a fun thing that people will
all you need to do
GKMessageInvite to your bundle.
And the same way that we will
to customize your notification
and customize your rich link.
Notice this is the same
that is being used for
to taking a wide
So what does this mean
Well, we don't need
because we can play with anyone.
So we're freezing
But you will still
of the Game Center
in that Recents Player tab.
And you can still
Friends still exists.
We're not deleting them.
They're still there.
But you won't be able
or respond to any
And because of that,
GKFriendRequestCompose
now deprecated.
It wasn't really used
So what does that mean
Well, if you've downloaded
you might notice some changes.
Well, what is the Game
In iOS 9 it was basically used
to manage your account,
You could browse
You could look at
check out your achievements,
send challenges, and
Well, it turns out all of these
in other places in the system
and more importantly,
And so we have removed
So where did we do
[ Laughter ]
[ Applause ]
If you want to manage
you can do that in settings.
you can still do
If you want to browse your
you can look at your
You view your leaderboards,
from GKGameCenterViewController.
If you're not using
you can also do your own UI.
If you're not presenting
and achievements in your
that you start doing that now.
And you can also view and take
GKTurnBasedMatchmaker
So we've removed the app.
Everything is really
more importantly, in your app.
We would love our users to
more time in your app.
We've got the rest of the phone.
We don't need any
And so we've removed the app.
Now let's talk about Sessions.
This is our brand new
really excited about this.
This is a brand new
So Game Center Multiplayer,
We basically have
with real-time and turn-based.
Real-time will connect
Those connections will require
If anyone drops from
then that whole connection
You're just passing
And as soon as that match is
Turn-based can connect
We have a very formal
and also exchanges but
to follow those rules and you
like fits within that structure.
And all games are stored
until they are aged out.
So what is Sessions?
Sessions is our new
So we have this great
and sharing game data.
These are easily shareable
that people can share
that they would like
It's a completely
We don't impose anything on you.
You can do whatever you want.
And we have really stable,
that you can set up
And this is going to allow
So what does a Session
So we have two main
We've got our game data.
It's probably one of the
But also equally
And really this is all that
that you have to have
is a player and some game data.
You can have multiple players
like to play with other people.
We also have the ability to send
These messages will come in
So you can have those messages
between players or multiple
messages all at the same time.
Along with these messages we
So you can send those messages
to let them know that there's
something within that session,
that they might want
Now I only show four players
up to 100 players in a single
than we've been able
And we can have multiple
So you can have small sessions
You can have four players,
Those players can be
onto different teams.
And you can have all
and your player can be in
of sessions all at
We also have real-time streams
and you would like to be able to
between your different players,
to set their connection states
and we will be setting these
that will allow the
to start communicating
So, let's get into the
of what makes up a session.
So we've got a couple
We've got GKGameSession which
to basically interact
as well as the other players.
We have GKCloudPlayer which
We have GKEventListener
when important things happen
that your players are in.
And we also have
which will give you a little
that you might encounter
So let's talk about
So this is your main workhorse.
This is where almost
to be done per session.
It allows you to do
You can create a
load and store your game
add your players, remove your
send your notifications,
join your streams, send
Basically everything you're
to be interacting
Some more details about that.
With your game data
up to 512 kilobytes of data.
This data is going to be
so it's not something
And the user is going to
It will count against
And it's going to follow
of who owns that data, how
and what happens when
Messages and Badges,
come in as Game Center
and they're badged as such.
And badging is now going to
by you, as the developer.
We'll get into that a little
to be very clear where that
and you should be able to
and change it to pretty
And we also have these
which basically leverage
This is running on the same
as well as iMessage
it's really stable, and it's
So if we want to make a
Well, first we need a title,
something to describe
Either you can define that or
You need your container ID
that you set up with your app.
And also set up a container that
so if you want multiple
that same data, say if
your pay version, or, you
of versions of your
if you set that up correctly,
to access that same data.
And you can also set the max
There's a hard limit of
in that real-time stream but
that lower, or something
that when you create
to decide that when you create.
So once you've, so you just will
with all of that
and that will give you a session
that you can start
One of the first things you're
with the session is
to load and save your data.
Any player that's in a
It's just one big blob
And there's a little
with that session that will help
which is last modified date
So you'll know who was
or not it's important for you
than likely up to date.
So you can just call
that will pass you your data.
You'd also probably
As I said before, 512 kilobytes
but you can do whatever
It can be whatever
So you'll call saveData
If there is a conflict, if
in the interim, you will get
that conflicting data back.
And we'll talk a little bit
Anytime someone does save
that goes along with that.
So if you set up your
for a session player to save
when someone else has saved
that you will more than
and resolve any conflicts
So as I said, Save
And this will happen where two
to try to save data in
Since there's no real formal
that two players can be
if that's how you design
So say we've got Players Two
to save at the same time.
Well, one of them is
to say it's Player Two.
That means when Player Three
to get an error and that
be returned.
Now you are going to
to resolve this conflict.
Since we have no
for what this data is we also
And so it's going to be up
in such a way that it's going
out what those conflicts
and recall saved data in order
for that data to
If you do not recall saved data,
and you need to continue
until you return
And then everything
Everything will be the
and you can continue forward.
And then everything
We've talked about
how do you get additional
Any player that's in a session
to join.
Basically you're going
that you need to
You can send this via iMessage,
print it out, paste
that's probably not
But as long as you can get
and they can click on
to be added to that session.
The easiest way to do this
because it just pops
and you can send off a message.
And that's probably the
So if like the Player One, if
from the session, they set up an
to send to Player Two.
They've added a little
want you want to play with me?"
It'll come out as
It will be sent to Player
and as soon as they click
So in order to get the URL
CompletionHandler.
It will give you the URL
that you can then do
And then anytime
to a session the Event Listener
And that will let you know
that someone else has joined
to proceed with your
So we've been talking
so what exactly are they?
Well, we've got GKCloudPlayer.
This is different
that you've been
GKCloudPlayer is only for,
It basically has two pieces of
to your app as well
that is what the user will have
as what they want they
This is not a GKPlayer
If you try to use this for a
for other multiplayer, for
So please don't do that.
Everyone will be
So how do we get
Basically you can get your
Most of the things in Sessions
from your current player though
to make sure that
that you are then saying, "Oh,
this player is saving
All that's handled for
But you might be
like who owns this session?
So you might want to know if
if other player owns it,
then that will delete the
And you also might want to
send messages, be a
You can also get any of
in the session, it's just
And that's the best way that
to send those messages
especially setting
So speaking of messages and
These messages, we say
in as Game Center notifications.
As I said before, all
at any time to any other player.
Those messages are
You can also send a little bit
if there's any sort of relevant
to pass to the other players
or what they might want to
And you can also optionally
so anyone that gets this
as well as that message.
So what does the code look like?
sendMessageWithLocalizedKey.
You've got all these arguments,
or not you would like
And the Event Listener
didReceiveMessage fromPlayer.
And that will be called any
in to let the player know
in that they might
or might want to deal with.
And badges.
So I've said badges can be
So basically anytime you send a
that badge state
You've got one badge per
like there's something you need
And these badges can be set
So if you send a message
I need some help with this thing
and then no one shows
clear those badges and
I didn't want to
And so that you can keep all
of that badge data
The app icon will
so if you've got three sessions
that app icon will say three.
If you have one, you know,
only one of them is
We could aggregate that for
what is set in that session
where that badge
So let's talk about
So we've made a session.
We've saved it.
We've loaded it.
We've loaded the data.
We've sent it to some players.
Your user has turned
They've done some other things.
You've come back.
You want to load those
that you've got all
so that they can
So the first thing you'll
loadSessionsInContainer,
that same app container
that you made the session in.
This will load the bare bones
that your local player
Then based off of that data
and figure out which session
That session has two main
One is that title that you gave
You can make it anything
And so that's not enough to be
Upon creation of a session we
and that is what you will
that specific session.
Call loadSessionWithIdentifier
and that will give you
for the session including
to do in order to start loading
to other players, and
You also might want
If you call
that's the same identifier
if the player does
it will merely remove
It will not actually
However, if you're
that that player created,
not only for that player,
but for everyone
And that may be one
that who your local player is,
to be doing that to
alert the user that,
for everyone," so that they
At any time a player is removed
called didRemovePlayer
that someone has left
to update your game accordingly.
So let's talk about
So this is the real-time
Everything else up until
of sound pretty turn-based.
You're saving.
You're passing messages.
We also have the ability to have
So Game Session Streams, you are
of the players that are
So everyone who is in that
like to start sending
that is how you're
You can basically see the
that are in the session.
You can send data to
in the connection
And you will be able to add
without having to
So you can someone join in and
third person wants to come
to reset everything up.
As soon as they start
They can start sending data.
You don't have to do any
of that in the background
So how do we set
Basically you just need
to set the connection
So you would just call
with completionHandler.
This can fail for a
of the reasons could
for that session has
So if this is the 17th
that stream and you've
then this will actually fail
to join into the stream.
You can see whether the players
basically the states are
so you can see how many other
and who they are.
And anytime a player either
either connects or disconnects,
the Event Listener session
will be called.
And so you can know whether
and how many people you
Once you set up the connection
to probably start sending data.
So all of the data is
of the connected players.
You can send this either
just the same as our
Whether or not it's more
that those players get that data
that they're getting the
And any time data is
didReceiveDataFromPlayer will be
that data and update your
on with playing your game.
So that's all like the basic
So let's talk about
of what this actually
like when you're
So first basically
your basic turn-based game.
So you've set up your session.
You've got your game data.
You've added a few players.
Maybe it's Player One's turn.
They're going to start by
and they're going
That data can then be loaded by
Message Player One can then
sending it that badge
"Hey, it's your turn now."
Maybe you would like to do that.
Player Two can load up
figure out what they would
take their turn, save that data,
and then pass the turn
Since there is no specified way
in which these turns can
You can pass it from One
Four to One, whatever you want.
There is no specified way
in which these turns can
we don't know what you're doing.
So you pass the game
They get to take their
So you've got all the
for a really basic
You can also do a
So you've got all of
You can then basically
on their connection states.
As soon as these connection
up the pipes in the
to communicate with each other.
And as soon as all
up then your players can start
And then this data will
as these connections
And then with sessions,
of information you would like
such as, you know,
or anything for this
you do have that ability
of a persistent data
to save with that session.
So those are your
But the real power session
to do much more complicated
So say you've got
It's a turn-based game but you
of a complicated turn.
They've got a game.
It's got some trading
so when it's the player's
to trade cards, maybe brick
And so the things that you
with table talk on an actual
easily accomplish with sessions.
So say it's Player One's
with the other players and so
"Hey, I'd like trade
Anyone interested?"
So you can send that message.
You can send a little bit
to let the users know,
and send it out to everyone.
Say Player Four is
That sounds really good.
You know, I'll take that trade,"
that doesn't work for me.
How about wheat for sheep?"
or something else.
So they can send a message back
and saying, "Hey, this is, I
or I have a different trade."
You can send that
figure out what you want to do.
As soon as Player
Well, I'll take that trade,"
they can their turn,
and save their data,
and then pass the
We also have the ability
into multiplayer games
that might be a little
So say you've got a multiplayer
like a King of the
You've got all these people in
of them to be able
So you're going to
You've got Players One and Two.
They're going to turn on
They're going to join into
to pass their data
They're going to have
a little one-on-one, and fight.
And one of those players
In this case let's
And then Player Two
with the next person in line.
You don't have to stop
You don't have to set up any
As soon as Player Three sets
can start sending that data
and Three immediately
to have their little
This time [inaudible] and
in and join in the fray.
They can make that
And you can continue
continuing to do any
If you've got like 100 players,
you can go through
And just continue to
of the Hill style fight.
And then you can store
that will allow to have a little
and a little bit more persistent
that are in this session.
Another situation
into is assisted single player.
So say you've got a
You're using Sessions to
which is totally fine.
You can absolutely do a single
and basically use this as
and send your data so that all
across all of your
But say your player is having
They've been playing this
Then they can't get
They're having a
Well, if you implement
then Player One can then share
And so they can bring
And then you can
that will allow Player
through that level,
or you could even just allow
that level for Player One
that really sticky point in
to have a little
So Player Two can come in, say,
do whatever you would
Save that data, so
And then they can lead
from that game and Player
that game just as if Player
been there.
So that is Game Sessions.
This is going to allow you
with anyone, anyone that has
play with.
You don't need to be their
So much more flexible game
to allow you, as developers,
in whatever manner
We have really, really simple
They are really easy to
They allow for lots of data
And we're really excited
to see what new possible game
up with because of
Because of this mixing
and real-time elements for
to see what you're
So that's what's new in
We had our new message-based
which are now going
with anyone that
We have removed the
We have those persistent
that we just talked about.
And we have also announced
If you would like any more
you can go to this link.
We are session number 611.
And we have a few
that you might be interested in.
We have the "Game Technologies
for Apple Watch" later
We've also had several
that you can go and watch the
even more than what's
Thank you for coming
[ Applause ]