[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and welcome
to Game Technologies
I hope you've had a great WWDC
about all the great
Gaming in iOS has captured
As a longtime gamer, I've
of games created by
We've heard that you're
for games on Apple Watch
to present gaming for watchOS 3.
This session covers everything
on this most personal device.
We will first show you
on Apple Watch and provide
We will then introduce you
that allow you to create
In addition we will show you
and multiplayer into your app.
And finally, we will show
to use during development,
of the best practices.
watchOS provides a rich set of
This includes some things
as WatchKit and rich
Today, however, we will
In WatchKit we offer new
to create your game in Xcode
You can now use just your
for precise control
There's also haptic feedback
to make your experience much
SpriteKit and SceneKit
that let you create rich
They provide good
and form a simple foundation on
Game Center provides API's
to your game including
leaderboards, and multiplayer.
But now let me show an
This is a game built
which is our 3D framework.
You start out with a collection
Your goal is to rotate them
until they form a
Now let's watch this
When the player, and now
we're going to play another
about what's happening here.
We use pan gestures to control
And when it is in the same plane
to rotate it into
So now that we've introduced
and showed a demo, let's dive
into how we can make your
in a much more natural way.
Apple Watch is our
We use it up close, usually with
or rotating the crown.
You can read motion
or you can even make it
When used together this
that you're using a
and responds in an
Let's start with touch.
On watchOS 3 we offer four
for different kinds of
And I'd like to go
Tap is the simplest.
You touch the screen and
or a position to move to.
Pan is nice scrolling
movement in a given direction.
Swipe is good when you want
such as your inventory menu,
Long press is a recommended way
And here you can provide
or even show Game Center stats.
Now that we've showed
of the four gesture types, let's
for you to adopt these.
So for tap, we give you
For pan, WKPan Gesture
And similarly for swipe
Now these gestures are available
When you go into the
for Gesture you'll find
If you select one, you
And in our example we've
These gestures are various
such making it a right swipe,
These other options
Now if you're using multiple
at this last option
to specify the priority.
And this is because
And what do I mean
Well, a right swipe
as a tap followed by a pan.
So you, as the developer,
which of these takes priority.
And in a game a tap and a pan
with your game world.
And we'd rather have that
that would take you
So going back to Interface
Fail First field for
And you set tap and pan.
And this reflects our priority.
Now that we've added gestures
to implement an action method.
This action method takes
and there are various properties
location In Object and Bounds.
And this last one, state.
And I think state is best
So from that puzzle app I demoed
And the first thing we do is we
And then we look at the state
we're going to set
If we're in the middle of a
or cancelled, we will update it.
So I'd like to finish
with some considerations.
Since the user is
of these gestures
so it's a good idea
It's also important to
to our other devices,
your finger is relatively
So please take this into
that content remains visible
And finally, you know, our
it recommends that we make
so you should follow them.
Now many of you are probably
but now let's talk about
to Apple Watch and that
The interface guidelines
for selection and scrolling.
But as a gamer, this harkens
with a physical dial
to rotate a spaceship
Or in this example we can
until we decide where
And when we're ready we can
Adopting the crown
You access this Crown
on your main interface class
and there are properties
such as rotation per second
Or you can define a delegate.
And this delegate
crownDidRotate which
This rotational Delta represents
since the last time
And it is positive if it's
and negative if it's
And this is true
on the left wrist
When the crown stops rotating
So to recap, we think Digital
It's also really easy to adopt.
And I can't wait to see
with this new kind of control.
Now the accelerometer
to enhance other
adding tilt on a
or to add spin to a pool shot.
You access the accelerometer
And there are some
As you probably know,
up here the screen is visible.
But when you lower your arm
When this happens it's going to
So as you move your wrist
so you should account for
And a recommendation here is
You can call the method
in NSProcessInfo performExpiring
to give your game loop
and give your user
Now let's show an example
The first thing we need to do
singleton so we set it as a
Then in willActivate in
if the accelerometer is visible.
If it is, we configure things
And then we ask the
to start sending
We provide a block that receives
to our game to give
When we are done we should
to stop sending us updates so
Now to recap, we feel the
to enhance other interactions.
Be aware that the
so consider using
And also make sure that
and you stop listening
Now let's consider haptics.
On iOS you could only
On Apple Watch you can create
through the use of
Each haptic consists of
by a brief audio tone.
By using the sense
in addition to visual
you can create a
interesting game experience.
We offer nine types
I'd like to go through
of how they might be
This is the notification haptic.
These magenta triangles
when the haptic is vibrating.
The waveform represents the
with it.
Let's hear how this sounds.
[ Audio Tone ]
As this example shows, the
for alerting people when
that requires their attention.
Now you get this for free if
But when you're in a game
and you're exploring the world
player, "Your village
The direction haptics, up and
when an important
or decreased significantly.
So in this example,
[ Audio Tone ]
Your health is low.
Or when you drink
[ Audio Tone ]
You feel better.
There's also a tone for
such as beginning a race.
Or when you wish to pause.
[ Audio Tone ]
The success haptic provides
And this is good for
[ Audio Tone ]
You won. Or if you didn't
And as a final example, there's
This haptic is a bit special.
As you can see, it's
and shorter than the others.
In fact, I'm not sure if you'll
but let's give it a shot.
This haptic provides the
at defined increments
In a game this might be nice
or giving the user feedback
that they have bumped
Now that I've given some
out that it's really easy to
You call play and you pass
that you desire and the
And let me finish
with some considerations.
The Taptic Engine differs
in that you can only play
Also note that these
to draw attention
And their effectiveness
to make the watch
So please exercise restraint
and I think you'll have a
So to recap, we discussed
and some ideas for
We showed how you can
for compelling game play.
We described how to incorporate
And finally, we discussed
to make your game
And now I'd like to hand
about our graphics frameworks.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Christy.
Hi, everyone.
My name is Fatima and in this
about our graphics frameworks,
that you can use to make really
So what are SpriteKit
SpriteKit and SceneKit are
for games and graphics.
You can use either
or you can even combine
They are easy to
with great integrated
They are available
and this year they are
On Apple Watch SpriteKit and
for the first time
real-time rendering.
And this will enable you to
and also make your games
So now let's look at
that you can use on Apple Watch.
And we're going to
You can create 2D animations
And you can create 3D animations
to make your games interactive.
You can use actions to move,
by either applying a single
of actions to make more
Next we have particles.
You can create particle
and SceneKit to add interesting
Using particle simulations you
and many, many other
Next we have physics.
Both SpriteKit and SceneKit
to make your game
You can turn on physics
and then define properties
velocity, and friction.
These properties will then
how they respond to
to forces in your simulation.
Next we have lighting.
You can also add light
And lights is just
So now you can apply actions
And one cool feature here
that you can automatically
using SKTextures.
Next we have camera.
Both SpriteKit and SceneKit
And if you decide
then we will render the scene
So the camera is really the
And the camera is also just like
So now you can move it around
Next we have shapes and text.
Text can be added as
So now it is really
and also apply actions
We also have shape nodes so
and geometric shapes
And we also have
in both SpriteKit and SceneKit.
You can create shaders
and you can create shader
to achieve most custom
So now that we have seen
that you can use, let's
and SceneKit are
And I'm going to
So in SpriteKit we
that we use to present
And our scene can
For example, we have
We have SKLight Node
And we have SKEmitter Node
On watchOS a few
First, we don't have an
to use WKInterface SKScene
We also don't have CIFilters but
with using an SKShader.
We don't have positional audio
like any other platform
And finally, we don't
but we can use WKInterface
And this table summarizes the
For SceneKit we almost
Instead of SCNView now we have
We don't have positional audio
And we don't have
but we can use Shader Modifiers
So now let's walk
of creating a game
for an already existing
And here I am using the
On the left we can
and we can take a look
And we can see here that we are
We can also take a look at
And we can see here that
to present our scene.
Now to create a game target on
to click File, New Target.
Choose the Game App
Give it a name and
Now this template created two
which contains our storyboard
which contains our Interface
So now let's take a
And this is our storyboard
that we have our interface
And our interface
from our object library.
And here we can see
between choosing
to display SceneKit content
to display SpriteKit content.
Also our interface object
in our Interface
to present our scenes.
So let's take a look at that.
And this is that
And now let's take a
And here we see that we
and in awake(withContext
that we are loading
like the way we do within iOS.
And finally we are using
to present our scene
within an SKView in iOS.
And these are all the steps that
on Apple Watch for an
And now I'm going to
to go over social gaming.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Christy Warren:
Now let's talk about
Today games are a lot about
and competition with friends.
Game Center makes it easy to
or even play a game together.
For multiplayer on
on turn-based gaming.
Turn-based gaming is something
that we think is a really
It supports brief
for both players to be present.
I can take a turn and when
You'll get a rich notification
and you may take the
There are various details on how
that we've talked
But today we'll highlight
For other details please
or view past sessions.
I'd also like to call out
for Game Center in iOS 10 that
And if you didn't catch that,
I'd encourage you to
To get started on making
talk authentication.
It is simpler than iOS
to enter a password
When you sign in on the phone
in on Apple Watch.
Also if you're familiar
you may be aware of a View
and you have to present
On iOS -- I mean on Watch
Now let's show this in code.
For those of you not
there is the GKLocal Player
of the focus of our API's.
In this case we sent an
and this gets called
when authentication
or with an error.
If you succeed, you can
if they have signed in and
Now that we've authenticated you
An important decision
up with other players.
Now the easiest way here is
to let Game Center pick
and this is called Automatch.
Alternatively, you can load
and invite one programmatically.
So let's start with Automatch.
Here you create a
You pass it to the method find,
the class method find
And when this returns it gives
instance that you can use
to store your data
Now please be aware that
if Norman created a
I may be joining his
So your game needs to take
So let's show this in code.
You create your Match
such as the maximum number of
When that succeeds you
It's really that easy.
And programmatic invites
You just set another parameter
and that is from a list of
However, to do this you need
who you can play with.
So I'll show you some
This shows you how to access
And a good place to -- and
There's a player picker
that will let you
So in awake we can call
on the Local Player
And this assumes that you've
in your main interface.
And we call loadRecentPlayers
of players that you, you know,
on phone, or pad, or on
Now it's important to mention
and saved it away you need to
So in order to help you
and give you a head start on
we've created a sample
that implements the basics
It's also built on the
And as a bonus it
to use gesture recognizers.
So I'd like to walk
briefly walk through
When you launch the app it
and it says, "Authenticating."
When the authenticate completes
on the top and gives you a place
to pick your opponent
This counter in the middle
that you've made
and saves them into
This is just a simple thing
that will save an error
Now if you've tapped Pick
it'll bring up a player
of recent players and
It also gives you the
but in this case I
So now he's playing with me.
If I want to access the list
and I'll get the Match Browser.
Here I can create a
or I can pick an existing game.
So I'm going to go
And finally, I can end
and that will pass it to Alan
So that's HelloGameKit.
You can download it under
under Session 612.
Click on the Resources
So to recap, Game Center
in watchOS gives you
It is a programmatic API but
that has UI for all the
So we hope that will
So with that I'd like to
about tools and best practices.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Christy.
So now you've been
of the frameworks you have
Let's talk about tools.
Many of you may be
of game tools already
And I'm happy to
of these tools are
for your Apple Watch
This includes our scene
of setting up and laying
and moves it into a visual
So instead of repeatedly
on a positioning of your
and manipulate exactly where
And on top of that you're able
to easily manipulate
of your scene using the scene
and modify your physics
all without touching
Now our scene editors
in action editor.
This lets you easily
and preview complex reusable
of your level.
So whether you're creating
to introduce your level
that you'll be reusing
it's all easily possible
Now as you're developing
to find the powerful particle
and SceneKit are going
in bringing your game to life.
But creating that
for your game can be difficult
if you're not able
And fortunately we provide you
and visualizing your particles.
So you're allowed access to
that we have on our particles
so that you can see
as they are changing them.
And we also have tools to help
in Apple Watch.
This includes our
When you place your images
within a Sprite atlas
and reposition them to
This reduces the number of draw
And what's great about this is
that nothing changes
You're still able to
as if they're individual files.
And when your game is running
Performance Gauge.
And at the top of the report
of real-time statistics.
This includes your
as well as your GP
of your GP are being
And your frame time for
And this will help indicate
or GPU bound.
Now in addition to
we also provide you
of our CPU and GPU frame times.
And what's great about
down your CPU frame times
so you're able to see
rendering, or running
or evaluating actions
as well as how much
And when your app is paused you
of your app's performance so
as you progress through
And if there's a particular
and examine details on it
So now there's some best
to make sure that you're going
to get great performance
A great way to reduce your
to avoid updating your
Both SpriteKit and SceneKit will
if we detect nothing has
And if you're working with large
at the start of your scenes
but you don't experience
to loading those
of your game you
And you should also aim for
to provide a consistent
And you can do this
by explicitly setting your
per second.
Now if you do find that you're
there's a number of measures
And the first being to reduce
within your scene
You'd also try reducing
that may be far in the
And what' great about this is
in your game's visual fidelity
And if you're still
try reducing the complexity
that right balance between
Now as you're developing
on Apple Watch there's a number
of design considerations
in mind throughout
Apple Watch, you shouldn't
experience and scaling it down.
We want you to be
And the Apple Watch
to lightweight interactions.
Users love to be able
of their game at a glance.
And you should be
around someone who is on the go.
In addition, you're going to
and simple, and should avoid
or being too busy on
You may even want to
across multiple screens so
screen space.
And if you have any
make sure they're large enough
so that your users can
And you should also aim
to maintain visual
What that means is
into yours should feel like
And part of that can be
that supports your game's brand
Now we also recommend that
background for your game.
And what's great about this is
that the black will
with Apple Watch's bezel and
of having an edgeless screen.
So now you've been
of the awesome input you have
and the great frameworks
to develop your game, and a rich
for your development workflow.
We can't wait to see
and fun games you're going to be
If you'd like more information,
and you can find us
And there's been a lot
from sessions previously
This includes What's
What's New in Game Center,
and Quick Interaction
So if you want to dive
that we touched on today,
we highly recommend you
And thank you and I
of your conference.
[ Applause ]