[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Welcome. My name is Eric Tamura.
I'm accompanied by Dominic
to tell you a little bit
[ Applause ]
All right so this is going to
for our presentation today.
I'll tell you a little bit about
Why we decided to build this.
Some of the new features
as part of Apple File System.
We'll do a short demo,
And then we'll wrap it
that you can use in your apps.
Okay, let's start it.
So as Sebastian mentioned,
in the WWDC build
that you all got yesterday.
And it will be available as a
in macOS Sierra once it
So what is Apple File System?
It's our next generation
that we've been building
And you might care about
on watchOS, iOS, tvOS and macOS.
So as far as the
we expect that some of you may
or you're a long time developer,
of the high level of the new
so you can follow along.
So, one of the hallmarks of
to scale from an Apple Watch
We also wanted to take advantage
because nearly all of
And finally it's been built with
from the very beginning as we
So you might be wondering
Well, we are currently shipping
But its original design
at this point.
So how many of you would like us
to ship HFS+ for
Great. So HFS+ which
where floppies and hard
and the world has
We now use SSDs and other next
evolving as well.
The data structures in HFS+ were
so our B-trees are relying
to access or mutate them.
And the data structures
And by this we mean things
or catalog record in HFS+,
to an inode in other filed
to add new fields, to
give it new features, we
of a backwards, incompatible
And by this we mean what happens
and take it all the way back
that same file system?
What will happen?
So if we're concerned about
as forwards compatibility
about well maybe it makes sense
to build something
And so we thought
So we wanted something
and tuned specifically
And other file systems
and they do it well.
In particular filers
or enterprise level storage
that might not make
We typically use a
of our products.
And we have a wide
So on an Apple Watch, you have
than does a Mac Pro, which
of DRAM potentially, and
So we wanted something
and that's the platform
So other things we wanted to
and enhanced security
So on iOS today we already
that uses per file encryption.
So every file is
on storage form every other
We want to take that a step
of those features a little bit
And finally, we just wanted
to add some new general
that have been requested
and that we learned
for the future of our platforms.
So before we get into these
to give you a brief
of what storage software
And so in terms of file systems
but it's actually not just HFS+
there's actually many
that comprise our
So in the beginning, we
you know over 30 years
We then added HFS+, some
But we added crash
So we gave it a journal of
We also added core storage which
as well as our fusion drive,
of an SSD with the
And let's not forget all of
We have an iOS specific
that supports the
that we just discussed.
So our intention is that all
of these technologies will
which is Apple File System.
So, let me tell you a
of the new features
So, this is a brief view of
so we've got some improved
HFS compatibility, Space
and directories, snapshots,
A feature we're calling
Atomic safe save
So you don't have to
we will go into greater
in the upcoming slides.
So, first let's talk about some
So first it's been
So on all of our devices, you
but a lot of our Macs we ship
as friendly to the solid
It's also crash protected, APFS,
or Apple File System
and write metadata scheme so
into a new location
We combine this with a
which ensures that if you lose
or anything bad happens, you'll
of what was on disk or you
We have modern 64-bit
so the inode number has
We have timestamps
We support nanosecond
We also support Sparks
on an Apple File System.
And all of our file and
at where the blocks
on disks have been
Our data structures
and allowed for future growth.
So one thing that we
that its data structures
And at APFS, or Apple File
that represent the core
So fields are either optional,
or we may not have
So new fields that we may
will be correctly
or I don't understand if
to today's version
In this way we can add
of harming backwards
This also allow us to
So on some systems,
of a file is enough to
And so if you have a 0-byte file
the machinery that points at
because they're needed.
So those fields are optional.
It's also been optimized for
So we wanted to add features
that are extremely compelling
for our platforms
And we also have a
And typically in file systems
between latency and throughput.
And we've chosen to lean
And we do this because we want
on them on the desktop,
on your phone you want it to
and have very crisp animation.
And the reason for that is when
we want to ensure that we
as quickly as possible.
And finally we have native
into the file system.
On HFS+ as we mentioned, it
but those are stored on disk
On Apple File System that's not
class citizens, first class
So that's a bit about
So HFS compatibility, if all
on HFS+ just fine, we intend
without any changes
So Apple File System
and replace HFS+ functionality.
And there's an asterisks there
that we will not
One of them is exchange
and the third is directory
But every other API and
as it is on HFS+.
So now I want to tell you a
which is one of the
into Apple File System.
So let's take a quick
in the audience have a
with more than one partition?
Okay, great.
We do as well, one of the
is we want a development
and we want you know the stable
Or you might choose to have
and other different data that
But one of the things that we've
that come back when users
and reporting their
that most end users
They just have the
And the reason they don't
You have to know exactly
out your disk at the
and changing it is
Moreover, free space
as you know does not translate
into available free space
So we're solving this
with a feature we're
So let's take an example
as we kind of explain
Let's say you're
and greatest cat video you
from your friend
And let's say that file
in fact so big that you've
on the partition on
Well there's not a whole
If you're out of space,
One thing you could do though is
immediately afterwards
So let's look at that.
We can destroy partition
and now you have enough space to
But this is also inflexible
of a problem if the file that
on partition 1, but it was
So in this case, you're going
to grow the file,
And then even if
or content that you're willing
we could destroy it, but then
because it's not adjacent
that we just made available.
So we think this is something
that we can solve
So in Apple File
up with this base concept
applicably named because
or individual file systems.
So, in this instance, Apple File
lowest level of functionality.
And this is what encapsulates
as well as our crash
So let's say we have volume
of free space in the partition,
volume can grow,
But in all these cases the free
to what's currently available
You can also create more than
which will occupy
And then if you wanted to
at this point you could do so.
And now if you ask for how
on the system you will
in the green rectangle
So developers take note, this
subtly different from how you
in the past.
If you're using some paradigm
like taking a total storage
to get the free space,
because other volumes
on the container are also
Additionally, you can't
of the used space either.
So, next, I'm going to invite
about cloning files
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. Again my name is
through a couple of the
that we have in APFS.
First, we're going
of files and directories.
So here we have a file, TOP
in his home directory.
And it has references
Now if Eric wanted to make an
as it existed at this point in
by reading it all in,
That has obvious
power, and disk space usage.
Instead with APFS you
By cloning the file,
to the data instead
So it's obviously much faster
you're not using twice
you're using exactly
of space plus a small
for the additional
What a clone guarantees
that if a modification is
or the clone, the
that data to a new location.
So the clone remains untouched.
So this is an important
When you have clones, you
you're not using any
As you continue to make
to use more and more space.
In addition, because APFS, or
in application bundles,
to clone an entire
So a document bundle is a
of files inside of it.
APFS can clone that
Next let's talk about snapshots.
Here, we have another
of a file system
BikeRacing and CoffeeOrigins.
BikeRacing has two
And CoffeeOrigins has one.
If we take snapshot of the file
independently mountable, read
that represents this data the
that the snapshot was taken.
Much like with clones,
into the live file system, the
in a new location preserving
Likewise, if we were to delete
up some space, the file system
because as you can see
to refer to those blocks.
This is an important
that developers need to be aware
because when a file is deleted,
of a snapshot, the
So snapshots can cause you
if you don't harvest
We expect that developers
for the purposes of having a
to perform a backup, but we're
from developers on other uses
that they might have
So please come see us
Let us know what you would
Now let's talk about
And this is another
So we have the same state of the
that well, we don't like
essentially a global undo.
We want to go back to the point
at the time the snapshot
So you can flag a
to the state of a snapshot.
And the next time it's mounted,
essentially to the point it was
And then allow you to
from that point forward.
So, again, you can see that
and the change that was made
to the other file
The snapshot continues to
as many times as you would like.
All right.
Now let's talk about
This is an answer
to the question how much space
Now applications frequently
for sizing an operation to
And the obvious way
to open the directory hierarchy
recursively and look at the size
of all the items
Of course users would
that answer a little
On this next slide, if you focus
of the screen, when the
you'll see it says,
And after a couple of seconds
That's what we're
So, the file system
Obviously you could store the
with the directory itself,
how do you safely
and its parents on up the chain.
So we're just delving a little
but when you have a lock on a
you can't also lock your parent,
because that's a
File system always lock
never from the child
And so if you start doing it
So APFS instead sidesteps
If the problem is storing
well let's store the
So by storing the
we can use atomic
in a separate record that's
And we don't have any
This comes at a small
for the additional size records,
in the noise with the IO.
All right.
Next, we're going to talk about
The first example is
This is how safe-save works
So here I have
And I come up with some
for making money fast.
And when the application
to a temporary location
When the application is happy
and is safe out on disk,
to perform a rename.
Now renames of files
The file system guarantees that
and it's safe, or it
In addition, the file system
previous version
So that's great for regular
if you have a document bundle?
So here we have a document
which is a directory
of the document inside of it.
And what happens today is
and they play a really great
that change is written out,
but now what commences
to do an atomic rename
of another directory, because
that if the destination
So, we begin playing
First, the document is moved out
So at this point, if
and the application crashed,
or the system lost
Then, the application moves the
to handle deleting
of the directory,
So this is not atomic
And this is something
for a very long time and
With APFS we introduced a
for non POSIX, which
of the directory.
So now, when the
to its temporary location,
and asks to perform the
with atomically handle the swap
and deleting the previous
So this is now atomic and safe.
Of course as a developer, you
to this low-level of system call
because it's already been
So you just get the benefit of
[ Applause ]
Next, I'm going to
So as Eric mentioned, with HFS+,
on the Mac we use a
that sits beneath HFS,
and provides full disk
It's a rather sophisticated
and it does a lot of things.
On iOS, we have a
that stores encryption keys and
And those encryption
with the accelerated AES
to provide per file encryption.
It's a kind of complicated story
with two rather different
And with APFS, we
and provide a more
across all of our products.
So APFS supports multiple levels
But first, the easiest level
is no encryption.
All data is written in
and metadata is written
The next level is to
So all sensitive metadata
and data are encrypted
This is essentially
of full disk encryption.
The most sophisticated level
that we support is
Here, sensitive Metadata
with a single key that's
that are used in
In addition, because of how
APFS supports per
So each region of a file can
This is unique and
out there supports
In addition, this allows us
across all of our platforms.
All right and with that I'll
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Okay so now I'm going
of Apple File System on MacOS
So probably the easiest
to start experimenting
with Apple File System
So we're going to do that first.
So, you can see on the command
create-fs APFS which specifies
of type APFS, we give it
to do a sparse bundle.
So it's going to warn you here,
because this is an
and we want you to be aware
that you are using something
So, at this point it will
And you've created the disk
You can examine that on
You can see that in fact the
So that's probably the
to just get something
So next I want to show
more advanced features
I'll close that.
So here I have two thumb sticks.
These are just ordinary
You can get them at any
So I will plug in one.
One is formatted as HFS+
as Apple File System.
So we'll also do
so you can watch the free
So at this point I have some
And there's a good
of those directory hierarchies.
But first we're going to start
of iTunes in the HFS volume
and then we'll do the
So start the copy, as that goes.
You can see the progress
but APFS already finished.
Because it uses the
So finder has already adopted
So if you do a copy and finder
for you behind the scenes.
And HFS still hasn't
[ Applause ]
Okay, so I could do the same
which you can look in here,
they're all several
Pay attention to the free space
So if I do a copy, it's actually
and you notice the free space
at all.
So next, I'm going to
So this uses the tool
which will be available
that releases to everybody.
Oh, sorry this needs
Okay so now I've
I can examine it
And you can see that it
So I've created a map point,
So I will mount this
And you can see that
up on the desktop and this
of the file system as
that I just took it, so.
[ Applause ]
So now in the APFS volume,
I'm going to create
hello I am a temporary file.
Save that, close it.
You can see that
in that APFS volume this
But it's not there
Correspondingly, I
of these demo photos.
I'll move them to the
The free space actually
because now they're pinned by
So if I wanted to delete
to delete the snapshot.
Okay, so that's just
of Apple File System in action.
[ Applause ]
Okay, so let's talk about some
to support Apple File System.
So first, is one that
that you're familiar with.
If you're using the Foundation
or the FileManager these have
So is use copy item or replace
clone or the safe-save
for you automatically, you
so it just comes for free.
It automatically figures
out if the file system
or Apple File System and
when it is appropriate.
If, however you decide
or the FileManager doesn't
you can go a little bit lower
and we have a library
And this supports the
and this is what we
of years before we had cloning.
So copy files supports a new
It's equivalent to the 5 or
And we decided to
because if you're using
like this you may not
[inaudible] and extended
to be copied exactly
Whereas cloning will implicitly
Again, this library will also
if the backend file
And if not it will continue
These are the new
and renameatx np are
to support the safe-save
These are available in the
of macOS Sierra that you have
at the Man Page,
And these are the
So clone files and its
of files and directories.
So a word on compatibility,
to get access to an
to use hdiutil as I showed you.
It's currently available
for macOS Sierra so as a
not been fully wired up into
So the fastest way
like this hdiutil create-fs APFS
and you can get a disk
You can also use diskutil
delete a container, add a
Whatever lower-level
to the container itself.
And finally, we also
that we've been working
So this will be able to
as well as perform repairs.
So that's also continuing
So, some current limitations
of Apple File System file
This will be supported
We don't support booting from
Time machine backups with Apple
right now.
File vault and fusion drive
And currently the volume
right now.
So if you're not sure that your
please give it a try, create
up on a partition on your
and running your app
and let us know how it's doing.
Some other compatibility notes.
Apple File System cannot
So if you want to use
that you use SNB instead
as a preferred file sharing
OS X Yosemite or earlier
System volume.
So please do not take an Apple
back to OS X Yosemite
You will inevitably
that you don't want
So, [laughter].
macOS Sierra will have
of Apple File System.
And it will be a developer
Sierra ships this fall.
So now you might be wondering
How do all of you get access
to Apple File System
We'll talk about that.
So upgrading to Apple
So you want these
that we've shown you,
Well one way we could do
all users to back up their
make sure everything's
and then erase the
restore it put a new OS back on
A process which will
and hope that everything's
after you've restored it.
Well, we're not doing that.
Instead, Apple will provide
from HFS+ to Apple File System.
[ Applause ]
In doing this, the user data
and we will write, or Apple
brand new, into the
And we're doing this
This is a multi-second
to multi-minute operation
And over that time, if the
anything bad happens we want the
and sound as if nothing
So the Apple File System
as atomic as possible.
It's not completely
but as the operation is
we intend for it
as if nothing had ever happened.
So Apple File System will ship,
by default on all
[ Applause ]
So to summarize, Apple File
system for all Apple products
it's crash protected, it
we support cloning
Enhanced data security features
that we just discussed.
It's also been tuned and
for the Apple ecosystem
So you can get more information
at this URL behind me that will
as some sample code so that
and directories in action.
So some takeaways for all
Apple File System
2017 will be here
I want you to please test your
with the macOS build
Try running your apps
Please let us know
If you report any bugs, please
through traditional means
We all want you to love
So, some related sessions.
If you're interested in
of the security features on
we recommend that
at How iOS Security
in this room today at 4 o'clock.
And with that, that's Apple
to see how you're
[ Applause ]