[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So my name is Dana DuBois.
I'm an engineering
that writes the frameworks
that help power the App
And today we're going
of those particular
Many of you know,
around for a long, long time.
It was introduced in
Since then it's been used by
to power all sorts
Everything from newspapers
even dating apps
It's really widely used.
And we've talked about
but this year we're going
and we're going to talk
So that's really exciting.
We've got some new APIs.
There's a couple other things
so that's really great.
Last week, many of you probably
of big announcements
This is something we're
I think a lot of developers are
of these new enhancements
So I'm going to give you
First up, categories.
We're really you know
that category will no longer
to use auto renewing
in your applications.
There are still going
to be criteria behind how
subscriptions, but category
Second, everyone's got
we're giving more
If you keep your
than one year, that's
And I think that's
[ Applause ]
Pricing. A lot of control
to developers through iTunes
for their subscriptions
to territory, region to region.
If there's a business reason you
in Europe compared to the
that you now have over that.
And then along with pricing,
to save the price, to
who may have already been
adjusting it for new users.
So, if you have early adopters
and you want to keep them using
to adjust the price for newer
And then upgrades
this is us giving the
to control exactly what level
of subscription they might
So if they want to go up
or go back down to the basic
in the Manage Subscription
So that's a quick overview of
There's a lot more to it.
I think if you're going
in your application,
to Introducing Expanded
that's at Pacific
Really, they're going to get
to set this up, how to manage
and I really highly
So that's subscriptions.
There's one other new thing that
and that's iMessage apps.
We announced that
We're bringing apps, a whole
into the iMessage app, iMessage.
You'll be able to build custom
to allow in-app purchases
right in iMessage aps using the
would use in a normal
that you have in
So if you have additional
or provide right inside
that's now supported.
And this will all be
so that's something we're
and I think developers are going
to take a lot of
So as I said before, StoreKit's
People have been using in-app
but maybe some of
So I'd like to just
of what exactly in-app
In-app purchases are
that can be bought right
However, to be clear, it's
There's other ways
This is really just about
Now when we're talking about
there's a bunch of
When you're configuring this in
of options and you
that you choose the right
So let's take a look
Consumable products.
Everybody's played a game and
currency, or gas in your
that they user's going
and buy again, and
That's what a consumable
A non-consumable product is
it will stick around for as long
They'll be able to restore it.
They'll be able to move
So that's a little different.
And again in a game
or you know some sort of weapon,
or a level, or if you
you might have a basic edition
to offer a pro-edition
That's kind of a
We also have two
when we're talking
There's non-renewing
as the name suggests
that don't automatically
and your application, and
to renew those subscriptions.
But then we also have auto
And these are subscriptions that
on a periodic basis, based
So if it's a monthly
we'll bill the user every month,
into that subscription.
So these are the types,
of adding in-app purchases
So, what I'm going to do is I'm
of all the various steps,
into each one and
about how to do this in Swift.
And you know exactly what you
as pitfalls, or any concerns
There's a lot of things that
when you're developing
A couple of things
So first off you're
out exactly what it is
to the consumer, the
So this is done just by
those in-app identifiers
to the user right
Once you have the identifiers,
and you fetch the information,
localized product
to those identifiers.
And that's key.
This is localized information.
This is a global marketplace,
that you're displaying
to your users in
And now once you have that
to show off the products.
You're going to market them.
You're going to sell them.
These are your products, this is
to build the best UI you
The users then are going to be
They're going to be you
to select the product
But it's up to you to
for that product and add
And we'll be talking a lot more
about the Payment
As the payment is going through
be notified about that
to have to make some
and that's how you
Finally, when the payment is
that product available.
Give the user what
And then finally tell the
with the transaction,
the product's available,
so that's finishing
So those are all the different
Real quick.
We're going to dive into each
but first special note
The Payment Queue is the center
of your in-app purchase
It's the source of truth
and payments as they're
from when the user selected that
And it's important to keep
on the queue and only the queue
that are progress,
and if you're using
the Payment Queue will tell
And then another thing
that if the Payment Queue
it's a valid and real payment.
In fact, there are
where developers might
where they've noticed that a
and they're managing
And then their app will crash,
or something will
the user will close the
payment, and they'll come back
that they were purchasing
And they don't necessarily
from the Payment Queue
to those payment transactions
because their own queue no
So you should really just
to tell what's going
as they're happening.
And in fact it's very
into some code here, to listen
and observe the Payment Queue
This can be done in the
we have
the first thing that
when it starts up and we create
in this case it's the
And we set it right
we add it to the Payment Queue.
And then if there's
that may have been there
we'll get notified
Another kind of case that comes
that have in-app purchases
So the user might have
and redeemed that in-app
of your app.
The user then is exciting about
they launch your application,
to the Payment Queue that
You got to do it right
So that's a quick note
Let's get back into the process
to add this to your application.
So the first thing you want
for your in-app purchases.
These are the same identifiers
that you set up in
You define them, you name them.
And you just need to
There's a couple
if your app is very simple,
you might just bake
into your application.
If you have an application
and a pro version, you might
and you just baked it right
However, we've seen more and
where they're interested
and fetching those in-app
that they provide so that
over time maybe they can
to the users, or exactly
That's okay to do.
Completely valid to do.
The thing we want to call
that make sure your host
This is the beginning of
The worst thing to show a user
while they're waiting
This should be, and if you can
If you can cache on the
Be very cognizant of
and preserving these
Now that you have the
to the App Store to fetch the
associated with those products.
This can be done with
You pass in the identifiers
Again, for the smoothest
you want to do this in advance.
You want to anticipate when
in looking at your
and have that information
So first thing you do, create
You pass in the identifiers
You set your delegate.
This will give information
about when those
And then you just call start.
That simple.
The delegate looks like this.
We have product request,
This will pass in
that you requested
And each of those products
like a localized
As I said before this is
you're marketing your in-app
So it's important to make sure
that you're actually using
to make your sales.
So localized title
even more important is
You want to present the user the
and you want to make
in a format that
Currency is represented
and you know it's important
We'll get into that in a moment.
And then finally if you're
content, this is something that
we actually give information
about the download
and versions associated
So as I mentioned the
that you do the right thing when
When you're presenting those
that price locale and pass that
and that will get
about that pricing information.
That NS number formatter, will
take the locale associated
If you set it to a currency
that you're getting that
The other thing you want to do
of currency conversion
The App Store knows
convert those currencies.
So you don't need to
Just present the price using
The next step after that
Not really going to talk
these are your products,
You know how to present
to make the best
However, once the
or once the UI has been shown,
into making the purchase itself.
And that can be done by adding
and creating an SK
and adding it to
Once you've created that SK
to the Payment Queue,
as the payment is
through updated transactions.
So this is that Payment Queue
when the application started.
You created your
It called Payment Queue
And you'll get information
through the process so all
SK payment.
Added it to the Payment Queue.
The information started
to get information about all
You might have one,
You should iterate through those
to the state for each
It's a couple different states,
the one you're probably
in is the purchase state.
This is where you know that
and should go ahead and
we'll get into that
and make that content available.
However, there's one other state
and that's the deferred
Deferred was added
for the Ask to Buy feature.
This was to allow
where children could
such as an in-app purchase,
their approver, will have
that purchase will go through.
The deferred state is the state
that you're in-app
on when it's currently pending
One thing we've seen
to make it very clear is you
in the deferred state.
You should handle that in a way
where maybe the purchase
just let the child who's
to use your app make that
and continue to use the game
or whatever it is
Because it might be hours,
it might be days before
and approves that purchase.
So no spinner, no
Just treat deferred state as
you know hasn't even
One thing I also want to get
to test your applications
just like testing your
And this can be done
Sandbox environment.
This is a special environment.
If you're running
and it's a developer signed
that you make will go to
However, if you're interested in
there's really no good
so that you can actually
So if you want to test your
it can be done using
This is where you create your
You pass in that product
and then you set the
This is a flag that's going
treat this as if a
and that child was
Once you add it to the
up to the App Store and the
with a deferred state
This is your way of knowing,
when kids are using it.
We also should talk a little
Not everything is
There's going to be error
Especially with in-app
One thing to keep in mind is not
I really encourage you to check
out the In-App Purchase
or the StoreKit Framework
to get a good sense of
that can be returned in
One thing to keep
of these errors aren't
to inform the user about.
Most of these are just errors
to handle in your application.
A great example of that
I'm using your application,
I'm doing a little bit
I click on purchase.
I'll get the price confirmation
And then I change my
and see what else is there.
And I hit cancel.
Cancel error, StoreKit will
to your application.
There's no need to
with a user did cancel alert.
And we'll see this in
The user knows that
There's no reason to
Let StoreKit handle
as much as possible.
Again, we got into
The Payment Queue is where
The App Store and StoreKit
for you will confirm the
They'll present a price.
That price should match
So that's why isn't important
to make sure you localize the
We'll authenticate the user.
If there's any issue with
we'll handle that.
No need for you to
or do anything special, let
So we talked a little bit about
and we talked about the states
that can be returned
Once your payment has made
you have a number
to make in your application.
Specifically, around validating
by a real monetary transaction.
So we'll get into a couple
But again, it's your
they're your products.
So it's really important to keep
in mind exactly what
and what level of
to validate your purchase.
So receipt validation, this is
to the application at
It's just like a bill that a
at a mall or something
It includes all this information
and the purchasing
And there's kind
that you can attack
First is on the device itself.
This receipt comes down, you
on the device to pull
make sure you know authenticate
make sure that it's from
And this can be done
for just unlocking features and
So again, this is one of the
Is this a purely client side,
right inside your
Or if you have a server
to actually have the
because you want that
for your content or service.
And this can be done by taking
to the device, uploading it
that server send the receipt
there's a backend API
And that can be done
One note with that though,
is yes the App Store does have
in that receipt and validate
that receipt to that API
That is not a secure
to how trustworthy that can
So if you're going to use
it should really be
right into the App Store itself.
So let's get a little bit
The receipt is a trusted record
It contains information
that this app was bought by
and those in-app were bought
Stored right on the device,
right into the application
It's issued by the App Store and
that allow you to verify
from the App Store itself.
And again, it's for your
If your app is running
on a different device it will
it will get a different
This is kind of, this
of what it looks like.
Again, stored in the app bundle.
We give you an API to get it.
We'll see what that
And it's a single file.
Old, old, old versions
to be multiple files for
but since iOS 7 we've
that contains all this
It also, again, contains
to allow you to verify
We do this through a Public
7 Container.
This is the container that
in it and this is
So there's a lot of information
on how to work with
The payload of that container,
the thing that contains
that you're going to be
in an ASN1 format, again
And there's a lot of
for verifying this, OpenSSL
Sometimes people
But again, something
that this is your
this is your business.
So you've got to make
to verify this receipt and
to use.
However, whatever you choose,
that you're going to go through.
First up, is you're going
in the application
And again, this is what
You can call right
and there's an App
that will be returned by that.
This is a local URL,
Once you have that URL,
and you get the binary
Now that you have
a couple things to keep in mind.
The certificates on there
but you've got to
about checking that
Just because it was issued at
that that expiration
for all time in the future.
So if you're checking
compare it against to when
from the App Store, not to
It's not like an SSL
to check it every time.
It's only valid for when it
to check the date for
Or it's perfectly valid not
But what you do want
up to the root certificate
That will verify that
That you can trust it
So check up to the root.
So again, this just kind
of what it looks like
The payload of it, that ASN1
about is a series of attributes.
You can think of it
It contains types and values.
And we're going to highlight
There's more in there than
And you can get a
through our Receipt
But some of the main ones you're
and type 3, that includes
and the bundle version that
Hopefully that matches
and you should check it.
So you should check
You should check
And then one thing to keep
in mind is you should use hard
binary of your app.
It's a lot easier for me to go
if that is what you're using to
for me to change the payload
of your application
So if you really want to make
for your application,
Now that you know that this
you want to make sure it is
for the device that's
and there.
And this is a little trickier.
What you want to do is take
that is returned in type 5.
Type 5 contains this hash.
The hash is made up of
that the App Store knows
And pieces of information that
That specifically
So again hard coded value
the bundle ID of your app.
The device identifier.
This is a, there
It's a little different on
to load up that device
And then this Opaque Value.
This Opaque Value is
of cryptographic entropy.
It's a secret salt that is
It allows the hash to change
and the device identifier
You should basically take
in the receipt and
Once you have that, SHA-1
and if they match, you know
And again it's unique to
The receipt also contains
of your in-app purchases.
So what we see here is a whole
Type 17 is for each and every
with your application it
for that in-app purchase.
The pay load for Type
it will actually be
and that will have its
So what do those look like?
Well 1701, that's the
So we talked about
the user could have
of coins inside your
That's going to be the quantity,
that was made against that
The product identifier, we
This is that identifier
to load your in-app purchase
and what you set them
The identifier, this is
This is a unique identifier for
to make that purchase.
The date of the purchase.
And then finally one
but one thing I want to
for auto-renewing subscriptions,
the subscription
So if you're switching your
that field's important to you.
You're going to use that to
that to know is this
Do we need to ask the user to,
that the user is still
So that field is very important.
And then one other note.
If you have an app that's
and it's a pay for app
in switching it over to
one thing you want to make sure
receipt, the app receipt
This includes the original
that that app was bought with.
So if I bought it as version
and in version 2.0 you
I want to take a look at
because I want to make sure I
that they are and not as
I think it's a really bad
over to subscriptions
that they purchased
So it's important
if you're switching
A couple other notes
The receipt is issued
But it actually is
But it's only renewable
for certain types
So when we're talking
and non-renewing subscriptions,
to be refreshed with
So consumable and nonrenewable
They appear right after
And they're not going to be
that receipt either on that
to a different device.
However, non-consumable and
always be in the user's receipt.
And you can get those back
and should get those
We can take a look at
It's a little different
On iOS, the receipt
you're going to want to use
But keep in mind that you're
We have to make a
We have to validate the user.
We've got to know
who have actually
So they're going to have to
or use their thumb print.
And if you're doing anything
like refreshing the receipt
which is really not a
or if you're doing anything
where you're checking
and then fetching it because you
something doesn't look
that you don't get stuck in
If your app crashes and you're
on launch.
Or if you keep checking
and there's something
about your validation code, you
that receipt over, and
So that's something
This could be done through
through an SKRecipt
You set your delegate
This will inform your
on the delegate when the receipt
and process the transactions
as if they were purchased
On macOS a little different
you're going to want
this will tell Finder, hey
Again, it's going to require
to have to be signed
And this can just be
And then I just want
with server-to-server
If you're doing an auto
an auto renewing subscription
of if you have content that's
you probably have a hosted
up your in-app purchases.
And so if you're doing
will allow you to validate on
that the user got for their
So again, you take that
and you upload it to the server.
However, I'm going to
don't send the receipt directly
It's not secure and you
One thing to note the verify
payload and that will
like if the receipt you had
you'll get the latest version
And it will include some
or if there was some other
So again, there are
about exactly how the verify
Okay so now we've gotten through
we've processed the transaction.
It's up to you to decide exactly
that receipt and what level
to put behind it and what
to use.
You validated that
That there was a monetary
It's up to you to make what
to them.
Make good on your
And so there's a couple
and we talked about it before.
You might just have
in your app that
A basic version of
A free basic version that now is
to set that state and make
Or if you have content that's
you need to download it.
Whole bunch of different
whole bunch of different
I want to highlight
One that's a little newer
that Apple provides is
This is a way of
and having the initial
and compact as possible.
Just the binary.
And if you're going to have
with that application, if
of different levels and
or videos associated with
into different components
On-demand resources is hosted in
to worry about hosting.
It's scalable and reliable.
We have caching all
Your users will be able
One thing to keep in mind is
executable code.
So all that code has to be
but it can contain any other
And it's also available
macOS doesn't currently
So that's a technology
to fetch additional content
If you're interested in
I highly suggest you check out
It's in Mission, this
Another technology that Apple
purchase content.
This is content that
with your in-app purchase, right
it's hosted on Apple servers.
So you don't have to worry
Scalable and reliable.
Around the world caching.
One thing to keep in mind
is that this will download
Your app doesn't
So the user makes a purchase,
launches another app, and you
that will keep running.
You get up to 2 gigabytes per
So that's not 2 gigabytes
for your whole application
And this is supported
So, again another great way
for your in-app purchases.
Let's take a look at what that
A payment came through,
and you're ready to
You're going to be in the
of your payment observer.
And you're going to go down
to look at your transactions and
of those transactions
And all you've got to do is
into the Payment Queue and that
If your application
in using hosted in-app
to have a Payment Queue updated
Payment Queue Observer.
And this will give you all this
as they come in, including
in and let you know
to use this to update UI.
Or time remaining.
Or if an error occurs and
that information will be there.
And then once the download is
again that's a local path URL,
so you can grab it and interact
with your content
So that's how hosted
But you may also want to
perfectly valid thing to do.
If you have a catalog
of if you have different things
to have Apple host,
to do self-hosting content.
One thing to keep in mind is
APIs that you should
It's the way to host
Content is downloaded even
If you're still using
that's deprecated.
And that's not going to be
for the user as NSURL Session.
So it's very important
This is how it looks in Swift.
You're going to create
This is a configuration you
to your application for what
You're going to create
You're going to pass that
to pass in a delegate, this
to get information back
And you're going
this operation queue is
to call into your delegate.
What thread or what
So you're going to want to make
operation queue for that.
And then to kick off the
and you hand in the
with you in-app purchase.
And you call resume.
That will kick off
in the background your
purchase download.
As the download is occurring
to get information,
into URL session didWriteData.
And that will give
you can take this
and it will give you the
You might have a progress bar,
to tell the user about how
But it's also important
that your application
downloading process.
And so when your
you want to actually reattach
to those background
And so in your application
to implement handle events
This will allow the
up your application and tell it
about hey this background
or is in progress, or
So handle events for
It will pass in the identifier
that you used earlier.
You just recreate
that configuration
Re-create a session
to that background session.
And then what you want to do
that's passed into that app
to need to call that completion
whatever you need to
So if the download's complete
into your container, and
you need to call that completion
everything with it
that you're done doing
So that's making
but you're not quite done yet.
Even though you've
and the user has
you've got to do one more thing
that hey you're done
This is important because
in our purchasing queue, we
and if your application
or if the user leaves and comes
to keep telling you about it.
It actually might
on your behalf background
to use up user's data.
So it's important to keep
up the transaction
But you should also
when the content is
If you finish the transaction
we're not going to tell you
about that transaction
So if the download fails,
you're not going to
So you want to make sure
and then call finish
So, again, the payment will stay
in the queue until
And if you're downloading hosted
in mind is yes you need
and if you finish the
download's complete we
And this can be done simply
Finish Transaction and passing
into the Payment Queue.
So, the user has
they've been buying
they love your content,
you know what I'm
I'm going to delete the app,
Or they switch to
It's always important that
non-consumable and auto-renewing
into the app.
They need to be able to
So restoring transactions
to restores non-consumable and
Consumable and non-renewing
that's up to you to
So it might be something
it might be something that you
in your own hosted backend.
That's up to you guys to
to restore those, but
and auto renewing, you can
restore APIs.
Again, we offer APIs for
Completed Transactions.
That will pull down a brand
and in-app purchase receipt.
Again, you're going to
You added that to
so of course you're
You're getting information
about those transactions
Because we're going to call
Transactions Finished.
That's going to tell you all
and you're just going
as if they were just
Or we're going to give you an
and maybe you need to ask
or update your UI accordingly.
So again, it's important
Again, once the restore is
at the receipt and
and features accordingly.
So now we're going to
of okay you're built your
to the App Store you
that you pass app review.
A couple things to keep in mind.
We've just been talking
You really need to have
It doesn't have to
you need to have some mechanism
to get their content back, or
Again, for non-consumable and
you're not going
of in-app purchases
One thing to keep in mind though
from purchases itself.
Restores are free.
The user shouldn't get confused
and they're getting a password
that it's going to
This has got to be very
that this restore operation
it's completely separate
So it's one thing you want to
Some other information
for auto renewable subscriptions
keeping the information
And making sure that once
that content right then and
to wait until the next period
If you subscribe you should get
And you should get
that you should only be able
not bundled products or content
to get free elsewhere.
So, these are some of
I highly recommend
out the App Review
I've heard there's even a
so I would highly recommend
because they're changing all the
up to date with what's
And with non-renewing
policies you want to keep
and making sure that he user
or opt out accordingly.
And then finally the
to pass app review is
if you have purchases inside
You make the purchase,
They should get that
that content right
If it's buggy or if
or if there's something going
on when the reviewer you
that app review environment,
with app review right
So test it.
Test it in Sandbox, make
as you want it to.
So just to summarize a little
Always observe the
I can't stress this enough.
If you're interacting with
one of the first things your app
observer to get information
about what's going
You need to fetch
from the App Store.
This is through an
That will return
So the information for the
to billing that's associated
And again use the
There's the SKProduct that comes
with that, you need to use
and currency information.
Use the receipt to
Again, they're your purchases,
You need to make
to validate the receipt,
or on the server.
What technologies that back it.
Be aware exactly what the
and make your decisions
And finally make the
You can just unlock it in your
or you can make a hosted request
or you can make a request to
Make that content available.
But do it in a reliable
If you're hosting it yourself,
make sure your servers
and you know cache appropriately
for users making
And then finally, always
The last thing you
that that transaction is no
or else your observer is going
about it when your
And that will incur weird you
have to authenticate
or there might be backend APIs
of your app, using
if you don't finish
So always do that.
And then, allow users to
You need to have a restore
if you have non-consumable or
This will allow the user
to get back what they've
More information will be online
I highly recommend you go back
and take a look at
And then a couple related
if you're using subscriptions
you should definitely check
out Introducing Expanded
in iTunes Connect later today.
Or if you're interested in
that out Thursday morning.
And that's it.
Thanks a lot.
[ Applause ]