[ Music ]
[ Applause And Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everybody.
Welcome back, if you came to
My name is Nick.
I'm here today with
And we are going to talk
Apple Pay on the web.
But first, I want to
How many of you, and put your
if you are watching
how many of you have tried to
up because the checkout
I'm seeing a lot of hands.
That's true isn't it?
It's a big problem.
Here's a site I went
completely legitimate.
Ignore the name, Honest
But his checkout was
And so I typed in my name, which
to protect the innocent,
And I typed in my
And I got this confusing error.
It said the card number needed
So I thought, "Well,
like the fact I had some spaces
was written on my card.
So I changed it.
And then I got this other error.
So apparently the
which wasn't even the month
This is very confusing.
Now hopefully the checkouts
as bad as this.
But Internet checkouts,
And we think we can solve that.
We think we can solve
And we are going to talk today
about how we can solve
on the web using
and the great benefits
We have got a lot to
to start off with
We are going to run through some
if you are not familiar with
Then we are going to talk
the new API that we've added
And then we'll move on
how you can actually get paid.
And finally we'll look at
how to make your sites
and have a great
So let's get started.
What is Apple Pay?
Hopefully most of you are
It's an easy, secure,
And you can pay both
within iOS applications.
Maybe you've tried that.
If you haven't, give it a go.
There are some great apps
that you can use while you
And Apple Pay within apps
eCommerce experiences.
They are apps that really shine.
And thousands of applications
across the world, in China,
And these apps are
They are seeing higher
Users who pay with Apple
to convert to paying customers.
And they are also seeing
These users aren't
they are spending more
And finally, users are happier.
Apple Pay has one of the highest
of any payment method ever.
It's so easy to use,
And that's great
But I think there is
A large amount of
of the app ecosystem.
Apps are great.
I love apps.
But many of us still pay
Most payment on the
It's laborious.
And it's unclear.
The checkout flow is different
for every single
It's different.
And so we are going
And we are going to solve
to more places and
And we call that
because there's three main
One of them is WatchKit.
You may have seen this
and Kevin talked about how
to WatchKit apps.
And we are also bringing it to
that you saw: SiriKit,
But perhaps the biggest
and the reason you are here
We are going to talk about
in the session right after this.
So if you like the sound of
But for now let's focus
on Apple Pay on the web.
I have already talked to you
about how eCommerce
Large amounts of retail
But these checkouts are
and they are hard to use.
And that's doubly
The screens are smaller, but
as complicated.
Users also want the same
from apps, the same ease of use,
the same security,
How many of you have
because you got an
that some site you shopped at
I know I have.
And so Apple Pay solves that.
And Apple Pay on
on any Apple Pay device today.
That's iPhone and iPad.
And it's available on Safari
It's the same Apple Pay
the exact UI, the
If you are familiar
you'll be right at home.
But there is something
and that's on the desktop.
Now in some countries
mobile eCommerce is the
But here in the U.S., the
for things on their desktop.
You have probably bought
And we think Apple Pay should
And so we are also bringing
Now you can pay directly
but with the same security
on your iPhone and
You can simply tap through
It's really easy to use, and
It's available on any
that can run Mac OS Sierra.
So that's pretty much every Mac
It's fully supported in Safari.
And you authorize the
or on your Apple Watch.
Now because Apple Pay
you might have missed the
So I am going to
Don't worry.
It's very quick.
Let me switch over here.
So I have got, on
and on the right
Now Craig booked a few
"Finding Dory" on Thursday.
I am going to crash
I am going to crash that.
We are going to join him.
I am going to take 10 of my
Yeah, we'll go say hi to Craig.
OK. I clicked the buy
and that's what happened
Let's do that again.
I'm going to cancel it.
And you'll see when I
from the phone as well.
So I' m going to tap
It's immediate.
It came up straightaway.
And then I just Touch
And we're done.
We paid in seconds.
It was instant between
And I get a notification telling
That's how easy and quick
It's blindingly fast.
So hopefully I have sold you
Let's talk a bit about
Now before we dive into the
over a few basics of Apple Pay
because perhaps you
into your application.
Perhaps you are solely
So Apple Pay provides you
And you send this token to your
or Braintree, or
Now this token is unique
It can only be used one time,
and for the amount
But when you use Apple Pay
it's also unique to
It's encrypted.
So even if the token
if the connection the user is
on was an unsecured
the token is still
because it's encrypted
and a merchant identifier.
Now the merchant identifier
and certificate identify
They look like this, like
If you are an iOS developer,
you'll be familiar
And they're generated
And because they
and because only you can
only you can read your
Now let's see how
in an actual application today.
So in an iOS app, Apple
with Apple Pay button.
Now when the Buy with Apple
iOS authorizes the payment.
It displays the Apple Pay sheet.
And the user Touch IDs
And so payment data is generated
on the phone; that's the
that securely holds
Now what happens next
in an app is this data is sent
through a process
And that's when it's reencrypted
This happens behind the scenes.
And so when your
it just receives
rewrapped payment data
to your merchant or your
and then just dismiss the sheet
Now the flow is very
There's a couple of differences
around how we actually validate
when you have an app, it's
It's a signed binary.
Before we go into
through a few requirements
Apple Pay on the
to any website that
But you have to have an
and your site has to
Finally, your site has to comply
Now these are very
Most payment processors have
of goods you can
Now some eCommerce platforms
on your behalf.
We'll talk about the exact
partnering with in the next
But if you are partnered with
you won't actually need to
it can be taken care of for you.
So assuming your site
of these requirements, the
to register your site.
Registering your
You just create a merchant
at the developer portal.
And then you register
to this merchant identifier.
This is the fully qualified
store.apple.com, that you want
Now when you register
we'll go off and validate it.
And you'll also obtain
a TLS certificate that we issue.
And we call this the
So I just want to recap.
We have got three
from registering for Apple Pay.
We have got our merchant
and our merchant certificate.
They identify us as a merchant.
And then we have the Apple
which identifies our domain.
And when you register
it's very easy, very
It should be enabled right now.
It looks something like this.
And just add a domain.
We validate it by checking
that we ask you to
And you're done.
So let's look at how
Let's look at the Apple
Now just like Apple Pay within
when you press or tap the
Now there's a key
You create the payment
that tells us what
And then something
This is a piece of validation.
You create a merchant session.
And this is requested from
It's returned back to
on with your payment request.
That's the only difference.
That's the only difference
within an app and
this merchant validation piece.
Let's focus a little more
Let's talk about why we do it.
So I mentioned just a moment ago
that the web is a
In an iOS app, security of
or Location is protected
If you are not familiar
of information that
into your binary
And this protects both
in the case of Apple
Now obviously on the web
and we don't have
So instead we have this
It protects both your users, and
If your site is compromised, for
to stop Apple Pay
Merchant validation
and really straightforward.
It's not that tricky.
You take an Apple
and this URL is provided
You send this URL
which then requests
Now to request the merchant
TLS certificate that we
It's a challenge response.
And if that certificate
if it matches the domain
that you are requesting
we'll return a session.
Now this session is opaque.
You don't need to worry
It's basically a unique
with a single Apple Pay request.
And it's used to ensure that
You have to request this
but it's a very lightweight
it doesn't take very
And you request it
You don't request
I have got some tips for
The first one is to always
from the client, because
on the country the user is in.
Apple Pay has many
and we'll use the one
in the region they
Now for some of you,
up front the IP addresses
through your firewalls
And we'll provide a list
on developmentalapple.com
You should also only request a
with the Apple Pay button.
Don't request it on every
You only need to request it
We actually display the
requesting the session.
So from a user's perspective
They tap or click
They'll see the sheet, and we'll
until this validation
You'll see how that works in
about the JavaScript API.
Finally, don't generate a
That's because you have to
this certificate is
You don't want to embed that on
It's very important
And so you perform the
OK, let's recap.
We have got ourself set up.
We made sure that
with Apple's requirements.
And we created our
and our merchant certificate,
and we linked it
And then we learned
how to validate our site
So that covers this
What about this portion?
I said it was the same
But it's obviously
because sadly we can't
And so we are going to talk now
about the new JavaScript API
And to do that, I'd
from the WebKit Team
Anders.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Nick.
I am really excited
and show you how easy it is
to use the Apple
As Nick mentioned, the Apple
in iOS 10 in Safari,
that use SafariViewController.
And now, with Mac OS Sierra, you
in Safari, using your
to do the actual authorization.
It's a relatively simple API.
It's got a single entry
And it's influenced
for doing Apple Pay with an app.
So if you are familiar
you'll notice a lot
Now before we dive
about this friend of mine.
She owns a store that sells
for dogs.
And a couple of months
where you can buy these clothes.
You can order them
and have them shipped
But unfortunately business
She's getting a lot of traffic
of actual orders go through.
So let's take a look
if we can figure out why.
So this is our website.
And let's say I want to
Well first I have to
Then I have to check out.
Then I'm at the Checkout page,
and I have to enter
And then I have to go
and enter the credit card
And then I can place my order,
So let's see how we can
to make this process
For example, what if we could
and supplement it with
so that you can place orders
Now we only want to display
that the user can actually
So in order to do that,
we can use the function
This is a pretty
This is how it would
Note here that I am
of the window.ApplePaySession
So I am not checking
for a specific version
I am just checking for the
And if it exists, I call it --
it returns a boolean and
If it returns true, I call this
And that will show the button.
It's important to note, though,
that this function only tells
supported by the device.
So if you are on an
it'll tell you whether
And if you are on a Mac,
it'll tell you whether there
that can authorize the payment.
It does not tell you whether
So in order to check for that,
we can use the function
WithActiveCard.
You pass this function,
And it actually goes out to the
that the merchant
and that it's properly
where you are making
Because of this,
and returns a JavaScript
Now if you don't know what
you can just think of
of doing callback-based
There are also some
when you can use this function.
You can use it if
to Apple Pay during your
to add an Apple Pay button
Now in our case we want
to our main product page,
Otherwise we would have used
But here is how we
Again, I am checking
of the Apple Pay session object.
Then I call canMakePayments
I tap in my merchant identifier.
And then I use this
when the promise is resolved,
to a boolean that's
the function I specified
And if canMakePayments is true,
So now we've got our
for every single
And the next step is to
when the user clicks
So in order to do that,
we'll create a new
JavaScript object.
The ApplePaySession constructor
One is an API version number.
This is something
so that we can extend
in a backwards-compatible way
without breaking
The current API version number
The second parameter you pass
If you are familiar
this is the JavaScript
of a PKPaymentRequest.
So it then takes all the
to display the sheet, things
where the payment will be
and optional list of line items,
that might be required.
And then when you get back your
you simply call Begin and
This is what it looks
So first we declare our
We specify the currencyCode
And here I specified
and the supported
as the merchant capabilities.
And lastly, I specified that
for shipping purposes.
And then I simply create
I pass in the merchant
and the payment request.
And I call sessions up again
Now with any payment API,
that we get all the
And because of this, before we
series of validation steps.
And if any of these
and just throw a
And because of this, creating
JavaScript exception.
For example, if you call
a page that it's not served
over HTTPS using the best
In fact, every single Apple
exception if you try to call
Creating an Apple Pay session
if you pass in an
For example, if you
of supported networks, or
that is negative, for example,
or if you spell the
so that it's something
that will throw an exception.
In addition, calling Begin can
in -- try to call
of an onclick handler,
We do not allow displaying
explicitly asked for it
to be presented using
Or if there is already a sheet
we'll throw a JavaScript
because we only allow showing
And if you get one
you can use the Web
to get a more detailed look
But if everything is good and
we'll display the sheet.
But notice that you can't
yet; we have this
And that's because we haven't
yet handled the merchant
that Nick mentioned earlier.
So shortly after the
we will send a validateherchant
to the ApplePaySession object.
This DOM event has a
and this is the URL that
and have it load to create
And then when you get back
from your server, you simply
pass in the session,
Here is what a validatemerchant
So here I call this
that I have written.
It returns a promise,
to the merchant session.
So when the promise is resolved,
I simply call
I pass in the merchant session,
And that's how you do
So now, when merchant
the user can authorize
on their phone or
And when the payment
we'll send a paymentauthorized
to the Apple Pay session.
This DOM event contains
that has all the necessary
So it's got things like
information about the
to make the payment; and it's
itself that you send to
And when you have sent that and
and you get back a reply,
and that will dismiss
So here we have a
I call sendPaymentToken.
I pass in the token.
And this returns a promise
that is either true
on whether the payment was
So if it's true, I set my status
to ApplePaySession.STATUS
If it's false, for example, if
I set my status to
Then I call completePayment.
I pass in the status, which
And then I call this
which will show a nice little
And when you call
in Success, you get
and the sheet will be dismissed.
OK. So now let's take a
to do all of these things.
Here we go.
So first of all,
And now let's take a
But before we start adding
out a couple of things.
Here I have added
These are used in the Safari
but they are also used in the
which we will see later.
And here I have listed
and I have actually gone ahead
I am just keeping them
So let's take a look at that.
Here is my CSS, and
for the Apple Pay button.
So I set this visibility
And for the actual image itself,
I am using this
so we can grab the Apple Pay
so you don't have to
OK. So the first thing we want
to do now is add the code
if Apple Pay is enabled.
So I have already started
I have created an EventListener
This event is dispatched
when the main document
but before any remaining images
from other resources
So it's a good place to do that.
So let me add the
Again, I am checking
of the ApplePaySession object.
Then I call
And inside my promise function,
and if it's true I call
So I -- let me save
And we load.
And now we got our
So the next step is
when a user clicks on a button.
So I have written this
that is invoked whenever
So here is where we want to add
So again I have declared my
I have hard-coded the amounts
but in real life we would
And I then create my new
and I call Begin.
So let me save and reload
OK. So it looks like
So let me open the Error console
OK, so it says that
"supportednetwork" is not
And it looks like I
So let me just go back
And now we have the sheet.
But I can still not
because I haven't handled
So let's go ahead and do that.
So I want to add my
And I'll do it here after
but before we call Begin.
And again I call
And when the promise that this
I call
I pass in my merchant session.
And then I should be able
And the last thing we need
to do now is add our
And this will send the
and confirm the payment.
And if we are successful,
otherwise I set it to FAILURE.
And then I call completePayment
So now I want to
so we can actually see what this
So let me reload, and I hit Pay.
And now I can confirm.
And as you can see, I get
That's because I added
And now I can pay
And the scarf is on its way.
[ Applause ]
So that's how easy it is to
And I think that
Canine Clothing sales are really
Back to you, Nick.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; You know all this -- I
up with all those dog
in the doghouse.
Aw, come on.
Throw me a bone.
I'm wasted in software
All right.
So we have seen how to build
Let's talk about something
to you.
That's how you'll
how to get some money
So Anders covered these steps up
What happens next?
Well you have two options,
The first option is to decrypt
on your own servers.
That's a good option if you
or you have a very large
You're familiar with the
It is documented, though,
But another option
to just pass this
to your payment provider, and
on your behalf if you
This is a really easy option,
and many payment
to do this in-app.
We are highly confident
that these payment processors
JavaScript-based SDKs;
these integrate directly
In fact, in the U.S. and Europe
over 40 payment processors
too many for me to
But there's a full list
And as I said, many of these
for in-app; and they'll
for the web as well.
I also want to highlight
As you may know, Apple
And of course this feature
as in the U.S. and Europe.
And we have four payment
that support Apple Pay.
They are China UMS, LianLianPay,
So if you are looking to
in Asia, you have got great
Now one thing I mentioned at the
Many sites don't build
They use the platforms provided
And we are partnering
with multiple eCommerce
We are partnering with
They are Demandware,
And if you are using any
you will be able to use
to have a developer account.
These platforms can
They can handle all
with their deep Apple
Now you are probably
to go off and try this.
I hope you are.
I want to talk a
So testing your sites:
We are introducing a
for Apple Pay called
It's a new way to test.
And initially Apple Pay for
within this sandbox.
Now if you'd like
we don't quite have enough
But you can check the
we are going to be
Or if you go to our site
we have some information
to use the Apple Pay Sandbox.
But for the initial seeds,
to test Apple Pay on the web.
Then we'll roll it out into
as we near the release of
Now also, when testing
please give us some feedback,
We really want to hear about
and all the great
If you just have compliments,
I'd love to receive
OK. Let's talk about the final
How to build a compelling
And a lot of these tips are
At the start of this
about how Apple Pay has three
secure, and private way to pay.
And your designs
They shouldn't make
They shouldn't make it
There are three main
There's pre-payment,
that's before you have seen the
of using Apple Pay before
There's payment itself,
when the sheet's
You can customize that.
How should you customize it?
We'll find out.
There's also post-payments.
That's the experience after
So let's run through
and discuss how your
with Apple Pay for each phase.
Prepayment starts with
And the Apple Pay button is
and, as I've just shown you,
that you can use as well.
It's available in a
Here are a couple of them.
And Anders showed you the CSS,
but just to reiterate we have
that you can use.
You can get an Apple
that for your buttons
There are some do's and
when you are using
Do use the built-in assets.
Sometimes, you never know,
You want to make sure
Also, place wherever a user
Don't hide it away.
Don't make it difficult
with what is a very
There is also some don'ts.
Don't modify the button, or
It's very important
on an Apple Pay button,
We want that expectation
And also don't suppress
As part of the Apple Pay
to suppress the button.
It needs to be at the same level
Let's talk about where
Now Anders' demo showed you how
to place the Apple Pay button
And placing it on product pages
We've seen some great data from
to show they've seen
when they place the Apple Pay
Now obviously you
in regular checkout
Let's look at a few examples.
We gave the Apple Pay API to
to come up with some designs
and some experiences
Here's one from StubHub.
Now StubHub has decided to a Buy
with Apple Pay button during
You select the number
and then you just
You can also bring
You can do what I call
This is from Warby Parker.
This is after you have
You see we have two options.
We can add the product to our
or you can just buy it there
Finally, you can place
on your actual product pages.
Here's an example
The Apple Pay button right
Let me show you that
Here you can see there's
So if I want to create my
Or I can just buy
Now one thing that
on the product pages is
Required registration is a
I don't know about you, but I've
because the site I didn't
to create an account up front.
And so Apple Pay can help
by making guest checkout
Also, you can optionally
collect in the Apple Pay sheet
to create accounts
I'll show you an example of that
Let's move on now to actual
Now the Apple Pay sheet
for merchants.
It's highly customizable,
but it also offers a
You can decide what
but the user always
Here is an example of
I am using the Mac OS sheet.
But the same fields
if you're making a web payment
The first field is where
It's also optionally where you
although billing
to process an Apple Pay payment.
The next field is shipping.
This is where you request
You can request billing,
and contact information
and you can also specify
You can change the terminology.
If you don't like it saying --
to say "shipping," you can
It's good if you're
or maybe a takeaway service.
Now you can list
You can list them
which we'll talk
But when you're collecting
make sure you have a
When you use Apple Pay within
to the App Store
to provide a link
Now when you are
obviously there is
So instead we just ask that you
on your site that clearly
to do with this information.
Now you can also
that lets you select
And just like the shipping
Users can pick from
Now these methods can
to address changes perhaps
if you already offer express
you can easily reflect that.
Methods could also be free if
And just like shipping
the naming can be
Now although you
and phone number in
they are separate
So this field here,
is where you enter
than postal address.
Now we support collecting
We support collecting
And if you are not
we also allow you to
That's useful if maybe you
and you want to have
but you don't need
Now is the most important field,
This highlights the amount
sorry, that the user
And you can use this
to display a concise indication
Things like subtotals,
Now it's not a line-by-line
It's not intended to
So you should keep it concise.
Also, be upfront and clear
Make sure that the total amount
actually going to be
That being said,
where you don't necessarily know
Sometimes you don't
Maybe it's a hotel
or car hire, or a taxi service.
And you can use the
on our summary item
Now again, just make
Why do I keep saying
Well as you may have seen
with Apple Pay normally you'll
from your bank with the
So you want to make sure
on the sheet matches this,
in the case where you
final amount.
Summary items also support
Items can be marked as free.
And summary items can also be
The total amount needs
But anything before that,
if you want to indicate a
Now there's one other
and that's the field that tells
Which brings me to
around the site icon.
So this is a sheet on iPhone
You can't customize
We inform you of the card,
you need to do that on a Mac.
By the way, if you
on the Mac the price here
So if you change shipping
that costs more, we'll
But this site icon is
You can specify it
It uses the existing Apple Touch
for Apple Pay at 180
The easiest way to specify this
But you can also specify at
Whatever works best for you.
I'd also like to briefly
That's semantic markup.
So many of you may already
on your pages to indicate
that are available for
We actually index the
in Spotlight on iOS.
You can also indicate that
appropriate semantic markup.
We think this will benefit,
people who want to know where
if you'd like to
OK, let's move on
of payment, the confirmation.
Now in your confirmation
to reflect the appropriate
So for example, don't
if you returned a failure.
That would be silly.
You can also leverage
by Apple Pay to offer
I mentioned this earlier.
I want to show you an example
Here's an example.
After you have made
you get a confirmation page
and you actually get a create
pre-populated with
that came from Apple Pay.
So I can create an
I can enter into a
and it's easy to do so.
OK. We covered quite
What did we cover?
We covered Apply Pay merchant
We learned about the differences
We also covered the Apple
with Anders.
And we also talked
of Apple Pay in our designs.
Now we have a lot of information
You can check out our developer
We've also got the
Firstly, don't go anywhere.
Stay right here.
Don't you even leave.
I am going to be right back here
with Wallet &amp; Apple Pay.
We're going to talk
And we're going to talk about
and Apple Pay for
There's also a session
Optimizing Web Content
That is Friday at 4:00.
That's everything from us.
Thank you so much for coming.
I can't wait to see all the
with Apple Pay on the web.
Thank you, and have
[ Applause ]