[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everybody.
Hello again if you just came
from the previous session,
And hello if you're new.
Hello to everyone downstairs,
and hello to everyone
My name is Nick, I'm joined
and we're going to
with Wallet and Apple Pay.
First of all, we're going to
We're going to talk
for banks and for retailers.
And then we're going
now you can use Apple Pay
on Apple Watch, but also
We'll also talk about something
and that's the new extensions on
All of these new
that can be enabled
And finally we'll talk about
I think you're all going
and the new Sandbox environment.
Let's get started.
What's new with PassKit.
So, hopefully you'll be aware
that Wallet isn't just Apple
And there's no better
because more users are
than ever, due to Apple Pay.
More people are opening
more people are using it.
Now, we don't have time today to
but we do have some
I'll tell you a little bit
don't worry, not too much.
Passes enable you to get
rewards cards, event
and more directly into the
And you can distribute
through an app, through email,
SMS or iMessage,
And these passes can
And these updates show up
Things like date changes, for
Your passes can be relevant,
they'll show up on
We have a session that talks
of these passes and provides
It's the home for
it was last year's session.
And there's plenty
at developer.apple.com.
Let me talk now about
Some things we've
that maybe you didn't notice.
One of them was app placement.
We've actually changed the
this happened in iOS 9.3.
Apps are now placed
and these app icons
into your applications.
So these are great for
if you're a gift card pass
for the user to quickly
you want to go to the app
for more information
And it's very easy to add this,
to your pass, the apps ID,
and also its URL scheme to deep
Last year we also
the value-added services pass.
So passes can now transmit
Things like loyalty
if you're in the US you might
which lets you transmit
And support for value-added
over the past year for many
Verifone, Ingenico and
of payment terminals now
There's some things
about value-added
they also support what we
It looks a little like this.
It's where you actually
on the payment terminal
and you'll transmit both
and your loyalty
So it's deeply integrated
This also works with
Now these value-added service
over NFC, and you can even
from these NFC distributed
to be shared and personalized.
You can actually sign up for
Now, there are a few caveats to
One of them you might be
to be signed using a
Regular passes are signed
at the developer portal, but
to be signed with an
Now, you need to request
You can contact us
I'm actually going
at the end of this presentation.
So you can go and
about using value-added
And we're also going to have
We got a lab right
so if you have any
we'd love to talk to you.
Let's talk about a few other
Now these are specific
but I think they're
even if you're not
you might be interested
We offer some unique features
for card issuers
We also now support store
Here's a Kohl's card.
So if you have a store
So these aren't just for banks,
One really great feature
Now, we added this
of apps have already adopted
This lets you set up cards
in Apple Pay directly
You never need to leave you app,
to open Wallet, to
And it's available to any
Now the API is documented
But you can also contact
We actually have an email
at the end, and we're going to
We also have this
which you can use
but also for adding
So if you're just
you can use the new
showing you here.
I'll have some codes to show
Now something that's new
for card issuers and retailers
either co-branded cards, or
with a bank, we now
in-store experience.
You can present your cards
A really good use case of
from your app and immediately
So maybe your app is
it's got a great
So you go into the store, you
you just press a button
with Apple Pay.
The card could be right
It's a really easy API to use.
It's just on the Pass Library.
And you can use the new
for some consistent branding.
And this is the style .inStore.
We have another style I
to different class actually,
but take a look
at the documentation
Another feature that's pretty
applications with your cards.
Again, this is great
and you have a co-branded
with an issuing bank, you
with your store or
which means it can default,
Here's the screen you'll
but it's the same
You can default your card
or new in iOS 10
when paying with an application.
And also a website if
of the new Apple Pay
Now the great thing about most
It's actually built
All you need to do is get
and URL scheme into the pass
Now to do that you can
or if you're an issuing
to us using the contact
of the session, or come
So that's some of the
I want to talk now about Apple
And I also want to tell you
So Apple Pay is an easy,
to pay both in-store
And it's got amazing
It has one of the highest
of any payment method.
And Apple Pay is usable
You can pay using Apple
And thousands of apps have
in the US, in China,
We've recently announced
in France, also Australia.
We've got many countries
And millions of users are
And we've seen incredible growth
and within applications.
And developers such as
results too.
Here's two apps that
One of them is Chairish.
Now the Chairish app, they found
that when they used Apple Pay
from other payment methods.
That's a huge increase.
I can't think of
that has such great results.
And StubHub in their
that Apple Pay was driving
than any other payment method.
So this isn't just for
Apple Pay can bring you
Apple Pay apps are often
in their own sections.
We often run promotions
We've also seen some
of the new countries
One country I want to
We've seen some great
I was so lucky to go to
and taught some developers
and they've seen some
Apple Pay in China
for China UnionPay
And the Apple Pay API
that's China Union Pay, PayEase,
These are major Chinese
We also have documentation
and our Getting Started Guide
they're also now
now that we're launching
You can check out our developer
Now I want to talk about some
for Apple Pay already,
you're probably really
One of the problems with
to set your networks upfront.
You need to tell us the
in your payment request.
So that's hard coded
And adding new networks
You either have to perform SDK
if the constants are
to hack something
And for those of you who
remember when we launched
last year, unless you
you probably weren't
if your payment processor could.
So we're introducing something
it's dynamic networks
Firstly, we're adding
onto PKPaymentRequest.
It's going to tell you
that are available
There's PKPaymentRequest
We're also going to
You're going to be able
as supported networks.
And these proxy down
So for example, if my payment
MasterCard, AmEx and it's
in as the supported
of the networks automatically.
And perhaps most importantly,
as they're added to Apple Pay
So you can check our
about payment processes that are
It's a really cool feature,
of pain I think for writing
One other thing we've changed, I
maybe you've already seen some
We have improved our
We've actually completely
talk about that later.
One change that's coming,
but it will be in seed two.
PassKit now uses stringly
If you're not sure what those
in Swift to take string
into enums, which is
for Apple Pay a lot easier.
Now let's talk about
This year we've got
where we're adding
We're adding support to
And we're adding support to
And finally we're
both on MacOS Sierra
Now we just talked about
It's online right now.
You can check it out.
Let's focus today, right
I'm going to start
And to talk more about WatchKit
to integrate Apple Pay on to
from the WatchKit
Leo.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Nick.
Hello everyone.
My name is Leo and I'm
on the Apple Watch team.
I'm really excited to tell
with Apple Pay on
We're adding support for making
We think this is going to
of apps on the watch.
And the great news
if you have implemented
the same code with
with very minimal changes.
So let's take a look at what
First we're going
on how payments work
I'm going to show you how to
to present a payment sheet.
And then we're going
So you get an idea of how
with Apple Pay on the Watch.
Finally, we're going
of the design considerations
when designing specifically
This is the Apply Pay experience
that your users are
Now let's bring up the watch.
The first thing you notice is
We only display the total amount
and the merchant
And users can simply
to pay at any time.
If they want to make
or review their information,
And they can have access to
as well as shipping, billing
And they can see a detail
When they're ready to pay,
they simply double click the
It is that simple.
Now let's take a look
from a developer's
We follow the same flow that
First you create a payment
to a payment authorization
This is the object that
on our platform.
As the user interact
we're going to call
for example in the payment
And you may use this opportunity
For example, you may not
to some countries.
Or you may want to
and the total amount on the UI.
When the user confirms
we talk to the secure
and we issue a payment
to process the payment.
Now refer everyone to
there is some setup
to enable Apple Pay
First, you want to go
and register a merchant
You may have done this
And then you want
for your WatchKit
And there are step
on our website on
Now let's take a
This is how you create
We use the same PKPaymentRequest
You create one of this and
and currency code, your
and the payment network sync
And then you specify a
that describe what the
Always remember that
on the list represents
And we recommend that you use
since we display that at the
When you want to
you create a PKPayment
and you pass in the request
Then you designate yourself or
and you simply code present.
Now, since you're
you're also responsible
So make sure to do
to payment authorization
in your delegate.
So PKPayment
This is a new controller
in the PassKit.framework.
It is responsible
for controlling the
And it has the same
as of PKPaymentAuthorization
But since it's not
it allows for presentation
from your WatchKit extension.
It is supported across
so you can share your user
and across different platforms.
Now, let's put all of this
So I have been working on
so that users can order and
on their watch and have it
Let's take a look at
Great. So we have a product view
to add a way for
I'm going to go to
in the bottom right corner and
We provide you with this object
to present the payment sheet.
We just need to drag and
And now let's add some code.
I'm going to bring up
so I can have the code
I'm going to control drag from
And create a new action
Now let's just focus
First of all, since we're going
to be using the PassKit
let's make sure we import that.
And now we're going to implement
to be pretty similar to what
First, we're going to
In this case we're
we're going to be charging
We specify the merchant
that we registered
and the payment networks
that we support.
And finally a list
in this case we're just using
Now, if you want to
we create a PK Payment
We pass in the request,
as a delegate, and
Now for seed one we
around Payment Controller while
Let's define the state
And then since we're
protocol let's conform to that.
And we only have
of the required methods
The first one,
these authorize payment.
It's going to be called when
And we provide you with all
to send to your payment
and to confirm calling
with a status.
The second one, as
PaymentAuthorizationController
It's another opportunity for
and perhaps present an
This is all we have to do.
So let's try bill and run this.
Okay, there's our app.
I'm just going to click the
and there we have
It's very simple, we have
that we can try.
And if you went to simulator,
user action of double
there's a new option on the
and it's called Authorize
We just click on
Our payment is confirmed and
pretty soon.
So that's our demo.
[ Applause ]
As you can see it's very
It only took us just
than 50 lines of code.
Now, before we finish
I want to talk about design.
How do we make something easy
Perhaps the most important thing
of experience you want
Users are not going
than just a few seconds
So try to offer them
and direct them quickly
Remember that the interactions
Next, don't request
This could be, for example,
While we offer users the same
for billing and shipping on
to enter a new one right on the
And then as we said in the demo,
use the Payment Button
If it's available on
it is supported on
so it is super easy to add.
And please follow the guidelines
This is probably more detail
used in the context of your app.
So to summarize, if
that implements Apple Pay most
You just need to make sure
to implement PKPayment
and use the present and dismiss
When you're designing
remember that the
and the screens are small.
And use the Payment Button
that we provide following
If you haven't done so already,
out last year's session
which goes into a lot
to create this kind
and how to customize the
I'm really excited to
with Apply Pay on the Watch.
And now I'm going to turn
to tell you more
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
Thank you Leo.
Okay. Extensions.
In previous releases, Apple
that well with extensions.
It's been difficult to
probably because we've always
to present from, and not
Frankly, there also weren't
that many interesting
There weren't that many
and iOS 8 that really lend
But that's changing in iOS 10.
We've got some new
The new extensions, in iOS 10
and they have built-in
And we've solved the
to display in a non-UI context.
The PKPayment
that Leo showed you on watchOS,
You can actually use it anywhere
I want to show you some
We gave the extension's API the
and they use it to
There's some other
You can use it to split
send gifts to friends,
So here you can see,
suggest with your friends,
we never leave messages,
And you're done.
It's really easy.
I want to show you
It's Apple Pay in Siri and
So there's a new ride
that works both in
And you can use Apple Pay
it's actually built in.
So you can pay directly
I'll show you a short
The sample code that
actually has a ride
So here we're asking Siri
to book a ride using
Siri asks us if we want
The Apple Pay sheet's
I can touch ID, and
It's that easy.
I never have to leave
never have to go to another app,
never have to put any
This is great if the user
with your app, if they've
they can still pay for things.
They don't need to
And so requesting and
in these extension points
There's no difference.
You can use this new PKPayment
in both your UI and
And I actually recommend that
You can have a centralized
and you could share
iOS app, and iOS extension.
That's actually what we've
So we've rewritten the Emporium
year, it's been rewritten
It's been simplified.
So it's a lot easier
And it shows a shared
where the actual payment
regardless of the
So, download that
Of course, you might have a
and that brings me on
I saved the best
Testing Apple Pay today
if you've developed
you'll notice it's
You can test on the simulator.
And we've actually got
in the simulator.
You saw the new authorized Apple
for Watch, we're also bringing
And you can test your iOS,
on the web, you can test
Now the simulator returns
Its payment data
It's not real and it's
So it's really useful for UI
But it's not particularly
It's not real card data, and
representative of
You know we always tell you,
of your sole way of developing,
But with Apple Pay that's
Apple Pay is available
but not all countries.
Maybe your developers
or you don't have a
Okay, we're going
We're going to introduce the
The Sandbox is a brand
for Apple Pay and it lets you
onto real devices and the data
that it returns is real payment
So it's just like paying for
or debit card in Apple Pay.
It's really easy to use and
And you can integrate it
where previously perhaps you
on production financial data.
Getting set up with the Sandbox
All you need to do is create
at iTunes Connect.
Now you can already do this
so this already exists today.
You then just log into that
If you're not in a region
that supports Apple Pay you
say the US, or to Canada.
And then you just use the
at developer.apple.com.
We have a list of test
There will be provisions
to Apple Wallet just
There's no developer
Environment's a switch
where you sign in
Now you should still
with production cards
You still should do an
I think this is going to be
a really great feature
And actually if you're
which we talked about
initially you're only able
because we're not going to
until later, nearer the
So the Apple Pay Sandbox
it supports American
And more networks will be
We're also hoping that the
in various payment processes.
So you can do that,
it's available today
So let's have a quick
of the stuff we talked
We talked about some new Wallet
Some of the new things
over the past year and in iOS
card issuers and retailers.
And we talked about
I think Apple Pay
I can't wait to hail a ride
without ever needing
We also talked about
I think there's so
to enable really compelling
for things without having to go
straight from maps,
And then we talked about testing
in the Sandbox and
There's one thing we didn't talk
that's Apple Pay on the Web.
So, you can use Apple
as well as in extensions,
you can now use it on mobile
on the desktop, on MacOS Sierra.
You can authorize payment
in Safari using your
both iPhone and Apple Watch.
Now, we talked about this
So if you're interested
to the website, check
And if you want more information
about today you can check
Now I did promise some
and some other things.
I promised you bank and co-brand
If you're interested in taking
or any of the features I
and card issuers, you
And if you're interested in
you can visit our website,
the links up here,
contact/passkit.
And you can put in a request
to use the value-added
We have some related
we just covered Apple
There's also a WatchKit session
Designing Great Apple
I think you should
if you're interested
See how you can really enable
with the new changes
So thank you so much for coming.
Thank you for making
with your own applications.
And I can't wait to see some
of the amazing things
And hopefully I'll see you
about even more cool
Have a great WWDC.