[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
You're all amazing for
at 4:00 p.m. I know
but thank you so
My name is Ivan Krstic, I
and Architecture at Apple, which
from the ground up into every
Today the focus is iOS.
And I am so proud to tell you
about the role security
as a key design philosophy
Before we dive in, we
Why is security so
and why do we believe it is
The answer is because our mobile
record of our lives.
Never before in history
that know so much about us.
About how we spend money.
About the emails we send,
About our messages.
From our quickest hellos to our
When you think of it that way,
you realize that protecting
that information is so much
For us it's a mission, and it's
of protecting the digital
of our users.
And when you think about it
that the very definition
Attackers today might
to hold your data for ransom.
They might be unscrupulous
to gain an edge.
They might be internet
to indelibly mark your
and advertising without
It could be nation states,
like in the 2014 hack
And sometimes curiosity
of even those close to us.
And then, of course, we must
of the advanced feline threat.
[ Laughter ]
Thank you.
So when you think about all
of these attackers,
We find that the motives tend
There is personal stalking and
to access your photos
gin access to your camera
then there is corporate
which is gaining access to your
and your intellectual
there is direct financial
from your online banking
and committing click fraud
And to do these things,
spyware, ransom ware,
and a variety of other malware.
How do we know this?
Because we've seen it
[ Applause ]
But not on iOS.
Nearly a decade after
there hasn't been a
that has affected
This is because nearly
Apple realized what role mobile
in the lives of our users.
We realized that existing
woefully inadequate, and could
and so we decided to build
that we could imagine to
at a scale that is staggering.
We are protecting users that use
over a billion active iOS
And every single one
of our security features
from real threats.
But we are not in this alone.
There are really three key
There is platform security
that we build into our
There is users who upgrade
and most secure versions,
like you, who use our
to build secure apps.
We're going to talk about
We'll start with
When you think about how
especially in enterprise
and complex list of
to do to try and be secure.
Loading secure configuration
complex batch management
complex password policies.
It was difficult,
and it set up users to fail.
It was so hard to be secure.
But because Apple owns all
we were in a position
in a unique and innovative way.
When you look at iOS security,
we've built security
We have made the
out of the box by default.
We've made it really easy
and run the latest and
We have made it really
into the devices
We have a curated App Store, and
IOS platform security consists
and today I only have
We'll start with Secure Boot.
One of the most important
to trust a device is to trust
And the way we do this is by
The Apple design system chip
Apple's public keys in an area
of memory called Boot
It's written in the factory and
And when your iOS device
and the Boot ROM will validate
which is the low-level
And only that validation passes
in the chain, and we'll repeat
which gives us confidence
that was used in boot was
When you think about secure
that we don't rely
to deliver secure boot trust.
We don't rely on
that are outside of our control.
The keys used or secure boot are
by Apple.
The code that does
that I just showed you
and only Apple is in possession
to sign all the software.
But there is another
which is that when an iOS device
of the software, it has
to contact our installation
and ask for permission to
And it does this by taking
of the update, sending
and asking whether
We do this because the
to deny an iOS device the
less secure version of iOS.
And so when you put these
you get a strong and trustworthy
on the software that
It's not possible to copy
from one device to another.
It's not possible to
of the software of this process.
Now, let's talk about
If you're really serious about
to take the cryptographic
and make them available to
or the normal processor
That is because the attack
too large.
If you're serious about
you build dedicated silicon that
We've done it.
We call it the secure enclave.
Now, when you think
normally they're very
And if somehow an
to take the encrypted data off
and attempt every
it wouldn't take them very long.
So what we do instead is we
and we derive a key from
with the hardware key
to our secure enclave.
Which means it's not possible
Passcode guesses must
and the device is free to
In fact, this is exactly
After a few incorrect
we start imposing a time delay.
But after 10 incorrect
the secure enclave will simply
This has nothing to do with
where if it's on, the data
after 10 incorrect
Even if you have
once 10 incorrect
the secure enclave
that device again regardless
So we built the system using
We've subjected it to rigorous
and third-party code review,
and then we've taken
We have taken our core
that underpin data protection,
for everyone to download
Let's talk about sandboxing.
Sandboxing is a method for
This is because even with
developers sometimes
and sandboxing is a
of the potential harm
It's a little bit like air
which mitigate the risk
We also use sandboxing to
around security directly
We have a mechanism called
and control, where we can ask a
app with some of
like location, photos
And once a user makes a
the sandbox mechanism and the
Another critical element
of our platform security
When an attacker is
the very first step
to get their malicious
Because of this, iOS code
operating system.
It covers every app
In fact, when you go to upload
X code will calculate
of every executable and
and will write them into a code
which is then sent
When the user then
our kernel will look at every
and compare it against the
that it hasn't been
As a result, an attacker can't
inject it into memory and then
Instead, they have to
and difficult schemes to get
Let's talk a bit about Touch ID.
We know that for
on average they unlock
And if you have a passcode
to each one of those 80 unlocks.
As a result, almost half
of our users didn't
and we knew that because the
of the key used to protect
this is a problem
We needed a solution that
and that provided
to the data of our users.
For us, that solution
But we didn't just take
and put it in a phone.
You can change your passwords,
but you can't change your
You can't change
And so we knew that we had
to afford the biometric
of protection we could build.
So what we did was we connected
to the secure enclave,
And we made it so that when you
that fingerprint is transmitted
where it is processed,
And it's never made available
that runs normal
Now, I mentioned
about half of our users
Now, 9 out of 10 do.
This is a shining example
It takes our hardware
our software engineering
to ease of use, and
where a normal user doesn't
doesn't care about secure
What they get is simply
for the security of their data.
The second key pillar
of iOS security is users
The latest versions of iOS
and we're constantly
on the threats we see today and
And we've built all
for trusting the software
but it doesn't matter how
if people are not
the one that is most secure.
So when we think about
about the device and
it is also about our
and our ability to get
and also the user experience
for how a user sees an
One thing we've done with iOS 9
of space it took to install
who had relatively little free
and more secure version
We then took a look
and said sometimes users
to do an update, so
to install an update
or to install it
when they're probably
or be reminded the next day.
The results are amazing.
Nearly 85% of our customers
of iOS, the most
and if you think this is easy
at some of the other
This, by the way, is a fair
and iOS 9 were released
of each other, and for some
of Android before 5.1.1 has
fright, which is
You can exploit it by sending
to a vulnerable device,
over that device.
And Google patched
But it doesn't matter,
of their users don't
And a fix that is not installed
which is why we invest
in building secure versions of
for our users to have that
The third pillar in iOS
using the security
to build secure apps.
This means following best
We have an amazing number of
to save their users from having
and type them directly into
we introduced a feature
that provides strong protection
across the network to
Today I'm proud to say
App Transport Security
for App Store apps.
This means that by the end of
with your own server
so using a secure TLS
unless the data being
such as media streaming and
This is going to provide a
for our users, and
that your apps have
There is another piece of
on you, the developers,
and this is to know your code,
but also any third-party
in your apps.
This is the because libraries
security of your app.
Maybe because they're doing
of behind your back.
But maybe because
and more secure version
There is kind of an
where there is a very popular
that had a critical
of security for TLS connections.
And this flaw was patched
of time, there were up to
that didn't have that
So it's really important that
from trustworthy locations,
and that you keep it current.
So these are our three key
Platform security, which are
mechanisms that we can build
Our users who download the
of iOS and developers like you,
using our security technologies
And it's a fair question to
How good is iOS security?
Security is interesting,
you can't measure it directly.
You can't run a test, and
to get an objective answer.
So what you're left with
And I have three that
The first one is that after
there has still not
of iOS malware affecting
This one is the one that
Our users have been
for nearly 10 years.
The next indirect metric that is
of the unfettered jailbreaks
These are jailbreaks that
and what is interesting
that the latest launch we've
to find and chain
and ten distinct vulnerabilities
to defeat platform
This is much higher than
And the reason is because iOS
in lock step in such a
of them takes a long
For my last indirect metric,
I want you to take it
As probably most of you
for software vulnerabilities.
And every once in a
on the black market
Usually these prices are
sometimes a hundred thousand.
But in 2013, the New
that an iOS vulnerability sold
Forbes interviewed a
that most experts agree
of an unfettered iOS
Take that with a grain of salt,
but it's a fascinating
So where does this leave us?
Clearly, security is a
We're not done with iOS
It's also not something that we
What you're seeing now
of our best work in
But the bad guys
and we will constantly
to defeat not only
but also the threats
We will take our
and our software expertise,
and we will build the
that we can imagine to
and how they use their
and also how they'll
and protect our customers
and tomorrow's, even if
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; For those of you who want
to read the iOS security guide,
of technical detail about
covered, including many others
like iCloud keychain and
and a link will be available
Thank you again.
[ Applause ]