[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon!
[laughs] Welcome everyone.
Thanks for coming out to hear
My name's Lucia Ballard
and I manage the Secure
And together with my colleague
through a bunch of new stuff
on to help you improve the
So, I hope a lot of you caught
before this.
It's a great overview of why
of the fundamental underpinnings
Here we're going to dive a
So, here's what's on deck.
First up we'll be talking
about some network
Then we'll discuss
to our cryptography APIs.
And then Simon's going to talk
about platform security
So, diving into network
as much as I do, you know
that it's accumulated an
about your personal life,
and a lot of that comes
Whether it's articles
or messages you're
all these little bits of detail,
even if they seem
can add up to a really
So, that's why we
of this detail should
We think HTTPS is the new HTTP.
So, for every resource you're
you should provide
and data integrity
The other key point here is that
HTTPS is built on SSL, or now
and not all versions of this
security that your users be
So, building on these
last year we introduced
App Transport Security
that you're doing,
or even the older
you have to be using top of
First off that means TLS
out for a while, but it's the
to all the vulnerabilities that
or the POODLE attack, or other
It also means you have to
so that's ciphers like
and certificates
Certificates signed with SHA-1,
Finally, it also
So, this is a way
between server and the client.
It gives an amazing
if in the future
the server's certificate
you can't reveal the
that have happened in the past.
So, you add all these together
is a secure connection
that protects the
Now, we know that it takes
with App Transport Security, so
You can turn it off globally,
up for particular domains
that you knew couldn't
Now I'm wondering
in this audience are
I set that Exception last
about it for a while."
Well, now is the
because this year we're starting
to enforce App Transport
This is going to kick in at
that for most Exceptions
to provide a reasonable
So, for all of these Exceptions
that actually turn off
or its key properties
you'll need to explain
to use this Exception
For other Exceptions like
that support for those
so for now those Exceptions
without any justification.
So for example, if you have a
with and you don't have control
over what cipher suites they're
to enable you to keep
We're also adding
to make it easier to adopt.
So for example, if you're
and that media's already
to offer an Exception through
that media without
I want to be clear, we still
that you use TLS for everything,
but in some cases we will be
to help you transition
We're also offering a
So, here sometimes your app
from around the web
and of course you can't
So, if you're WKWebView, then
in your app's Info.plist.
NSAllowsAarbitraryLoads
of those loads will be exempted
from the App Transport
but everything else your
to your own server, will
So, that's App Transport
but we're also making changes
because cipher suites keep
and more effective attacks
So, no matter what
we've now disabled
for anyone using
We've also disabled SSLv3
So, even if you're dialing
down into our lower level
to access SSLv3.
Research has simply
of these technologies
that they provide effective
So, these are disabled.
Other algorithms are
specifically SHA-1 is showing
to attacks, as is 3DES.
So, if you know that you
of these algorithms now
And I recognize many people in
and aren't in charge of their
to reach out to the
or whoever's hosting your
that they've dropped
on these older algorithms
It would be a great time to
of loading things using
that you are cleared for
then you'll be able to
So, that's App Transport
It's making sure everything
but strong TLS is not enough.
You also need to have
that you're using to validate
that TLS connection
So, I want to talk about a
that we're using today to help
in fact reaching out to the
when you're establishing
So, first let's back up
about how certificates
So, if you're connecting
that server has had
from a certificate authority.
That authority validates
and says, "Yep, sounds good.
You are in fact example.com.
Here's your cryptographic
And when you connect the server
But this is not always
If there's an attacker who
for your host name, then
that certificate, and you as
to distinguish the attacker's
This could happen
if the certificate
worse case scenario,
someone else uses their private
So, today I'm proud to announce
for certificate transparency.
Certificate transparency is a
verifiable logs of
These logs collect certificates
so there are many participating
but in fact anyone
Then the logs issue
that the certificate
and a client can
There are a bunch of
Proof can be embedded in
or it can get handed over
or it can be delivered
which I'll talk more
So, here's a quick
First, the certificate authority
to the server, but it also
it gets added into
The log then sends
that the certificate
and the server hands both that
over to you, the client.
That means you can
So, certificate transparency
to launch attacks.
Basically it puts the
If the attacker can
from an authority that's not
to get that cryptographic proof
that the certificate has
So, they hand over
and the client can reject it.
Alternatively, if they are using
participating, then that
and is publically visible, and
to revoke the certificate at
So, we think this is a critical
to have confidence that the
to is in fact the certificate
So, here's how you
You can actually use the same
up your app for security
It's a new keyword, so for each
that's participating, you
and then your client will reject
that it's been publically
Our current policy roughly
from at least two logs.
These logs -- we're adding
but basically if your
in Chromium it'll
And there's a lot
about the general technology
So, I encourage you
Now certificate transparency is
but it doesn't totally
There's still that last
out the certificate is flawed
to actually stop trusting it.
So, I want to take a
about our recommended
It's called the OCSP stapling.
Now this is a standard that's
but we think that it --
now's the time for folks
and start adopting
for it is now quite widespread.
OCSP stapling is an enhancement
to the online certificate
and solves a bunch
So, as a refresher,
We have the same set up, right?
Where your certificate authority
to a server, every
to that server it sees the
to know whether it's
So, it asks the certificate
in the middle of
and the certificate
the certs still valid," or
Don't trust it."
This has some issues.
One of them is that it's slow.
You're right in the middle of
to get your resources,
to make your network
especially if that
you might be hanging
The other major issue is
about whatever activity
Your certificate
which host names
to because you're
up each time you connect.
OCSP stapling resolves
So, here's basically
Instead of the client asking,
the server asks the
and the certificate authority
to the server.
Now it's signed by the
so you know you can trust it.
Then the server gives both
that it's valid over to
all in the same handshake.
So, this means that your
delivered reliably and quickly.
There's no extra waiting.
There's no concern there.
And it protects your
because the only connection
to your server.
You may have noticed
like the certificate
because you can use
to deliver certificate
As long as your certificate
can hand all of that information
And, like I said, OCSP
across many operating systems
so you can go turn it on
whatever your backend
And it's now fully supported
So, if you could take a step
with network security, now's
to App Transport
So, that's strong algorithms
forward secrecy, and
Also, it'd be a great time
with certificate transparency.
Find certificate authorities
and get integrated
And please, go enable
so we connect the
that you can have confidence
in making secured connections
So, that's network security.
Now I'd like to take a
about some cryptographic
So, first up is SecKey.
SecKey is our algorithm,
is our API for asymmetric
And in this release
across macOS and iOS APIs.
SecKey now has support for all
want to do with asymmetric
So, that's signing and
This means that SecKey
for the deprecated
And it also replaces any use of
to do cryptography
So, we strongly recommend
We've also tied this into a
CryptoTokenKit is system support
so that smart cards you might
and various enterprises
we now have out of the
and they can integrate
So, that means the Token content
as you would expect, and the
using the SecKey API.
Now this is a complex topic
and there's a lot of
So, please come see us in the
through your use case.
So, thanks for your attention
to Simon to talk about what's
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you very much Lucia.
Hello. I'm Simon Cooper.
I'm the manager of the
So, I'm going to talk about
but first of all I
a little bit about how software
a little bit about Developer
about Gatekeeper and
surrounding Gatekeeper.
So, let's start off about --
talking about how
for a couple of our platforms.
So, for iOS you can get
You can build and
and install them on
And there's some enterprise
to deliver and manage
You'll notice that all of these
silently handled by
So, now I'd like to talk
So, you can also get apps
and that's a very good
You can also get apps that are
You can also use Xcode
and use the traditional
to build things in
So, let's go back and talk a
So, what is Developer ID?
Developer ID allows you
to deliver apps outside
These apps are usually
The Developer ID
with a Developer ID signing ID.
And when you sign apps using
that identity they are treated
There are actually some improved
to properly export
signed applications.
So, there's something
and that's a change to
and this was announced
We're actually allowing
to be used with iCloud.
So, Developer ID can
That includes iCloud
Push Notifications, and VPN.
So, what does this mean?
This means that you can deliver
of the App Store and you can now
with your iCloud
You will be able to deploy
to macOS 10.9.
So, I'm sure you want to know
when you'll be able
So, you can start iCloud
That's using the Xcode 8 tools.
And I'm sure you're aware
of iCloud there is a development
When you're going to deploy
to be deploying against
and you'll have to wait for
to start testing that.
When you are going to do
in Xcode 8 because they make
against the production servers.
The Xcode team also
that please don't distribute
GM tools.
So, the other side of
Gatekeeper allows us to
to run on your machine.
And there is a Preference Panel.
And on that Preference
there are these options; you can
you can run from the Mac App
or you can run apps
When you first run an app
before its first run.
We're actually making
and we're making changes to
We are changing the
and those default
you can run from
you can run from the Mac App
Now if Gatekeeper rejects
there's usually a button that
that allows you to open
Unfortunately I have to say,
in the seed build this function
but it will be fixed
I also want to say that we
that this underlying
that the policy works.
So, this means that if you
or you use command line tools
you can re-enable
So, I want to talk a little bit
to Gatekeeper, but
about a repackaging problem
that we've developed
Now the repackaging
because of the way
There are a certain type of apps
that when they are written they
and use external resources.
These apps may be delivered
in fact be correctly signed.
But the external
out to may not be signed
and they can be code
They could be libraries,
they could even be HTML content.
And you may not be aware
that if it contains JavaScript
These resources could also be
or even Apple Scripts.
So, what's the problem?
Well, if you put these two
container and deliver the app
or a disk image or using an
into the container, and then you
when the app runs and it talks
to the external resources
dangerous things.
And you'll notice that the
meaning that it's signed, is
outside of the signature,
and trying to touch these
So, if I take that app
but instead of packaging it with
the developer, would
and I put malicious
then when the user runs
to be getting your
to be getting the experience
Now if that malicious code
that you may have put into a
then your app is almost
to be doing what you
So, we're calling this
and there are some things
that are actually
by the packaging problem,
that are delivered
And that is the best
Other things that are
if you install your apps using a
That doesn't mean to say
that the app once it's been
and delivered in
but the actual Apple Installer
of reaching outside
So, there are things
and that is if you are
or a disk image, or if you've
in an ISO image, and any
It's also possible that if
in such a way that
to assemble an app using a
from here and there, you can
So, I -- we need your
And we also need to
because of this problem.
So, what do we need to do?
So, if you're delivering
with some external resources,
through using a zip, or a
And we need to ask you to
And the reason we're
because we can now
You can sign a disk image
and that is the current
or any of the later
You can use the cosigning
to sign the disk
and that will basically
and the app together.
These signatures are actually
and are carried along with it,
and this signed disk
with older OS releases.
So, I'd now like to give
So, one way to avoid
repackaging problem is
and put your resources
and then sign the whole thing.
If you're distributing just a
consider delivering it
You should certainly
Perhaps package it
but please verify the
Alternatively if you
up you can use a signed
For a container with apps and
please use, and switch to
Sign any content that you
so that app that's inside
and you should sign
And please verify all
release it.
So, some final words
so if you're adding
or licensing information
when it's being downloaded
on the bundle route of the app.
And there's a tech note that
and that's Tech Note 2206.
And you could also do this
by signing the personalized
Here are some things that
You should not modify
because this will break
and when Gatekeeper comes
to verify your app
You should never deliver your
and please stop shipping
So, now I'd like to talk
that we have developed that
And this is all about
This mechanism, we're calling
it supplements existing
all the existing
and there's no change
And there's no change when
for any apps that were
This mechanism will
for any newly downloaded apps
on unsigned disk images.
So, let me describe exactly how
So, this is a complex
in your Downloads folder and
or this could actually
that contains your app
So, when you double
when your app runs it will be
into a randomized place on the
to access the resources.
So, this stops the
So there are some situations
where this relocation
If the user explicitly
and it's just the app
with something else, then
turned off.
If the user moves the
maybe to Slash Applications,
then this mechanism
This does not happen if
So, any apps that are run
from a signed disk image will
to them.
This mechanism also
if you install software using a
It also doesn't apply to any
So, in summary if there
from this talk; sign the things
that things that are valid.
So, more information about
[ Applause ]