[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everybody
Introduction to Notifications.
I'm Kritarth Jain an engineer
and today I'll be joined
for the later half
Now the team's been
over the last one year to
for notifications for iOS
to share it with you today.
We're going to start
out by doing an overview
And today we're existing
for doing user notifications.
As part of this, we're
content creation, scheduling
managing them, and action
And lastly, we're going
to introduce a brand new feature
that we think you're
But there's a lot more to cover
and we're not going to get
So there's going to be an
following this one
So do make sure to check it out.
So let's begin by talking
Now I'm sure all
with what a notification
This is how your
to your app users when your
It's a push mechanism
versus a pull mechanism where
to the application to get the
Now, you as app developers,
in which you can send these
They can be visual alerts,
down from the top as a banner.
You can do sound and
with your notifications as
So that the user knows
which application has
Depending upon the
there're different ways how
If the device is unlocked
down from the top as a banner.
While the device is locked,
on the user's lock screen.
And if the user ever
they can always go to
and see all the pending
for them there.
So what are the different
as app developers can use for
Mainly there are two types.
Local notifications and
depending on their
So let's look at
Now local notifications
by applications that
Examples of local notifications
or location based triggers,
where your application
with the system showing
to the user's device, and
notification, your
As I mentioned, examples
of these can include
calendar alerts, or
Now, not all your
on the user's device.
A lot of them have a
where your server-side
across the network
So to facilitate notifications
for that we have
Let's take a look at how
The main piece involved in
Notification Service,
It's part of remote
Your remote site application
to APNs, which then does
of this notification to the
that notification and then
to be handled when the
Examples of remote notifications
where your server-side
breaking news and then
to the different devices
that have your application
Instant messaging alerts as well
on your servers, and when a new
that notification along
Now remote notifications in turn
they can be either
Now user-facing notifications,
as the name suggests are
to the user on the device.
And by setting up your
way, you can add this content
As opposed to user-facing
we also offer silent
Now, these silent
where your notification payload
flag when this notification
the system knows to wake your
to perform a background
So then your client-side
to your remote server
and get the latest
so that the next time your
to your device they see the
to them giving them a
So that was in a nutshell
type of those notification
Now before we proceed,
of the existing API
for notifications
Now, you use UI application for
and then scheduling
that your application
This is part of the UI kit
of you are familiar with.
However, there were some
For example, there are
and remote notifications
to the duplication of code.
There's also limited control.
After your application has
to the user and there's
for notifications across
that Apple supports today.
So we really wanted to
and on top of that give you
for really elevating the
for your app users.
So today we're really excited to
for doing user notifications.
Let's take a look at what's
To start out, it has a very
with what exists today.
So transferring your code
to the new framework
We've also expanded the
on the notifications for having
to your user.
We've combined the
and remote notification handling
for handling the notifications.
[ Applause ]
We've also simplified
that your application gets
with actions on these
We've also included better
What this means is that
to notifications that are
or already delivered to the
as well update notifications.
We'll take a look at all of this
Starting in iOS 10 we now
to do in-app presentation
[ Applause ]
So now, your apps get the
as the system supports
You can now also schedule
and handle notifications
And lastly, we've
to notifications themselves,
So what this new
to have a single notifications
that Apple supports, including
Let's take a look at what
for all these different
On iOS, we give the full
and scheduling notification
On watchOS, we continue
of forwarding notifications
to their Watch, but
we now let your WatchOS
to do local notification
What this means is that
to be connected to your device,
and your applications can
For example, you have the
of your application
but forgot their device behind.
You can still send
of when they meet
or when their workout time is
For more information about
on WatchOS we have a Quick
for WatchOS session.
And continuing, for
to badging app icons for both
This can be used
For example, if your
to let the user know the number
you can just badge the
Or for a turn by
if the user has a
then badging the app
that that's waiting for them.
So that's in a nutshell summary
of what this new
on all these different
Let's continue and dive into
How does your application
to the user's device
Well, even before you can
that your application needs
Let's take a look at
Now notifications are an
So it's very important you
and permission before you
So you can ask them permission
or badging the app icon and the
user gets prompted
You need to do this registration
as remote notification.
And performing this registration
as calling request authorization
on the UN user notification
with your application,
that you want registration for.
However, do note
that the user might
configurable in the settings
So your application users can
or off depending on
In iOS 10 we now
to access these user
so that you can be smarter about
to send to the user depending
[ Applause ]
But registration
For remote notifications,
for token registration,
which uses the existing
So you register for
you need a network connection so
to APNs for this registration
for your device and
This token gets returned to
which then you need to forward
to your servicer-side
Now this is important because
as part of the notification
that your remote side
through your APNs.
Because this token acts as the
and the application to which it
So that was registration.
Now your application is ready
to start sending
So the first thing
after that is create the
Now I'm sure all of you have
looks that we've
We're really excited about
To start with, we now show the
in all iOS notifications.
[ Applause ]
We've also included an
so you can have more
of information you're
And of course, there's
Let's take a look at how
So it's as simple as creating
object and setting the different
For remote notifications,
Your notification payload
and again you set the
of your payload before
However, that's not
we decided to go one step
in iOS 10 we now let all
attachments right in
[ Applause ]
So now you can have much richer
and colorful notifications
For more on media attachments,
on how to set these up in the
So now that your content
that your app needs to
to send the notification.
And for that there are triggers.
In iOS 10 we support four
timer interval, calendar,
Now the push trigger is
with remote notifications
when your remote side
notification to APNs it
with the push trigger, all the
that are associated with
Now, time interval based
notification at a certain time
For example, if you wanted
in two minutes from now,
or you want to send it every
This also lets you schedule
by setting the time
Now as opposed to time interval
calendar triggers that
at a specific date and
So you have more
when the notification gets sent.
Example of this can be at a
or repeating it on a certain day
And lastly in triggers, we
which uses your devices absolute
in relation to Bluetooth
if your device is entering
or leaving the region you can
Examples of this is when the
and the device is
or say that the user
and your application wants
to send them a coupon
So those are the different
of this new framework.
Now that your content's ready
to send the notification,
the next step left is
with the system.
For local notifications this is
on the UUserNotificationCenter
Which then on the trigger
notification to the user.
And for remote notifications,
your service-side application
which does a best effort
notification to the
So let's summarize this
that we've talked about so far.
Your application starts out by
Then it creates the content,
to send the notification
and finally schedules
with the system leading
to the notification getting
It's as simple as that.
Let's take a look at
Start out by doing registration,
you create the content
You create the trigger, in this
based trigger, and then
in a UNNotificationRequest
passing a unique identifier,
which will be important
about later in this session.
And then you schedule this
completing the notification's
So, so far we've talked
to a notification while your
and the user's not
but what if your application
when it receives a notification?
And for this we do offer support
for notification handling while
Your application needs
to implement the
delegate.
And it has a method of
which lets you get the
of the UNNotification object
Now this method also
which must be called at
One thing to note is that
presentation options parameters.
Now, what this enables you to
that we talked about earlier.
Let's see an example of how
So, say your application still
as well as your sound alert
in foreground.
So this is as simple as
with these different parameters.
And if you don't want
you just don't pass
So that was notification
is in foreground.
Let's move on and talk about
Now notification management
and what this allows you to do
that are pending delivery
for your locally scheduled
to delivered notification
that the user might
or remove notifications.
Now you can also
that have already been sent
and promote these notifications.
And important piece
of notification management
Now, in the summary you saw that
on the notification
And for remote notifications
APNs collapse id that you
The system uses this
which notification
to be removed or updated.
Let's take a look
at notification management
Say your application wants to
and it wants to send
for the start time of the game.
So you start out by creating
and scheduling it
but say that the
So this is as simple as calling
Request, passing it the
that you created for the
But what if the game
Then you create a new request,
giving it the exact
for the initial request,
and just scheduling
And this in turn leads to
Let's continue this example
and talk about score updates.
Again, you just start
out by creating this
and sending it to the system.
But say that the wrong
then you can simple
by calling
giving it the same identifier.
And what if the score
which of course is a very
So all you can do in
notification request, giving
passing it the new
and then simply scheduling
Now, what this means, let's
say that notification
for initial score update.
So by calling update, as I
to is that that notification
in the notification list,
replacing the original
so that you're not cluttering
at all.
[ Applause ]
And you can use this in multiple
that is right for
So that was notification
it really gives your
on the notifications that
So so far in this
about how your application
to the users.
But what about the other
Notifications are very
of default actions as
that your applications
So, to talk about notification
colleague Julien to
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
I'm Julien.
I am a software engineer
Kritarth showed you the web flow
with the current user
from registration up to the time
when notifications are
So now let's talk
that the user can take
There are three types of actions
that your applications
The first one is
It is when the user opens
This can be done when
and the user receives a
on the banner, which
It can also be done from the
from left to right, as well
when the user swipes down to
they can tap on any
to open your application.
Now the second type of
And they are within the
We introduced actionable
and they provide
to execute an action
without the need of
Now these custom actions,
with customizable title below
In iOS 9 we introduced
so that the user can for example
of directly from
And these custom actions can be
A background action will
and give you a short amount
to process that custom action
On the other hand, a foreground
notification and launch your
so that you can process
Now these custom
on both iOS and watchOS.
So first, let's take a look
Here we have an example
On this device, the
to expand a notification.
When they do so the custom
notification content.
And some of these actions,
as you can see can
so the user can quickly
Now on watchOS, same
appear below the
and some of these actions can
And on the watchOS, you
to provide some suggestions that
for your text input action.
Now for more information
on watchOS you can attend the
for watchOS Session later today.
So now that we've talked
about what the custom
Let's first talk about how you
and then present
So for registration, the first
to create an action object.
You give it a unique
The title will appear on
that we previously saw.
Action will be by
but you can also provide some
to be a foreground action.
Now, all your actions they need
to be associated
The category requires
You give it all the
You can also provide now
for more information
you can attend the
There are also some options
that you can provide
We will talk about one
Now, once you've
and all your categories, the
to register them
to the UNUserNotificationCenter
with your application.
Now let's talk about how you
to your user.
You can do so from both remote
So first for remote
the only thing you need to do
in the APS dictionary of the
Now this identifier needs to
for the categories you
For local notifications
to set the category identifier
on the mutable content
Same thing this identifier
that you [inaudible] before.
Now let's talk about
that your app can be aware
Now the dismiss action is
when the user dismisses
You could use this
you have a calendar application
and let's say you send a remote
about an upcoming meeting.
The user looks at
and decides to dismiss it.
When in this case you might want
to stop sending other remote
of this user since they have
Now, how can the user actually
Well they can do that on
from right to left, and
They can also do that from the
from right to left as well,
which will dismiss
Now since this is not the
to update for it.
So remember earlier
about the different categories
we talked about some
the customDismissAction option.
So let's look at the
to register our category.
The only thing you
is simply add the
to the options of this category
and your app will
when the result dismisses
with this category.
So let's summarize the actions
The first one is
when the user opens
from the notification.
The second one where
within actionable notifications
for the user to execute
from the notification.
And finally the third one
it is new to iOS 10 and
when a user dismisses a
[ Applause ]
Now let's talk about how you can
from these actions
So until now we had
on if the user opened the
or if we had custom actions or
from a remote or a
Well now with our new user
we have a single method
of the UNUserNotificationCenter
The method you will need to
with CompletionHandler.
Now let's take a closer
and what you can do with
Your response object has
which can either be the
or any of the custom
It can have a user
if it was a text input action.
It can also have a notification
and the identifier of
as the trigger and the content.
Based on the type of trigger
from a local or a
So this is all with the new
you can handle your
Now, let's talk about
This is your current
with remote notification that
You have your service
which sends a remote
to Apple push notification
And then it is delivered to the
Now, maybe some of
where you have your server side
to your iOS application
end-to-end encryption.
Well, wouldn't that be great
to end encryption for your
Well for that in iOS 10
service extension.
So now we are going to talk
about what the service
and then how you can
in your application.
Now the service extension is
on iOS 10, which means it
And its main purpose is to
of visible or remote
displayed to the user.
So let's take a look again
for remote notifications.
So you have your server-side
to Apple push notification
and then it is sent
Well, now with the extension,
you're able to modify
between the time you sent it
from your server-side
and the time it is displayed
As you can see in this
as well as a subtitle,
and I modified the body
Now a few more details about
You will get a short execution
for long background
And in case you fail to
in a timely manner, you
In case you still fail to
we will show the original
that you sent to the user.
Now some potential uses of
encryption for your remote
as well add some attachments
to make them even richer.
Now there will be a
that in the Advance
Now let's talk about how you
service extension
The first thing you would need
to add the new target.
You can use the template,
under the application
And it is known as the
Now this template
So we are going to take a look
So this class, is a subclass
of the UNNotification
and it has two main methods.
The first method is
Now this method will give
which has the identifier
as well as the content.
Then we have the ContentHandler.
You will need to call this
to present the notification
to provide some content for it.
Now, the second method is
expire, and this will be called
if you cannot provide updated
So now remember if you fail
in this method, we will show
content that you sent.
So now let's talk about how you
from a remote notification.
Here, we have a very
of remote notification
And as you can see we have a new
Now, you will need to use this
that you want the service
to update the remote
You do not need to use
only use it when
to replace the content
Now you can see that I also
of my own.
So let's take a look at some
to process this remote
So you can see here we have
and the first thing I do here is
of the remote notification
I then create a
object and I assign the
with the decrypted content
And finally we call
to present the notification
Now, this is how simple it is
to implement the new service
[ Applause ]
Now let's recap what
We saw an overview of
and remote notifications.
We showed you the new user
where is available on
We talked about how you can
as well as how you can
How you can schedule
either local or remote.
We also talked about the new
on the pending and
And then we talked about
that the user can take
and how you can handle the
within your application.
Finally, we presented the
which allows you to augment
of visual remote notifications
to the user.
For more information,
on developer.apple.com.
We will have some
There is an Advance Notification
we strongly encourage you
if you are interested
There is also if you want more
on the Watch you can attend the
for watchOS Session.
Thank you everyone.
[ Applause ]