[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Welcome to Advanced
I'm Michele, and today we will
about new notifications
We'll start with the new
We'll go over a little
and we'll see what
Then we'll see how to
in the new notifications,
to customize the user interface
Let's start with the overview
User notifications in iOS X
You see here the new lock screen
with beautiful animations
Here is a banner.
You see they are
They have more content.
They show title, subtitle, and
and notifications look the same
In iOS 8, we introduced
where you can add actions
to make them more interactive
with that much more quickly.
In iOS 9, we introduced
to enhance actionable
so you can even allow the
that they type to
In iOS X, notifications
because notifications now are
as we interact with
They are a very important way
and a very important
with your applications.
So in iOS X, you can
and notification will expand
and show a much more detail
for your application, and it's
It shows more detail, and
The user can also
and the user interface can
and the effect of the
Calendar, which just
We also have Find My
that when a friend shares
you see their location
so you can see how late they're
We also have notifications
If you shared a photo on iCloud,
in the notification
and you can like it or comment
to look at the, at the picture.
At last, messages.
This is not all of it.
Messages support Quick
but you could only
and you can only
Now you see the entire
when you open the notification,
you can wait for your friends
can type more responses.
This is the power of new
But is this was all there was to
for half an hour and show
in iOS X.
So the most important feature I
that everything I just
with the new API's that we
so you can do exactly the
and add all the same features
and your notifications.
The first thing you can
You know, one of the most
by my friends are pictures
So it's really important
that was shared [inaudible]
so I can see it more
to open the app and download it.
But the problem is
push notifications are
and even if we increase the
that's not nearly enough
even if it's a small one that
So how do we do that?
We use the new service
that we introduced earlier today
So to do, to download
in the service extension, you
to be mutable, as you
I send a mutable content flag,
to the attachment that you
In this case, I use
but you could also
that your app knows how to
After you've done this, and
to the device, the system will
In the service extension,
you can download the
Perhaps you can use
so that the system helps
And then the notification
to the user with the attachment.
Let's see it, a little bit
This is a very basic example
At the top, I implemented
withContentHandler,
when the notification
and I have to download
I download my attachment, again,
or other techniques
and when I have the
I can create a notification
When I created the object, I
and I pass it onto the system
After I've done this,
with a beautiful picture
without waiting for
or without having
And you see the notification
actionable notifications to.
So you can like or comment this,
So media attachments,
They support local, every
We only talked about local here.
We only talked about remote
You just create the
when you're scheduling the
Attachments support
and the system will
for this three types of content.
You download the attachment
but you have to remember
that the service extensions
that it can run, and file
because these are meant to be
They're not meant to deliver
So you may want to send
of the image, and then
when the user opens the app.
Or you may want to
if you're sending a video, and
when they open the app.
When you downloaded it, you
and at this point,
and manages the file for you.
You don't need to worry
The system moves it
and handles all the data.
Oh, yeah, I almost forgot.
Of course, we support GIFs.
[ Applause ]
So attachments are pretty cool,
and they provide a very rich
but at the beginning I said that
that I showed you with the new
messages, and they
using attachments.
They were using custom
and this is what we're
To create a custom
you use the second
to our standard notifications,
and it's a
The NotificationContentExtension
to add your own views,
You can draw anything
most important limitation is
that there is no
They don't receive touches.
The user cannot tap on them.
But notifications
because you can use
and the extension can
and we'll see later
So I said that we can
that the system is doing.
Let's start by seeing
and then we'll see how
This is a calendar notification.
You see at the very
with the notification icon that
the application name,
This is standard UI
to all notifications.
Underneath the header,
and this is where your
will live.
This is where you
You show all the extra details
And underneath these,
that the system shows.
This shows the content that
This was what was visible until
And at the very bottom, there
and interact in notification.
When the user taps on them,
and show what happened.
So let's see how to make
We'll start with a party invite.
Parties are fun, and we're
This is the basic notification
by the user when you just
and it's pretty similar
Let's see how to expand this
and show custom user
The first thing you want to
in your application, and you
that Xcode provides,
the NotificationContentExtension
This template will create
A view controller, main
and the info.plist
up customizables
This is the view controller
for the
As you see, it's just a UI
It's a regular view controller
It also implements the
protocol, and this is what
to use these view controller
This protocol has only
The required method is
as you see here, and this
with the view controller
when the notification is
To your extension.
So when the user
you will receive all the
and these one in addition.
So you can receive the
and update your UI and
The, the next thing you want
to find your content extension.
Content extensions, you use the
that you use to register
In this case, I use
for my party invite invitation,
but extensions can
with multiple categories in
for different types
of notifications
In this case, I'm using the
They could be very similar UI's.
So I can just use the
because they may have
So I set up everything.
I have my view controller.
Now I want to add some custom
It's a very controller.
I added some labels
that I'm not showing
when I receive the notification,
to have the information I need,
on the labels that
You see that I also have some
to the standard one that comes
to show something more than the
In this case, I'm
because it's pretty important
And this is my notification now.
You see that I have
I draw my own UI with my custom
but these notifications
The first problem is that
I don't need all
It's all empty.
I have much smaller
The second problem is that the
I don't need it because I'm
information up top
But we can fix both
Well, let's fix the
because it's easier, and this
in your info.plist, and you can
to yes to hide the
The system will not
The second problem was the
but since it's just
I can resize it the way I'm used
In this case, I'm setting
but you can set the
You can use the storyboard,
And after fixing
this is my notification now.
It looks much better.
It's the right size
There's no duplicate content,
but did you see there
When the notification
it was not the right size.
So the system had to animate
to show it the right size.
Let me show it to you again.
See? We could make it better.
The reason this happens
to know the size of your final
to display it so you can
But your extension
when the system starts
So you need to tell the
of your code runs what size
But the problem is that
in different devices
with different sizes
So the way we do that is
content size ratio.
So these, this defines the
that you want to use
Now this may, of course,
because you may have
You don't know what
You still want to
So sometimes this may not
figure out a size that works
This is the way to do it.
And the result after I've done
that now present it directly
at the right size
So let's review what
We wanted to do a
We may, we started
That's pretty basic, but has all
information that was
but it was the wrong size.
So we fixed the presentation
by using the initial
And then we fixed the
by setting the default
and we went from the
This looks better
Still not great, but I
that is unlocked
But I also know another trick to
We can add pictures.
Pictures are always nice,
So we can use the
that we used earlier also in
Since they're added to
you can access them inside
So when you receive the
notification method, you
from your content.
As I mentioned earlier,
by the system, and it's
This means that it's
So you need to tell the system
and tell the system
When you have access, you
In this case, I'm adding
And here's my notification now.
You can tell this
[ Applause ]
This is much nicer than
and it's our own custom UI.
We want, we wanted to show
to the user, and we added that.
We wanted to add a picture.
We have that, too.
Well, we missed the next step.
We want to make this
We want to implement
Let's do that now.
Default actions by
as you're used to since iOS 8.
They are delivered to the app.
When the user taps
the app receives the
and the notification gets
This is pretty convenient
that you often use, and it's
but sometimes you want to
of the action for,
of the calendar invitation.
That when the user
the content highlighted the
And you can do that in your
You do that by intercepting
in the notification extension.
When you do that, the action
and it can decide to delay the
So it has time to handle
and dismiss when it's done.
This is very simple,
with the second method inside
protocol.
This method is optional.
You don't need to implement
to intercept the actions,
it means that you have
that are in that notification.
You cannot handle one and
So when you receive
you can send a response
to update the information
When you receive the
you update the UI saying
to the party, of course.
And when it's done, you can
So that the interface was
In case you want to
to your application,
If you want to do
or you want to keep the code
you just call completionHandler
And what happens when we do this
we tap on that, and
and we dismiss later.
So you saw in my example code
and decline action, and we
Because sometimes
to a party invitation,
we want to tell your friends
to the party or how upset
So you tap on the
The comment action is
like the ones we introduced
in the same way, except with
This is a texting production.
A tiny bit of newer PI on this.
You can set the place
and when you created the action,
so that it's displayed
So when the user taps
the text will display.
Now since this is an
you can handle it
So you can intercept it
and handle it there.
Here's how you do that.
You receive the notification.
You check if it's a
You extract the text of the user
And when you're done, you
And this is what happens.
You tap, type, and there's
with this notification.
I want to respond to the invite,
and I can't say if I want
So what we would like to do
but also two buttons
or decline the invitation.
Something like this.
Would that work?
Well, there's no new API to do
because it already exists.
You can use the existing UIKit
to add your own custom into the
[ Applause ]
To do that, the first thing
that your controller can
This tells both the UIKit
of the responder chain and
that you don't want the
Then you create your own
in this case, like mine,
there was a text
And then when I receive
the comment action
I can make it first responder
and the keyboard appears.
I need to do both calls here
because the first one makes a
So the text field appears,
and the second one makes the
so that the keyboard appears.
You notice that in this case, I
in the fact that it's a
You can use regular
to get the text from the user
So I have access to that UI.
And the result of this is
now you can type your response
and actually respond
So this was all for
There are some other small bits
and talk to us at the labs
And what we learned today is how
in Notification Content
We learned how to download and
by using a service extension.
We learned how to do
with your specialized content
that can use media attachments
For more information
there's a special
We had a session earlier today
up to learn about the new
and more details about
Thank you.