[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone and welcome
to Engineering Privacy
I am Julien from
and I'm super excited
Do you ever wonder how
without creeping them out?
Do you ever argue with your
and transparency to others
Well to answer these questions
through privacy technologies
and how you can adopt them too.
As many of you know we at Apple
Just last year Tim Cook quote.
"People have entrusted us with
We owe them nothing less
that we can possibly provide."
I mean it's not just Tim, all
down believe that privacy is
In order to build
that protects your data.
So privacy engineering, we're a
across Apple in order to build
And year after year we
and services are those
without compromising
They are great services
and also respect user privacy.
They encourage users
by offering transparency,
but also securing the
that you collect and limiting
As more and more
on our devices, we believe
that privacy is becoming
and it's worth your investment.
But privacy is also more
as they said here,
to do smarter engineering.
To consider other
for the benefits of our users.
For example, it encourages
to bring the intelligence
for faster user experience and
So it encourages you to only
in order to improve
So today we're going to
how to collect data tied
which kind of controls
to your users, as well as
to build privacy into your app.
Let's start with identifiers.
Many of you every day rely on
to know your users and analyze
And this is great, after
with good identifiers.
But, if you track everything
it creates an uncomfortable
sort of a chilling effect
if I tap on this link
to be tracked back to me?
And as soon as your users
Identifiers are very
to build customized
to know your users and offer
But if you use them for too long
to build creepy suggestions that
Identifiers are also super
and to prevent and
as early as possible.
But they do not justify
from all your users.
So what can you do?
Well there are a number of best
First of all, favor
You don't systematically
of persistent identifiers
So you can make them change
or make it very easy
Stick to random identifiers
and systematically using
email address, or phone number.
Most of the time
And ask yourself do I really
or is it enough to have
an anonymous experience
By following some of these
to make it very easy for your
without having to worry
So let's have a look
In our own products we seek to
So for example in Spotlight
that change periodically
so users can engage with
to worry about their privacy.
We customize the experience
within those session where
We also seek to make it easy to
So for example, in Siri, it's as
and on and you get a new
over again, you're in control.
We also generally seek to
because most of the time
to provide our services.
We also want to make it easy
of techniques and
So we have a number of APIs
very easily generate
So for example, the universally
a simple line of code
to create an identifier
So a quick example, if you call,
whenever you call this
random numbers.
It's such a large
to be a globally unique random
So if you call it again,
call it again etcetera.
So then it's up to you
with this random number.
You can use it to identify
But what if you're looking
you're not looking to
but you want to access one.
Well the vender IDs
The problem it solves for you is
that it can just access this
for a device, it's very easy
you don't even have to
And the way it works is
for a certain app,
you will get the same
to you, the same UUID.
So if you have the two
made by the same vendor,
and this just makes
to customize your
Now, an app from a different
UUID altogether.
Note that users have
by uninstalling your apps.
Another stable identifier
by the operating system
This one is to be used for
and the way it works is
it will be able to
for the current device.
And so this number will
unless the user decides to reset
So in summary there are a
and each have a different
about generating an identifier
or accessing identifier
In addition to identifiers
there are network identifiers.
So whenever you scan in
to a Wi-Fi network, you reveal
to see and that can be a
So in iOS 8 we changed
so that we start using locally
that change over time
for your privacy, you
because we make it much harder
And we're very glad and proud
on iOS, but on macOS as well.
So if you're a Wi-Fi lender
we encourage you to not
with iOS seeds, but
You must have heard of messages
This is a super cool feature
So app extensions will not be
what they will see is
And that UUID will be different
for each app extension
So it's super privacy friendly.
Now, even if you're
or generate identifiers, you
that looks innocuous.
But the problem there is that
you might actually end
and stable device fingerprint
And that can be a problem
Where you thought your
and then some researchers
that actually it was very easy
So you don't want to be in that
to minimize the data
And we also try to
We seek to build a strong and
and your app from
and also protects you from
So what we do there is we
and amazing APIs
but we provide a protection
that could be used
So for example, this year
and we also whitelisted some
for you and blacklisted
that could be used
So in summary what does
Identifiers are great,
that you favor short-lived
and that you also stick to OS
or generate identifiers.
We think that the users will
with your app and to
So talking about data, let's
Many of you every day
And this is very helpful to
to product development.
And this is super cool.
Now one day, you may end up in a
so much about your
about them then they
And that's weird.
So ask yourselves how would you
that you had about them?
Would you feel embarrassed?
What if you had to collect
or your mom, or your siblings?
Data is as much a
And you need to balance
So what can you do?
We recommend you put in
collection practices.
And in particular, instead of
just grabbing everything you can
in the future, try to stick
and collect data for those.
Here is a number of techniques
Bucketing, sampling
Let's look at bucketing.
The idea of bucketing is to
that is sufficient
So, let's say you
how often are your users
So we ask this question
So it's quite simple, you
and you look and you measure.
So let's say for this user,
on a given day to
So this information is helpful
that maybe something is wrong
Maybe you want to make
But do you really
with this level of precision?
Would it be sufficient to only
to your in-app settings
That would also give
that maybe there's
and to further refine
But what if you're
not just about a specific user,
Well, you can just collect
and ask the same
And so you will say how often
on a given day?
Well it turns out like
to collect the average
to collect this data from
to get good statistically
of the average.
It turns out if you only collect
you get a good estimate
In fact, if you collect
your estimate is as
So you really don't need to
from all of your users
of performance indicator
But what if you're looking
to collect some data
Something that you really
in the first place.
But you're interested to learn
Well, what if there was a
to learn from the crowd while
Well there is such a technology
and it's called differential
So, differential privacy
for users to donate their data.
It is one way to learn
protecting individuals.
It provides strong
and mathematical
And this year we are
So, before I get
First, we believe that
in our privacy toolbox.
We have a number of tools
and this is a very exciting
Second, this is going
into a fascinating
to inspire you and get
So let's get started.
I said it gives you strong
So let's start with
No, I think we can try to do it
So the idea is there's some
and you add noise to it and
And then you can aggregate
to extract some signal.
So let's say an example, how
to prepare these slides.
So it was a busy week, so
So, I can add noise to that and
that I change this number to
So let's look a little bit more
So, disclaimer this is
but that's going to give you
So I have this number 128, and
it's sort of a hash
So what I do is a print a
and I only write one
So it's a huge vector full
Then by noise, what I mean
of these zeros and
So some zeros are
And some ones are
The trick here is that zeros
to remain zeros than
And ones have slightly
to remain ones than
So this is one way to
to sharing it with Apple.
It's another thing that's an
is that if I were to
even if it's the same number,
each time it will give
And unlike a typical hash
to do a dictionary
out what this value
So this is all done
So, this is all done
to sharing it with Apple.
So, in this example let's
of hours people worked
so I worked 128 hours, Jessie
So we collect all of this
and the noise is added
And what Apple ends up
and noisy vectors,
where individually these vectors
But we're able to combine them
out and learn some
For example, here the average
at Apple last week was 41 hours.
So the way we do that
up all these vectors
And then we look at column
by column whether there is a
that is larger than random.
So why is this cool?
So we think it's really
to learn popular
You can learn averages, the
or even frequencies
And this is done in a way
where each individual
Is kept private from Apple.
We can only learn
But you might ask yourself what
that is contributing data here?
At some point maybe a user will
Well, to avoid this
of privacy budget that restricts
that can be made by any certain
We also don't have any
with this information.
And we permanently delete
So let's have a look
Say we wanted to learn
that are opting in to
that we collect from customers.
So when people will start
and use emoji's we will
and then Julien here,
which contributed their
on device prior to
And what happens is as more and
we're able to extract
which ones are the most popular.
So what's cool here is that one
UI to reflect that.
And we can come and do
And so this year we're
in four types of use cases.
We're using it for
we're also using
So when we learn
in our local dictionary,
We also use it for
which Deeplinks are
to promote them in Spotlight
So this is super exciting.
And we're looking forward to
But this is only collected
in into diagnostic and usage.
So if you are not opted
we're not collecting
So you are in control.
So in summary what does
Well we think that differential
technology in order
to do privacy friendly
We're very excited to adopt
to do crowd-driven insight
We don't use any identifiers,
we don't collect any
This is yet another tool
And we hope to use it more and
to build our future features.
We think that your
because they will see the length
in order to protect
So we hope this is
to develop privacy
In order to speak to
I'd like to invite
Thank you [applause].
&gt;&gt; Hi.
I'm Jessie.
I'm also on the privacy
I work on privacy on for
photos, and education.
So Julien went into great
about how you can identify your
about them in order to
but in a privacy friendly way.
So in addition to that it's
to your users about
and the data that you collect.
When you do they have
of their privacy
And when users have that
you gain their trust and you
within your app.
So one way that we're increasing
with advertising in iOS 10.
So now in news and in the
to see this blue Ad button
When they click on it
about why they're
So when you and other developers
you pick specific
to target your advertisements
Well now users are able to
to see exactly what,
into for this advertisement.
In addition, users can also
Advertising, View
And we are being completely
About all the user data we
as advertisements in news
And this will be
So a way that we give users
through Limit Ad Tracking.
So, as Julien talked
about earlier we have the
and you can use this
for advertising purposes
When users toggle the
this is signaling to us that
for advertising purposes.
So in iOS 10 we're taking
So when a user enables Limit
identifier becomes
It is now technically
that when a user enables
we cannot track them using
Now if a user disables
your app can get access to
So you may be wondering, can
to users with Limit
Well of course you can.
You can show contextual
Things that make
You just cannot track them
if they have Limit
And remember that it forbidden
to cache the advertising
as this does not give
over resetting it.
So, what does this
Well, there's an increase in
to users in news
and Limit Ad Tracking is now
We know that when users are able
like enabling Limit Ad
to make good privacy decisions
Another way that we give users
of decisions are
So in iOS, macOS, tvOS, and
to decide which apps get access
to certain protected
Now protected classes of data
contacts, photos, HomeKit.
So the first time that
to this protected class
iOS shows an alert
And at this point the user
if your app should
When the timing and the context
the user can make the choice
We call this a just
I want to talk to you
that we have this year, that
and consent alerts
The first is the media
This give access to Apple
subscriber store front,
and now reading from
We know that users'
and Apple Music subscription
personal and can be identifying.
So we want users to have
which apps get access
Now if your app got access to
you will continue to
So how do you know if
Well with most of
of data we have what's called
It has a little bit
with each protected
But this is the example
So you can call this API and get
If you see notDetermined
from one of two reasons.
Either one, you haven't asked
for access to this
but since then the user has
If you see denied, this means
They do not want your
to a certain protected
And at this point you
You can take the user down a
and show them all the
without giving you access to
Or, you can open up the
And at this point the user
decision if they so choose.
Now if you see restricted,
for one of two reasons.
Either one, there's a parental
saying that your app cannot get
of data, or two, this
maybe it's in an education mode,
And the device administrator
that your app cannot get access
And of course if you see
So we have some other
that also have privacy settings.
Another one is speech
So this allows your app to
to be transcribed into text.
Now the reason that we want
to decide which apps get
because we want them
that if they grant your app
files that are theirs
to be transcribed
You can request access to this
We also have SiriKit.
This is really exciting.
Users can now make
that are completed
But in order for Siri
of request a user might make,
up contextual information
about the user, and
And we want users to have
which apps send up this
about them and which don't.
So you need to request
before any Siri requests
And you can do this using the
You also probably heard
about the TV Provider
Now, this allows
to request access to a user's
and sign them into
Now, because this is
reach out to your WWDR partner
in becoming one of these apps.
And everything you loved about
as well, and same with HomeKit.
And both of those also have
So, in addition to these
we also have some updates to
to certain protected
So in 2014, we started requiring
to location to declare
and to declare a purpose string.
We find that users
to make the choice
when they understand why an
So, in iOS 10 we
to all protected
So if your app is accessing
of data you will need to
in your app's info
and meaningful purpose string.
So take a moment,
Think is my app accessing any of
How many of your apps
Yeah. How about two or three?
Okay well you're going to need
in your app's info plist.
And if you're a tvOS developer,
of data are available for
And you'll also need to
in your aps info plist.
Now, I'm going to
of the purpose string
key names that you'll need to
Now, you don't need to
Because they'll be
in the development
So, let's say you have the
The first time a user downloads
through the various features
And then the first
and add their first disco
when it makes sense, your app
When the timing and the context
the user will see the
And at this point you have
and meaningful purpose string
I'm going to show you now how
string using Xcode.
So you go to your app's
custom iOS target
In this case we're going
to choose privacy
And at this point we're
and meaningful purpose string.
So we're going to put
to create disco light
When the context and
the user now sees why we
And they're more likely to
for them.
So, what's going to
if you don't declare
Well your app's going to crash.
So, to preserve privacy any
that attempts to request access
of data must declare so ahead of
If you don't, your
So, your user will just see
But this is the error that you
It will tell you exactly
of data you tried to access
to go add to your info plist.
Now, the reason that we crash
that your app was compromised
for your app to request access
we do not want your
to any data you did
And remember your
for any third party libraries
So be mindful that when
that they do not breech
So what does this
Well there's some awesome new
And they also have
You need to declare it ahead
to request access to a
in your app's info plist.
And having a clear
and meaningful purpose
better decisions.
So in addition to these
we also have some changes
to help you build in privacy
So first I want to talk about
You can now set the expiration
to any values you put
Setting the expiration time
on the pasteboard
after that date,
And setting the local
will exclude those values
So here's an example, in
that we're going to
along with the string
We're going to set
to 120 seconds from now.
And we're going to set the
So in two minutes, this
on the pasteboard.
And, these values cannot
universal clipboard.
So why would you
Well, if you know for a fact
that a user is copying
such as a password or a phone
and you don't think it should be
set the expiration time.
And if you don't think it's
to be used in universal
set the local only
We've made a couple more
The first is that all named
to non-persistent and
of a pasteboard will cause
In addition, trying
of the find pasteboard will
with no value.
And we really want
to use shared containers
when you're trying to share
on the same device that are
It's a much more
than putting items
So a lot of your apps also
And we have a couple of
about today as well when you're
into your app.
The first is that every
in an NSUserActivity
You don't want to flood the
that don't make sense
Only really significant
to go look back for later.
And do not set eligibleFor
if the data is sensitive
You also probably heard
for widgets in iOS 10.
So when a user enables
on the home screen,
So because of this,
about some best practices.
Things that you can do when
to remember that they're also
So the first is that you
of data you put in your widget.
If you don't think
on the lock screen, don't
or engineer a way for
when it's on the lock screen.
Make sure that the data is
So when I enable
do I expect to see
How about a month from now?
It's okay if it's not
but I should understand what
And remember that its data
that is file protection
will not be available
So I want to show you an example
with the Find My Friends widget.
On the lock screen the
We know that the location
of your friends is
and should not be
So we have a string that
And the location is not there.
Then once I use touch ID
to unlock my device,
Consider doing something like
of the data in your
So Julien and I talked
of different things today.
We started out by
The real root of how
within your app.
And how you should favor
and OS provided identifiers.
And we talked about how when
to build your features
in privacy friendly ways
or using new technology such
And how when you give users
over those identifiers and
and you encourage
And that when you let
about their privacy
to make good privacy decisions
And of course we showed you
and some great tools to
into your app from
For more information about
web page.
Here are some related
to check out this week.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]