[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
Thank you for coming.
Welcome. My name is Dennis
of the HomeKit engineering
So before we get started
we'll spend the first couple of
and I want to highlight
of what makes HomeKit.
HomeKit is a framework which
that allow your applications
of HomeKit enabled accessories.
Your applications can use
with accessories from
HomeKit maintains the user's
Now this is great
in the system have access
and configuration
And if the user has multiple
in to the same iCloud
of synchronizing this home data
that the user may have.
Now this is great because
up on the user's part, the
of their devices and
with the HomeKit accessories.
HomeKit also supports for
So a user can share their
and friends also to
that the user has
Sharing is very simple.
All that a user has to do is
their iCloud account, and once
HomeKit automatically takes
across to additional
as configuring all the
so that now the shared
and control these accessories.
The owner, of course, can
at any point in time.
HomeKit supports a common
to securely communicate
So all HomeKit accessories,
of their underlying
use the same common protocol.
Now all this protocol Apple
of profiles which describe
Now with this profiles,
This is great and it provides
to communicate and control their
When the user is at
between their Apple device
and their HomeKit enabled
So all that a user need is their
and their Apple device to
This communication
or Bluetooth low energy.
When the user is away from
to their accessories at home
which acts as a remote
And Apple TV then securely
between the user's device
and their accessories,
Security. We have built
in mind right from day one.
All HomeKit communications
What this means is
to secure this communication
on the user's devices.
So even if the communication
through intermediate
they cannot be decrypted.
Not even by Apple.
HomeKit provides for
as perfect forward secrecy.
What this means is every
between an Apple user's device
and their HomeKit
user's new session keys
for that session, and after
these keys are then discarded.
Now this is great because
of the device is compromised and
that then cannot be used to
that would have happened
Home data is private.
We take care of privacy
as applications have to
to get access to
HomeKit supports a
Working with our accessory
of accessories in
and many of our partners
and exciting classes
to the HomeKit ecosystem.
So that was a very
With that background,
with what's new in HomeKit.
So we're going to cover
First, platform.
We are expanding
through Apple's platform
We are introducing support
of accessories in this release.
And all this new
as several enhancements
to your applications via
and we will cover
First, on platform,
to deliver an Apple app
The home app provides a very
to control their
as configure their
It also enables users
that they have in their home.
Home app is supported on all
looks beautiful on an iPad,
home app is also supported
We think this is going to be a
Not only that, we are also
into the system.
Now HomeKit is also available
So the user can configure
and can have control of the
to [inaudible] directly
Second on platform is remote
With tvOS 10, we are extending
on the Apple TV so that in
now the Apple TV runs
that the user has set
[ Applause ]
Yeah, that's great because now
the virtual part of the world,
that all the automations now run
from their Apple
Apple TV also enables
for additional controls
Now it is also possible now
to grant administrative
So a shared user with an
configurations in the home.
So they can add or remove
or they, in turn, can also
to the home and give
of the accessories at home.
Now it is also possible to
So it is possible to grant or
to your accessories at home
It's the same set
of functionality is now
Not only that, if
of these remote access
in their home, like in this
or any combination
they will automatically
and extend the HomeKit
And to communicate
they will automatically select
No additional configuration
This is all just
Third update on platform
We are thrilled to bring the
[ Applause ]
Now with the HomeKit
your applications can
control the accessories
as execute scenes
This also means that
for HomeKit on the Apple TV.
[ Applause ]
So directly from your
you can control your
So those were the major
Let's just quickly recap.
First, home app.
An Apple-designed app for
up of accessories as well as
of the accessories very easy.
Second, remote access
We're extending the capabilities
so that it now runs automation,
and it also enables additional
And the same capability is
And, third, on tvOS, we're
So we are really thrilled
to bring these capabilities
The second area we will
First on new accessories, we
of air treatment accessories
So now HomeKit can support
air purifiers as
This is great because our users
which are also HomeKit enabled
in their home and add it
to their automations
Next, we are really thrilled to
of camera accessories
[ Applause ]
Now with camera accessories,
your applications can
from the camera.
Display take and display
Control all the settings
as control the speaker
Third, doorbells.
Now doorbell is a
It generates and events once
Also the doorbell has control
where it can control the volume
and also if the doorbell has
those can also be controlled
Now doorbells we are
with other kinds of accessories.
So doorbell camera
Now this configuration is
Not only are these powerful
by HomeKit, we are also tightly
into the system.
So now, for example, if you
and a camera which are
to be part of a room, maybe
entryway, HomeKit will
from these different
and they can provide
to the user.
This enables for some
like rich notifications.
So, for example, now here,
HomeKit will automatically take
and the user is presented
Also, there are controls
where the user can press,
and start an audio session
so chooses, unlock the door,
and the notification
from the camera.
And, yes, the same
on the Apple Watch.
And, yes, touching on the,
on the picture there will
from your HomeKit camera
And, yeah, you can unlock
directly from the Apple Watch.
Next, let's look at the updates
So we'll start off first
but very powerful
to the framework that
about the accessory
First up is primary service.
Now this is an example
which has two services - a fan
So this is what your
Now just by looking
it is not clear what the user
Is this a light with an
which also has a light?
Now, with update to
the accessory can mark
and this is available back
to your application using
on the HMService class.
Now this will be great for you
because now you can show
about the accessory
Second example is
Here's another example where
services and a switch service.
Now, again, by just
it is not clear what
Does the switch control
or any other combination
When a user looks
it is clear that that switch
Now with linked services,
with each other and communicate
to HomeKit, and this is
So in this case, the
to these three outlets
relationship that the switch has
in controlling these
So now for your users, when
at your UI, which is
you can now additionally
whether it is powered on
that it is linked
Third is valid values.
To explain valid values, let's
to build an accessory.
Let's say we're building an
and as we're building
we want to incorporate the
for this accessory.
So we will pick a target and
So this is how it is
Now the air conditioner that we
let's say, heating.
So the heat and the auto
for my configuration.
Now it is possible for
in Apple-defined characteristics
for its configuration.
So in this case, the accessory
as not supported, and this
available back to
through the
values property.
Now you can show controls
to that particular
Next, setting up of
Today, to set up a
which is probably the first
involves a few different steps.
First, you will start
and once a new accessory is
of your Wi-Fi network, or if
which is in range,
to you via the accessory
delegate callback.
And once you have
you can then call the add
to start adding this
But for Wi-Fi accessories
of the user's Wi-Fi
you need to do some
to get these accessories
into the user's Wi-Fi network.
You do that today using
So there are some additional
We thought we can do better.
So now in iOS 10, we
add and set up accessories
of all the steps
to configure the accessory
So on calling this method,
the user is guided
to select the accessory.
So in this case here, it's
as well as accessory,
that are part of
The user can select the
and once it is selected,
of the user's Wi-Fi network,
it is added to the user's
Then the HomeKit
and HomeKit pairing is
and then the user is prompted
select a room for the accessory.
And also in this case,
which is generally
the user is also prompt
of accessory is connected
So in our example here,
is being connected to a fan.
So we select the fan as
for this accessory,
the user can also choose to
of their favorites, and using,
doing that enables this
of their control
So that's it.
Just one simple API,
through this complete
And now all applications
consistent experience.
We think this is going to
and we really encourage all of
[ Applause ]
Next, let's talk about
So a camera is a rich
It has many different
So rather than exposing all the
to your app, we are providing
to take advantage of
with cameraProfile objects.
A profile is nothing but a
that describe a general
So cameraProfile objects
that is needed for you to
So on an accessory, you can
from the cameraProfile
An accessory can
and those are all
So it will be one
in this cameraProfile array.
Let's look at what a
A cameraProfile provides
that allow you to control
So you can display and
which is both the audio and
display, take and display
control all the settings
as control the speaker
and microphone settings
Let's look at the
that provides these interfaces.
First is stream control.
Let's look at HMStreamControl.
So HMStreamControl provides
that allow you to start
from the camera.
So you call the startStream
to start a live stream
Once the stream starts,
to you using the
So once a stream starts,
the camera stream control
that the stream has started.
Similarly, to stop the stream,
and, again, using the same
to you via the camera
with error delegate callback.
Once the stream is started,
to the stream using via
Let's look at what the
The cameraStream
and the video parts
So on the cameraStream class,
you have additional controls
audio settings from
So using this, you can
or fully allow incoming audio
or allow bidirectional
Now that you have a stream,
Well, you would like to
How do you do that?
It's simple.
On iOS 10 and tvOS
to do is create a HMCameraView.
And to the view and on the
the camera source, and you
that you just got when
to this property.
That's it.
All that is needed for your app
to show live stream
It's very similar on watch OS.
You just create an
and call the setCameraSource
to show live stream
So those were a few different
to control your camera
but in reality, it's
Let's look at an example call.
So first we get to our
and in this case, we're just
that is there, and on the
we call the startStream method
which will start
And to display our stream,
and once our stream is started,
it's informed back via
cameraStreamControl
and all that we need to do here
to the camera source
That's it.
Now your view in your
stream from the camera.
Next, let's look
Snapshot control interfaces
to what we saw with
So for snapshotControl we
which once a snapshot
to you via the
snapshot method callback.
And the most recent snapshot
in this most recent
Let's look at the
The SnapshotControl has
which will show you
of when this snapshot
It has both the time and date.
And, again, similarly,
into a view, all that you
and assign it to this snapshot.
So here's an example to take
and display a snapshot
It's very similar, core
First we get to our
On this cameraProfile's
we call the takeSnapshot method.
We create a view to
and once a delegate is
with a reference
We just take that and assign it
to the camera's source
That's it.
That's all you need to show
Next, let's look
So settingControl gives you HM
to control all the settings that
So you have interfaces to
zoom, rotation, and
So if the cameraSupport does
then that property will be nil.
Otherwise, you have full access
of this camera from your app.
Last, we'll look at camera
to control both the speaker
and microphone settings
Again, these are also
which will allow you to
on the microphone, change the
control the gain
or control the speaker volume.
So those are all the key API's
to take advantage of
So let's summarize.
We covered three major areas.
First, platform.
We're bringing the home app, an
For remote access
We're extending the capabilities
as adding iPad to
and automation capability
We're bringing HomeKit
Next area on accessories,
of air treatment accessories.
We're adding powerful
to the HomeKit ecosystem.
And we're also adding doorbells
which are doorbell cameras.
On the framework
but powerful capabilities that
about your accessory
So you can show rich
and context-sensitive
We have greatly simplified
Now with just one API call,
all apps get the consistent
through the complete setup for,
And we introduced cam,
that allow your applications
of this powerful
Now before I conclude, I want
HomeKit accessories and your
way that our users
With system features like Siri,
also combined with the rich
on Apple platforms like
these accessories are,
becoming accessible to users
with various kinds
This is powerful, and it is
for many of our users.
So I encourage you to check out
that are available to
and take full advantage
and applications
For our MFi program members,
a preview of the updated
available to you soon, and for
who'd like to join the program,
this URL gives you more
and talk to one of us.
More information about this
and references are
These are some related sessions
on video if you have
The first one is
Thank you very much.
Have a great conference.
[ Applause ]