[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Thanks for coming
This is NSURLSession: New
My name is Jeff Jenkins.
I'm a Software Engineer
in the Internet Technologies
I think we have some great
like to share with you today
So why don't we just get started
and show you some of the
The NSURLSession API provides
and methods that
of modern day networking.
Today I'm going to discuss
with you how the
And I'm going to share
and enhancements that
And we're going to have a
some of these features and
I'll spend some time
It's important for your
and privacy be safeguarded.
If it's important to your users,
and to your applications.
So I'm going to share
of the enhancements we've made
with regards to use security.
Now, during the entirety of this
with you some best
so that you can make your
Now, let's start by looking at
to applications across
For many years, Foundation
NSURLConnection API.
Now, NSURLConnection was a
It enabled a lot of great
functionality for you
But you know, we
What could we do better?
And what is it that you
And we sat down and
And we found that a lot
with configuring networking --
that configuring network
especially if you need
of networking all from
So, we took action.
We officially deprecated the
And this really means we're not
And it's really receiving
But prior to the official
we introduced NSURLSession
for Foundation layer networking.
Now, we encouraged you then, we
to move your networking
in your applications today
to be developing in the future.
Now, since NSURLSession
for network programming
let's review some of the
Now, if you want a real
inside into NSURLSession, I
to WWDC of 2015, and
at the videos and slides
with the sessions
So, I've been praising
and recommending that
So what really makes
of all this praise?
Well, some of the benefits,
for the HTTP/1.1 protocol.
We also have support
Now, we don't recommend that
on SPDY, but really
to HTTP/2 and that protocol.
We obviously have support
Our support is based
And we're adding new features
The app transport
This is a great feature
It's a security feature
and data integrity
between apps and Web processes.
One of the most important
that your apps must
Now, at the same time it
to implement best practices
to remote servers
The HTTP Strict Transport
another great feature
This feature protects your
Now, it can be configured
from your Web service.
Or it can be configured using
in the system along
Once configured, all the data
received over a secure
The great thing about HSTS is
changes in your applications.
All the great built-in
in for the handling of
authentication challenges,
all these things are
And last but not
As I said, we talked a lot
or configuring networking
We feel that we need to have
So, we looked at
So what we did to achieve
over your networking
we created this new class called
Now, this class contains
that you can configure.
You can create configurations
on different networking needs
Now, here's a sample of
that you can set with
The Transport Layer
You can control the minimum
that your app wants to support.
We default the minimum TLS to
You can control the use of
Do you want to let your app
Maybe you want Wi-Fi
This is the place to do that.
You can specify your
Some examples of this
which is the standard
Your app might have VoiP control
All sorts of different
And really, this is just a
of what type of data to expect
of service that's
on the device that
Cookie policy.
Now, maybe you want your
or a persistent cookies.
This is the place to
Similar for cache.
Maybe you want an
persistent cache that's
This is a place to
You can also specify
Well, maybe you want to share
of networking or cookies between
all within your same app.
This is a place that you
for that configuration.
And time-out specifiers.
You can set resource
so that your app can handle
Now, I expect many of
to NSURLSession API.
If not, really, go
at the WWDC 2014
You're going to get a lot
on how that API works.
But I think for us in the
it's good for us to take a
from a code perspective.
So very simply, the first
to create a configuration
First thing we do.
Here we call
.defaultSessionConfiguration.
We take all the defaults
and we've got a very
Now, we take that config
We create a session by
that takes a config object.
And boom! We've got a very
Now that we've got this session,
Now, the first thing we're
and specify what's the
to retrieve or request
Once we have that,
Here we call the
And we pass the NSURL object
that we created to
We also provide a closure.
Now, this closure is
when our task is
and the requested
Now always, don't forget, make
All of our tasks are
So you must call task.resume
All right.
So in review, very
NSURLSession is really
First you're going to create
Once you have that config you're
And now you're ready with that
and you're going to create
Now, I want to suggest to
Want to make sure that
to one-session model.
You should really not set
Really, what you want
to design this is have
many tasks.
So of course, you can
But avoid the one-session
And the reason for that,
it really boils down
You're going to get
and OS resource utilization
by having few sessions
Now, as I mentioned, the
I'd like to talk about
and what we've been doing
in this protocol
Now, the support of
within the NSURLSession was
And it's increasing
You know, large Internet service
Now, what makes HTTP/2
Well, let's look at
One of the great features
and concurrency support.
Now, this feature allows
to be in flight concurrently.
Responses can be received
on the same single
Another great feature of the
This reduces the size
It cuts down on network
This is better for
for performance for
Another great feature
As a client of HTTP/2 you
at which resources are
And this really allows
and tune the networking
So in essence, HTTP/2 is
Now, this will result in an
as they interact with your apps.
Now, there's one more
to take a look at of HTTP/2.
Today we're introducing
for HTTP/2's Server
[ Applause ]
So what is Server Push?
Well, when a client
a server will respond
But concurrently, it can
to the client.
So if you think about a Web
and lots of resources.
Instead of the client having to
over the network, a server can,
in parallel to the original
about additional resources
So, Server Push prevents
that HTTP/1.1 and non-Server
Now, I want to bring to
that the server obviously
has to support HTTP/2 and
to enable the Server
Now, Server Push is
that use NSURLSession.
There's no need to opt in.
No funny properties
It's just there.
And it just works.
So this is all more
that NSURLSession
for your applications today.
Now, let's take a minute here
about how Server Push
Here I've got a graph that
of NSURLSession using
to do some network loading.
Now, as we move down this graph,
we're going to accumulate
And this will be
for our network loading
So, first our app is
And that task is going
We'll assume that
because networks just do that.
And we're going to get our
with the requested data.
Now, in addition to the
we note that time has passed.
And that our total latency has
Now, our app is going
and request style.css
And again, assuming
we're going to get
And now we have style.css
and our total latency has now
to fetch that resource
Here the application will
and request background.jpg.
We get the response
And here we've got
Our application is now finished
And we look at the graph,
we see this is our total latency
Now, let's take a look at our
to use HTTP/2 and Server Push.
And I'm just going to shift
over to the side
So again, our app will resume
Again, our total latency,
And our total latency is pretty
for the non-Server Push case.
That's expected.
What will happen, however,
to our response for
the server will push other
Now, this comes along with the
from the original request.
When our application
and requests style.css we get
And this is because Server
really knew we needed it.
Now we have style.css and we
for style.css is substantially
to the HTTP/1.1 needed to
Now the app makes
and requests background.jpg.
Again, we get a real
The app has background.jpg.
And we add the total time
At this point the app is done
And we see that the HTTP/2
with Server Push latency is much
or the non-Server Push load.
The reason for this
that with Server Push we were
of network round trips needed
Now, I'd like to
to show us what Server
like in a real application.
Andreas.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jeff.
Good morning everyone.
Today I'm going to
of using HTTP/2 Server Push when
You are looking at the very
of you may already
or at least have seen while
What you see now could
for photographers showing
where you can list the
for a certain photographer.
View the individual pictures.
Go to the next.
Go back. Go back
Choose another one to view.
And so on.
This app could be
or a music streaming app
So an app which is loading
In this case, it is loading
Now notice here for demo
It allows us to choose
with Server Push configured
In both cases, first we request
the image URLs to load.
Then we request the images.
If the Server Push is off,
So we need to send the requests
for every image over
In case of the Server Push,
to this mode, as Jeff explained
of the initial document
of the resources from the
There will be no need
for every image over
The data for your data
out of the Server Push storage
Now, let's compare the
and non-Server Push loads.
I'm going to switch between the
and non-Server Push a couple
when the Server Push is on,
this entire collection
But how much faster?
Well, let me show you that.
Now the demo application is
It's the bottom of
For the fastest non-Server
And for the fastest
Let me do it a couple of times.
Now the same with
A couple of times.
Server Push off.
Server Push on.
You can see here that
at least two times faster.
Pushing the images is about
than loading them on the high
using here.
The kind of network your
when on cellular or slow Wi-Fi.
I prepared a video showing
and non-Server Push
Well, let me show you that.
So, you can see when the Server
pictures, the other guy is just
Let's see it one more time.
Once again, the Server Push
through much faster than
on the left.
Two to three times faster.
Just think about it.
Think about the user experience
if you configure the Server
And you don't even have to
And this is great.
Just awesome.
This was the Server Push demo.
Thank you very much.
Have a great conference.
And now, back to Jeff.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, thanks, Andreas.
So let's summarize
and discussed regarding
Server Push is supported
So if you're writing new apps
we highly recommend that you
There's no coding
to take advantage
It's not an opt-in.
It just works.
And with Server Push
in the most optimal manner,
giving your users an
with your applications.
Now, another evolution to the
of Network Statistics.
Now, who out here
We have any statistic people?
We got some folks
All right, I've got
Are you ready?
Here it is.
All right.
Right. Sorry about that.
Sorry. We're going to get to
And this is, we believe,
of that 2% useful values.
So, why is it useful?
Have you ever had slow
in your applications?
Imagine some of you have.
And how did you go about
You know, how did
We believe network statistics is
to be able to use
and debugging environment.
You could use this to
possibly out in the field.
Maybe you could leverage
and collect some information
about your app running
Network statistics is
of network loading
It's about finding and fixing
And it's about giving
of what your networking is doing
Currently, network
macOS and on tvOS platforms.
Now, before we get started with
let me explain to you how you're
And to do this, we need to
Here we have a brand
didFinishCollecting metrics.
This is a delegate method
of the NSURLSession
Now, when you implement
it's going to be passed a task
for which the metrics
and a new class object.
This is NSURLSessionTaskMetrics.
The NSURLSessionTaskMetrics
named taskInterval.
This is the interval of
to the point in time when all
and are ready to be delivered
to your
delegate.
Another property I'm showing
Now, that's fairly
And as the name indicates,
that an HTTP redirection
task's execution.
The last property
of NSURLSessionTaskMetrics
Now, this property
This is the meat of
This is where you get an array
of NSURLTaskTransactionMetric
Now, let's take a closer look
because this is really
of the great metrics
Now, in order to understand
we're going to chop them
Now, the first two properties of
up the first category.
And I'm going to call
There's two properties here
And they really allow you
to analyze what was
And what was the response
The second category of
with protocol and connection.
The property networkProtocolName
it tells you what type
of protocol was used
at which statistics
And here's a possible list
HTTP/1.1, HTTP/2, or SPDY.
Now, this list can and
Another property you'll
This tells you whether
or had a proxy connection
collections were gathered,
or statistics were
And the isReusedConnection.
This property is set to Yes
if a persistent connection
of the resource.
Now, the third category of
And it deals with
about the resource
The single property
Now, it tells you how a
Now, some of the values you
This indicates that the resource
as commonly referred
You might see local cache,
which indicates the resource
It was stored local
No network transaction
And Server Push.
This tells that the resource
of a Server Push cache hit
The fourth category of
with connection establishment
Now, the first group of
to the setup of a
The second group of metrics
of a network load.
These properties are timestamps
when the event actually
So let's take a closer
and when they are collected
of a network load.
To do this, we're going to look
Now note that this is just
There's all sorts of activities
that happen during
You've got cache lookups.
You've got cookie lookups.
You're dealing with
sometimes authentication
But we're going to keep
for our purposes here.
The NSURLTaskTransactionMetrics
that contain all these time
So, we begin with fetchStart.
fetchStart is a time when the
a resource.
A fetch could be satisfied
or possibly resource
So now we're looking
So the domainLookupStart
This is the time just
for a resource begins.
Now, this is the DNS query.
And this converts a host
So, domainLookupEnd is
And an IP address is
Here we're going to take a
for connection establishment.
The connectStart property is the
to start or establish
with the remote server.
Now, this value could be nil
if the response is
I'll discuss the connectEnd
If you're doing HTTPS you're
So we've got a statistic
The secureConnectionStart
the point in time just before
security handshake to secure
And secureConnectionEnd, well,
that's when the secure
It's finished.
Now, as I mentioned, connectEnd.
Now, that's the time immediately
to the remote server,
security-related handshakes.
This is the point in
considered established.
Now that we have an
we can actually do some HTTP.
So, we have a few stats
for you regarding the
So first we have requestStart.
And this is the time when
resource regardless of whether
from a local cache
If an origin load was
at which the first byte of the
requestEnd is the time
of the request was
responseStart.
This represents a time
of the response is
Now, if this is a cache load,
this is when the cache response
And responseEnd was
after the application
of the resource requested.
Now that we've been looking
at stats collected
That is, we had to send bytes
It's possible that the
satisfied from a local cache.
And I've mentioned that.
So if a local cache contains
then there's no need for DNS.
So there's no need to make
Those statistics will be set
So just be aware of that
as you're looking
Now, you might be asking,
How do I get these
So, to do that, let's
Now, as I showed you earlier,
And here I have an
of the NSURLSessionTaskDelegate.
This implements the new
delegate callback.
And the one I'm showing you
of any interest at the moment.
I totally expect
to do some really
Maybe you're going
A good point to do some
at what's happening
Again, maybe leverage Test
so you can collect some
about how the networking is
That's all up to you.
So, let's keep looking
Maybe a little bit
First thing we have to do
with our delegate implementation
of it.
Now, we're going to create a
We take all the defaults just
by calling
Next, we're going to
or we're going to create an
And we have to do that because
some queue, so that our delegate
And as I mentioned earlier,
with that configuration object.
But here I'm calling
that takes additional
And namely, those are the
object and the NSOperationQueue
So now we can actually
We create a task
And what do we want
Well, let's just simply load
And here I'm using,
And this requires a
Now, note with this closure
that our
delegate callback will be
that closure is invoked.
So, oh, and also, don't forget
Got to make sure
so that the work can
Now, this is an overly
to implement
callback and the code
I'm sure that you guys are going
to do much more interesting
with your use of Network
Now, I hope you like what you've
What do you think of those?
[ Applause ]
All right.
Now you can access information
under the hood with your
This will help you in your
to be able to get, you
and make your apps work
And tune, really tune the Web
that you're making so
in the most optimal way.
And again, this new feature is
It's a great time to
Now, in the final
to discuss a topic that's
And now, as developers,
we all care about guarding
The NSURLSession API
security features.
And I want to share with you
made to these features.
Transport Layer Security,
that protects data transmitted
So sometimes you've
This was the predecessor to TLS.
So, TLS and SSL are sometimes
TLS makes use of ciphers
Ciphers scramble
scramble data sent
And the other receiving
to unscramble that data so that
If somebody were to grab
it's just big glob of blah.
They can't use it.
So it protects the data.
Now, one of the things
and I want to make you aware of,
is that Apple's platforms no
So for more details, I recommend
review the security sessions
Possibly attend one
and ask some questions there
for a little bit
So, what this means to
is that connections
to make successfully could
And this could be due to servers
that are supporting
Now, we have a way that you can
There is a command line
And this could be used to test
that your apps communicate with.
Now, here I'm going
to grab the root
So if I execute this
I see that, hey, the
Hmm. That's funny.
I used to be able to
Let's find out if our theory
Here I've added a flag to
And that means that I am
on the client's side
So I run this.
Wow! This worked
So this proves to me that this
I'm going to have to go have
and figure out what could we
onto that server so we
within our application.
So I hope you get
The RC4 cipher is no longer
And this could affect
So just be aware of that.
App Transport Security, or ATS.
This is a great security
It allows you to set the policy,
You specify keys that
And these become your
Now, we've added two new keys
The first one is
WebContent.
So, if you have a WK Web
to that class, if you have
and you have this key present,
to make any sort of network
It'll ignore whatever other
But again, that's contained
Any loads outside of
to your security policy.
The other value we have
Transparency.
Now, this requires that certs
that your app receives must
transparency feature.
Certificate Transparency is
This allows you to use
with greater assurance that
And that you can
that gave you that certificate.
For more details on that
recommend that you take a look
or attend one of their
on Certificate Transparency.
Everything that I've discussed
We've seen this API evolve
with new features
And we're really excited to see
with your applications as
of these great new features.
I introduced support for the
This means that your
to perform even better.
I introduced Network Statistics.
Now you can introspect your
like never before.
This will result in an
for your applications.
I shared with you some
and the deprecation
Your apps can now implement
and keep your user data
Now, we hope that you
in your applications for
but for all the great features
that are inside of
If you want more information,
this is the URL for
So you can go back
of the things we
Some related sessions we think
in on this subject I've
Well, that's it.
Thank you.
Hope you have a great
[ Applause ]