[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and welcome.
I hope that everybody's
My name is Justin Stoyles,
and Media Group here at Apple.
And I'm really excited
about working with wide color.
We're going to cover
I'm going to start
with discussing some
And we'll talk a little bit
and why does it matter.
Then I'm going to hand
who's going to walk you
of getting wide color assets
And then I'm going to
who's going to talk about
So let's get started.
As I mentioned, I'm
about wide color today
because we're actually
that we handle wide color,
on the Mac and iOS platform.
A good place to start
So Apple has always
of solving the color
And a good place to
So ColorSync is our color
and it was developed in
Apple and a number of other
together with the idea that
and color reproduction
of the problems faced by
when working with color.
That group later became known
as the International
which you may be familiar with.
The work of ICC was then
and we built that
Now Apple has also been at the
We now have these
across our product line.
People really, really love them.
But what really is
Well, last year we announced
with P3 displays.
And the feedback we got
They display 25 percent
And they have the
which people really,
And if you fast forward
we have these new iPad Pro
So we've taken that
Now, there's a lot
and we're going to try to get
And I'll start with
Let's start very,
So, what is a color space?
Well a color space
in which colors can be
It can be a 1, 2, 3,
that is defined by the intensity
Those color components
to as color channels.
One representation that you
So, this is very
where your subpixels are
And to think about these
that the intensity of each
of these color channels
that you see on the other end.
There's many different
I mentioned RGB spaces, which
But there's also lots
which are used in
In color printing we
And if you're trying
and transformations, we
like LAB, which are
So now we have color spaces, and
to create a coordinate system
where we can compare
So there's the concept
So color primaries generally
that you can get with that
So in this example of an RGB
that the color primaries are
where we anchor 1.0
So for black, I would
of my color channels,
For white I would have 1, 1, 1.
And for red I would only
and I would have 1, 0, 0.
Very simple.
And when we refer to color
about all of the colors that
of those individual
So now you understand some
that we're going to be
So then what is wide color?
Well first we should
about what is the standard
So standard RGB, or sRGB is the
in computing today.
It's based on the
We use an approximated
Typical lighting conditions.
Which in this case is D65.
And it's the default
And it's actually the
for a lot of platforms.
Which is very convenient,
out there that are
and there are some that are not.
And when a lot of
in existence today is sRGB,
on your incoming content
and have it reproduce
But that's not always
sRGB does a good job of
with on a daily basis, and our
at displaying those
But really there's a lot of
A lot of textiles are
that have lots of colors
mainly because these
They're really vivid
If you're watching
a lot of the uniforms are
because they're striking,
Whether you're watching
or you're watching the
to see a lot these
that are actually not
A lot of products are
that are outside of sRGB.
And these are products that we
But really the most compelling
Sunsets, autumn leaves,
These are all things in
that are outside of sRGB.
And we actually want
And the nice thing is you
that you've taken
especially if you're
that actually contain a
but you're not seeing
if your display is only sRGB.
So what do we do about this?
Well, last year as I mentioned,
with a new color space.
And that color space
So in our iMacs, and in
we use this color space.
And it's based on the
But it's a little bit different.
DCI-P3 is a color space that is
And it works really great
But our viewing conditions
And sRGB is really great at
with our viewing conditions.
So we adopted the same gamma,
for our white point, as sRGB.
These are the key differences
In order to understand what
of sRGB, but can be
I'll try to show it
So here's an image
and I exported it using photos
This is a really
and even though we're viewing
or if you're viewing the video,
This image still looks
But there's a lot of
that you might not notice right
of colors that aren't
These are colors that are
And in this case what you
in those regions, so
on the edge of the sRGB gamut.
So how do we fix this?
Well, we're moving more
to our mobile platforms.
And in order to enable that,
it's not just putting a wide
There's a number of other things
One of those things is we need
to upgrade our factory
So, now all of our products have
that from device to
on those colors being
And then finally, we had
to build full system-wide
And that's exactly
But we can't just build the
with the same approach
There's different considerations
when working with
One of those considerations
that already exist
These are applications that are
and performance in sRGB.
So how do we make sure that
on our platforms that
without any impact
And what we did is we
So we've introduced an
This is our working space
We use the same sRGB primaries.
We use the same gamma 2.2.
The same white point.
But, the interesting
that we actually allow values
and less than zero,
to not only keep the same
of your applications that are
that are negative and
than one allow us to express any
while still keeping our
The best way to describe
So let's say I want to
in Display P3.
So that would be 1, 0, 0.
Now, if want to express
it would look a little
So in the red channel,
that is greater than one.
And in the green
I'm actually using
So I'm subtracting
and adding oversaturated red.
And what that allows me to do
of the sRGB gamut, while using
in extended range sRGB.
The interesting thing is if
that allows you to go very
this approach allows
in the visual spectrum.
So this is scalable.
Speaking of pixel formats,
sRGB is largely standardized
So 8 bits is largely enough
not perfect, but great.
Now an easy example to
between the precision that
and the precision
for wider gamut, is
So say I wanted to build
from the basement
I would use, say 8 stairs, I'd
for simplicity I would use 8.
This is the appropriate
Now, if I wanted to extend that
I wouldn't just use the
And when we're using
it makes sense that if you're
you would want to
So if we're talking about using
really our recommendation is to
Now, before I hand
I wanted to end with
So, we've gone through our
of our frameworks and
But if you're building
with open source tools,
or you've built your own
from scratch, you need to
that the tools that you've
Otherwise, we've
And for more on that, I'll
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Justin.
Hi. I'm Patrick Heynen.
I'm a Senior Engineering Manager
And I'd like to ask where
Well the answer is it turns
No, it comes from you.
Namely, it comes from
and the user experiences
that you provide in
So what kind of content types
Well the first one is the one
with and that's static
These are the sort
or individual graphic files
into your application
with your application
The next category is document
and network-based
These are individual
that you may either download
or store in your document data.
There's also further
which refers to things like
from the build-in
I'm not going to go
about wide color implications
but I refer you to the
and Editing Live Photos
for more details about that.
And lastly, there's also
If your program -- if your
at the GPU level, like your game
of graphic software, and you're
in the form of either
to the GPU directly, there
as well for wide content.
I'm not going to go into much
but I refer you to my colleague,
of this in What's
Okay. So let's frame
Justin gave a great
But how does it apply to apps?
Well app content can come from a
in a broad range
all the way from grayscale,
all the way through to even
At the same time, devices and
of color capabilities.
For example, in iPhone
of representing sRGB, all the
which does a great job
and extended range sRGB.
So, how do you bridge
Well, we're going to
And the backbone really
So, what is color management?
The job of color
that an image looks the
no matter what color
or how it was originally
That's pretty much it.
But how does it work?
Color management
or content type having an
sometimes referred
This informs the system what
And then the color matching
those colors to the
of the device that
Of course, this is a
and it is not for free.
In fact, every single
and converted and matched.
Also, it's important to
lossy operation.
Especially if you're going
down to a narrower one,
down to an sRGB 8-bit,
of color fidelity
So that's something
So these are important
The first good news is that
the way they're algorithmically
into the details of the
But it turns out
they're very easily
either by the CPU or by GPU.
Which leads to the
that we've built
into the system itself, so that
the Quartz 2D, ColorSync on
In fact, all you really
that your content is tagged
there's no code required to
and have the colors
So, platform color management.
Well, macOS, as Justin eluded
to has been color managed
Some might even say since
when it was previously
during the ColorSync times.
So there's nothing new there,
but there is something
We have, since iOS 9.3,
we now have automatic
on most devices.
So that's color management,
of solving the color problem.
But now let's talk about how
and how the toolchain and the
enhanced to accommodate
into your applications.
First, as always it
So, what is important to think
about when you're
from a design perspective?
Well, the first thing I would
to use wide gamut content
It doesn't mean everywhere,
that we interact with on a daily
within that nice sRGB triangle.
That's where the bulk
There are however, these nice,
that may make sense for
So really it's important to
as being a tool that you can use
where vivid colors really
and add some value
There is no need to go and
and immediately upgrade
This is not that kind
This is merely a new
where you want it,
And the good news is we've
to make this gradual opt-in
So let's say you do want
to wide color, what are
It's really important
when you upgrade a
A common pitfall is to
It starts out as sRB, assigning
This is a mistake, because this
color information
It's a pretty effect, but it's
Because it will just stretch
and the appearance of the design
Instead, it's important to
This will actually do a
your resulting design should
but it will be prepared
of its content boosted
vivid saturated P3 colors.
When you're working on wide
to use, and we recommend
that you use the
as your working document
Also to maintain
and highest quality
in 16-bit per channel
And of course, it's nice to
So, if you are going
with wide color it's good
on a system capable of
such as the late 2015 iMac,
When it comes time
for exporting delivering
to use 16-bit PNG files with an
This is sort of the gold
for wide color content.
Now, a brief note.
There are some very popular
out there.
They come under different names.
I'm going to talk specifically
about the Adobe Photoshop
They come under the names of
Many of these workflows
to wide color yet, and
with exporting 16-bit
So, stay away from them for now.
And instead use the workaround
with 16-bit and embedded
Okay, so that's the
and how wide color impacts that.
Now, let's talk about tools
up to incorporate the
out of the design process.
Well the first thing
and really the epicenter
of the content tool story
Now you may be familiar
This is the general tool in
and catalog your image
and provide metadata,
and deliver it inside
What do asset catalogs
Well, they're the best
for static assets.
We automatically color
and optimize it for the target
So even if, maybe your
and always can deliver their
and all the right information
but that may not
That's where this automatic
to make sure that we
into the appropriate working
Also, we do automatic
making sure that the
up in the right device.
And, last, but definitely
asset catalogs are the
which is an important component
that assures that only the
delivered to your customers on
of the content that doesn't.
So, what have we done in asset
to work with wide color content?
Well the first important
bit source content and
for 16 bit image resources.
This, we store it
but it is available
The next important thing
to catalog a display gamut.
What does this mean?
This means that you really
in the inspector to provide
for either the sRGB
display gamuts matching devices
Okay so that's the feature.
That's what Xcode has to
But how do you use it?
How do you think about using it?
Well, there's really
Choice number one, do nothing.
This may seem radical, but it is
in fact a perfectly
Because if you make no
you may not need any of
we will continue to render your
on all devices.
So nothing will change.
You don't need to go
to make sure it works
So this is a perfectly
Of course, this does mean
wide colors.
That's a perfectly
That's the outcome of
So let's say you do want
to use some wide color
Brings us to choice number two.
Upgrade to P3.
So, the way this
like to call Universal P3 Asset.
So, all it involves is taking
that you may have gotten
and just replace your existing
with this upgraded asset.
What happens at build
to automatically generate
from that 16 bit
We're going to do a
and a high quality
And then of course at
we're make sure the right
on the appropriate device.
But let's say you're
with this automatic conversion
Well the good news is we
And that's choice number
It's a very simple option.
It's basically, you provide
and your original
We provide places for
of those in the asset catalog.
And they'll get built
and thinned appropriately.
Okay, that's wide color
I'd like to now give
of creating content.
Okay, so let's say I've got
Let's say I have this
There we go.
That's much better.
And I really decided this
from some more vivid
How is this done?
Let's take a look at this here.
This is just a simple gradient
And I just want to call
in the gradient is a
Okay, that's what
So what do I do to upgrade it?
Well the first thing
because I'm an organized type,
of this and not just
I'm going to name it
And, okay now I'm ready to work.
So the first thing I'm going to
to 16 bits per channel.
Now, we're ready
And now the all-important
And what I'm going to do
to the Display P3 color profile.
Okay, now we're ready to go.
In fact, I can confirm with
Display P3, 16 bits
I'm good to go.
Okay, so now let's take a look
at what happened
And look at our favorite
Okay, so that's interesting
That green it didn't change.
Notice that the hue wheel didn't
That was actually the
as opposed to assigning.
But I'm left with
being only 70 percent saturated.
Well this really indicates just
is to punch out into
and deploy a more purer green.
So, well let's say I want to
on stage all day, I'm just going
Now everything should be
100 percent saturated, but now
in that pure P3 wide
So there we are.
Now I have my beautiful asset,
And of course this is just a
in my app until I save it.
So I'm going to do that.
I'm going to save it as, whoops
I'm going to make sure to
And save it.
And viola I'm done.
Well, actually I'm not done,
I've just finished
I haven't incorporated
So, let's go do that.
Where's my app?
There's my app.
So here's my app, unmodified.
Here's my existing
Well, what I want to do here
to the pop-up here to expose
This will immediately
of additional cataloging
And I take my P3 hue wheel
and just drop it
And I'm ready to go.
Now if I build in run, it
into my asset catalog.
And if I was running on
I would be getting the
whereas on an sRGB
I would be getting this asset.
Okay. That's incorporating
Okay so we talked about tools
and how they work
Now it's time to talk about some
and what happens after
and how it might impact the
So, with asset catalog
to ensure that the
to a given device.
And this is really important
because this is potentially a
of your application.
And, with that slicing,
we ensure that there's
for your actual end-user
for adding this wide gamut
because we make sure
wide gamut content only
sRGB content goes
And it doesn't waste
that it's not relevant for.
On the Mac, there's
NSImage has always been able to
from available representations
It's going to continue to do
of your target display.
So if you are on a wide
and you have P3 content
it's going to go
that when rendering its content.
Also, just like the behavior
on the Mac, NSImage
and all the related app
to refresh the content
when the display
Such as when your window
and the external display, or
or back end scale
So that's great.
Okay, but how is this
and what impact can that
Well the good news is that at
to optimize the pixel formats
of all your image content
And do so in as efficient
to the best of our
We do now use 16 bit
for wide color content.
I mentioned this before.
This really allows you to
precision in your
And, we also have compression.
Now this is quite handy because
More information is
to large footprint unless
Now, we've always
we've always had
Akin to what happens
But what's new this year is
to help counteract, you
The first one of these is what
Now this is a compression system
except the added bonus that it
and alpha as well.
It has a similar
and performance characteristics.
And the great news is it
on almost all, on
Just like JPEG does.
So it's something you can count
on to give a very slight
to get a really excellent
Now, new this year as well,
we have this exciting option
using ASTC.
So this stands for Advanced
which is a GPU compressed
which many modern GPUs
as other systems support.
And we have brought this
in two different forms.
One is GPU best quality,
4 bits per pixel,
Which is a great choice,
of visual performance and visual
And then we also have
where if you're really wanting
and your memory footprint,
greatly then you
and that's a 1 bit per pixel
which has excellent
Of course, since not
that is supported today
we take an extra step for you
and automatically generate a
that lack that capability.
What's great about this is it
about having incompatibilities
for all the supported devices,
we're going to automatically
and use it and thin it,
to those devices that
So you can use GPU compression
of compatibility breakage.
A brief note about how
with wide color assets
So, we use the ASTC Low Dynamic
which really means that
to be reduced to 8 bits
because LDR is an 8 bits per
The good news is we
We automatically do perform
down to 8 bit at build time when
But we preserve the wide gamut
within your original 16 bit
and compressing in the
thus preserving the ability
within the Display P3 gamut.
Okay, so that's the deployment.
A little talk about
but this talk was
Well what about colors?
Specifically colors in UI.
An important observation is
on screen drawn by
don't come from images,
to get top billing
Most pixels on screen are
by your code in your
And wide gamut colors it turns
in just working at
So let's talk about that.
In particular, the first
about is actually
because this is an
under-appreciate problem.
Usually when designers
in written form, or
or visual form code is
with an assumed sRGB
That means you're probably
down as something like
You know very simple.
They don't tell you what
And it's just assumed everybody
because everybody's
Well, not anymore.
This is no longer sufficient for
So what do you do?
Well the most important step
about what color space you're
or write down, or, you
Use Display P3, instead of
on wide gamut designs.
And indicate that as such.
And if you need more
to 255 8-bit representation
and use floating point.
So as an example, next time
maybe you'll refer to them
with an annotation, P3
Okay that's how you communicate
that color come from
You probably picked it,
the designer probably
How do they pick it?
Using a color panel.
This is the standard color panel
it's part of AppKits,
This of course is a very
from some of the
about in calling colors.
Typically, you pick red,
green and blue values,
The color panel is
in different color spaces,
but that hasn't always
or easy user experience.
So I'm excited to say that we've
in the color panel, in
with wide color a little easier.
The first thing we've done
and important working spaces,
right up there in a
for the number picker, sRGB,
The next thing we've done is
to change the numerical
from integer to floating point.
So that you can standardize
if that works for your workflow.
Another exciting thing we've
or wheel picker, we've actually
so that it can actually render
when placed on an
And we've added a new
to either use this
where it just basically switches
and sRGB as you cross displays,
or pin it to a specific
if that's more what
Okay, now we've picked
we know how to communicate them.
Well, to actually make
to code them don't we?
How do we construct wide
We've introduced two new
in AppKit and UIKit to
numbers directly.
This is NSColor Display P3
and UIColor Display P3
Great way to work with P3
But of course your code
with extended range sRGB
from a designer, but maybe came
or an API that might
you know extended
How do you work with those?
Well the good news is we've
red, green, blue alpha
and UIColor color to not
and allow values to
than one and less than zero.
So now you can construct
very easily.
Okay, now storing colors.
What if you actually
into your document data, or
Well special care really needs
because like many other
there has traditionally
of assumed color spaces and
about the same thing
green and blue number.
All you should ever need
That's all you need
What could be wrong with that?
Well it turns out there is.
Because you may not be able to
and a P3 color, and you may
up with the wrong
So I'd like you to
encoding a compatible sRGB color
color, which allows
especially older versions
because since this is
and backward compatibility
Allows the older applications to
and treat it as if it was sRGB,
which is the assumption
Whereas the newer
about this new wide gamut code
How do you create that
On iOS you can use the
And on the macOS you
NSColor.usingColorSpace
to the sRGB color space.
We actually ran into this in
You may be familiar
And the text editor
And its document format is
which has been around
by the Cocoa Text System as its
And it turns out that when you
a range of text, the way
that in the RTF document was
green, blue, 0 to 55 values.
Which is kind of a problem, I
because we have no idea which
blue values are in, and
to express the full range.
So, we had to take action.
What we ended up doing
and how we write and read
By including an expanded
which actually annotates
which have now been
with individual color space
to specify colors in
Okay. That's great.
But this is California,
to be surfing aren't we?
Well, what does that
Well, there's colors on the web.
The good news with wide
that as long as your image
and has appropriate color
all of the content
when it's rendered on webpages.
So as long as you do
Also, there are now
to resolve assets between
which is really handy.
And lastly, there's a WebKit
for specifying CSS colors
than the assumed sRGB,
since CSS's inception.
And with that I would like to
who will tell you a little
with wide color in your apps.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Patrick.
So, in your applications
that you get from
but also you might get some
or pulled down from the internet
And maybe you want to
as part of that.
How do you deal with
Well, when you're
I'm going to take a
Now, this is a box where
with the most saturated
And the other half of
Unfortunately, because
and you're watching it
that doesn't have the
as our new displays
So, we've actually
So what you're seeing isn't
that I'm going to show you
on a device and it
So, I'm a Frameworks Engineer on
so of course I'm going to start
When you're on the desktop,
it already has some great
for color profiles in your
If you have to do manual drawing
to be done off screen,
to do this is using the
It's called with
And you can use this anywhere
it will just work there.
So, let's look at some code.
So, pretty simple,
and we initialize our
We don't want this
And we configure
We get the Rect from the
We divide it up in halves,
allocated displayP3Red
Then allocate our sRGB
And then return true,
And we're done.
There you go.
It all just works.
If you're using this in
you're already doing
So, that's pretty
What about iOS?
Should be just as simple right?
So you must all be familiar with
It's a nice little API.
And, let's see the code again.
We get the size, we made
We divide our Rects, draw our
We get our image and
And this is what we get out.
That's not correct.
Why didn't this work?
Well, if we look
at the documentation we
We've documented that
in the UIKit will only
integer context.
That means you only get 8 bits
green, blue, and alpha.
This has a pretty big impact
Since we can't create
than 8 bits per color channel,
in the extended sRGB
And, because of the existing
well we can't expand
And we didn't want to make
with more options.
So, we have some new
It's called
And the way this works is
So I'm just going to jump
Here we are.
First we instantiate our
You can reuse this.
And it retains the
across every implication
out with the drawing handler.
And you just call
You supply your block,
as you would otherwise.
The bounds you can
which describes the
that this particular
And then you just
You get and render
And then you configure and
and just like we had
we have a correctly rendered
half sRGB red square.
So just a few other
It is fully color
And it also supports the
by default.
And it's pretty smart
If you have a device
like the new iPad Pro 9.7 inch,
we'll just turn it
You don't need to do
But if you're on a device
that does not have the
like every other iPad and
to get the more standard
sRGB context to draw into.
So we don't waste
for having the 16
The other thing this does
for you is it manages
You don't need to worry
or any other management
And for any legacy code that
it works with
So if you call into some
you'll do the right thing.
So, that's rendering
What about to the screen?
Okay we'll start
On [inaudible] view we
newly named in Swift 3, Draw.
And we do the right
When you call draw in
if you are on an iPad 9.7 inch,
in the correct, extended
with the floating
And if you're not on one
well you get what you get
And of course if you have
which has been color managed
to be color managed today.
If you need to know how
at a new trait on
in view controllers
It takes a UI display gamut
if you're on a new, P3 class
on a new sRGB class display.
And this can be very useful
to match a particular UI
from your asset catalog.
So you can properly match
Now, what if you know
to need the extended
Well, there's a new
and that is contents format.
And this controls exactly how
for you when it renders
By default, on the
it is to use the
And on all of the
to use the traditional,
And you control it with any one
of these various
So on Cocoa, back
NSView, same thing as UIView.
It will draw with the current
And you can look at any of the
with the Window Backing Store,
the screen target
If the window changes displays,
then you get the
in properties callback
And you can also listen
BackingPropertiesNotification,
from your view's window.
These are the same that
with since a very long time now.
And just as a refresher.
The backing properties
on the NSWindow include the
and the output display gamut.
And just like in iOS, you
of a context you get in AppKit,
on NSWindow, and you
of these depth properties.
So if you are on a wide
that extra precision you can
and it will not create the
So, what did we learn today?
Well, you've seen our vision
that to the next generation
We've talked a little
and color management,
with that wide gamut
to bring to your users.
We've reviewed how to use
And how to take your drawing
by making sure that
in these wide gamut scenarios.
Now for more information you can
on the session's website.
And there are a large
This is page 1.
So please check them out.
If they've already
to enumerate them,
See the videos through
or online at the WWDC website.
Thank you.