[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Hello everyone.
A very good afternoon
My name is Bharath Rao.
I'm an engineer with
and today I'm really
about health and fitness.
In this talk, I'll be showing
framework to add some
and fitness features
Before we get started, for
to Core Motion, I'd like
out some of our past sessions.
They have some excellent
about how sensors work, and
those sensors to provide APIs
that help your apps
and Device Motion,
Go check them out.
So with that, let's get started.
Here's what we have in
I have an update to the
that I would like
We have a new pedometer
both for the iPhone
And finally, we are also
to Apple Watch, with watchOS 3.
Thank you.
First up is Historical
Last year, we introduced
With this API, now
to raw accelerometer samples,
And you can also get this
After your apps have
to start recording these
And the OS will offer
even across device sleeps.
And when your app is ready to
and make a query,
of those buffered samples.
In watchOS 3, we have a
First of which is
Now, your apps have a 36-hour
and get access to all
Accelerometer samples.
The second update should not
this is one of the most
So I'm happy to announce
now the sample delay is
With these updates, now you
not only to observe user
but there are some
for which you can use the
to track sports activities or
or even health diagnosis.
Imagine an app on
that can detect hand tremors.
So now, whenever the user
they can launch the app.
Your app will be
of the historical accelerometer
on them and get a report that
and what kind of tremor it
and maybe even with the
so that it can speed
and the treatment
So that was a great update
to Historical Accelerometer
Next up is pedometer.
CMPedometer is a versatile API.
It records stats and
that the users climb
So you could use it to build
where you set some interesting
And that way you
to lead a healthier lifestyle.
But where CMPedometer
in the context of workouts.
Take for example,
We have stride estimation
on the iPhone and Apple
we are able to provide
and distance metrics, even
when the phone doesn't
Or when you go run
and you leave the phone
the users get very
The pedometer events API that
going to help you make those
engaging and accurate.
Let's consider a typical
As third packet [inaudible],
that you'll face with this
all those starts and stops
at intersections while
So the user comes to a
and your app will continue to
that they're just
So by the time they get
now you have accumulated
if you try to compute
over their entire run, you'll
that will resemble
Or maybe granddad's gone faster
So what I mean to say is,
you'll end up with
which is probably much lower
So one probable solution is you
and resume option.
But now, once they have paused,
to resume the workout
And if they don't, now all
of the running they do
is going to be not recorded
So if they forget to pause,
If they forget to resume,
So clearly, you need some auto
that is not only accurate, but
It has to feel like your
of detecting those
At this point, you
why not just use GPS and steps.
After all, you have access
If you have ever used GPS
to do a considerable
so that you can remove
Which means that it is going
And with the steps that you
it has a built in delay.
And we do that because we
We use steps to estimate stride.
And from that we compute
So it's very important for us
to have accurate step
So in this release, we are
that is going to help you
not only with good accuracy,
Our pedometer events
and resume solution uses
This predictive algorithm
so that we can improve
of whether the user is moving,
or have they come
Of course, all in a
By doing this, now we are able
that is associated with the
But we are able to do so
I would also like to point out,
because the predictive
of whether the user is moving,
we can also support walk base.
So when you are -- when
whether from a walk or a run,
And as soon as the user
you'll get a resume
Pedometer Events API,
on iOS 10 and watchOS 3.
Let's take a look
You have the pause
Each event is timestamped
when the algorithm detected
to not moving state,
And you had to start and stop a
and deregister for these events.
I've been talking about how
to clearly demarcate just
complete running workout
derive accurate metrics.
But you can also
in some other interesting ways.
Let's take a look at an example.
This is a trail-running
So here we are going to use
to figure out when we can engage
how we can present them
with some interesting
to make them respond
And because this is
there is going to be an
run so we are going to see
if there is some
We are going to use the
for the pause and resume events.
And we are going to get the
or the elevation changes
If you want to continue to
within your app, even
your app has to stay running.
And one way of doing that on
to continuous background
If you are interested in
I suggest that you go check
out the Core Location
that is happening at WWDC today.
Next, we are going to register
for the relative
availability check.
And then we provide
and provide a callback handler
to start receiving
In this example, I'm
of the most recent update.
But potentially in your app, you
And at the end of the workout
nice elevation profile
Next, we'll register for the
So first an availability check.
And then register by
This is just a quick tip to
into any concurrence issues,
of the handlers on the
So now that the app is
out when the user
and when they have
We are ready to see
that in a very contextual
As soon as they start
to get the resume
At this time you could make
when we got the resume
of the workout, you can
of those running times
to compute very accurate
In this example, I'm
of the most recent
so that I know exactly
when they started running.
And when the user
now this is a very
to figure out, because we
out if they have run up a hill.
And if they have done so,
this might be their
So why not just give them
Or if they have been doing that
because we have exact, accurate
now we can compare those
of how well they are doing
So that was an example where we
to arrive as very
and demarcate those
But it's also an example
do something interesting
At the end of the run, of
down the registrations and this
handlers that have been
Pedometer events are available
and of course the Apple Watch.
So that's pedometer in
Next, let's talk
As you're all aware,
on the iPhone since iOS 5.
With watchOS 3, now we are
to the Apple Watch.
With the Apple Watch, we have
that is at a fixed
and we use it throughout
And because we use our
that we do throughout the day,
to observe all of
And what Device Motion does
from the accelerometer and
to give you a very clear picture
and all of this right
All of that motion at wrist
using four distinct
rotation rate, and
If you want to know in depth how
and how they behave, I
out these sessions
In this talk though, I'll be
of this property so that we can
at some examples of how you
and fitness apps in
The first property is attitude.
Using attitude in your apps,
of the orientation
And when you use CMDeviceMotion,
you get these three
As Quaternion, rotation
Whenever you are using
one thing to note is every
going to be relative to
What this means is every single
to be observed from a point
that is not fixed to
So the reference frame remains
around, and that's
orientation-using attitude.
And furthermore, when
to start receiving the updates,
that is when the
And so every subsequent
within your app is going
that relative reference
at the start of updates.
So this is something that
of when you use attitude
And so that you don't
about where the device is
The next property is gravity.
Gravity is -- well,
It is the force that
down to the center of the Earth.
And within Device
as a unit vector in
Using gravity, you
and the tilt of the device.
But you might be wondering,
isn't different tilt also the
But one key difference is,
of this orientation
So take for example, if I were
to hold my hand perfectly
to my side, and then I move it
to observe this using gravity.
Because the x, y, z
to remain exactly same
To observe something like this,
that is external or fixed
Which is basically attitude.
So you could use gravity
but only in a limited form.
But it might work just
that you are thinking of.
One other thing about gravity is
when you hold the
you can observe it
It's a constant acceleration
that the accelerometer
and you can read it right
But as soon as you
now the accelerometer is picking
up not just the gravity
up all of the user-generated
So it becomes harder and harder
to just get the gravity
What Device Motion does, is
we switch over to the gyroscope
to start tracking the
Next property is rotation rate.
As the name suggests,
of change of angular motion.
It's very good for observing
When you are rotating
there is a rotational motion
and you can observe that
You can also observe any
Because most of us, we fix
so there is going to be some
So there is rotation and you can
rate property of Device Motion.
The last of the properties
And the user acceleration
through Device Motion is
Recall how I mentioned
up both the gravity component
and the user-generated
So this is just the
But it has been compensated
that was derived using
So that was a very quick
Now let's take a look
of how you can use
The first property is attitude.
Attitude is very good
for observing any kind
Like rep counting
So when you are lifting
through a set of
So just by looking at how
repeating, you can
And the best part about
that is now they might
where they're pulling
and you can observe all of
Gravity, as I already
for measuring tip and tilt.
Which basically means you
So if they're doing a downward
then you can figure out whether
And when they're also going
you can figure out whether
in a graceful way, or just
One of the most useful ways
to observe the speed
Take, for example,
So when you are swinging
you're not only rotating
but there is also the
So you could use both of those
to estimate the bat speed.
Of course you'll need to
and at what point on the bat
User acceleration is best used
when there is some
Because accelerometer
that the user is doing, if
where you're using
to measure some small movements,
it might get drowned
So wherever there is a very
to use user acceleration.
So something like
You can tell how much
on that sandbag,
that is hopefully
So those were only a
of how you can use Device
By -- after going through this,
if you feel that
that could use Device Motion
about how you can apply
by our lab tomorrow,
than happy to help you.
Now let's take a look
You have the four properties.
Attitude and gravity,
Gravity's the uniflector.
User acceleration is in
in radians per second.
Before you can start
within your app, you have
You can set sample
And once you have set that
and register for updates
From this point onwards,
to poll the Device Motion
to receive the most
Or you could provide
on which you can get every
is generating for you.
And of course, once you
listening to the Device Motion
and deregister using the
That brings me to the end
Now I'll be handing it forward
through an example
that uses Device Motion
Thank you very much.
Over to you Paul.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Bharath.
Hello everyone.
My name is Paul Thompson,
and I'm an engineer
So Bharath just talked
with Core Motion APIs.
What I'd like to do is show
in an Apple Watch fitness app.
So in this app, what we'd
like to do is create a
Then we'll do -- we'll subscribe
to sensor updates
Finally, we'll detect
between a forehand
Now to do this, what we'll need
from Core Motion, as well
as some new capabilities
Now as you may remember,
on HealthKit and Core Motion
and sensor output and
such as step count, flights,
Now, during a workout session,
and process Device Motion
directly engaged in your app.
But of course, this ability
To begin with, you must have
entitlement in your
Further, this background work
active workout session.
And in addition,
you must minimize
If you do not minimize
your app will be suspended
until the user explicitly
Now since this background
by HealthKit, I encourage you
to learn more in
With that in mind, let's think
about what our app
Well with app, you would
to the tennis courts
and practicing volleying
There, you simply
and hit the ball back and forth.
Then, you'd expect that at any
at your watch, and get some
So with that in mind,
let's think about the
Here, there'll be three layers
First is the UI, where
to the user what we've done.
Then, we'll have
We'll interact with
and stop our workout sessions
and enable our background
Then we'll enable our -- then
Here we'll interact with
and implement our
There we'll respond to 50
and add the resulting
Afterwards, on every update,
we'll assess whether a
we'll implement the UI.
So how do we want to -- how
that we wish to detect?
Well, tennis is a
So in this case, all
at the essence of two gestures.
A full forehand and
We'll do this using the
as provided by Device Motion.
So if you expect the watch
then you would expect
to include a simple
So if we take the dot
from a potential swing with
we can isolate this movement
of the device.
And also ignoring some
Then, once we've got
we'll see if we've
and fast enough to
So now that we know what to do,
let's take a look
To begin, we'll envision
We'll display our
Here we'll have three watch kit
to update during runtime.
These will include
The forehand count label.
And the backhand count label.
And what the workout label will
when we've started and
And the forehand and backhand
how many times we've
Here we'll also have a
and stop the workout session.
So now that we know what the
at our workout manager.
Here, we'll handle our
as well as create
We'll also direct our motion
and stop sensor updates.
So here, in our workout manager,
So to begin, we'll create
which we'll use to initiate
Since we're creating
let's use tennis as
And outdoors as the location.
Then, after initialization,
we'll have HealthKit start the
to Device Motion updates.
At this point, we'll now be able
to do work while
In addition, we'll also
Here, we'll simply do the
from sensor updates,
to end the workout session.
At this point, normal
So now, let's take a look
He will interface with
and implement our
So to begin, what we'll do
to the CM motion manager.
As well as create an
or samples to do work on.
At this point, we'll
on the left or the right wrist.
There's a difference
and the backhand swing
on this perspective.
We'll also keep a local count of
as well as mark as whether
We'll also choose 50
And create a running buffer
that should hold no more
Now as Bharath mentioned
Device Motion samples
at a rate up to 100 hertz.
While you generally want to pick
as you can get away with,
with fidelity that you need.
In addition, we'll set three
in our detection algorithm.
These will include the minimum
the lower bound on the peak
and an upper bound on the
Now we chose these values
and sample data that
But generally, you'll find
and picking these values will
Finally, we'll create this
which we'll use to
So now, after we set
we'll adjust the operation queue
that we'll use to handle all
I'd like to emphasize
we created this operation
of our data processing
So now we'll also create
to reset all the
as well as zero out the UI.
And then, as a final set
we'll create some complementary
Here, we'll simply implement
mark that we've recently
and then let the UI know it.
So let's start interfacing
So as always, the first thing
API's supported on the
Then, we'll tell Core Motion to
And finally, we'll subscribe
by passing our operation
that we'll use to respond to all
All this block will do
if there are any errors with
to our detection function.
So let's take a look at what
to do.
So as Bharath mentioned earlier,
Device Motion gives
But in this example, we're only
and rotation rate vectors.
Now, as you may remember,
the gravity vector is simply
The gravity univector,
regardless of how much
And the rotation rate is
for the device, giving
So now, what our [inaudible]
product -- will take the dot
from a potential swing
So we only analyzed
of motion about gravity.
Then, we'll add the
to a running buffer holding
Once we have enough
in the content within.
So the two metrics we'll use
to analyze the swing are the
and the peak speed of the swing.
Here, to get the accumulating
the accumulated samples that
over the second that
Then you have peak rate, you
depending on the
Further down our
if we subtended far enough and
If so, we'll choose forehand or
of the Apple Watch and
And finally, to end the
to see that the swing
This way we can reject
as the user's arm moves back in
And finally, to finish
we'll have the stopUpdates
Which we'll use to unsubscribe
when the workout has ended.
And that concludes the
We simply described a
We then created a
Handle interfacing
And then we created our motion
as well as implement
So I hope you all have
to use Device Motion as newly
So before I wrap up, I'd like
on the use of this API.
So now while you may expect
and predictable location,
which wrist the device
of position can have significant
Further, when using
always try to remember --
try to understand what
operating in.
And further, as we said earlier,
with samples at a
We always want to
between the resources required
and the fidelity demanded
This is especially important,
given the restrictions
of a workout session.
And so to summarize the talk
about the performance
to historical accelerometer.
Then we demonstrated how
to precisely tag
contextual feedback to users,
to Device Motion
And walked you through
and backhand swings
So now if you'd like to
such as documentation
please check out this link.
And further, as you saw, this
from HealthKit so
to view this HealthKit
in detail what's
In addition, Core Location has
to review, and encourage you
And finally, I also recommend
in store in watchOS 3.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]