[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon,
It's great to see
How many of you are here
Wow! That's incredible.
Well, welcome.
I hope WWDC is going
Now we're going to talk
I've got five things
We're going to give
on Explicit Congestion
that we talked about last year.
We're going to give you an
We're going to talk a little
which is becoming
We're going to explore
to network interfaces
up big data bills
And we're going to finish
of network quality of service.
You may have heard
Fastlane announcement.
We're going to talk a
that might apply to
So let's start with ECN.
To recap from last year,
we showed how Smart
and marking packets instead of
reduce delays due
and improve the user
and especially for things
In iOS 9, we did not enable
but in an unrelated change,
the VPN software would pay
We found one ISP in Germany
"congestion experienced,"
The good news is they
within a couple of weeks.
We had no reports of any
in the world, and what that
out iOS all around the world,
the Internet is now
And because of that, in iOS
five percent of TCP connections
and we're using this to gather
that the Internet
In the Developer Seed
100 percent of Wi-Fi connections
on these three carriers
So last year, I reported
of the Alexa top million
which is a pretty
for a technology
I talked to my good friends
Brian Trammell and
and their colleagues reran
This year the percentage
And if you only look at IPv6
So this is a call to
and their vendors who
The clients are now doing ECN.
The services are supporting ECN.
It's time for the
to start marking packets
It gives you a better
it reduces delays due
and it makes more
because you are avoiding
retransmitting packets.
Our next topic is IPv6.
World IPv6 launch was
and it continues to grow.
I looked at a variety of
to show you just a
I looked at accesses to Apple's
In Belgium, it's now
On T-Mobile USA, we're
On Verizon, we're
So it's pretty clear
that IPv6 traffic
And the reason is clear.
IPv6 is simpler,
it's less expensive to operate.
So it's very clear why the
But at what cost to
Is IPv6 less mature?
Is it slower?
Is there less capacity
These are important
and developers pay
They use statistics
to measure things like page
of their users viewing the
so they can tell how well
in different countries around
different carrier networks.
LinkedIn reports that now 10
over IPv6, and they find the
to 40 percent faster
They theorize that that
setting up connections through
Facebook found similar results.
45 percent of their
and they reported recently
that on average ATP GET requests
If you only look at the iPhone
it turns out to be
So IPv6 is better for
It's better for users
And that's why Apple is 100
to IPv6.
And you will have all seen
We announced last year we were
to be compatible
and we said we would be testing
with the NAT64 Gateway.
Starting this month we started
and we looked very
that this was causing
of application rejection,
we would have to look into
But the good news is,
we don't find any change
so what that really tell us is
that are working just
which is what we expected,
to have that confirmed.
Now, if you've had
and you think it might be to
to the labs today or tomorrow.
You can test your app here
and we can help you troubleshoot
Our advice continues to
use the high level APIs that
If you have to use the
then there is extra work that
which is why we really advise
that do that for you.
Another key piece of
not literal IPv4 addresses.
Because IPv4 addresses are
And let me give you a
This is a typical situation
You have a client on IPv4.
You have a server on IPv4.
The packets make their little
and that's how you
Nowadays, many more carriers
with a NAT64 Gateway, and the
detour through the NAT
to that old legacy IPv4
Now, if your data center guys
but you're still using
then the packets are going
through the NAT to get to the
But if you look up by hostname
and they put the IPv6
that's how you get the straight
through the NAT Gateway.
I talked about literal
We now support using
in selected APIs.
And if you use one
we will actually do the DNS64
on the device, create a
corresponding with your v4
and then connect through
Now, remember, using literal v4
from ever connecting
But that said, if that's what
here is an example
If you're writing
and the high layer
for you automatically.
But if you're writing
and you're using BSD
to use is getaddrinfo.
You pass in the address
to as a literal string.
You pass in the port you want.
Here https is a synonym
You loop through all
Remember, don't just
You'll get back an array of
of course, free the memory
Another question we
about the Internet of things.
There are developers
with the device that
and some of those devices
Now, we'd like those
And if they don't support
at least support IPv4
So even on a v6 only network,
devices can use v4 amongst
with link-local addressing.
Now, if the device
of those things, that's okay.
Inform app review, when
that is not grounds for
It probably is grounds
of these stickers on the device.
[Laughter] And remember, all off
to be compatible
So to summarize, we recommend
at both ends, in the
We recommend you use hostnames.
That way you can get a v4
and a v6 address
If you do need to use
those are now supported
as long as you do it properly.
But remember, imbedding
communication to v6
So that brings us to our next
You may have started to
and if you're a native
this can look pretty
And what I want to talk
about today is how
International support in
to be a big task.
In fact, it really is no
So even though the title of this
and Networking, really we
For now I just want to talk
about how you support
I'm going to start
Not because many of you will
to day, but I want to
and make it less scary,
complicated than ASCII.
So the first concept
Unicode is a big list of
to each number a human
and it's like a big
In fact, it is available
It's a big, thick book
of number and character.
And that's an abstract concept.
You have integers and you have
Now, to use those integers in
of representing those
on disk, over the network.
One way of representing
which is just a 32-bit number.
And like any 32-bit number,
you have to be concerned
or little endian.
And it takes up four times
UTF-16 is more compact.
It uses 16-bit numbers.
It still has the same problem of
and because it's only 16-bits,
it can only represent
So you have to use
to represent the values
So that's a bit cumbersome.
UTF-8 is an 8-bit
Because of that, there
and this is really what makes
So let's dive in a
It was invented late night in
of those rare pieces of
And when I first
I immediately saw,
This solves the problem
So I want to tell you guys a
so you can understand
The Codepoints in Unicode from 0
to 7F are exactly the
And UTF represents them using
So what that means is if
of plain ASCII files, I can wave
I declare you to be UTF-8.
Not a single byte
The meaning of the
You have automatic backwards
that legacy of ASCII, so
UTF-16, UTF-32, other encodings
For the values that are
they are represented as
But all those multi-byte
above 128.
So there was no overlap
and the multi-byte encodings
of the higher value
That property is not
that re-use the high code
UTF-8 has three flavors
It has the plain ASCII bytes.
If a byte starts with the
that tells you it's plain ASCII.
If the top two, three,
that tells you it's a two,
And if the top bits are 1 0,
that tells you it's
of a multi-byte sequence.
So I'll show that in context.
The ASCII characters
The bytes with two leading
Three leading 1s is a
Four leading 1s is a
And this gives it a wonderful
into the middle of a UTF-8 file
at any old byte, you can
Does this stand alone as ASCII?
Is this the start of
Did I land in the middle of a
to skip forward or back to
So it's very, very robust to
It's an encoding that is
but has just enough
Another useful property it
of a string, there
And C treats 0 as the
so that's a very
UTF-16 strings have
And another nice property is
if you do a naive simple
on UTF strings, they
as if you sorted the
So a whole bunch of really
and this is why just six years
the IETF issued a document
all new Internet
to work with UTF-8.
And that philosophy has
Four years ago, Google did a
of web pages were UTF-8, and
that were old fashioned,
which is of course a
Last month that number
And because of that, the
also recommends that we only
And this is wonderful.
There is, however, one catch.
For some reason,
the DNS community
and they invented a
that they call Punycode.
And Punycode re-uses
to mean different things.
So those are the byte
to letters, digits, and hyphens.
A result of this is that if
I can interpret those bytes as
like that, or I can interpret
and get what they're
And that dual interpretation
of the same bytes can
because it becomes unclear what
or what the user meant.
If we contrast that with UTF-8,
the first thing you notice is
It takes fewer bytes,
and there's also only
So there was no ambiguity there.
The good news for you guys
about this, because
In iOS 9 and OS X El
to ping a UTF-8 hostname on the
You type in UTF-8, those
to the APIs on to the network,
into the DNS as UTF-8
Starting now in iOS 10 and macOS
on the command line with
we will now translate that
do the query, and it
Now, here the ping command
and displaying it as if it were
on the screen instead of the
and that's part of the problem
of having dual interpretations
But the good news
and DSA APIs will now accept
in UTF-8 format, because --
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Because the Punycode
it doesn't support even simple
and we use DNS for Bonjour
to be that restrictive.
So the way the algorithm works,
in RFC 6763, we will
and if the DNS administrator
which is very easy to do, and
in the '90s, we do the
we get the result,
What's new now is that if we
we will do one more try with
So we support both
Email addresses are
internationalized today.
And this is also not hard to
for a silly, trivial reason.
Many apps, when you sign
onto the website to sign up for
if the email address is valid
in .com or things of that form.
And users with perfectly valid
to sign up for accounts because
So we need to remove those
Really the only thing
for in an email address is
And if it's got that, it could
If you want to know if it's
and have the user respond
If you're writing an email
there are a bunch of RFCs you
But for the rest of you, you
Let the user enter their
stick it in your
and have the mail server send
with the email standards.
So to wrap up this section, we
Makes everything
Don't worry about Punycode.
We handle it for you.
And be liberal about
in this new international
That brings us to
Now, Wi-Fi Assist is something
Really, this is not new.
This is the way things
since the very first iPhone.
If I have Wi-Fi, I want
If I don't have Wi-Fi, that's
so I have network access
And the first iPhone did this.
What we changed last
We were smarter about
because there's always
on the edge of a Wi-Fi network.
And mobility factors
We have a situation that we
and it happens at the end of
You leave the office, you get
you're walking out to the car
or weather forecasts or
and your phone thought
It had Wi-Fi a moment ago, but
and it hasn't realized yet.
With Wi-Fi Assist,
We'll try to use Wi-Fi.
If it doesn't work, we'll
But like any new feature,
for the new thing to be the
for people's problems.
Everybody hates it when
and they get a big bill
and it's human nature to
But if you actually look
you will probably find
Wi-Fi Assist is normally
Now, apps have the switch.
If you don't want
of data, you can turn it off.
But that's very crude.
That's kind of an all
And a lot of apps want to do
Say you have a video
You may want the user to be
see little thumbnail pictures,
read the descriptions
Doesn't cost very much.
But you may want the
that says don't stream
because users may
that much money on mobile data.
And if you have that, you're
to differentiate between getting
over cellular, and streaming
A lot of developers have
They use the reachability
Yes or no?
If I'm not on cell, go
Well, things don't stay
Things change from
And between you checking
and actually doing
the user may be walking
So this is not the
The right way to do it
to the networking layers, and
The first step here is don't
If you want to do a network
If that's a transaction that you
then you can express that
Using the CoreMedia APIs,
you set the allow cellular
If you set allows
then we won't use
Nice and simple.
[ Applause ]
If that connection fails,
do you want to stream this
or you can just wait, subscribe
and when the phone comes back on
and then you can retry your
available again.
So to summarize, don't
on Wi-Fi now, you will still be
or even half a second from now.
Conditions change.
Express what you want
and we will respect that.
Our last topic is
Last summer, we announced
and Apple, and I'm going to
of the new APIs that you can
to the networking layers.
There are different kinds
99 percent of what
standard Internet
We want the best
and ideally we'd like low delay.
But we definitely want as
This supplies browsing
Another thing that we
uploading photos to iCloud.
And that also wants to have
as the priority stuff.
We'd like to be able to upload
in the background without
The photo upload should take
It is what we call
It uses the otherwise idle
that would otherwise have been
to sending emails,
anything that the human
The third class of
interactive voice and video.
And I say interactive,
When we're having a
you hear me, you respond,
If that round-trip is more than
human communication breaks down.
When people talk about voice and
that watching a YouTube
but it's not interactive.
It doesn't need that sub 200
Listening to a podcast
that doesn't mean a
It's not interactive.
So that's why I labeled this
because this is interactive
For that traffic you want the
and it's very small throughput.
It's a few kilobits per second.
You don't need 50
So marking your traffic
as telephony tells the
but you also don't
If you try to do any kind of
you're going to lose
because a very small amount
of the network capacity is
So one of our FAQ
will Fastlane make
And the answer is no, it
It will lower the
You may be wondering,
to the Smart Queue Management
and Explicit Congestion
that we were talking
And the answer is those
for all traffic across
but telephony will probably
that wants the very,
and doesn't mind sacrificing
Starting in iOS 5 we had the
and that lets you express some
But many of the developers
and Facetime that
of voice telephony
And to use UDP today on iOS, you
So we now have a socket option
that exposes the
so your UDP clients
We know some developers had been
of service bits in an attempt
The problem is those type
of service bits are
They are not specified anywhere.
Some Wi-Fi chip vendors will
and use that as a hint to
to voice, video, background.
But the problem is with no
that interpretation
So you may test it in your
but for a customer, it
And that's why we have
that gives you reliable,
consistent behavior
If you're writing Swift code,
you can set the network
to voice, video, or background.
Or if you don't set it at all,
then that is traditional
If you are using
we have the same options.
We have about another seven
than most of you will need.
These are the four
When you set these options,
On the device itself, there
and the type of service you set
for your traffic controls
On Wi-Fi interfaces, it
multi-media access category.
This is supported on all
and the outband queue
for Ethernet as well as Wi-Fi.
Now, if your device is on one
of these new Cisco Fastlane
and we will also set the IP
Code Point so that you get
not just on the first
but in subsequent hops
I want to stress this is not
to feel obliged to go
If you're writing an
definitely set background
If you're writing the next
But for the rest of you,
standard best effort is almost
Some other things you
The outband queue
quality of service marking
but remember it only
The packets coming in have
at the other end sending them.
And the IP layer marking is
It's today only supported
with compatible hardware.
It's only on iOS.
It's not supported on Macs
And for now it's only
I know most people don't use
but if you do plug in
the quality of service is
And finally if the
to install a management
then that management profile can
to use this type of service
that are listed in the
to set type of service.
It will be a no op
So to summarize this section,
most of your traffic should
If you are doing
that are not time critical,
for you to be less disruptive
and be a better citizen
Remember, it's not
There isn't a ranked
of high priority
It's a web expressing whether
and low latency or high
So that ends our session.
Thank you for coming.
We've talked about Smart Queue
to action to all the ISPs and
The clients are supporting ECN.
The servers are supporting ECN.
If you start marking the
of dropping them, you will
The message for developers
in the room is IPv6 is now
for many carriers
Support IPv6 in your
Support IPv6 and
For your text, UTF-8
It's no harder than ASCII.
It's really very
All of our devices
for all the Unicode
so you should have no worries
about supporting UTF-8
And finally, we have new ways
to the networking layers.
You can control when you don't
and you now also
of the throughput latency
So with that, there's a link
where you can find
We have other sessions
that you may find interesting.
We have sessions
and security, which
We have a couple
about internationalization.
We have some sessions
about higher layer networking
So with that, thank
[ Applause ]