[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, and welcome
My name is Eric Bainville,
Vector and Numerics group.
Our group provides
Performance libraries means
provide very compute intense
[inaudible] transform,
Most, most of these
Accelerate framework.
We find for example, image,
which is an image
It will transform between types
and also do geometric
Next to vImage you will
for signal processing,
and other signal
Then we have the BLAS, which
It's very old.
It comes straight from the 70's.
Few years ago we added
SparseBLAS computation on
We also provided LAPACK
which is higher level
Outside of Accelerate, we also
which is a set of headers
to vector instructions
and they are not
in the CPU's [inaudible]
or assembly code.
We also have compression,
for lossless compression,
and everything we
for all the CPU's we support.
So when you get a new phone,
so you don't have to do it.
Alright. Today, first, we start
with a quick refresh
Then we'll introduce two new
BNNS, which is a set of
for neural networks;
which is a small
to numerical integration
and then my colleague,
and introduce new
Well, first, before we start,
let me tell you quickly
So depending on your language of
or include the, the
and then you need to link
So from Xcode in your project
on your target, and then you
and as a window appears,
you click on link
You open that.
Alright. And those
with the little plus here,
of all the libraries and
and Accelerate is the first one.
[ Applause ]
Yes. Alright.
Well, if it's not the first one,
there's a search
So if you look for compression,
I knew we'd get compression.
Alright. So that's, now
OK. Yes. Then compression,
when Sebastian introduced the
of the union where we still
but today we're announcing
So you will find
and we publish it
Just let me remind you why
So these are the platform
and zlib compared
So we are 1.4x faster for encode
Alright. That was
Now let's jump to BNNS.
Basic neural networks
So the name looks
BLAS means basic linear
As I said, it comes
and BNNS provides a, a set
of very low-level
So I will [inaudible] later.
We do only low level
like matrix products but
Before I enter into
and what the API is,
let me remind you how
Let's say we have this
to recognize animals, OK.
So on input you will
and then you have
Inside the orange box, the red
These are the parameters of,
this thing we output
which are the probability
a giraffe, or a snake.
OK. So first you
Let's say you have a cat image.
You process the cat image to the
So that's the highest
It says dog.
Well, that's what you
So it was a cat,
that you [inaudible]
and what if I slightly
So the networks now will go
and you need to do this millions
and at some point, you will
correctly for, for
So if it was a, a giraffe,
because we trained it properly.
Alright. So that's
and notice the difference
During inference, we
So usually let's say
What will happen is that you
when you build your app,
and then when you shift the
and the, the network
on the device is on
OK. What's inside this
So let me show you an example.
If you have been to the
Part II speech yesterday, you
that was a scene
and lots of demo [inaudible]
these are more advanced networks
This is state of the art from
this describes a, a
So on input you have the small
of something written, and then
Here you have a 5
and the output will be
That's an output of five
with different weights, and
You take these five images,
to them, and you will
of fifty images with
So what's happening here is
into the feature space
So the content of this
and more abstract, and at the
which will tell you that's
This is what you want on output.
OK. And so with a very
you can really do that,
So after these convolutions,
take them as a single big vector
and apply a fully
which is just a big
and it will mix all
and produce a set of 100 values.
That's called the hidden
and then you need a last one,
mix them together, and produce
So at this point you are
value here is a probability
Alright. So that's what
and as you have seen here,
of layers, and this is
We provide the compute
OK. Before we start about
and what the API is, let
So this, this, here
which is a well-known package
for [inaudible] network
and this is a convolution
So we have 14 different
Here, you can read them.
And this is the time Caffe takes
So higher is better.
This is Caffe on
and this is what
So on average, it's 2.1x faster,
and if you have even
you can even reach
Alright. So that
Now let me tell you
So that's a set of low
Very similar to BLAS.
That's why we named it BNNS.
It doesn't really know what's,
That's, that's your
What it does is provide really
OK. And it only,
Actually I'm not sure
to run training on the device.
That's, that's too expensive.
You need millions of images
That wouldn't fit.
So usually inference would be
you will just do the inference
And we provide three
Convolution layers,
and the fully-connected layers.
Why? Well, actually in
you spend more than 75 percent
of the time computing
and then the next one on
with something like 15 percent,
and fully-connected layers
but usually you find them only
like we have seen in the
two fully-connected
but this did take a lot of time.
OK. Now that we know what
into the details of the three
and what we compute and how to
Let's start with the
So this is a convolution.
It takes an input image, a block
on the middle, and each pixel
by taking a block of
multiplying them by
and then you take
and you get your upper pixel.
And you need to do that
So if you count, that's
because you need
and then on the kernel
Actually what they do is
because what we have on input
We have a stack of images.
So we need to duplicate
and know what we compute is
and then we take the sum of
and we get, to get
So now the, the loop
I added the IC [inaudible]
and really this is
because we also have
So what we really compute
We do this many times, one
and now we have a
That means even if the
like in this example, we
It's very small, but when
together, what you get is
That means tens of
and in an entire network,
you can have trillions of,
That means seconds of CPU time.
OK. A compute in the
now how do you create
Well, first thing
to describe your input stacks.
So you need to specify the
the number of channels, and
So the increment between
between two layers, and
what type is used to store them.
For example, we, we work
On neural networks, we don't
and usually people will use
because the storage
So instead of having 20
and if you can go on
you will have only
And you usually, usually don't
So you can specify the type
You need to do the same for the
to describe the convolution
That's the kernel dimensions,
the padding which is
of 0 added to the input, the
of the loop in x and y, and the,
the channel counts for input and
That's what the orange block in
and, again, you can have a,
of the weights, and
or 8-bit storage
Again, because it will
and the storage needed
Then once you have done that,
you can create a convolution
You tell it, OK, this
that's my output stack, that's
and you will get a filter
to apply the convolution
and once you are done with it,
you will call a [inaudible]
and really the resource is used.
This was for the
Now, let's go and with
Pooling is slightly
So what to compute one output
block of input pixels and take
and that's your result,
for all pixels in all channels.
That's what the formula says.
Well, again, to create a, a
you need to describe the input
as before, and you also
the pooling layer itself.
Again, with the kernel
and this time you don't have
to use to compute the output.
That will be max average.
And then once you have done
and you get a filter
to the one we had before.
The last kind of layers
connected layers.
Well, it's called
but that's a matrix
So on input you have a vector,
by the matrix, add some,
and then you get the output.
So just a, a matrix product.
So this time, you don't have
So you need to describe the
Point out to the data
to store these values, and,
floating point, and integer.
And the you need to
through the dimensions
and the matrix co-efficients.
And also the bias is not on
And then you can create the
again, if [inaudible]
Now what we have on this
So you have your input
and your filter,
you have two functions
So it's called filter apply if
and output, and you have,
you will call filter apply
we tell you the number of
from one pair to the next one.
That's a stride in memory.
Alright. And that's it for BNNS.
Let me wrap up.
So BNNS is a set of, of
for our neural networks.
Really low level.
We do the compute.
We do it well.
We do it fast, but it doesn't
It just does the compute.
So we optimize it to be
and important thing, it will
OK, that was it for BNNS.
Now Quadrature.
We have a request, will, people
to do a numerical
So here it is.
Yeah, remember your,
So this is computing
of a function between a and b.
So that's a green area
Well, so to do that, you first
So you need to provide
Once thing we did, and which
the old library's
that the callbacks takes a
Because usually when you compute
to evaluate the function
and if you have a callback,
that faster, it's all good.
You can do much, much faster
So it will, it will pass
and you will have
of xi inside each value of y.
So that's your function,
to tell it how to integrate it.
So we provide a set of three
with different complexity
of them are able to integrate
you will find details in
And you also need to specify
on the output, and
of intervals we can
to complete the output.
And then you pass that to
and you also tell it a, b,
and you pass a point
It's called estimated
and it will return you the
and also status, we receive
because if you ask a
sometimes it's not
and we will get that
And that's it for Quadrature.
And now let me call
He will tell you about
&gt;&gt; Thanks very much, Eric.
My name's Steven Canon.
I work in the Vector,
Eric took you back to
I'm going to take you
to linear algebra right now.
We have this nice module, simd,
which provides geometric
for C, Objective-C,
And it really closely mirrors
It ties in closely with
and all those graphics
If you find yourself writing
small, you know, 3 x 3,
4 x 4 kind of linear
this is the library you probably
of writing that by hand.
We have most of what
If something's not there,
It's all really fast
So what's there now?
We've have a bunch of types.
There's vectors of floats and of
and unsigned integers
And we have matrices of floats
And this is just what's
in C and C++ and Objective-C.
There's a bunch of other types
for writing your own generic
to focus on sort of the common
on all the languages on all the
We have operations on those
There's all the usual
for vectors and for matrices.
And we have all the familiar
if you've done any
Most of what you
is going to be available here.
I'll show you a little
So this is the same
in three different languages.
We have it in Objective-C
in the middle, and we have
and you can see that the
different between
because function
in these languages,
in on the actual computation
in all the languages, and it
the way you would just write
So you don't have a lot
You don't have to write
You just write your code in
and we translate
So it's, it's nice and easy
like the Metal code you would
Now it happens that the reflect
built into the library already.
So you don't need to
Calling functions
like there's a whole bunch
that exposes Objective-C
Situation is pretty good.
The vector types are
Objective-C, and in C++.
And in Swift, they're
but the compiler knows how
So you don't really
Here's a simple example.
If I have an Objective-C
I call some function here
and I want to call that function
from Swift using the
I can just do that,
I don't need to do
These types have
So there's no cost to converting
Similarly, for matrices,
the Swift matrix types are
Objective-C, and C++ types.
So if I need to work with
I'm going to create a
All I need to do is
Works fine.
Doesn't have any
It just sort of changes the
similarly, I can use the C
to get a C type to call C or
So we have a few things
that I want to show to you.
We have three new functions
simd insphere - and these are
of different types and different
Basically everything in the
So even though we have
it's actually a lot
So I'm going to start
What orient does is it lets us
of vectors positively oriented?
And what that means,
if you don't remember
is do they obey the
You might remember that from
is there determinate positive.
If there's any math
you're objecting
of vectors does not
What I mean here is just
and you slam them
Take the determinate
Is that positive or not?
So why do we care about this?
This is kind of simple
You can use this to answer a lot
of computational geometry
Like, is the triangle facing
If you think about a
that are pointing towards you,
on the backside that
And if you're doing graphics
which ones are facing
because those are the ones
Similarly, if I have
and I want to answer the
on the line, or if it's not,
I can use the orient predicate
Now this seems kind of
that it can be very hard to
when the point is close to the
about that more later.
So here's a simple
I'm going to have a plane over
the display here, and I have,
going to put some
So I have three points,
to query the orientation
Now because we go
to b to c, there, we say that
That's what it means
to be positively
If we move one of the points so
now it's negatively oriented,
so it's exactly on the
then they're co-linear
or you might say
Now it's very hard to tell in
on the line especially with
And that's because orientation
So because of floating point
of this determinate
you can easily get the wrong
that doesn't matter, but
you can actually
or you may get the wrong result
For collision detection
it can actually be quite
to answer this question.
Also for things like triangular
and things, this is
to be able to answer exactly.
So let's look at
where this is actually
I'm going to put two vectors
and these are almost
They, they differ
by the smallest amount
And I've magnified
on the right-hand side.
So you can see that
If I drew these to
they would overlap entirely.
And if we compute the
that you would normally compute
because of floating
Now this is a simple
With dimensions bigger
we can actually get the
So it's not just that it could
But if we use the
we get a tiny positive
which is the right result.
These are positively oriented.
And I should point out here
that don't interpret
as meaning anything.
It is not the determinate.
It is sometimes the determinate,
to have the right sign.
So what we're really
in the sign of this number.
How are we able to do this?
So the geometric [inaudible]
that I'm showing you
adaptive precision.
We go and compute as many
to get the right result,
and this lets us return
very fast in most cases,
and do the exact computation
we will, we will do that.
So you can just trust that that
in your code, and you don't need
Incircle is very similar.
We take three points
That determines the circle.
You can notice that
around the circle here.
That's important.
And if I put a point
then simd incircle can
In that case, I get
If it's on the circle, I get 0.
And if it's outside the
And insphere is exactly
Just in three dimensions now.
I need four dimensions
I give it my point x,
I'll show you an example I
out if a triangle faces
Here I've got a really
to represent a triangle
Triangle is determined
that I happen, a
And I have this predicate
the triangle is facing
So the usual way you
to compute a normal to the
and then take the dot product
to the camera, and
then the triangle
We can simplify this code
by just using the
So my code is simpler,
and it gives me the
Is it, these are all things I
to do in Accelerate across the
for complex mathematical
So we showed you a bunch
We have some new
We have BNNS for
We have Quadrature, and we
orientation and incircle
Every one of these features and
to a request that we
So we really want to hear from
what we can add to make your
We want to give you
that let you do what you
We've also done a ton of
In vImage, which Eric
we have a whole set
for interleaved chroma planes.
This is absolutely one
of the most requested features
So we're, we're really
If you don't know what that
but if you know what it is,
And we also have expanded
in the vImage conversion
This underlies a lot
that you may have heard about.
So this is, this is
We have improved the performance
for interleaved complex
With the FFT's, we support both
where the complex and imaginary
or put together.
Planer layouts are what we
and we recommend you do
to have interleaved data, you
and they'll be really fast.
We've also improved
of all the Level
Some of that's motivated by
and some of that's just
after that, and there's a
in Accelerate, lots
Every time new processors
that we're tuning for that.
We want to take care
of all those low-level
so you can focus on writing
that just sit on top of that,
and you can do the
In summary, we want to
for computational algorithms
where we give you
that are correct, they're fast,
and we're going to keep
as it comes along so you don't
If you want to [inaudible]
a new processor, then you're
for that, and if you let
then you don't need to worry.
Keep the future requests coming.
We love to get them from you.
We talked to a bunch of you
We got a bunch of great
Can file radars.
We love for that to happen.
If you want more information,
I also encourage you to check
where you've gone into more
of the library that are useful.
There were two great
that I really highly
out from yesterday,
in this kind of stuff.
Thanks very much for
[ Applause ]