[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and welcome.
My name is Kushal Dalmia, and
I'm going to be representing
for performance and
In this talk, we're going to
how it affects your app, and
performance by improving
So let's begin.
As we all know, devices
and better every year.
Screen resolutions
as 16 times in the past decade.
Similar improvements
in [inaudible] technologies
and amazing high-quality
All these improvements have led
and consumed every day.
Just to put it in perspective,
of the iPhone wallpaper size.
If you look at the size of the
and generations, you notice that
The size of the wallpaper on
as 14 times its counterpart
And there's a similar trend in
We build and use
messaging, and social networks.
We work and store richer
And we all share and
and video files.
Now to manage this
apps need to be really efficient
and the main system resources
For CPU and memory, I'll refer
Performance on iOS and watchOS,
and today we're going
I/O, or input/output, are
with the local file storage
Operations that interact
with reading or writing files
Talking to a web
of network-based I/O.
Now one of the reasons
that there is a huge variation
and the performance
Consider the latency to do
of the most common I/O medium
and a common Wi-Fi network.
As you'll notice here, the
from a couple of milliseconds to
on the I/O medium
And the reason I/O
that the I/O performance of your
on user experience.
Latency variations in your
as responsiveness issues.
Since I/O is a shared
your app's I/O performance
system performance.
And as we'll see shortly,
I/O significantly impacts the
Now to help you reason about
we've come up with our
and the I/O philosophy
Reduce the amount of I/O
use the right thread to do
and efficient API's to do
test and measure your
As we move through rest of the
of them in further detail.
Now the best way to
of your application is to reduce
Every I/O operation interacts
with multiple hardware
Here's a simple block diagram
of its competence and their
When your app is using I/O,
accesses memory, and
to or from the disk.
If the network is involved,
the network-based radios
The combined power cost of all
of these competents makes
in terms of battery usage.
Since I/O has such an adverse
of the device, let's
of best practices you can
of I/O in your application.
And the first one is caching.
The main idea here is to
of your data rather than going
out of the disk for
To decide if your data
in your application,
at the access patterns
Data which is frequently
or updated might
to cache in your application.
Also, data which [inaudible]
from the disk needs an expensive
decompressing an image file
of data you should cache.
Having said that, you should
between memory and I/O.
Just like I/O, memory is a
in the system, and
in your user [inaudible].
If you do decide to create
we would recommend
since they handle memory
appropriately for you.
The next best practice
and the main idea here is to
more suitable time
Due to the way I/O
fewer I/O's are always more
One of the ways to do that is
to use the application app
for example, application
to schedule your I/O's.
On macOS, you can use the
API's to schedule your
and the system will figure
out an optimal time
To learn more about these API's,
at WWDC 2014 talk Writing
Now that we've taken a look
to reduce the amount of
I'd like to introduce our
and I have been working on,
for the rest of the talk
to demonstrate the
of these best practices.
And that app is called ImageBox.
ImageBox is our amazing
that lets you add
For each image, it
shows you associated
or whether it has
with the particular image.
When you tap on a
to a detailed view, which
as a favorite, unfavorited,
Now that we've created
if our app is I/O
in terms of I/O performance.
So I'm going to talk about
to decide this for
and the tool is the
So let's see how that works.
In order to use that tool,
simply run your project
This launches the
on the device or the simulator.
Click on the Xcode
Now this shows you live data
about all the system resources
You have CPU, memory,
Since we're interested in the
of our application, let's
Once you do that, you notice
about the reads and writes
and it looks like our
of writes every few seconds even
to it.
Now to investigate this further,
and use instruments to
So let's go ahead and click
and hit the restart button.
Once you do that, instruments
that you can choose from for
And since we're interested
of our application, we go ahead
and select system usage,
Doing that opens a new
ready to record the I/O
So let's go ahead
As you now notice in
this template shows you
by our application which does,
It shows other useful
and requested number of bytes
and the file path
I'll go ahead and stop
Now in order to find out the
in the Xcode debug
by the actual number of bytes
and identify the large
Once we have that,
into the extended detail viewer
of the piece of code doing
It looks like it's our
Double clicking on that takes
which shows you the exact block
If you click on the Xcode
it takes you back to Xcode
of code doing these
So let's take a look at this
and the code in question
of the application
delegate method.
As part of its implementation,
we create a new timer
schedule it to file
and as part of the event
we write out our
Now a lot of us write code
to make sure that the
out consistently and regularly.
However, there's a more I/O
and to fix this code,
that we'll do is eliminate the
So let's get rid of that.
Instead, we create a new method
which is culled from
in the application
to the to the data store.
As part of this implementation,
we push out the timer
by 15 seconds into the future.
This way, we collect all updates
for our application's data
out into the future and
Once the timer eventually
it has basically
that were frequently
out as a single I/O operation.
So let's see what these code
We run the application again
Go to the debug navigator
to find the I/O activity.
As you'll notice here that the
writes anymore.
Since it's completely idle and
with it, this is
We've effectively
that our application does, and
Now that we've taken
of best practices you can use
let's take a look at what
to do these I/O's, and for that,
I'd like to invite
Terry.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Kushal.
So we just saw some great
in your applications to
battery life.
Now let's move on to the second
I'll explain some ways
and queues effectively
for great I/O performance
Every thread or every
with a single thread
This thread is special, and
The first purpose of the main
So if I tap on a button
the main thread is
that input and responding to it.
Additionally, the main
for updating your interface.
This is for doing things
doing layout, or animating.
When your main thread is
to respond to input or
But if you're doing other
such as executing lengthy
like expensive image
of work keeps your
which means it won't be idle,
to input, or update your UI.
Additionally, what
you should avoid doing
As we've already seen, I/O is an
that needs to be
If you're doing I/O
someone using your application
The first example
Someone may see the
The spinning cursor indicates
and that you won't be able to
Additionally, on iOS, a
as a frozen or just
And, lastly, doing I/O on your
for animations.
For example, if I do a
in my application and then do
in more data, the time that
that I/O is time that it doesn't
which can cause issues
I'd like to mention, again,
out earlier, Performance
This talk also has
about using your main
Now I'd like take a look at our
this time running on macOS.
I've been noticing an issue
to the main collection view.
So let's take a look.
First from Xcode, I'll
Xcode launches my application,
and then I'll click
on the right side
Then I'll select an image from
As you can see, the open
and we see the spinning cursor.
Eventually, the open panel
that we selected shows up
So what might be going on here?
Well, as we already saw, the
that your main thread is busy.
So something must be running
on the main thread that's
So we won't be able to
We need to figure out what's
we can use instruments.
Back in Xcode, we can choose
Xcode recompiles our
and then launches instruments.
This time, I'll choose the time
Time profiler is great
for seeing how much
of your code are
So we can use this to figure
Now I'll click choose, and
blank time profiler document.
By default, instruments time
while the CPU is
Other things like I/O aren't
The CPU's just waiting
So to also see those
in our instruments trace,
on the record waiting
under the record settings.
Now instruments will also show
things like waiting on I/O.
So let's get started and
in instruments.
Instruments launches
and then I'll take the same
to reproduce the problem.
First, clicking the add button,
selecting an image,
Again, we see the issue.
So now we can hit
and see what's going on.
Before I continue, I'd like
in this output by focusing just
and not any other
And to do that, first, I can
on the right side
Then click on hide
Now instruments will only
and not any other
that I might be calling.
So now let's take a look at the
Instruments shows all
in my application,
that they're spending executing.
In this case, we know that we're
So I can expand the
and find the heaviest stack.
In this case, I can see that
in our application, which
on our data store.
That add method is then
out to disk.
And instrument shows us
that saving is taking
and that's really bad.
I happen to know that this
out a pretty big Plist, and
to the problem.
Kushal will mention some
on how we can optimize
so that this is really fast,
on how we can fix this problem
that operation takes,
our application is still
To do that, let's take
Here I have the open
It's waiting for a response.
Once it receives that response,
that points to a valid image.
Then it creates a new item
from the image and tries to
If that was successful, it
to reload its data so
that we just selected.
As we saw earlier, and what
calling that add method is
out all that data to disk.
So let's see how
To recap, our application
The main thread is running
That callback then calls the
and this is where we
Once that work is done,
we finally update our
and this is obviously
This entire time, the
and we can't interact
and we can't update any UI.
So one way that we
by using Grand Central
With GCD, we can create
Dispatch queues are a way
to run code concurrently
We can use this to move our
onto this queue, leaving
To do that, we can call the
and push that expensive work
onto our queue rather
Finally, since UI related
on the main thread,
we can asynchronously
to finally update
And now this is exactly
Now the expensive I/O work is
which leaves the main thread
to interact with the application
Let's see what this looks like
Here I have the same open
To get started, first I can
and provide a descriptive label.
In this case, I've created a
of my data store operations.
Next, we can move the
that image onto this queue by
to the async method
Finally, to update our UI,
we can call dispatch
and pass it in a block that
Now that we've done that,
like if we rebuild and run
So first I'll click the run
to launch, and then try
Click the add button,
from the open panel,
As you can see, the open
and we can continue
and adding more and more images.
You'll also notice that I've
in the main view.
This is just to give
that we're currently
and saving it out to disk.
Once all that data is done
all the images show up in
and now this entire time,
which means their application
and that's exactly what we want.
So now that we've moved that
to a dispatch queue, we should
intent of that work so it can
and to do that, we can use
of service.
Quality of service is a way
of the work that
so that it can properly manage
It manages these resources among
on the system and
within your own application.
When thinking about
keep in mind three attributes of
The visibility, importance,
Ask yourself three questions.
Is the work that you're
to someone using
Secondly, what is the
Is that work required
to complete before someone can
And, lastly, how long is
Is this something that happens
that you might assume takes
Before I continue, I'd
from last year's WWDC
and Efficient Apps with GCD.
This talk goes into a lot
to use quality of service,
and I highly recommend
So once we've thought about
of our work, we're
of the four quality
The first quality of service
User interactive is
This is for doing
to input and animating.
All other work that
from the main thread
of the other three quality of
of those is user initiated.
User initiated work is visible
to someone using
and they're expecting immediate
They probably also
to complete before they
with your application.
A good example of that is if
to a new view, I may need
on a different queue in
and that work should be
The third quality of
Utility quality of service is
that have progress bars or
This work generally takes
and it's something
to someone using
A good example of this
This is something that doesn't
to use your application,
to take a longer amount
And the final quality of
Background work is not visible
to someone using
In fact, they may not even
A good example of
Indexing is usually
of your application,
that someone using
All of these quality of
because if you, when you choose
it helps inform the system
so that less important work
and indexing doesn't adversely
like animating, even if
in a different process.
So once we've chosen from one of
there are two main ways that you
in your applications,
by supplying an optional QOS
on the dispatch queue.
In this case, I've
This means that when
of code is running
it will be using the
Additionally, if you're
or operation API's, both
of service property that you
So now that we know a little
and how we can specify
to our ImageBox application,
and see if we can choose
of service for adding images.
And to do that, we can think
of this work: The visibility,
Well, adding an image is
to someone using
but it's not necessarily
to complete before we can
like browsing images
Additionally, because we are
we've given an indication
that could take a
For all of those reasons,
of service may be an appropriate
So now that we know some ways
that you can move
off of your main thread and
and how to specify the intent
of that work using
Let's take a look at the third
adopting appropriate API's,
like to mention is
If you're not already aware,
to easily manage resources in
They're used to store
and launch images and
for the different devices that
like retina or non-retina.
When building games
Asset Catalogs are also the way
And you can use Asset Catalogs
with the on-demand
And another good example of how
for storing resources for
So why are Asset
Well, Asset Catalogs
efficiency properties.
First of all, because
of their images in a single
than many individual files,
you can have a lower
by using Asset Catalogs.
Additionally, with features
when you download an
it uses the metadata in your
which resources it should
For example, if I download
the App Store knows
to download any resources for
with different screen
and this can save a lot
Furthermore, Asset Catalogs
Because of this optimized
image loading can be faster.
And if you're using them to make
since cheap user much better
at managing a single
than many tiny resources,
these Sprites Atlases
rendering times.
And, lastly, if you're
on hard-drive machines
you can also improve
In fact, we've seen up to
in app launch time on
by switching to Asset Catalogs.
And you might be thinking to get
such a big performance
this must be difficult or
to Asset Catalogs, but, in fact,
if you're already using
and UI image based API's,
switching to Asset
and I'd like to demonstrate that
Here I have a project
yet adopted Asset Catalogs.
To get started, first
from the file menu.
Then, from the resource
select Asset Catalog
Xcode creates a new, sorry.
When prompted, enter a name
for your Asset Catalog
Then you can click create,
and now Xcode creates a
in your project.
To move all of your existing
into this new Asset Catalog,
at the bottom of the screen,
Xcode displays a list of all
and when I click import,
into my new empty Asset Catalog.
Xcode automatically
for which devices and
Now when I rebuild
it will be using this new
It took less than a
to change a single line of code.
So it's really easy, and
to adopt Asset Catalogs
One more thing I'd
with Asset Catalogs is
and that's image compression.
By default, images in your
but new this year, you
of the lossy image
These formats have hardware
So they're really fast,
and because of the compressed
in lower memory footprints.
If you have a lot of
you may benefit from
and space savings by
So let's see how we can
in the project that I just
First, let's click on
Then open the utility sidebar
And then click on the
New in Xcode is a
When I select that,
of the available image
In this case, I'll
so that Xcode can choose
So that's a little bit about
in your applications,
and use the new image
Now I'd like to hand
who's going to tell you
that you can adopt
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Terry.
Asset catalogs are an
to manage your app's assets.
Another thing that a lot
and where our application
A lot of us are familiar with
For example, Plists,
The reason these data
because of their
and they have been made popular
in a lot of web-based services.
These data formats are good
such as configuration
in your Info.plist file.
However, they are
and the biggest reason
that minor updates to these
file to be written
which is really bad
For all your data storage needs,
we would recommend using Apple
core data.
Core data is the, is a Cocoa
framework for managing
It handles your data persistence
by using SQLite as
It automatically manages
and relationships between
to manage your data
It also does change tracking,
and redo operations
And core data is
with the Xcode tool chain
and visualize your data model
Now that we're aware of this
to use for designing or
let's think about how to
And the best way to do that
on the UI needs of
Let's go back to ImageBox,
which up until now has been
out all the files and
with the application,
and instead move it
Now if you think
there are two main
The first is the list
in the collection view, and
with each of these items.
So let's go ahead and put
And the first table is BoxItem,
which represents a particular
and the second table is notes,
which represents
The BoxItem table
which represents whether the
and contains the full
that you need to represent.
The Notes table contains a note
with the BoxItem, and we relay
one is too many relationship.
Now when we use this data model
of our application, we noticed
that the app launch
We investigated using
out that app was spending most
of its time fetching the core
So we need to take a look at
from core data's
luckily core data
It has a set of tools that let
doing on your behalf.
For example, you can
on your application which
with a velocity level that
interacting with its
The core data instruments
[inaudible] patterns
and loading too much data.
And, lastly, the standard set
for example, explain
which lets you dive deep
and find out its performance.
To learn more about these tools,
I would recommend you watching
in Core Data.
Now that we have these tools,
out what's wrong
In order to do that,
and click edit scheme.
In the window that opens,
we're going to select
and then add a new argument
at the highest velocity
Once you are done with that,
And now we simply launch our
This should rebuild
and launch the application.
As you'll notice here, the
from core data about
in terms of the data model.
Another thing you
that the app is taking
and it still hasn't
We see some more data from core
finally, the app launches.
If you go back to the Xcode
of these logs and figure
out what was wrong
So let's go ahead and do
Now one of the first
that core data is doing
from the SQLite database for
that is exactly what we expect.
However, the next log tells us
that that fetch took almost nine
and one of the biggest reasons
Now if you go back to the
to fetch all this data,
that we are fetching the full
of the items in the BoxItem
thumbnail images on
Moving on, we also notice
between the BoxItem
for every item it fetches
And the reason it's
because there is a one
between these two entities,
in the launch screen
to represent whether
with the BoxItem.
So let's go ahead and
The first thing we'll
between these two tables,
and the reason the core data
because it needs to show the,
for whether notes are present
So to improve this model, we
to the BoxItem table, which
The presence or absence or
of this particular field
to put a UI badge on
The next problem with
that we were fetching the
at the launch screen.
So let's go ahead and fix that.
We replace the image
and instead move the full
into a table of its own,
by a simple one is
Now as lot of you know, these
and it might be a good
as a separate file on the file
in the SQLite database.
So we're going to replace the
of the database itself
and store the images
Now let's look at the
of our application once
Again, we run the
with the new data model that
As you saw there, the
to five times faster just
So basing your data model
on your UI needs has significant
and overall performance
Now that we've taken a
and optimize the amount of
let's see how you can test
One of the things we
on a variety of devices.
If your app shifts on this,
it might be a good idea to test
of devices from all
Even if your app shifts
it might be a good idea to
because I/O characteristics
Now another thing that can
and probably your app user
condition, and to help you
or the worst-case
we provide a tool called
In order to get to the
open the settings app, scroll
to the developer settings,
which brings you to this menu.
Now as you see here, we have
and tapping on that
which shows various kinds
of profiles you can
We have 3G, high latency DNS,
and my favorite,
So let's go ahead and use that
and enabling it with using
And that's it.
Your device will now behave as
and you can test your
Another factor to remember is
that I/O is a shared
So the I/O performance of your
by other system resources
or other I/O's happening
For example, if there
that are running
your app's I/O performance
So it's a good idea to
in the presence of other apps.
Also, the system tries to
between its memory
and under memory
your I/O latencies
So we would recommend
under memory pressure
Lastly, the system maintains
on your behalf to
and store your data better.
The state of these caches
and I/O performance
And to test the worst-case
we would recommend rebooting
and on macOS, you can
which flushes all these caches
and simulates worst-case
To make sure that
against all these
we recommend following
to reduce an optimize
So here are some key
Reduce the amount of I/O's
since that significantly
Move your I/O heavy workload
that main thread idle
Specify proper quality of
of work you're performing.
Switch to Asset Catalog
and efficient way to
Use core data for all your
test and measure your
For more information,
and the session ID is 719.
Here is some related sessions
that you can refer to for
and tools we mentioned.
And thanks for your time.