[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
So I'm going to talk to you
to structure your programs
and what we've done this year
My name is Matt.
I'm going to be joined
We're both on the Darwin
So when you create a new
to have something that looks
You have your application.
That application
That main thread is responsible
that powers your user interface.
As you start to add code to
to find the performance of
quite drastically.
For instance, if you start to
say data transforms or image
you're going to find
suffers drastically.
On macOS, this can be the
On iOS, it could be
Your user interface
or maybe even stop entirely.
So I'm going to take you
to struct your application to
And later on in the talk, Pierre
through some more
So how do we deal with
We have to start by
of concurrency to
Concurrency allows multiple
to run at the same time.
On our system, you achieve
A CPU core can execute one of
but the payoff for
the penalty for introducing
to your application is
to maintain your thread safety.
The other threads that you've
effects of you breaking your
performing operations
This becomes a bit of a problem.
So how can we help?
Well, GCD is the concurrency
It helps you write code,
on everything from
through all of our iOS devices.
Apple TVs and all
So in order to help you
we introduce some abstractions
That is, dispatch
A dispatch queue is a construct
of work to that queue.
In Swift, this is closures.
And dispatch will
and service that work for you.
And when dispatch is finished
on that thread, it can tear
that worker thread
As I said before, you can
and on those threads,
And then finally, on the first
thread, and the main
It gets both a main run
So dispatch queues have two main
for them, the first of which
This is where you can queue
to your dispatch queue,
will bring up a thread
Dispatch will one by
that queue and execute them.
And then when it's finished
the system will reclaim
that it bought up for you.
The second mode of execution
This is where, for instance,
as we had before,
with some asynchronous work.
But you have your own
to run code on that queue
You can submit that work
and then that's where
It will wait there until
to execute has completed.
We might add some more
and then dispatch will
to service the items
Again, the asynchronous
and then when it comes time
that you've asked to run.
The dispatch queue will pass
that was waiting, execute
of the dispatch queue
to a worker thread
It will continue to drain the
and then also reclaim the
So now I've shown you how
to dispatch.
How do we use that to help
had earlier?
What we want to do is get the
causing you to block
and we do that by taking
on that main thread and
So you can take the
with a dispatch queue.
And now when you want
you can move the value of that
on the other queue,
and then send it back
This allows you to perform
that work while the main thread
So what does that look
Well, it's really simple.
So first of all, you can
to submit your work to by just
It takes a label, and that
as you're writing
Dispatch queues execute
in first in, first out order.
That is, the order that
to the queue is the order that
And then you can use the async
to submit work to that queue.
So now that we've actually
here to a different
that back to the main thread?
That's very simple too.
The dispatch main queue
that you execute on it on
This means you can just
and then call async
and that code will execute,
and you can update your
As you can see, it's very simple
to another queue and back
So now we've seen how to
and put it on different threads.
It comes at somewhat of a cost.
You have to control a
The thread pool that dispatch
you achieve in order to use all
However, when you
if you wait for other parts of
in sys calls those
that are blocked can cause
Dispatch is trying to give you
by giving you a new thread to
This means it's very important
of dispatch queues to
Otherwise, you can
Another thread will come up,
and you will block
And this pattern is something
We covered thread
in last year's talk,
and Efficient Apps with GCD.
So I recommend you go back
So now we've seen how
like getting work off of the
But how do we actually apply
Well, if we go back to
what you want to do is identify
with independent data flow.
So as we've seen, it
or you might have a database.
You want to take those
into distinct subsystems,
to back those subsystems
This will give each subsystem
on independently without
of having too many queues
And we saw a couple of
to chain work together.
That is where you can
and then to another queue,
and then back to,
But there's a second
that we feel is equally useful.
That is grouping work and
If you have a single
to spawn multiple different
to make progress if
when those work items is
And in order to do that,
So if we do back to the
if the user interface spawns off
you can create a dispatch group.
Dispatch groups are here
and they're very simple
You just create a
And now when you submit work to
as an optional parameter
You can add more work to
to different queues,
but associate it
And each time you
the group will increment
that it's expecting to complete.
Then finally, once you've
you can ask the group
that work is finished,
so on a queue that
So now one by one, these
and as they execute the count
in the group will
item completes.
And when, finally, the last
the group will go ahead and
to the queue that
So here, we submitted
to the main queue, and it
Now there's a third pattern
These two have been asynchronous
to deal with synchronous
You can use synchronous
to help you serialize
Serial queues, dispatch
And you can use this for its
That is, when you submit work
you know the work that
on that queue isn't
You can use this to build
to the thread safe
from your subsystem
So for instance, here
and you can return a
and we will capture that value
to you as that work
However, you have to be
to introduce this
to introduce a lock ordering
Now, what does that mean?
Well, if you have the subsystems
from one place to another
and then finally, you end up
Well, now we have a deadlock.
Pierre's going to come and talk
about deadlocks later
So now we've seen a bit how
in your application as a whole.
How can we also apply it to
Well, you can use dispatch
that you submit, and to do so,
we need to introduce
These are classes that provide
of the work that you are
So it allows you as the
of the code that you are
And dispatch can use that to
that you've given us.
That is, the code
at a different CPU priority,
different IO scheduling
And we covered QoS in detail in
Building Responsive and
So how do we actually
Well, it's as simple
You can pass the
as another optional parameter.
So here, we're submitting
And if you come along later
at a higher QoS, dispatch will
inversion that's created.
That is, it will raise the
on the dispatch queue
so that they execute quicker
and you actually get
through as quickly
However, it's important
this doesn't help your
All that does here is elevate
so it executes as quickly as
And then you can also
that have a specific QoS class.
This is very helpful,
if you have background work
at background, you
that executes all
And when you submit
that's the QoS that we'll get.
So on a more granular
to a dispatch queue, it
at the point where you async.
Now, execution context
It also means the login
But if you want more
you can use DispatchWorkItem
where you have more control
For instance, here we're
with assignCurrentContext,
of the execution context at the
rather than the time
to your dispatch queue.
This means you can create
and when you do finally
to dispatch with the properties
And now while we're
there's another part that's very
and that is waiting
You can use the wait method on
to dispatch that you
to complete before
Dispatch will respond by
of work ahead of
like it did with priority
And it can do this because
where it was submitted, which
And therefore, dispatch knows
in order to get your
And it's very important to
on Semaphores and
ownership information.
This means if you wait on
to cause the things in front
to execute any quicker.
And now I'd like to invite
He's going to take you through
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Matt.
So with Matt, we've
from the perspective
I will walk you through more
But first, a note about Swift.
Synchronization is not part
You only have one grand key
which is that your
initialized atomically.
But what you don't have is
that your class properties are
of your classes aren't
What that means is that if
in our initialize
your lazy initializer
So you have to synchronize.
The language doesn't give us
but that doesn't mean that
There is no such thing
What that means for you is
that if you forget a
you will end up with crashes
of the user of your apps.
I invite you to go
that happened earlier this week
about T San, which
Which is a tool that
in your app you're missing
So what do we use
Traditionally you
And in Swift, since you have
at your disposition, you will
traditional C locks.
However, Swift assumes
that is taught can be
with a mutex or with a lock.
So we really discourage you
from using these kind
If you want to a traditional
is Foundation.Lock, because
based C locks, it's a class,
of the problems I
However, suddenly that means
that you're locating
which may be undesirable
And if you want something
like the locks that you have
into Objective-C and introduce
that has your lock as an ivar.
And then you will expose
and a try lock if you need it
to call from Swift when you
You will notice on that slide
It's a new API that
It's not prone to
It doesn't spin, unlike the
It's most important
That being said, this is a GCD
to do is to use dispatch queues
The first reason why is that
to misuse than a
Your code will run
which means that you
The other thing is that
integrated with the run time
So how do we use
I will walk you through
of implementing an
So here we have this object
that we want to access
We will use a queue
How do we write our
The getter is just
about returning this
It gives us mutual exclusion.
Matt talked about this earlier.
And the setter is as simple.
You will just set your new
of sync and your queue.
This pattern is pretty simple,
to products significantly
I told you that queues
with your debugging tools.
They also have more features.
And new in this release, we
It lets you express that you
that really need to hang
and you had that this way.
A dispatch precondition
Sometimes the opposite
You want to make sure that a
on that queue, because you
with that queue, and you express
that you're not in the queue.
So that's about synchronization,
And as Matt said
if you can just organize
that your passing
that don't need synchronization
However, in real life code, you
from simple, obvious subsystems.
What that means is that
reference in these
of them actually
I will now walk you through
that will help you get
up with weird crashes that
Your state machine starts
Setup is about creating
and giving it the property you
Second, you will want
What that means is that you
known to other subsystems.
You start using it in
in performance duties.
And then the hard part starts.
You want to get rid
And so the third
Invalidation is about making
all your subsystems know that
so that, fourth, it
So let's look back.
Setup, activation,
This is quite abstract,
through a more concrete example
Let's go back to the application
and focus on two
First, we have our
which will handle stuff such
And I will assume that you
of state changes in your
for example, for our
when it starts performing
we present a visual
And then when the data transform
that visual indication
So how do we implement
So we remember the
Setup is about you picking
for your code, and the
That's really up to you.
Then we'll want to
and that's activation.
We activate it.
What does that mean
What that means is that we want
to start receiving these
state changes notifications,
with that subsystem, and
to be received on
We're doing UI we want to
Now that it's activated,
That you want to do.
That's your animation.
That's your very nice
But then, there are
that maybe don't need
or that maybe don't use the
and you want to reclaim the
and you want to get rid of it.
It's very tempting
the main thread is
that really owns
so I will get rid of it
and register it from
and hope for the best.
That doesn't work,
through two examples of why.
So let's step back a bit.
Our BusyController is
from the main queue and
However, when we registered it
with the data transform
that reference was taken
onto this object, which means
of the reference that
there's still one left, which
which means that it
it doesn't get collected,
and you end up with
However, you're very
and you know how to fix that.
Weak references, and I
However, that's not
because this is not really
The graph object is
It's not uncommon to have
and a whole bunch
such as this octopus
We will continue getting rid
of that reference
And unlike before, this
because this octopus object
But then, if we get rid of that
of the data transform
It will get rid of that
on the BusyController,
will run beyond discretion,
And then you have a problem,
that to do that you
with the dispatch queue that
And you guessed it, we
Actually, that bug is so common
that we've made it an
If you run that code on the
and on OS X or in the simulator,
the crash report you get
application specific information
that actually points you toward
so that you can fix it easily.
Okay, so now we know
to unregister from deinit.
How do we fix that?
We fix that by having our
be an explicit function call.
And under this invalidation,
Also, since we have
because this object,
really should be managed from
to make sure that users of
So you will want to
that this only happens
or the main queue, even.
But that's not quite it.
We have a last problem.
Remember, this all
and you have this subsystem,
who is sending you
and you may have some
at the time you're invalidating.
How do we resolve that?
Well, you want to track
And what does that mean?
Well, just what it is.
You want to track invalidation,
in your object, and you
At the same time, let's
and make sure, enforce,
that before your
it has been properly
It will help you find bugs.
Why is it interesting?
Because now, in your code
for the state transitions,
that the object was invalidated
and actually drop the
and update the UI in a
Okay, that was quite
However, I hope that you
at your applications and your
where this pattern will help
of your code, and
It should also not
given that we're giving you
whose purpose in life is
follow exactly the same pattern.
So let's look at the GCD
So we remember the
Setup for dispatch objects
when you build the object and
Matt already showed labels
And here, we also have
where we monitor all the
Sources also have handlers,
and the event handler
that will run when the resource
and that is events pending.
For the resource that
that's when there is
Once you've set up your
you want to use it
New in this release, we've made
that step an API
It used to be that
the initial resume had
We've actually now
and activation be two
Also in resume activate can
and it only acts once.
The contract however is that
you won't mutate the properties
We've also found that creating
creating them initially
and we've added a new attribute
and is actually named
Once the queue is created, you
configure it the way you like,
Many of the dispatch objects
invalidation, such
because they become
of you stopping using them.
However, the story is quite
and sources have an
It's called Cancel.
Cancellation in sources does
which is that you
for the thing you're monitoring.
But it's not only that it does.
The second thing it
up a cancellation handler on
it will run on the target of
It is actually where you want
that you're monitoring,
frame memory.
Last, but not least,
when your handlers
Handlers are closures.
They capture via subjects
They can be part of
Calling cancellation is how you
It's why it's very important
So you remember a bit earlier,
in our code, because
that concurrently used
in a way that you can expect.
Dispatch is no different,
and expects that at the time
it's in a different state,
and dispatch expects
First, that your
And second, that they
The reason why is that being
that you as a developer
to run the code associated with
to get rid of the object.
Okay. So we've seen today how
in terms of data flows and how
into fairly independent
for communication purposes.
If you need to synchronize
we also showed you how you can
And finally, when you
in a very heavily concurrent
and invalidation to
Here is a link that will show
with this talk.
And a few related sessions
with dispatch, you
because they are
And that's it.
It was Concurrency with GCD.
[ Applause ]