[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome all of you
and Tracing Activity session,
And I'd like to thank
out this late on a Friday.
So my name is Steve
[ Applause ]
Certainly, didn't expect
So my name is Steven Szymanski
of the talking and a little
by Matthieu Lucas.
So let's get into this, there's
I'm going to start with a
and then go into some
of the basic concepts behind
that we've introduced this week.
There will be a short demo, then
about how to actually use it.
How to use the APIs,
and then some discussion of what
of how to use this.
A little talk about how
to gather the logs once you've
some talk about some
So let's get started.
A little bit of background.
For those of you who have been
that back in 2014,
Apple introduced the
This is the ability to
that is done throughout
on behalf of some operation.
Whether that work is done
inside of a library of
from that application
in a separate process on
Another thing we introduced at
of Faults and Errors, which
that will trigger additional
to collect additional data.
The last thing I
of introduction is we recognize
that Apple has several logging
by the end of this talk you'll
this new API and how that
So what are the goals
First and foremost,
to do was build one common
across the whole system
in both user mode
One of the purposes of this
of information that we could
observer effect.
By observer effect I mean
of us have had as developers
you stick some logging
and suddenly the
because you've changed
We want a very, very low
that has minimal impact on your
So the way we accomplish
into more detail in this talk.
First off, we compress the data.
So you can fit a whole lot
without using up more space.
Another thing we do that's very,
very important is we
As anything that we
at which you display the
at which we collect it we
That's one of the key ways
And then another thing we do is
in new ways.
The idea being that different
around in the system for
to maximize the chance
that you want will
when you actually go
The background of all that is
as much logging turned on
without having to go back and
and give me a new log.
We want it all on
The other thing that
to design privacy into the
and I'll talk more
So what are the key
There's new and improved
and filtering log messages.
So there's some new tools that
to you for you to
so when it comes around to
to find log messages
Another important thing is
information for you, so there's
to pass file, line to identify
We are automatically
[ Applause ]
There's also a whole bunch of
that allow us to format binary
to spend the time doing it.
There's a new Console
and a new command
to access all of these features.
This is supported across all
watchOS, tvOS, and
It is supported in the
and Objective-C and support
So to give you a little
This is the current Console
and this is what the
Now one thing I want to point
out to you here is take a
that I highlighted there.
That is a tree showing you
as it flows from process
so you can see visually all
on behalf of some
So now let's back up and
and the abstract
First off, adoption.
If you want to use the new
need to start doing is
that was released this week.
What'll happen if you do that is
asl log, message syslog,
all of those will get
You don't have to
to start using the system.
Now obviously to use some
to start using the new APIs, but
with the new system
into the new logging
On the other hand, if for
to start using the new logging
with the old SDK and there'll
So new file formats.
In this new system
in a compressed binary
it's called a .tracev3 file.
Those files are now stored
with additional supporting
There are new tools
there's a new Console, a new
of the things you have
because the data is now stored
in a binary format you must
So you can no longer grep
to use our tools to do
There's also another new
which is there for
Essentially a .logarchive is
out of /var/db/diagnostics and
into a single file that's
to attach to bug
Another new concept that comes
in with this system is
Log messages can
with a subsystem and a category.
They can be used to control
and displayed.
A subsystem can in fact maintain
and you can use as
and categories as you need.
So as an example, you
and you might define
your-company.
your-application that has
inprogress and teardown.
In that same application you can
your-company.
test.your-application with a
And you can then use those
to control how the log
Logging behavior, this is kind
Each log message has a
that you used to create it.
There are three basic levels
and there are two special
Each basic level has
that can be set either
for a specific subsystem
or for a specific category
The first of those
if you make the call does it
Note that the fault
you can't turn off
The other characteristic
of those levels is, is it
Now storing to disk it's
but what I mean by
Well the new Unified Logging
of in-memory circular buffers
to which some log
These messages are then saved to
This is very useful for messages
So if you have a
that basically the
and all you ever look
of that message whenever you
to store hundreds
of that log message on disk.
Instead, send it to the memory
on a Fault and Error and
that you need without a lot of
The levels here are
by that is if you set Debug
that info will go
And all this behavior
by installing profiles or on
So what's the standard
if you don't install
Well, default level
and by standard configuration
Info level messages are
Debug level messages
they're not enabled
since they're off they
So the other two
that occur are Faults
Faults and Errors are always
So let's talk a moment
As you know, Apple values
As a guiding principle
in our apps, in our services, in
about their privacy respected.
And all developers, including
that responsibility with us.
So how does it apply to logging?
What we want to prevent
of personally identifiable
where someone can actually get
So to that end, dynamic strings,
and the like are assumed
Static strings and scalars
And I'll get into
about how you can control that.
Okay, Faults and Errors.
I talked earlier about how
of Tracing Release,
we introduced the concept
One of the basic ideas
that we do additional work
we save additional information.
So an Error represents
within the different
On an Error what
through the in-memory
of the log messages that were
out to disk as part
Alternatively, Faults
in the system where
On a Fault we again look through
up all the log messages from
that was involved
And we also we actually collect
information that
Faults and Errors and all of
as part of them are
into a separate set
We do that so that normal
and cause them to
and cause us to reclaim
So the idea is the Fault
around even longer than
So okay, I'm going to give a
of how the system works with a
So this is like a
Okay within each process there's
into which we log messages.
These buffers are actually
with the logging daemon.
As these buffers are filled up
to compress that data into a set
of larger buffers
As those larger buffers are
out to disk or we
of the memory only buffers.
So the other activity
if you request livestreaming
so you're on the Console
that are happening
The way we implement that
over to the diagnostic daemon
who then distributes those log
The side effect of that is
that there is a significant
of livestreaming of log data.
Basically, a lot of the work
and speed up logging so it
on your code goes away
on every single call.
The other thing to note is how
from applications or
through this can be changed
So enough of me talking
at this point I will
up to give a demonstration
in action using the Console app.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Steven.
So as Steven mentioned
this year we introduced
So we wrote it from
We wanted to leverage
and making your developing
Let's look at the app.
So here's the new look.
As you can see, the layout
You still have your mainstream
on top, and then different
Let's look at the
So you can still see your
or user reports, the
that you may have
But here you can see that
Now we display all the
to your machine and we also
So we support iOS, tvOS,
so you can plug every
So let's just look at the
So now the log stream
You have the messages view
as Steven mentioned earlier.
So in the activities view
activities and the related
in the details it tells
Let's switch to the
So here you can see
so in order to include Debug
to manually do it in the
up along the default stream.
So now we should see more
so let's create some logs.
So here now you can see that
So you can see the
through those color dots
So the gray one are
the yellow ones are the Errors,
and the dark gray
Whenever there is no dots
So you can also expand
or collapse your messages
or right arrows or using the
or Collapse.
Then whenever you are
on the single message you
of a specific message directly
in the details view
So we are able to show you all
about a specific log, that's
So now we can show
the library where it comes from.
So as you can see for this one,
from accounts D and then
You can also see
as we gather during
So you can see we have now
the activity ID, the
Now let's switch to the
So I connected an iPad where
that has some figures and we'll
through the different features.
So first, we can start by just
so to do so I can right
and then include or
So I'll just add the subsystem,
and then I will just
So this layout is
so you won't have
So now we can see
of information from this device.
So in order to refine your
to do it.
You can first right click
and then you'll get option
mute the process or
So in that case we
by muting a specific category.
Let's say that we
Now you can also the second way
of just refining is
So as you can see, we just
Let's say that I want to
that's the app that
So by doing so now I have only
without the category widgets.
Let's just add another token
So now we only have messages
without the category widgets
So we can see that we have
from the web view, so
we relate it down to
So in order to reuse it later
on the Save button
So I'll just name
So you can see that all your
in this section here.
So you can reorder those as
if you want and you also have
which are All Messages
Now let's switch to
if we can find more context
if we can reproduce [inaudible].
So here we can see that we
So the activities view is based
so we could apply
and then save it as well.
So here we can see that we
with different children.
So we can see that we were
then we retrieve an object and
and then we configure
and then we load the web view.
So as you can see now, the
in the bottom of this
that are related
So this message was written
in this specific activity,
Now we can see that
those two failures were part of
So now we know that we
of what happened to this Error.
So now we also added the
so you can just select a bunch
and share it directly
So I'll just add it as a note
Now the next.
[ Applause ]
The other input that we
So [inaudible] log archive
that was previously
So if you do have one too you
and Console will open it.
So as you can see whenever you
it just loads everything.
And then you can see that we
filters as we just said before.
So in order to see if this
same -- contain the same Error
that we stream we
and it will automatically
So we can see that we have the
at the activities view to see
So that's it for Console
and I'll let Steven
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So thank you very
I really like the new
So let's talk about the
and how you actually use it.
So to start off with
of all the new APIs
Os log is your basic logging API
that logs something
Os log info is the call that
into memory and that's for the
that you want to gather.
Os log debug is for your
And then there's os log
for generating a
And the last call
that creates a log
to customize your behavior.
So let's dive into that
because it's probably the one
of analogy to other stuff.
So we have a call os log
the name of the subsystem
And what it does is it creates
that controls the behavior
of the log calls
So by default it ends up having
but you can customize it to
profiles or the log
The way you use it is you simply
to all of the other calls.
So here I call os log and
which is the value that got
What that does is it causes
and subsystem that was
to be stored with every log
which then can be used
to filter and display messages.
So if you don't care about
and category, then
to simply pass an
which is a default log object
It doesn't have a subsystem
if you really don't care
Built-in type formatters.
We all spend way
to convert binary
so that we can log them.
The Unified Logging System takes
by providing built-in
What's even more
that conversion work until
so you don't have to
at the time you generate
Avoiding all of the different
So just to talk a
There's built-in decoding
The syntax is instead of doing
and that basically says
that you're passing in is
when it gets printed it should
Likewise, for errno, if you
that into a human readable
We also have a new basic time
P, which has been around
to display arbitrary
And there's decoders for
so for instance %(uuid t).
And in fact, here is a list
which we have, so all the
errno, uuids, all the
And we do anticipate having more
So Per Parameter Privacy.
Privacy is now handled on a
scalars and static strings
On the other hand, dynamic
and objects are assumed
to contain private information
So that behavior
on a per-parameter basis.
So instead of doing %@ to say
to include in my log
to tell us it's an
in that object is public, so you
Alternatively, if you
where you have some integer
that for some reason is secret
to log that data as being
You can by the way, combine
So I could do %(public,
uuid t).16P to basically
it's public information and
So let's give a little
of what the difference this
So log message simplification.
Okay, here's the old
All right, first off
and say is the current log level
and then let's say you have a
Well the first thing you
to convert that into a string.
You also happen to have a socket
to also convert into a string.
Then you call NSLog with all
that stuff that's been
you have to pass the
and the line number for you.
And then when you're done
to free the string that was
And you're done.
Now here's the new way.
You simply call os
of checking the log
In this case I'm passing
I specify in my format string
and a socket address, so I
None of the work happens now the
And then I simply pass the
[ Applause ]
While I'm doing examples let
of an example of using
So here I do a log create
and I specify a subsystem
The subsystem is
and the category is general
and so this is my
I do the same thing, but
with a category timestamp.
You know, the basic
I use the general log object,
pass it a string,
Here's a little bit more
I call os log info, so this is
into the memory buffer
if there's a Fault or an Error.
And then in my format
for the filename because the
and we would assume that it's
tell us that it's public.
A little bit more
I open the file, I
if it returns an error
and in my format
that the filename is
to format the errno as an errno.
Another very example, this
but gee I'm calling fstat after
so maybe something
if I'm getting an error on that.
So I call os log fault,
And then the very last
but this time I pass
and then I basically dump all
What that means is
at the Console I can
and say all I want to see
or I don't want to see
because I'm looking
So the new Unified Logging
in this release.
There are also some improvements
Activities are now
that can be stored and re-used.
And the act of creation
over the relationships between
at the point at which
There's also some new APIs
that scope the activities
So here's all of the new APIs.
So there's a new os activity
like os log create to create a
identifying an activity.
There's two calls that
that to your code os activity
I'll show you examples
about how they work differently.
And finally, there's os
that labels an activity
as a user action UI-based
So let me give an
First off, I call os activity
that I'm calling init.
Notice that the second parameter
of this function is a
That's basically saying this
to whatever happens to
Now I go off and do os activity
but my second parameter is the
So now I've created
between these activities
So now I have a block of
and then I have some code
The first thing I do is
and I'm passing in this
What that does is it means
in that block is considered
until I hit that closing brace.
There's no need to have to
at the end it just
And as soon as you leave
that scope you're now no
The other call that we're
you pass the activity object
and then it basically
with that activity as the scope.
Tools, so Matthieu already
of the new Console,
through the functionality
You can view live
You can open log archives.
You can use the new activity
You can use advanced
and you can see logs
Now let me talk a little bit
about the new log
It provides all of the same
but from the command line.
So you want to stream live
log stream.
If you want to get fancy,
predicate eventMessage contains
for you is it will stream
that contain the
Just like the Console it could
You can display a log
You do log show and then
and it displays the
Another thing you can do on
to actually change
of your subsystems
So here's an example,
mode level:debug and then
and what that does is it
on that subsystem for
So coming soon.
We do appreciate that
to be developing applications
with macOS 10.11 on your
Tools for being able to access
in fact coming, but in the
of a hackish workaround, which
from inside the simulator.
So xcrun simctl spawn booted
and then you give log show
and you can run all
like you would otherwise.
The alternative is
[ Applause ]
So let me talk a moment
about best practices,
Try to ensure that your messages
information, don't have
or filler data in there.
Try to keep it compact.
Let us do the formatting,
leverage the built-in
The more work you do
in advance the more that's going
to letting us do the
at which it gets output.
Avoid wrapping os log
If you wrap it in another
ability to collect the file
If you absolutely have to
in macros and not in functions.
Only log what's needed from
Dictionaries, I mean
They take up a lot of space on
to pushing out other log
Try to only log the parts
really need for your logs.
And avoid logging in
So a brief word on what
of our new APIs are.
Os log to log basically
on logging information.
This is the kind of information
to help debug your problem.
Use os log info for
that is very, very timely.
So use this first
to get stale very, very quickly.
Use os log debug for high volume
Error in the case that you want
and captured for your app.
And fault if you want additional
about the system.
A quick word on gathering logs.
Sydiagnose is the
to capture data for bug reports.
If you do sysdiagnose
in the system I've just
within that archive as a file
You can use key-chords
If you do a sysdiagnose on an
on both the watch
And then you can use iTunes
over to your Mac to
This is the file that Apple
from you when you talk
So either attaching it to
to developer technical support.
So here's the various
Shift + Control + Option
for Mac OS.
Volume up + Volume
On the phone you'll get a slight
On watchOS it's press and
and side button for
If you don't present it long
screenshot instead.
There will be a slight haptic
Play/Pause + Volume Down tvOS.
Note that on older remotes
to actually hold it down
Deprecations, so as part
that we're going to
First off, all of the ASL
by these new APIs
those old APIs are deprecated.
There is an interesting
A new API for searching
to be made public
What that means is that
to asl search functionality.
If you absolutely depend on
that may be a reason to wait for
There's also some
that are being deprecated.
Instead of doing
and os activity end we now have
as I showed you and then
to apply it to a block of code.
Os activity breadcrumb
with os activity user label.
Os trace with payload
by any of the os log calls.
Note that these functions as
So if you continue calling
to do anything.
So in summary, the new logging
and gives you more control,
but it does require using
Related sessions, I've
in 2014 Activity
in which we talk about that.
So if you want go
And if you want to
about this talk, that's the URL.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]