[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, and welcome
on developing CarPlay Systems.
My name is Emily,
for Car Experience
CarPlay was designed from
safer way to use your
CarPlay takes the
with your iPhone while
on your car's built-in display.
CarPlay brings the
and interaction patterns
Users already know how
because they know how
CarPlay is about more
on the car's display.
CarPlay is thoughtfully
with your car's built-in system
to deliver the best
CarPlay allows you to
With CarPlay, you can
and when Apple introduces
users will immediately
Your car will remain fresh
Today we'll give you an overview
of how the CarPlay
and discuss the most
for you to consider.
We'll explain the user
to enable with CarPlay
that we've provided.
At the end, we'll talk about
IPhone user interface is
when held in the hand, when
CarPlay translates that
making it appropriate in that
It works with what you
It's comfortable to use
Now let's talk about how
Let's start with the native
When an iPhone is plugged in,
When a CarPlay session
information is sent
communication protocols.
Video can be sent
to the car as well as audio.
Audio can also be sent from the
Once a CarPlay session
different combinations of
When a CarPlay Home
and no audio is playing, the
for setup and location
An H264 video stream showing
from the iPhone to the car.
If we then play audio
the communication protocols
to send information
The video stream here is
and audio for the song
If the CarPlay UI is exited,
the CarPlay session
The communication protocols
for now playing and
The video stream is
but CarPlay audio still plays,
even though CarPlay
The screen and audio are
Video from the native system
is playing.
If the CarPlay interface
audio from the native system,
Let's see what happens if Siri
push-to-talk steering
The communication protocols will
that iOS voice recognition
The CarPlay UI is
and the Siri audio chime plays
In this case, audio is also sent
from the car's microphones
These examples gave you
of how CarPlay works.
Now let's look in more detail
at what's happening
For wired CarPlay,
All data is wrapped in IP.
Except for the iAP2
Information from vehicle sensors
telephony, and turn-by-turn
The communication plug-in is
and that receives the incoming
as an additional
The audio and video is sent to
connected to the speakers,
Control events from the
or touchpad are sent
Now in the case of
much of the system
Both Wi-Fi and Bluetooth
For wireless, all
Connections to the vehicle's
Now that you have a
of how CarPlay works, we'll go
over the most important
We will talk through
We want to make sure you
before you begin to design a
that it's capable of
First, the vehicle
A high-quality display
to the CarPlay experience.
Several standard display
and those resolutions
Most are approximately 16 by 9.
Extra-wide screens
Today, all supported resolutions
We have support for screens
Asset sizes in CarPlay have
on the resolution of the screen.
So that assets will
and high resolution screens.
Without this, icons on the 720
If you do have a display with
than what was listed here,
if it can be supported.
We require that aftermarket
than six inches
since aftermarket
into a wide variety of vehicles.
There is no minimum for
The automaker has the
that CarPlay is appropriate on
I should mention several
Twenty-four bit color
and a 60 hertz refresh rate
for a responsive user interface.
Make sure that your H264 decoder
This is a hard requirement.
A high-quality display in
to the CarPlay experience.
Let's talk about the car's
CarPlay audio is separated
into two streams main
Main audio is bi-directional,
and other media plus
Alternate audio is
and it must always be mixed by
If the head unit is playing
the head unit must
from iPhone with that audio.
LPCM is used for wired CarPlay.
Wireless CarPlay
AAC-LC is used for media, and
and AAC-ELD for other audio.
CarPlay supports the
in your vehicles.
The CarPlay UI can be
on the head unit, by knobs
The Siri button on the steering
input device.
Many vehicles have touchscreens,
and let's talk about
When the CarPlay UI is active,
the head unit sends
y coordinates of that touch.
The head unit sends all
when CarPlay is displayed
CarPlay is controlled
We support two types
what we call high-fidelity
High-fidelity touch
So swipe gestures that track
A high-performance system
one that has less than 140
This is how list scrolling
that tracks the touch
with a high-fidelity
Low-fidelity touchscreens
and are often resistive screens.
Taps control the UI, and
user's finger.
This is how list scrolling
with a low-fidelity
Some vehicles use knob,
Sometimes these are the
and sometimes they are
All combinations are
Knobs are supported by the
select, and back events.
This is the minimum set
for a knob that's used
Rotate, select, and back.
Some knobs also support
This capability is
Vehicle touchpads report
as select and a back button.
If a knob or touchpad
back and select are required.
Secondary touchpads can also
Buttons for various functions
and telephony functions
The CarPlay UI will
to match the user inputs
All combinations are possible.
If the main controller
then combinations
or knob plus touchpad
A hard button for
Siri is really important
The user needs a quick way
if the CarPlay UI isn't showing.
Usually this requirement
with a push-to-talk button
For the Siri button, we require
that the head unit send iPhone
so that interaction during the
This wraps up our
Sensor information is
CarPlay needs location
so that the map's
Speed and GNSS information
Every vehicle needs
Speed information is used
and is critical if the
or GLONASS receiver.
GNSS information includes
if the vehicle has
Satellite location information
in addition to the
to determine the
This data from the
since a larger antenna can
This is the recommended
since it will result in the
Sending satellite
to iPhone is required
if the vehicle has the
GNSS information
for any system supporting
since it's more likely that the
or somewhere where the phone
What are the requirements
for connecting an
Apple CarPlay supports both
We're excited about the
since it offers a very
for customers.
Users can leave their
which is especially
Let's first talk about
USB is used here,
and control information
Your head unit will need
The head unit will switch from
High throughput is a
to make sure your USB
required data rates.
If you have multiple USB
and not all of them
you'll need to properly
Wireless CarPlay is
Both Bluetooth and
Bluetooth is used for discovery
Once the Wi-Fi credentials
over Bluetooth, Wi-Fi
Bluetooth is disconnected,
and all subsequent CarPlay
During the CarPlay
including phone call audio and
as well as the control protocol.
CarPlay requires a
and 5 gigahertz is recommended.
Note that high throughput,
25 megabits per second,
The Bluetooth subsystem needs
to support the communication
Wireless CarPlay offers a
experience, and we're excited
to see your vehicles
Now let's hear from Donald about
&gt;&gt; Hi. My name is Donald, and
Now that you've seen
let's look at some
that will help you provide
in your cars.
One of the most important
that CarPlay is really designed
CarPlay is instantly
and they feel comfortable
because it's a consistent
visual language, and system
Every interaction with
when users can trust
on the screen is
If a user has to discern which
and which elements are part
then every interaction
Also, your car's native user
that resemble or have
to icons within CarPlay.
And it can be confusing
on the display at the same time.
Instead, use the entire
Let's take a look at what should
CarPlay always starts the moment
Users should never have to
When the user connects
for the first time, the
to show CarPlay right away.
This provides feedback
and creates a strong association
and the familiar
Don't show notifications
to announce state changes
The needed appearance of CarPlay
in the display is the most
Now let's consider
after the initial
When users connect their iPhone
like a continuation of
So if CarPlay was
when the user left the car,
when iPhone is connected.
And if CarPlay media
when the user left the car,
when iPhone is reconnected
as the user did not select
between their CarPlay
In other words, we want
to always respect the last
in the car.
Let's see how last
Notice that I'm using CarPlay,
and it's showing on
Now if I disconnect, CarPlay
to its native user interface.
If I plug in again, CarPlay
because that was the last
So if CarPlay was the
when it was disconnected,
CarPlay should be shown when
If CarPlay media was playing,
Let's see a different example.
This time, CarPlay is active
with the car's display showing
Now if I disconnect
CarPlay does not
because the native user
was using in the car.
So if CarPlay was not the last
in the car's user interface.
But even if CarPlay was not
if CarPlay media was playing,
CarPlay is available the moment
but they can switch
and the native user
As we saw earlier,
to the car's user interface
in the CarPlay Home screen.
They can switch back to CarPlay
by using the Apple
The Apple CarPlay button is
that CarPlay is available.
As soon as CarPlay starts,
the Apple CarPlay
in your top level menu.
And the Apple CarPlay must only
and CarPlay is active.
Be sure to hide the
when iPhone is disconnected.
And they also show the
in an enabled state
and in a disabled state
You can optionally replace an
menu with the Apple CarPlay
Just remember that the Apple
on your car's Home screen
When iPhone is disconnected,
the Apple CarPlay button must
Let's talk about the
that should appear
There are a variety of approved
to use as buttons in your
Choose the one that makes the
There's a black logo and a
and black variance
And, finally, there's
Let's talk about how
when iPhone is disconnected.
Let's say that CarPlay
and the user is listening
When iPhone is disconnected,
that they're about
Your system should
being disconnected.
When iPhone is disconnected,
and audio should not fall
If the iPhone is disconnected
on the car's display, you
to the last screen displayed
Don't show a CarPlay unavailable
So, again, when CarPlay
and the user disconnects iPhone,
The hardware buttons in
to support CarPlay.
Siri is an integral
and requires a dedicated
Because it's so important,
on the car steering wheel.
Users expected Siri to
or not CarPlay is currently
They also expect the
like the Home button on iPhone.
Pressing and holding it for 600
Siri, and the activation
than one second.
The media buttons in your
to CarPlay media playback
move to the next track
and fast forward and rewind.
Finally, if your car has
media, or navigation,
to the respective
&gt;&gt; Now let's talk about
Apps supported by
on the CarPlay Home
Three categories of
Audio, those specific
to particular vehicles,
If a user has an audio app
that app will appear
in any CarPlay car
The user interface for
with the structure
and the content provided
You'll notice that
like the built-in music app.
Users choose what to listen
and the Now Playing screen
and controls.
The app needs to have a
to be compatible with CarPlay.
We've made some improvements
to make the audio apps
New in iOS 10 is support for
to navigate list hierarchies.
In the Now Playing screen,
and additional playback
In the list views, you can
which are available
explicit or live stream.
Some apps are designed
as they're launched,
for these apps in iOS 10.
All of these combined make for
Check out the new tabs, the
and the way tend to note
In the now playing
and the additional
Now let's talk about that
to work in specific vehicles.
Apps published by
to control vehicle functions
or give information
They only appear in vehicles
A CarPlay entitlement is
New in iOS 10 is Siri
that control vehicle functions.
Siri now has built-in support
changing climate
The automaker app
to perform these functions
after Siri tells the app what
Let me explain how
in the cars that support them.
An app icon is enabled in
if the iPhone is
that supports the same
A protocol name supported
and the app need to match.
iAP external accessory
to head unit communication.
Head units can declare
to support current
with different groups
Head units should
to match all cars
For example, com.brand.
They should also use
with specific features,
electric vehicles
A protocol name for the specific
so that apps that target just
that model can be
The head unit needs
at least one supported
Likely more than one.
Start and stop external protocol
and external accessory protocol
If the car supports
these iAP2 messages
on all supported transports.
Most automaker apps will
to perform tasks such as
These apps need to design
and implement a communication
So how does the app
The app's Entitlements.plist
to include the protocol
on the target head
With these additions plus
to communicate with the car,
your app will be
We're looking forward to
from automakers.
We have a new category of
and iOS10, messaging apps.
When a messaging app has been
that app will appear on
Messages can be received
all driven by Siri interactions.
We're excited to extend CarPlay
making that experience
We hope this has been a
CarPlay is a great way to
in vehicles fresh long into
to get a chance to talk
that are new in iOS 10.
For more information, check
We also have a follow-on
that may interest you.
Thank you for watching.