[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. My name is Tanya,
to the second session about
The video to Part 1
So if you haven't watched
In this session, we'll
on how CarPlay is integrated
into a typical automotive
We'll start with a system
and resource management,
and finish by discussing
Now, let's dive into an
If you watched the first video,
you will recall the
to implement a CarPlay receiver.
In summary, you need an IP-based
over USB or over Wi-Fi, IP
an instance of the CarPlay
implementing the control
to play or record sound,
to render the video stream.
However, those components are
in a typical automotive
In addition to the
your unit has its
audio sources, and logic.
Both together build
Then you add all hardware
Microphone, speakers, displays,
and you have the
OK, so we have the full system.
Now the question is how do those
work with each other?
Let's understand it.
First, let's look at how
And we will take location
Location information includes
or sensor data like
The data reaches the
must be always available,
by the phone when needed.
Next, let's look
at the instrument cluster
These secondary displays
to show metadata
Such metadata could include the
the active phone call,
the next turn-by-turn direction.
Again, the data is fired
and exchanged on demand.
Now let's see what happens
Of course, to operate the
the user must either
an app controller, or both.
So we can consider
of the user input devices
When the CarPlay UI is active,
the unit is rendering the video
And both the screen and the user
But if the native user interface
then both the display and
to the native sub-system.
However, additional user
like the Voice Recognition
may be linked to CarPlay even
when the native UI is
That way, Siri can
or the next audio track played.
OK, now that we looked at the
let's talk about audio.
Audio in the car can be roughly
The first one provides access to
and it's used for phone
Then we have audio playback
for any media content
And last, we have the alerts
for navigation prompts or any
Within the native sub-system,
these three categories
Within CarPlay, we have
which includes phone
and audio playback audio.
And an Alternate audio
for higher-priority
such as navigation prompts
So the media channel can either
or media playback from one
OK, now that we have
let's see what happens
when there is a phone
The phone call needs the audio
to both the microphone
So media playback is interrupted
And audio switched over to the
to both the microphone
In addition to switching
the screen switches to CarPlay
And metadata information
on the instrument cluster
Of course, if the native system
outside of CarPlay, then that
on the in-car displays.
But while on a native
the user can be using
So each time there is
Apple Maps will play a sound
through the announcement
The phone call continues to
of the car, but the turn-by-turn
as they are mixed
Of course, in such situation,
to hear the phone navigation
that an upcoming turn is coming.
And if the user wants to
the main display
And last, after the phone call
through the native sub-system
as that was what the
to prior to the phone call.
Now, the navigation announcement
direction as the user is
All right.
As you see, integrating CarPlay
especially in regards to
But before we get
let's look at volume controls.
Volume management.
As you might know, a usual
volume indicator while the user
and that volume knob
of the currently-playing audio.
The same principle
but there is a different
of the major CarPlay
Let's look through them.
During Siri playback, the volume
to voice interactions.
For an incoming phone call,
the volume of the
When the user is
the phone call audio
And if a next turn
navigation prompts are played.
Then, the user can change
And remember, media could
but its volume will be
and cannot be adjusted.
Once the announcement is over
the button controls
All right, now let's look
We are going to take a look at
talk about how they are managed,
and go over a couple
So we saw that there are
but let's understand which
And there's only two:
The mainScreen representing
and mainAudio as the
to the car's audio system.
Those resources can either
When you take a resource,
for unlimited amount of time.
It's basically yours.
When you borrow a resource,
but you have to give it
OK, so let's have the
over the display permanently.
The user can be using native
to FM radio, or adjusting
What triggers such permanent
The native UI can
when the user presses a hard
from the entry point
or by using the native
out a specific native
Now let's say the user
from the main menu.
In this case, CarPlay
as the user explicitly
Again, what can trigger
Any hard key linked to CarPlay.
Or, as we saw, through
within the native UI.
Or through Siri, for example,
Now, there are other
that need to borrow a resource.
Remember, they just need it for
Which applications
That's phone calls,
notifications, or alerts.
Let's look at an example.
The native UI has taken
and is permanently
Now the user gets a
The CarPlay UI borrows
for the duration of the call.
Once the call ends, we go back
until further user action.
Then, let's look at the
Main Audio can be split
Each type is used for a
as it provides access to a
Media is audio output only and
Alert is also only output
and plays ringtones
speechRecognition
as it adds access
Same for the telephony type,
And same for the default, which
But don't forget the
for navigation announcement.
alternateAudio is not managed.
It is basically always
to take it or borrow it.
alternateAudio is mixed
within the mainAudio channel,
And with this, I'm going
about the resource manager.
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Tanya.
Hi. I'm Tom, and I also work on
So now that you've learned which
and you know you can either
let's talk about how you
To be able to distribute
between the two sub-systems, we
And we call such an
So what does the
It has three main tasks.
First, it holds the current
Second, it follows a set
which system will
Third, based on the current
it assigns the resource
So let's see how this
Let's say both the
to show something on the screen.
So both send a request to
Then, the resource manager
and decides which of the
to the display.
Let's say, in this case,
the native UI request
and the screen is
The resource manager
that the screen can now
Only then the native UI can
It's important to note that
until the resource
So where does the
Is it part of the native
Well, when we designed CarPlay,
we asked ourselves
We considered the complexity
of exchanging detailed
We considered the future.
What, if any, of those
What if new applications became
that the vehicle had no
What solution would give us the
down the road?
So we decided to implement a
on the native system is lower
after the vehicle has been
in the customer's
Hence, the resource manager
And because the resource
with which the native
we refer to the iPhone
and the head unit
But don't forget, all
of the iPhone applications
in the same way as
Next. What commands
with the resource manager?
It's simple.
You only need two commands.
The changeModes command
or release a resource, and the
to describe the current states.
changeModes is the notification
the accessory in this case,
to the resource manager,
This changeModes command
to do with the resource.
It declares why it needs
or borrow the resource
The modesChanged is
by the controller
modesChanged provides
which describes who's the owner
It sends so the accessory knows
if a resource has
and the owner has changed.
Now we'll talk about how
in more detail.
We will start with
of switching audio
Then, we'll talk about
then how to handle
where you would not
to interrupt you unless
where Siri triggers
So let's look at
Let's say iPhone
through the car speakers, then
through the native system
The unit sends a changeModes
of the speakers,
as the user might continue
for a prolonged period of time.
The controller assigns
and it sends a modesChanged
And the head unit is the new
so it can now start
The mainAudio resource
to the head unit at this point.
So, in summary, this
when to take a resource and that
that resource before it is
Let's look at the next example
FM radio is still playing
Let's see what happens
if the user triggers the
The unit requests to temporarily
so the transferType
to borrow the audio and screen.
Both the mainScreen and the
to the accessory.
And the native voice
Once the voice dialogue
the head unit returns
by sending an unborrow command.
And since the unit was
the resource is again
and FM radio can resume.
Now you may be wondering,
to borrow the resource if
Well, that's a great question.
Whenever the resource manager
to change the ownership
it must know what the current
The resource manager needs
to know why you're
so that they can take
if somebody else needs
Let's move on to
showing the backup camera.
Let's say CarPlay
and the native UI is
When the user switches
the unit borrows the screen.
However, notice it also
that the screen cannot
The resource manager assigns
and also notes the limitation.
So the backup camera
CarPlay audio continues to play,
but now the user
The iPhone cannot show
as the head unit has
but the ringtone plays
So how did that happen?
With the changeModes command,
the unit told the resource
by the resources
By setting the borrowConstraint
the unit allows the
to borrow the resource.
By setting it to user-initiated
by the user can borrow.
With never, no application
as with this example.
As you see, the constraints
on the system behavior,
that they are used properly.
Only restrict access
for immediate user attention.
Do not restrict permanent
when CarPlay is connected.
So that was using backup camera.
And the last example we want
when Siri plays music.
Again, we start with
The user triggers Siri.
Siri is launched on the phone
and the resource manager
that the resources have
Siri shows up and the user can
Siri returns the display
but the music app now needs the
So the resource manager notifies
with the phone, but the screen
The head unit does not
and so iPhone audio
So what did we see here?
On two occasions, the resource
without a request
And this is completely
on the device request
And if they get them, the
So, how to handle this?
First, after each modesChanged,
If you are, resume
Otherwise, you should wait
Second, do not ignore
when they are triggered
OK, so far, we've looked
at examples showing how
But there is another
to accomplish the same task.
So let's look at how
We need to manage native
which have similar features.
But what are those applications?
They are active route
and voice recognition.
We achieve those
But what is an appState?
We use different appStates to
in the shared application
on the accessory or the
So the three different
PhoneCall, and Speech.
So let's have a look at how
that route guidance
When turn-by-turn navigation
it uses a changeModes command
to update the TurnByTurn
With this example, it is
So the controller grants
to the accessory, returning a
accessory as currently
Now let's look what happens
when the user sets a new
while the native system
The user says, "Siri, take me
Now, the iPhone has
So the controller updates
This is the instruction
to stop its own native
Now, the iPhone has
so the controller updates
This is the instruction
to stop its own native
So now, the Apple Maps
shown on the display and
And there will be no conflict
So now when the Apple Maps
shown on the display and
there will be no conflict with
So that was route guidance.
Now let's look at a phone call.
If the unit supports
over Bluetooth Hands-Free
and there was an
the call uses mainAudio
The phone call cannot
So what happens if the
on the CarPlay device?
The CarPlay call rings
as it should not interrupt
This is managed using
And lastly, let's look
If the unit has a native voice
it has borrowed the resources
and is exclusively using
and screen resources.
But it can be interrupted at any
So if Siri is triggered
native voice recognition
on the in-car display.
The Speech appState is
So, in summary, CarPlay
as your native system and
with your native
For a great CarPlay experience,
for each use case and follow the
The CarPlay specifications
through the MFi Program.
If you haven't watched
Part 1 yet, I'd encourage
For more information
please visit the