[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to the
in Apple Push Notification
My name is Mayur Mahajan.
And I work on the Apple Push
And I'm excited to share with
Let's get started with a review
that were released last year.
First, we introduced a brand
on HTTP/2 persistent Pushes.
HTTP/2 is a binary protocol
over a single connection
The new protocol has
to send Push notifications
The new protocol supports
to indicate which device
It is also possible to
up to four kilobytes, that
of for creating rich
In addition, we'll simplify
so you will now have to maintain
to connect to APNS.
We have received a lot
from the developer community.
We deliver hundreds of thousands
of notifications per second
If you are not using this
try it.
So let's recap the sequence
in sending Push notifications.
On the bottom right is
And on the top right
which is the server component
and sends Push notifications.
Now, before you start
you should register
in the developer account.
The application will register
running on the device
The device will request
on behalf of the application.
And then return it back
This device token will be unique
for your application
Your application should forward
Now, the provider
to APNS using the
and then use standard
to send a Push to
HTTP/2 provider API will provide
success if everything was okay.
And APNS has received
that the Push request
Now, if there was an error, say
APNS will return an error
with adjacent payload
For example, a bad device token.
The new provider protocol also
So if a device token
you will get an HTTP/2 response
It will have a time stamp
when APNS last learned that the
We also simplified
of the new provider protocol.
You can now provision
for your application,
The same certificate can
and production environments.
This has reduced the
and revocation of
for many developers.
Now, we are listening
from developers like you.
And we understand the importance
of simplifying the work
in sending Push notifications.
We understand that managing
for some applications.
So today we are thrilled
and a simple way of
Introducing token authentication
for Apple Push notification
Token authentication is a way
of client certificate when
The authentication
to simplify how services
In addition, the tokens are easy
so there is no need
to reissue expiring
This is enabled through
as a mechanism to generate
There are a number of libraries
with the programming
to generate these tokens.
Now, before we get
of how token authentication
let's first recap how
will work.
You opt in.
Provide a client certificate
When connecting to APNS
APNS will provide a
that you will trust
As part of the handshake,
your provider will also
which APNS will validate and
At this point, there is a
between APNS and the provider.
Any Pushes you send on this
to the application identified
When using token
in a token sign-in
Your provider will then
without a client certificate.
However, before sending
on this connection, the provider
token that includes
And then sign it using
Now it's possible to
on this connection.
Every notification message
authentication token.
Also, the application topic
APNS will first authenticate
and then process the request.
If this request is
APNS will send a response
If no token was provided
or if the token was invalid,
a response will be sent
As a reminder, APNS will not
So let's take a look at how
You should start with
from the certificates,
and profile section
A public-private
And the private key
to cryptographically
Apple will use the
for validating the token.
Next, let's look at how
At the top is an example of what
of the request might look like.
Let's go over the structure
You can see it has three parts.
Each part is a URL friendly
delimited by a period.
Below is the decoded
of this Web token.
The first part is the header.
And it includes attributes
that specify the algorithm
In our case, it's ES256.
It will also include the
that is used to sign the token.
The claims section will
which is your developer team ID
that can be obtained
The next attribute in the claims
expressed as seconds
The last part of the token
in base 64 obtained by
to the header and the claims.
This prevents any
of the token once
Here is what an HTTP/2 creates
for a request using token
As you can see, this
and a data frame.
The header frame consists
of various header fields
Now, you will notice that the
authorization header with
by the signed provider token.
If the request including the
the response will be
Here is what the
if the provider token
In this case, it is
Now, APNS will require
periodically generated.
If the token is too old,
be a 403 "Forbidden" error
that the token has expired.
APNS will require that the
within the last hour.
However, a new token should not
In fact, for performance
that the token be reused
So here are a few more details
As mentioned earlier,
to be generated periodically.
However, note that the
Now, if you suspect that the
compromised, you can revoke
and provision a new key.
As a reminder, APNS
to support certificate
So that is token authentication.
And it's coming later this year.
For more information visit
at
Here are relevant
that you might be
to Notifications will be in
at 9:00 a.m. followed
on Advanced Notifications in
at 10:00 a.m. And we
Thank you very much.