[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. I'm Todd Ritland,
and the lead engineer
And this is Deploying
AirPrint is Apple's
It's a technology that helps you
to create full-quality
to download or install drivers.
If you're an app developer
to your app, see
for a previous talk I gave at
and download the sample
If you are a printer
or a print server
to license AirPrint
please email airprint@apple.com.
This talk will focus on
for deploying AirPrint
about all the enterprise
that make AirPrint work great
Printing in enterprise has
Our enterprise customers
of printers, often
and with different features,
or across many different
and in many locations.
These can be hugely
The network infrastructure
Often they're wireless
and their network
to the physical location
IT departments also have
such as no access
no multicast packet
and certain ports blocks, which
Enterprise customers also may
since every page
And of course security
and are increasingly important
The top requests we get from
to create PDF and have more
access control and accounting,
and better discovery
So let's go into
for each of these in detail.
First, create PDF
Mac OS has long had the ability
to get a PDF anywhere
And now in iOS 10, all iOS
as well and I'd like to
Here we have an iPad running
I just pinch out with my two
And from here, I have a Share
Any app can accept PDFs will
as well as AirDrop and other
This also works with the Managed
that keeps business items
On devices with 3D Touch, you
and Pop gesture to
from the Print Preview.
We think enterprise users will
workflow on all of
Next onto a hugely
AirPrint on iOS and Mac
encryption so your documents
AirPrint supports the latest
encryption on top of HTTP.
This encryption technology
for all new AirPrint
Next, for additional security,
many enterprise customers don't
around in the output
where an unauthorized person
iOS and Mac OS support PIN
that support it, where the user
to receive their output.
On iOS, when a PIN is required,
the Print panel has a
And when the user taps
with the PIN to release the job.
On Mac OS, the user can
to use to release the job.
Mac OS also supports
and not required to print.
Next, Access Control
AirPrint has always
that require authentication
We store the username and
so the user never has
iOS 10 now supports
that stored authentication
where a different
Also new this year is support
so printer can be protected
with just a simple
When an enterprise
or account information
iOS and Mac OS both support
that account information.
If the account information
the user will be
that information before
And iOS and Mac OS
or required account
and this is what the UI
Next, Better Discovery.
AirPrint has many supportive
The main method which
with AirPrint is Local Bonjour.
There is no setup required.
The printer automatically
in the list without any setup.
AirPrint has also always
Bonjour is based on
And if a DNS server
with the correct records,
printers can be discovered
and I'll go over how to do this.
Both iOS and Mac OS also now
or MDM profiles with a
And new in iOS 10, we have
as a way to discover
low-energy beacons.
Configuring a DNS server
to advertise AirPrint
First, the configured DNS
of DNS servers used
and Macs you want
There are lots of ways to
and search domains are used,
And next you want to add A
of the printer and the printer
Add a PTR record for the
and one additional PTR record
This is key for AirPrint
IPPS service.
It has a subtype of universal
and that's what iOS
You'll add a SRV record for
or text record that
and information about
It's super important to
of the printer or server,
which can easily be accomplished
OS, dns-sd.
To use dns-sd to figure out the
on the same subnet as the
You run with the -Z option
in zone file format and
underscore ipps.service
like shown here in blue.
This is the output you'll get
for each printer that's
These are almost the PTR, SRV,
to add to DNS server
The changes are highlighted
As I mentioned, you'll add
for the universal subtype, like
You'll also replace the local
with the fully-qualified
the A record I mentioned
to replace any other instances
with this fully-qualified domain
in green, with the
If this isn't fixed, users
in Mac OS that quickly
to the printer's admin webpage.
And so this is the text here
into a zone file and a
of printers for your users,
if they have this
as one of their DNS servers.
So the key to setting up
to get some help from the
MDM profiles are very
to configure printers
The AirPrint payload can
and that payload
or IP address and
The resource path is ipp/print
and for an AirPrint server,
And the screenshot shown
one of the most popular Mobile
Next we have a new
about that's new in iOS 10
and that's the AirPrint
So what is an AirPrint Bluetooth
Well, it can be configured
of the many third-party
available on the market and
or can it be built into the
printer's built-in
And future AirPrint printers
right in.
What it does is beacon out
And if the iPhone can
the printer will be
This is really powerful
don't matter.
All that matters is that
This could even be a public
So long as the iOS device
and the IP address
the printer will show up
on the list for users.
And the AirPrint Beacon works
Here we have an AirPrint server
on the network has an
which is advertising
and the Queue ID
When the user prints, the
with the queue information, and
to the associated printer that
Let's go into detail about what
format is so you can set
First, we have a header.
This is what identifies this BLE
It's the same for all
so this can just be copied.
Next, we have the
This tells whether the
in the beacon is an IPv4
It also tells whether the
or identifies a printer
if the connection
For this example, the
the IP address is
and this is not a server.
See the specification
for how this byte is set up.
Next we have a printer
to a print server or information
if this is directly
This printer has ipp/print
Again, see the specification
about specifying resource paths.
Next we have the port
631 is the standard IPP port.
Port 443 is often used for
For this example, 277
which is the standard IPP port.
And next we have the IP address.
If you're using a non-updatable
make sure the printer
Otherwise, this IP in the
when the IP address changes.
And last, like iBeacon, we have
at 1 meter.
This uses the same methodology
This gives the iOS
about the physical
For this example, the
to be on average 64 decibels,
The format of the AirPrint
similar to iBeacon.
iBeacon format is
but the beginning
If you're following setup
with iBeacon technology,
and use a similar setup for
and many manufacturers of
or will have specific
setup procedures.
So for enterprise users, iOS
and Mac OS provides
to support PDF workflows for
And AirPrint provides great
accounting, and new
to make printing great
And as always, let
about what specific enterprise
on apple.com/feedback.
For more information
and for referenced
out
You may also want to
in Apple Device Management
at Wednesday 11:00 a.m. and also
in the Marina at