[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, I'm Caroline
and production manager
Today, I'm excited to talk
about inclusive design.
When you put so much hard work
you really want it
But ultimately, everyone
in their own way and if you
of people who could
you have to consider how
Some people are just learning
Others are digital natives
with the latest and greatest.
And there's some who are just
with the new way to communicate.
And some will have
that are very different
And some will interact with your
like a Bluetooth
So when you're trying to
like there isn't enough time and
and it only gets worse the
So that's why it's important to
as early as possible in
The problem is that early in
to talk about the cool
So you need to convince your
And here are some statistics
to make inclusiveness
Tim Cook recently announced
in the second quarter
Your app needs to be
to reach this huge market of
Worldwide, 285 million people
That's like half the
Over one billion people live
That's one out of every
Now disability and diversity
think about when you think
But these numbers make it
that use your app and creating
at the heart of the
So, how can you make
Fortunately, there are a
that I have found to be helpful.
If you incorporate these
you will have more informed
And in the end, your app
for more people, but
on localization and QA.
So today, I'm going
that I found eye opening and now
I'll discuss how to use
in different localizations.
I'll show you why layouts
to accommodate translation
screen sizes and dynamic type.
And we'll discuss emotions
when making design
And we'll go over certain
around iconography.
So first, we'll talk about
for everyone regardless
Because the most fundamental
to communicate information
and we largely do
So let's look at a quick
One of the ways you know
by using basic typographic
and compositional elements to
You can use extra space between
or try different font sizes.
Or you can explore typographic
or character styles like
Or start adding color
you have so many good options.
And at this stage, it's
to preview your favorite options
to localize in because
to have this same impact
In this example, the hierarchy
and subtitle of the
because the Chinese writing
of upper and lowercase.
In the second design, the title
size and color from the subtitle
which helps maintain a
So out of my two favorites,
this second design is
because it creates hierarchy
through using two
both localizations can support,
I've found that once a design
into multiple languages,
of change will be
in case a treatment isn't
And sometimes, designing
like these can help come up
for everyone.
Here's another example
They use font size, color, and
to maintain hierarchy
And so now for you to have
and feel informed to
I want to dive a little
First, it's important to
we speak different languages
So, I want to introduce
that you may not
and how hierarchy can be
of their typographic support.
So everyone here knows this
But you may not be
in the extended Latin
And you really might
with all ten writing
in over forty languages or
A few typographic things that
that some writing systems do
and lowercase as I
Also, the same subset does
and it's not in good
on these writing systems.
So now you need to know
for these writing systems
of font weights.
Currently these are
in the system font,
But you can see that the system
at the moment do not have the
So this means your designs using
to the reduced set.
And this can be unexpected
and sometimes lose
In the next consideration,
about is using larger text sizes
between languages and
So let's start with
which is, "What is too small?"
Maybe everyone here can
on this enormous screen.
But on a smaller device,
Legibility is really
on what device you are targeting
because the standard viewing
But, even if the
it doesn't mean it's going to
Let's look at a non-Latin
It gets harder to read
because rendering dense writing
clarity of letter forms.
The meaning can be
because the strokes
You want people to read their
So leaning toward larger font
readable for everyone.
Now one more thing
Some writing systems are
because they have
As you might have noticed in
some of the examples
that we don't use in English.
These are call diacritics,
and sometimes they're
For example, in this Thai font
higher than Latin characters.
And in these Arabic
they have descenders much
And you should also be aware
that in some code
characters that draw
and descender boundaries
and text views can
to bounds is true for the label.
This should be off,
Missing marks can change the
So, also in design comps,
you should avoid assuming
because the letter
in different writing systems.
So you might be thinking how
So let me show you
of how labels will
for these tall writing
If you look at this
of three separate
and you can see in a tall
larger line height
And here they are, side by side.
And you can see that Thai text
to expand appropriately.
And it's important that you
of the view so this
because letter forms could
And later, we'll explain how to
between labels increase
to accommodate dynamic type.
So some things to remember
to make sure designs will retain
in other languages by
by choosing universal character
to three levels of change
in one of the localizations.
Use font sizes that will
of your localizations and
who will use your app.
And don't restrict drawing of
So now we've looked at a
For more information about
out my friend Antonio's
Typography and Fonts
on typographic treatments
But now, let's talk
We've talked about the
over the world, but
about how they come
An Auto Layout can really
considerations, but I'm
about Auto Layout
I want to focus on why having
on so many different levels.
It helps with localization,
adapting to different screen
when type is able to scale.
So first, let's see how
with varying translation
As crazy it sounds, the
the longer the translations
The word edit in English
but in Russian, it's
Just kidding, it's
If an English word is less
the translation can be
A seemingly concise English
in another language.
And an English sentence
and might need to
So this variation
of maximum text lines should
and text should be
by having a flexible layout.
You need to allow enough space
especially if there's no other
You would hate for the end
of a very important
Titles and other key texts
because it can lose meaning
So those expansion
and I hope it is for you too.
I can't stress enough that
for what you aren't
that you are designing in.
Let me show you an example
of a dynamic layout
looks like in a few
Here's this What's
that was created
In Chinese, it's actually
and in German it's much longer
and would start a Scroll
And here is Thai with
and extra line height.
And here's Arabic which is also
It's best to look at each
in each language that
in so you aren't
that will create
Accommodating translation
into making your app inclusive
and it will have
from the people who
But I have one more reason
and that's Dynamic Type.
This feature might be one of
that you could add to your
In settings, you have the
This enables a broad audience to
in control of their
But it also allows them
to choose how they
Small text sizes may
And larger text sizes
This is a highly used feature.
In fact, who here uses a text
Nice. So let's get
across all of our apps.
And you also might not be aware,
low vision people can get even
And here is Ulysses.
They do a great job scaling
So, how do I specify a
First you start by specifying
for semantically distinct blocks
body, etc. for the platform
This gives ample variety to
and today I've got a
when making designs
The font size, leading,
for each style is now published
on the iOS Human
in the typography section.
And you will be able to download
[ Applause ]
Okay, so, let's go into detail,
I'm focused for a
These are the font styles
at for the default
When the user slides the
these other columns
that the fonts will appear at.
You can see how the font sizes
and down in text
in the text size slider.
And here's an iOS
And I'm going to show you some
about how to use text styles
First, you will need to assign
The sender and the subject
and will be headlined so
The To field and the time stamp
and will be subhead.
And then the message
Then the next step,
to add a baseline measurement
of each label to other
And in the dynamic type
to create a ratio to scale
to the font size as it changes.
These are not fixed
measurements.
The bottom space under
to be specified dynamically
so that the text cluster will
in the header and the
follow similarly.
The next step, you'll specify
or enforce the standard
It's important to at least use
because the actual value is
You want to be consistent
And lastly, we'll
between horizontal elements.
So now together, with the
margins, and padding,
to be coded dynamically.
And so now, let's watch
So, ta-da, this is the
growing from large to
There's also another legibility
for free if you use text styles
This helps people who would
reading lightweight fonts.
And additionally,
for tall writing systems.
So sometimes, with the 12.9-inch
or large blocks of texts,
for the reading experience
if the layout margins were
So when you're reading
it's hard for your
to the beginning
So in iOS 9, we introduced the
of UIView to respect a suitable
on the size of the font
which makes the margins
And now, so the margins adjust
when the text size
This way, the line
for each font size.
Also, layouts need
for right-to-left writing
and Hebrew because they
of the screen to the left.
These languages require
Here's Tweetbot.
They've done a great job at
If using Auto Layout's leading
the flow and elements
However, it's important
that some things do not mirror.
Like numerals.
They are presented
of right-to-left phrases.
You should not mirror phone
graphs, and video
Video progress sliders
to the right and rewind always
and fast-forward to the right.
And images do not need to be
of direction or design
to other parts of
So now let's internationalize
so you can see how this
Here's a step one, two,
in a hypothetical app.
If we were going
for right-to-left languages,
through three with step
And then of course,
by making them localizable
of being baked into the art.
But here, the story of the
in the opposite direction
So we would want to mirror each
of the images follows the steps.
However, we should not
because checkmarks
And now, the onboarding
for right-to-left languages.
So some things to remember
that translation lengths are
and longer, than the
Dynamic Type is an
that allows scalable type.
And reability margins help
at nice readable line lengths.
And Arabic and Hebrew will
So now we've looked
and I hope your apps
to these size changes
There are new additions to the
to implement, so check out
for more information.
The Auditing Your App
for Accessibility
for previewing your app using
and Making Apps Adaptive, Part
of the new Dynamic Type
in International User Interfaces
for handling right-to-left
But now, let's talk about color.
Color is another
There's a -- and there's a lot
for your app because
to the experience.
So first, it's important
to recognize what
to your particular
So let's talk about
of the three most
Surveys have told us that blue
favored color around the world.
And the second most popular
but is usually green or red.
So first let's talk about blue.
Why does everybody
I mean, blue has a short
and actually makes it
And our eyes are trained to
because the short wavelengths
by the molecules.
FYI, that's why the sky's blue.
But also seeing some colors
in your body and lowers
However, universally,
some shades of blue
and loneliness likely
with the vast and
So now, let's talk about green.
It has a wide range of
In the western cultures, it's
live healthy, and
as a natural eco-friendly
In Ireland, green commemorates
on Saint Patrick's Day
and is also known throughout
Green is also a universal
It's used in traffic light
over the world to indicate
So now, let's talk about red.
It's pretty consistent around
up both similar positive
Red has a long wavelength
which grabs our attention
Therefore, in many parts of
of revolution and conflict.
It exudes passion and love.
And to most Asian cultures, red
and good luck because
with the Lunar New Year.
And it's also worn at weddings.
In fact, red is so
that the Chinese stock
and green to mean losses.
And the next color consideration
And you need to be aware
that color blindness affects
It's actually one in 12
That's almost 5 percent
of the total population
And all of these popular
implications to color
It's not that these are --
these colors are confused with
of blue, red, and green
in all colors.
For one kind of color blindness,
this color palette may
This is why our platforms
to differentiate key information
Like here in mail
between an orange dot or an
because if you are color
to tell the difference from
with the blue and red dot.
So the additional shape option
And the next topic is about
for legibility between
Contrast is important
because you want people who
as well as situational
or wearing sunglasses to
And to find what
you need to calculate
between two colors or one way
without calculation is to
You can quickly see if the
with each other in your app.
And soon, on the iOS
in the resources
to download a helpful tool
by using RGB values and it
in compliance with common
for different text
But you can also use
ratio calculators.
If we calculate the contrast
and orange, it was
That is not in compliance
because it is a very low ratio.
In fact, 1 to 1 is the
Let's look at another example
to see the highest
and that's between
A contrast ratio calculator
and black has a ratio of 21 to 1
and of course it passes
Now let's check out some gray
The ratio comes in at
It's okay for large font sizes,
but it's too low for
When font sizes are small
your eyes can't distinguish
to easily read the text.
Let's look at one more gray.
Maybe not on this screen,
this is really hard to
That's because the
And this fails at
You wouldn't want your
at this low contrast if
and be able to use it.
Ideally gray text should be
or inactive states rather than
Now, have you ever debated
text or black text on
Happens to me all the time.
If we use this calculator,
on an orange button is a
And black text on an
So in this particular example,
It's a higher ratio.
Your texts and glyph colors
to the background color for
So some things to
some of the most popular colors
around the world.
Additionally, you should
to show the difference
that have different meanings.
And you need a high color
and backgrounds for legibility.
And so now we've
Let's talk about iconography.
It's important for you to know
that iconography can
around the world too.
Semiotics shows us
of visible symbols is
and how cultural references
For example, to be -- in
the International Red Cross
for protection during conflict.
They have the red cross for
the red crescent
and the red crystal
These religious connotations
risk the safety of people in
So, when you design glyphs
to remember that different areas
of the world might
with even the simplest
Something as simple as a hand
around the world.
In most places, it means stop or
But in Hinduism and Buddhism,
of Abhaya and it means no fear.
However, maybe you wanted to
to spread out the fingers
in a glyph, but an open,
facing palm is actually
And I'm not going to
Additionally, non-directional
to be more universal
on one region's alphabet
or particular cultural
For example, iBooks using
of a book showing the binding
for right-to-left locals.
You don't want to alienate
because they can't
or if something will
Also, sometimes you
that mimic other
For example, in right-to-left
the notification
to match the way it appears on
The badge should be on the left
of the glyph representing
So some things to remember
iconography can conflict
or symbols can have
Iconography are ideally
And iconography should match
for right-to-left languages.
You want the meaning of your
and used, not offensive,
Okay, so we've looked at ways in
to be more intuitive
for a culturally
and in ways in which
around more assessable
But it's a lot to consider and
if you're doing something
So what I encourage you to
in the countries you plan to
and ask them for feedback.
Ask them how they
If it feels logical
Is everything easy to read?
And then I want you
"How can you be more inclusive?"
So to watch this talk again,
and to also find
for what I discussed today.
And it also has a link
to the completely redesigned
It has been migrated to
with fresh imagery and
for designing great apps.
It's also been updated
on the new features in iOS 10.
Be sure to check out these
all week.
As I mentioned before,
and Fonts tomorrow morning
information about
The Auditing Your Apps
for Accessibility
for previewing your
And Making Apps Adaptive, Part
readable content guides, assets
All information that
to put my considerations
And the What's New
in International User Interfaces
for handling the right-to-left
Thank you and have