[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. My name is
and I'm User Experience
I work directly with developers
of their apps on Apple TV.
And I'm here today to talk to
This is a really exciting time
because this is the
Yeah. Right.
[ Applause ]
And your Apple TV apps
to change the way
And Apple TV App Store
And this newness provides
for your apps.
So, today we will
because this is a unique
of design considerations.
But, before we dive
we need to first take a
This is TV.
And we love TV.
We love TV because it's
It's a way to learn, to
TV's are powerful.
And the TV is something that
at the same time, which
at Apple TV unique from the rest
of our devices are close.
Their personal because
and we interact with
But, the TV is not in
And that screen is
So, if you want to make
you must first acknowledge
between you and the screen.
And you have to understand
with that screen that's far
because of that distance.
So, this makes the
from the rest of our devices.
So, you have to design
So, today talking about
we will first go
And that way we will
And then we'll jump into
of the TV.
And how to design
And how to design your app
We're going to touch on some
and those will be the ones
And I also want to
that have designed
So, let's go ahead and
If you're coming over from
app layouts don't
to the size of the screen.
Your interface is going to
of the TV screen size.
So, you need to design with
by 1080 pixels, which implies a
And all of your assets
And there's something
over scanning can
And this could cause
So, keep your apps
from the edges of the screen.
And a good guide is to avoid 60
and 90 pixels from each side.
So, that's it.
Those are the basics.
So, now we can talk about
that makes the TV unique and
And that is our distance
So, on average we are 10
And that's significant,
of that distance when you're
So, keep in mind that
to see from far away.
Everything in your user
And that's starting
Both graphics and your user
buttons or controls
so they can be easily
Now, I know it may
if you're used to
But, on Apple TV you want
to struggle to see
So, larger items are simply
In addition to increasing your
to include plenty of spacing
between those elements
This will help people
And it makes them easier
Now, grid layouts tend to work
And if you use a grid
of your content doesn't fit onto
to those off-screen items.
This will let people know
And only those partially
in this zone.
So, for Apple TV, if you want
there's some templates
and they're all highly
You have control over
background, tinting, and more.
You can find these on the
And I'll include a link to them
So, now let's talk about text.
Let's just imagine we're
and we're sitting away
All right.
So, let's just toss some
And can anybody see this?
Well? Somewhat.
Okay. People in the
But, people in the back, it
So, what's my point?
Make your text much
This will insure your
and descriptions
But, increasing the point
that you can do for
You can also use a heavier font
This weight is significantly
So, when you're evaluating a
font's with weights like
and bold are all great options.
And you typically want to avoid
So, if you have a brand
I highly recommend
And then see where you can
Even if it's just up to
so much easier to see on the TV.
And I know that beautiful,
of your brand identity.
But, if people can't read
it's going to be a
And that's going to reflect
So, in the system, we
and it's called San Francisco.
There are two variants
Both of which were designed for
There's San Francisco text
So, let's take a look
This is San Francisco
And when you use San
tvOS automatically applies the
based on point size.
And it's going to respect
such as bold type.
San Francisco will work
But, if you need to
make sure that it respects
and it's legible
So, for example, in Badland they
within the style of the game.
It reads clearly across the room
because of its heavier
So, unless your app
for a custom font, stick
because above all text on
So, I've only touched
to consider with text on screen.
If you want to learn more about
out the Typography and Font
on this stage with
So, we've already
spacing, templates, and text.
All to accommodate
between us and the TV screen.
But, there's still one
And that is your apps hierarchy.
Keep your app approachable
Do you remember how you
and just instantly be
Well, that ease and instant
to your apps on the
So, in designing your apps
Let people jump immediately
Too many choices or options
which will add a psychological
to the physical distance
So, if you have a
a great way to simplify your
This will instantly
and it'll organize all of your
that are quick and
Each tab bar should provide
from the top level of your app.
And if you use a tab
on the screen at once.
And don't just use it as
If you need to declutter
I recommend placing your app
People tend to only go
that you don't need to waste
or in the main level
So, to recap, when
remember on average
between you and the screen.
And to accommodate
you want to use larger
You want to provide adequate
so they're easier to see,
With text, legibility
Use large point sizes
So, don't be afraid to go big
And remember to keep
with a very simple hierarchy.
Don't add to the distance with
And there's actually
to check your designs
And that is to toss your wire
and review your layout,
and text on an actual
And you can ask yourself,
can you see everything
And is it easy to jump
I know this may seem like
but I've been in many UI
of issues could have been caught
if the app had simply
on an actual TV across the room.
I've seen some really great
tripped up on designing
because they have not
If you don't have a TV to
And don't just, yeah, and
to you at your desk.
You need to place it across
of that, people will be able to
And they will love being
into your apps experience.
So, that's designing
And because of that distance,
with the remote, which is the
to consider when
So, as I mentioned, the rest
and where you interact
However, on the Apple
The Siri Remote allows
with the TV screen
And people want to be
They expect interacting
So, if they have to look down
to go back, the connection with
So, to avoid breaking
that connection you
to work seamlessly
And to do that, you need to
First, there's a touch surface
on the Siri Remote
And that's going to move focus
And that's typically used
You can also click
and that activates a
to enter into an edit state.
And this could also be great
and drag an item
And finally you can
through a collection one by one.
But, it's also a really
So, it could be great in a game
as long as that action is
So, moving on to the buttons.
You have the menu button.
And pressing this should return
There's Play/Pause,
that during media playback.
And it's also a great
And also remember that you
accelerometer, gyroscope,
Siri, home, and the volume
for the system.
But, I want to go back
of special attention, and give
So, here's your app hierarchy.
If you click, that's
into each level of your app.
And pressing menu will return
This is the correct and expected
However, only in
there's a slight variation,
and I'll like to
So, for example in the
if I press menu while
I'm presented with a pause menu.
And because we're used to
to bring us out of
pressing menu here
So, it's important to
to exit out of the game.
So, in this case
And if I navigate to
to the level selection screen.
And this is where menu
If you press menu, it brings you
And with one more
on the Apple TV home screen.
So, that's how the
And it should behave exactly
So, as you may have heard in a
new remote app that works
It has a great game
And speaking of game
if your game has an
that can't be supported
you can now require the
And if your game
or if you support game
to the Siri Remote, make sure
to navigate through the Apple TV
And you should always
if a controller is required,
because your app can be
And even though your game may
remember that the
with every single Apple TV.
And a controller is
So, if you go controller
out on new players who want
to try your game first before
So, remember, with Apple TV,
and they don't want to look
to navigate, or interact.
So, use intuitive gestures
And if your app works
new remote app, and
people will stay connect
So, what do all of these
They control focus.
And focus needs to be obvious so
So, on Apple TV,
when an object is elevated,
to subtle movements on the touch
Did you all notice how your
to that movement?
Well, that's exactly
And that's why the system
People expect to be able to
to navigate around onscreen.
And they should always
and what's actionable.
So, now watch closely.
This will be a very slow
to illustrate something unique
Notice how it gently indicates
which direction you're
And this helps aid
This focus model is used
And this consistent look
and feel helps maintain
with what's on screen.
So, use the system focus model.
Only in a few special
you may want to customize
So, for example, back in Badland
And this fits well within the
because focus is obvious.
So, if you want to learn more
check out the Focus
on tvOS session tomorrow
So, with your app icon on
with focus and parallax in mind.
You can create some pretty cool
transparency, scaling,
And there's a great parallax
in include in the
So, when you're designing
you should use intuitive
and expected button behaviors
to the previous screen.
And implement your
with the Siri Remote's new
You should use the
for clarity and consistency.
That way people will feel like
with the screen even though
And if you make a
be sure to make focus obvious.
And focus should always move
to help aid in navigation.
And finally with the
that you don't break people's
So, that's designing
All right.
Awesome. We've made
And there are a lot of great
For those of you who were in
about these directly from
And don't worry, if you missed
first, thank you so much.
And secondly, you
that session on your WWDC app.
So, I'm just going
on the new appearance feature,
because that is what
There is now light and dark
And this is user
And it changes the look
Pretty much every single
to some degree for
This include place
they're dark instead of light.
Shadows have different values.
And this is a great
So, to support dark appearance,
And I encourage you to do
in this talk today
So, opt in and your app will
on how they wish to
in their own environment.
Now, user preferences also
And Apple TV is packed full
that provide the best user
Apps implementing custom fonts
behavior of system fonts and
Accessibility options
reduce motion, and more.
So, if you have a
that could be made accessible
So, I encourage you to check out
So, appearance and accessibility
on tvOS 10.
And I'm looking forward to
So, that's features.
Now, I would love to
that have not only designed
but they're also changing
So, first this app is Zova.
And it's a lifestyle fitness
into a yoga studio or place
where you could workout
Not only is this significantly
in some workout DVD's, but
on Apple TV, because
to find a workout
It has a great well
It's very easy to navigate and
for right from this main screen.
And with one click
you're instantly into a workout.
That's it.
Main screen to workout.
It's that easy.
And it's not overwhelming,
because you don't want
between you and getting fit.
Zova does a great job
because they use large graphics,
on the content of the app.
This app also does something
If you put Zova in the top shelf
to jump immediately
because it uses dynamic
If you want to find
I will link to the Apple TV Tech
So, that is Zova.
This next app that I want to
And Reuters really
on the Apple TV.
If you think about traditional
on you may be popping in five
and you've already missed all of
And I know you can
from the internet, but
to just watch a nice segment
to know, well, wouldn't
Well, that's exactly
When you open this app you
And that is, how much time do
You make a single action.
You choose whether that's
And as soon as you select one,
you are immediately
You're given a quick
in your playlist, and then
If you wanted to swipe up
you can jump to stories that
And that's the beauty of
Not only did I choose when
but I was also easily
to what I wanted
This app makes it possible
Now, while there's an amazing
of this news content, the apps
makes it great.
All right.
So, that is Reuters TV.
Next up is a game.
And this game is
This is a colorful,
and you may be familiar with it,
because it is an ADA
But, that's not why
I have it here for a
So, let's just say that I
from the app store, and I've
So, let's just see what
Did you guys see that?
It was awesome.
We were instantly into the game.
We just started playing.
Right from launch you're in
And that is awesome.
So, now I just want to continue
through this first
because there's something
You are reading a text,
on the Siri Remote, and
all at the same time.
The texting graphics are clear.
So, you're able to play and
And that is fantastic.
So, let's just fast forward
I assure you I landed
and I only had to
So, when you pass
which is your first experience
And you feel great.
You feel accomplished.
And now you're just
Chameleon Run is so much
It has great game play.
And they support
But, most of all I love
to jump into the game.
Now, granted not every single
But, you should still
to make your apps experience
to as possible, because
They just want to
And that's Chameleon Run.
This final app is unique.
And it is called, Late Shift.
This is a cinematic game
that lets you control
Decisions you make change
And if you want to watch
there's a companion app for the
and make decisions together.
So, potentially you
that then turns into
This is a
with a really easy
and a very simple
And the majority of your
And this game play is
You control the movie's
The onboarding is integrated
into the first level's
And it lets you know
Late Shift is an intriguing,
that I'm really excited
in apps on the Apple TV.
So, we just took a look at
an auto-runner, and an
So, what do all these
Well, they all design for
But, they also really thought
about what their app could do
While we've gone through
remember that TV's are not
They're in classrooms,
conferences, airports, and more.
So, what do you want your
You need to get into the mindset
of what you want
And then how to elevate
This is not a traditional
so why have a traditional
We are on the precipice
And the TV deserves
because you can create
that people will love.
So, if there's just one
from this talk today
For more information including
of this session,
This is has been session 802.
And there are a lot of
including the Typography and
on tvOS Talk that I mentioned.
And there's a great design
at 10 AM, here on this stage,
And if you have an idea for
to get started, that would
This has been Designing
Have a great conference.
[ Applause ]