[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Good morning everyone.
My name is Antonio Cavedoni,
about typography and fonts.
I am a type designer at Apple.
So, on the agenda today we
and update our system fonts.
We will see some
We will look at some
And then tools that you have
Lastly, we will see some
to adopt while working
Okay. So, San Francisco, it
We introduced them last year.
This is SF you see right here.
And it is the system font
We introduced this family
There is a video that
and application of SF.
And we've been applying
So, Apple TV, we've been
But we've also been applying
Now, in case you haven't
in Moscone Center, there
of the SF family, and
SF Mono is a new
and it comes in many ways.
We started with a light
semi bold, and then we're
like bold and even heavy.
So, all of these come
And they cover the Latin,
But, also the Cyrillic and the
and all the weights
So, SF Mono is a
But, it's also monospaced
which means that if you change
not reflow.
Of course this was
when we were designing
So, we have to squeeze
But, we designed that SF Mono
And so we tweaked some of the
or the bracket braces, some of
And of course SF Mono
of choice of Swift Playgrounds.
It's also in default in Xcode.
Check out the new
Okay. So, that was small
and the new SF Mono family.
Next I want to talk to you
Get us all on the same page
that can be confusing at times.
So, before I get started I just
which is that today we'll look
at the Latin Cyrillic
But, if you're interested
and you should, there are,
there were actually
that you can catch on video.
That talk exactly
So, let's get started.
What is text?
Text encodes language, and
Text is the stuff that you type.
It is the stuff that gets
and sent to your friends.
Now, what is text made of?
It is made of, oops, characters.
A character is an
and it literally is
Now, before you can
of these you need representation
a glyph is stored on your device
as an outline, a
And it lives inside a font file.
Now in a font file between
there usually is
However, things are
There could be something
which is a mechanism that
and makes things
For instance, you could have
for F or I, this
And instead of getting
you actually get just one,
into what is called a ligature.
Now, this ligature
by a typographic feature, which
Not all fonts do this.
Some fonts have optional
that change the shape of digits.
For instance, San Francisco
for the numeral 6 that
to make it a little
Now, fonts have multiple styles,
which of course look
Some fonts have just two styles.
Some fonts have many, many more.
And you may have heard some of
Bold Italic, Condensed.
All these are style names.
Now, what holds all of these
if you will.
And that is the idea of a set
There are many, many typefaces.
And you may have seen or
Now, what do you do with
Typography is using type to
Typography is the foundation of
So, we just saw a few terms.
We saw text, text is
characters are encoded by
Between characters and glyphs,
typographic features can alter
They're all stored in what
which can have common
They are all grouped under
which is the design idea
And typography is
of this stuff to convey text.
Now, writers and editors, the
concern themselves with text.
The characters are defined
So, you don't have
And the type designers and font
who come up with the design
and make them into fonts.
And then create the
that you can then alter.
Now, typographers are the
And I have some good
which is that you
As matter of fact, we
Whenever we change a font,
when we change the point size,
this is all the act
Now, as typographers of
But, you can also alter the
Choose them, combine the styles,
and alter the typographic
Turn the optional ones on.
Okay. I am almost done.
But, I have a few more terms.
And they actually have to do
with the negative
So, I just showed to you what
that represents a character.
And in a font it's
But, it also has a width,
Now, if I picked out a space
in a line, I get this rhythm,
So, type designers alter this
to get an even rhythm
Spacing is built into the font
But, you can change tracking.
Tracking is a modifier
And it can either be neutral,
And it is global for all
And it either moves the apart
which is actually useful
when you're doing
You'll probably want to bring
and pull it together
Now, tracking can be confused
And kerning really is
for individual pairs of glyphs.
So, in this case the
and so the font has a kerning
bring them closer together.
The kerning table again, is
and put inside of the font.
And you don't control it.
It just happens automatically.
However, leading, which is
is something you can control.
So, the name leading comes
when to put lines of type
you would have stick pieces
So, we just saw spacing,
Spacing and kerning
But, tracking and
And that is really all I
So, now you are all caught
Now, let's look at some
We start with legibility.
The legibility has to do
and distinguishing them
You may be familiar
that some typefaces have
However, what is not legible
at one size is actually
in another size.
Scale is connected
And when you alter the
details that were
and not visible become visible.
So, what is affected is
Now, in these situations
like road signage.
So, you're driving on
that you see is very
but it's far away from you.
And so a scale is not just
but also distance from the
to the reading surface.
Now, in these situations
to small scale typography
So, for instance, bringing
or making the type bolder may
But legibility does
It also applies to layouts.
It's probably very obvious
where hierarchy is clear
so legible at another scale.
And the issue there is the
It actually increases very much.
So, what you could do
is you could spread
But, often times it's
to rethink your hierarchy and
your layout for different
Now, if you want to know more
on Friday that talks
which is the methodology
And also they'll have tips on
which is the important part.
Now, the scale and density,
and layouts, but
So, let me give you an example.
What is this glyph?
What is it called?
Of course it's the at sign.
But, in Italy we have
We call it chiocciola,
So, when we have to design
we started with SF Mono, sorry,
we started with the
And of course we did this, all
However, when we have,
in the right context and scale,
we realized the density
It was just getting muddy
So, we came up with a
Now, let me blow it up.
So, in this example,
of the glyph by very much.
And we did that by
which is very critical
Now, consider also the H, M
Now, if I blow them up really
that the strokes aren't
And that is because you,
when they are big you
but when they are
So, we're sort of
that they have the same density.
Okay. So, imagine you're getting
And you're trying to
and where you're trying to go.
Now, you're probably
probably to Church Avenue.
But, where are you?
I know where you are.
You're in New York,
Now, I also happen to know, I
to know that this is not exactly
So, I recreate that sign with
But, what I'm trying to
of typographic voice, which is
to a different style, even
not only does that sign
but it doesn't feel the same.
Okay. So, typefaces
and this does not feel
and nor does this one.
So, this voice property
And actually it helps
So, for instance, I am
and now I'm playing a game.
Maybe that's not so appropriate
So, typefaces really help
and helping your user
Okay. So, these are the
We saw legibility,
So, now I want to talk
When we do typography
you have three fundamental
The first one is system font,
and the third one
Now, a system font you already
And it feels native to the
To access it the system font
watchOS, tvOS, and the macOS.
So, NSFont and UIFont
And they have a lot of benefits.
They give you access to the
of the nine weights, but also
Basically the letters
or further apart automatically,
that you request
You also get such specific
And you get access for the Bold
in the settings in iOS.
People can turn it on
on all their devices bold.
Now, the second tool you have
And it's a great tool.
It's available on
And dynamic type is
The first one is the
preferredFont forTextStyle.
And these give you access
that give you fonts that are
So, you can request a font for
and you get fonts that
But, they're tweaked
But, dynamic type is also
which you may be familiar with
So, people can go
they can move the
and they can change the global
It's a great accessibility
Now, if you use dynamic type and
dynamic type support is
However, if you're
or you call a system font
to do some work to
But, it's really easy.
And let me show you
First you have to
then you can have a
with content size
to override this
This is a method
You control the subclasses.
Then you update your fonts
and you relayout,
So, let's see these steps
How do you actually
Well, that's easy.
You just drag it into Xcode, and
in the info plist list.
There is a key for it.
Now, for the concise
to of course have a lookup table
and possibly weights,
or even leading, depending on
So, I have a lookup table that
I have a tool pool, a
leading, and tracking.
And the symbols that you
size categories.
Notice that they
than the notches in the slider.
Because there's five
people can turn on in their
So, when you went
remember about these as well.
Now, once you have that,
you just override
DidChange method.
And inside of there
You can have code that
and whatever it looks like,
can adjust the font
So, when you're inside of that
trait collection of
And look up the preferred
And then you just
of your lookup table
Now, step 5 is relayout.
But, if you're using auto layout
If you're interested in
there are sessions
about this specific topic.
All right.
So, we just saw how to
with custom fonts.
But, imagine you want to
How do you actually go about it?
Now, if you're getting
to use custom fonts,
with one typeface at a time.
It's actually much
But, more importantly,
that you're considering, try to
because it really
Typefaces are tools.
They are designed by people
And understanding the purpose
of the font, as the
And also consider knobs
Kerning is not something you
from your app context.
So if the font is not kerning.
Well, you might want to
But, however, if
that is too tight you
So, no worries.
All right.
So, we just saw system
and we saw custom fonts.
So, next I want to show you some
to consider using
The first one I want
Arrows are a great thing.
They are useful for
But, also they're
where the information density
to get just a little
Now, arrows in a staff,
in the font as characters.
So, you can copy and paste
in Xcode for instance, and
But, more importantly
they are weight matched
And if people change
or use dynamic type, the
Now, the second deal
about is high-legibility
I talked about alternates
And we have the new
which helps in situations
If you're typesetting a string
where the context is
which glyph is which, and maybe
or type it somewhere else.
They have to read it
it has to be ambiguous
So, there's a new statistic
of these glyphs to
So, the I gets a serif,
the L gets a little tail and
from the eight.
Now, these shapes we don't
on all the time,
they're pretty, they're
And they're highly disruptive
and feel actually
So, use them sparingly
But, this is the
And this code, by the way,
and NSFont, is exactly the same.
You start with the
you derive a font
And then you can modify
And then derive another
Next, the small caps.
Now, I'm sure you're
and lowercase letters as well.
But, there is a third member of
Now, small caps are a smaller
that align with the lowercase.
And when I say align,
They actually ought
Now, when are they useful?
Well, when you type
like acronym, for instance.
Acronyms or when you want
to create subtle
like you have the
to de-emphasize another piece
Let me show you a case study
of how we use small
Now, you have this paragraph,
of like a list on the
on the right hand side.
And you want the text of the
to stand out a little bit.
Now, if you look at his as
of start telling that that
of trumping everything
It looks a little bit too large.
Now, one thing you could
you could change the point
But, if you did that it would
and too close.
So, the density will start
to be non-matched
So, what you can do, small caps.
Small caps preserve
But, they also preserve
and the stroke thickness.
Now, there are two fundamental
to get small caps
And they have to do
between the typographic features
So, imagine you have a piece
and you're turning on the small
you get a piece of text
This looks good.
Now, if you get, if you have
upper and lowercase, and
from uppercase feature,
This does not look good.
The problem with this one is
that the capital letters are
And they almost look
So, please try not to
And lastly, if you have a
and you turn on the small
you get all lowercase, which
But at least it doesn't
So, we're fine.
Now, the small caps from
the code is exactly the
that I showed you earlier for
And you just have to
and the selector.
Now, there's another way of
and it's from a lowercase
Now, I'm sorry, if you have
and you turn on small
you get all uppercase,
which again is not really
But, at least it
Now, when you turn on
on a mixed case string,
You get a mixed caps
which is legitimate.
We actually do use this
It's certain zoom levels.
Small caps are really
And this is one way to create a
So, again, this is fine.
Now, if you have an all
on the small caps
you get all small caps,
So, again the code to do
I just changed the piece
And one thing you
you can actually turn
So, depending where you got
if it's under your control, if
to turn both at once
Now, there's one
Which is, well they're
but there is something
Which is that they also operate
but also on numbers
And you may be wondering why.
The reason is because you
like this, and you want to
So, we support small cap
and all of these in system font.
All right.
So, we just saw some details
high-legibility alternates,
And that's really all
We just saw the San Francisco
with the new SF Mono
We hope you enjoy it.
We saw some terminology.
We looked at some typographic
and yeah, design concepts.
And then we looked
And lastly we saw some details.
Some small new feature that you
Now, for more information,
at this URL you will find
But, you'll also find a
to sites that can
in your new journey
And there also related sessions.
These have yet to happen,
There is, the first session
that will greatly help
But, I don't want to spoil it.
The other two sessions
with making your apps adaptive.
So, auto layout topics.
The iterative design gives
and of how to evaluate
And then, What's new in Auto
It's really good too.
And that's it.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]