[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everybody.
My name is Mike Stern, and
at Apple.
And it's a great pleasure
about designing for Apple Watch.
Now, in today's session,
to apply design best practices
and leverage the new
to design Apple Watch
focused, and delightful.
But before we get there, I
Now, after all, some of you
watchOS app.
There are three basic components
complications, notifications,
A complication is
that people can display
The term complication comes
and it refers to any feature
on a timepiece beyond the
Complications made the
and repair of watches
and more complicated,
Now, fortunately for you,
to make for Apple Watch and
Complications on Apple
for people to access information
and provide a really
Notifications tell people
that they might otherwise
And because they're also
to push interactions to the
And lastly, apps offer
with your product or service.
Now, providing a complication
or making watch-specific
to also have an app.
These three basic components
Each plays an integral role
in the overall user
So, for example, let's say
that I'm ordering
I might start out by tapping
to launch the app.
I then use the app
And after doing that, I would
with a time estimate about
While I wait for
I might periodically
to see how much longer
And when my order
I might get another
And finally, if I hadn't already
I might get a notification
if I would like to do so.
So that's the basics
Now this presentation
to design each of these well.
But before we get there, there's
even more fundamental, that
And that's the concept of time.
Apple Watch was specifically
to support lightweight
meaning that people should
and take action in very,
Now I suppose this is an obvious
to lose sight of this.
Of just how quick
when you're designing comps
or testing your builds
Now as you design your app,
to find faster and less
There's always a
For instance, many
of our built-in apps
and quicker to navigate.
Previously, starting a
to the Home screen,
select a workout type, pick
that you used last,
The new flow is much simpler,
especially if you use
You just tap the complication,
then click Start,
Now Quick Start lets
for selecting their workout
for a separate Start button.
Now most people workout the
So, for those people,
to start a workout.
And the UI shown
out has also been optimized
Previously, there
that people could swipe through.
One for controls, and one for
And navigating between these
much time.
In watchOS 3, there's just two
There's basically no need to
with your workout or if
Now this frees people
on what's most important
for a run or riding their bike.
Focus on your cadence,
Look out for cars, pedestrians.
Enjoy the scenery,
With watchOS 3, the
and engineering team rallied
for this release which I
Those themes are glanceable,
Glanceable means
so that it's immediately
Your design must communicate
You should only display
most relevant.
Ideally, the information
that your app displays
This means inspiring people to
to what your app communicates,
to access functionality from
And apps should be responsive.
Launch times and screen
to an absolute minimum.
Content and data should
and UI feedback should
Now to help your apps be
and responsive, major
to the navigational model and
The new Dock provides people
of timely and
from their favorite apps.
Apps in the Dock
and can periodically
which means that navigating to
and people will spend
for app content to update.
And once you're in an app,
between detail screens,
which greatly reduces the
These changes can
interaction time.
In fact, with watchOS 3 our
was reduced from 5
Now, admittedly, the first time
"That is pretty ambitious."
I mean, it literally
to say the words "2 seconds".
But, the truth is
like checking scores for a
or checking stocks can
Now, throughout the day,
than a few seconds checking
But each of those interactions
of seconds.
And taking action
Simple actions that only require
on Apple Watch.
People should be able to set
or check things off on
in 2 seconds or less.
Now even if you can't
down to 2 seconds, the
so will help you spot workflow
to streamline your app.
All right, so now let's get
to make really great apps,
notifications, and
Now, in my humble opinion,
and most glanceable interaction
that someone can
Checking a complication
as raising one's
No additional interaction
This is definitely
that takes 2 seconds or less.
And with watchOS 3 and iOS
to raise awareness
to make them easier to install
and to give them
So, for starters, you can now
to browse and configure
of sense because this is
which takes more than 2 seconds.
Now the configuration UI
of how the complication
and it's easy for people to
and the value it
The Apple Watch app also
that are preconfigured
And there's a section dedicated
Now if you've made a
Apple Watch owners who have your
see your complication here.
If your complication
people can simply
And this will install your
The feature complication
to raise awareness
It will now be so much
about the complications
Now another big change has
Any app with a complication
on the user's current watch
and have more background
This means that launch time
and app data should
Complications are great app
that they display
to want to know more.
So that process has to be quick.
So seeing the current
curious about this
Or, seeing that your primary
make you want to know how
And the last big change
to the frequency of updates.
In watchOS 3, your
to update your complication
You control the frequency
So a travel complication
around the departure and
while a sport complication
around a game that
By controlling when
your complication can stay
Now as you work on
consider how external factors
and user activity patterns
of your complication updates.
So, if you're going to
you should make a complication.
There's a reason why they became
so popular among watch
All of that complexity
So I hope I've done a decent
on the idea of making
And if so, I'd like to
about what it takes to make
Now the most important
when designing a complication is
to display.
The best complications answer
to ask themselves
Now I run most days
So the night before,
to see what time the sun
alarm clock.
And when I get up, I want
to know what the
so I know how to
And I'll check to see what
to make sure I have
And I'll also check
to make sure I don't need
to leave really early
Now the answers to these
how I plan my day.
And by answering these questions
of the wrist, these
and immediate value
And complications can be a
They can inspire
More actionable.
The Activity complication,
shows me progress towards
the day.
I can see if I'm on track
or if I need to go
with my dogs after work.
And WaterMinder's complication
making towards my
And it seems I'm actually a
to take this as an
Hold on one second.
Ahh.
[ Laughter ]
[ Applause ]
So, if you had to pick just
with your complication
that use your app,
What's the thing that
in knowing throughout
Does that information
to remain interesting?
Now, sometimes, the answer to
Now if you can't quite narrow
of information, consider
That's what the app
They let you configure what type
of weather information
Temperature, temperature and
precipitation, chance of
Now during the summertime
in California, it
So seeing the chance
of precipitation is
0% today. That is
Of course, just as an aside, I
It's actually supposed
So, heads up.
Just in time.
But, you know, during the same
the UV index is incredibly
And allowing this complication
to be customizable is
And CARROT Weather has
of making their complication
Each one, except for
uses a simple and
to label the value that's shown.
And they don't try to cram in
because that would just
that are too small to read.
Now if you haven't made
it's important to know
that there are multiple
Circular, modular
utility small, and
And new to watchOS
I wanted to get a
but I didn't have time.
Now each of these complication
or more complication
to particular watch faces.
The Color watch face uses the
The modular watch face uses
family and the modular
The simple utility
and chronograph watch faces use
And the utility and Mickey watch
complication family.
And the all-new extra-large
does anyone want to guess?
That's right.
Extra-large watch face uses the
You guys are quick.
Now I hope you wrote
because that information
No, I'm just kidding.
All of that information
in the watchOS Human
This is your go-to place
to the design of your watch app.
I highly recommend
Now it's important that
for every complication family
so that people can
on the watch face
And be sure to use
for your complication
of what people will see
when they actually
Without placeholder data,
for people to anticipate what
All right.
As you can see, some
for more detailed information.
On the modular watch face,
if someone has made your
they certainly care a lot about
Take this as an opportunity
to provide slightly
that they might find helpful.
In fact, you may want to display
based on the complication
If weather information is
there's no reason why you
of the CARROT Weather
Maybe you'd use modular large
and condition, and modular small
Now even if you can't quite
to show in your complication,
you can always just
The complication for Just
for recording voice memos,
Tapping it launches
but it also begins
It's super convenient and fast.
So if it's not already clear, we
And we think that
the more Apple Watch
about how useful
the more complications
Now to make it easier to access
people can now easily switch
With a simple swipe, you can go
to the workout watch face, and
to the weekend watch face.
Now think about all of
that we do with our time.
Right? The variety
No, seriously.
We workout, we hangout,
we play sports and do countless
Now, it'll be easier
and complications installed to
And this should lead to
of complications on Apple Watch.
Make one of those
All right, so that
Now, let's move on to best
Notifications should
and they should be
to communicate information
In other words, they
Keep in mind that the person
could be anywhere and
They could be at dinner,
riding on the subway,
or in a meeting discussing
Now, in so many situations,
in the task at hand or just
to the world around them.
So your notifications need
to communicate clearly
Luckily, making your
so difficult.
First, you just need to
Now notifications
ashort look and a long look.
And as the name implies,
to give you a sense of
about really quickly.
And the title that you provide
Now, in some cases, that title
need to know about
Second, only show
I can't stress this enough.
The more you show
the harder it's going to
on what's most important.
So let's say you're making
for a travel app.
The notification might
of potentially useful
about the traveler's flight.
But seeing things like the
in a notification when it's
that important, so
that information altogether.
Third, present important
By putting the most
people are more likely to
without the need to scroll.
And this is really helpful if
and they might not be able
or access the Digital Crown.
So for our check-in
we might move content
and boarding time a
down in the notification.
Fourth, vary the size
to establish a clear
Your notification should
on the most important
This notification has all the
in the right order, but
with equivalent visual weight.
Apple Watch notifications
You have full control over
background and sash color.
Use this capability to
out what's most important.
Now this design really
like ticket class, seat number,
And the purpose of this
for you to check in
And lastly,
thoughtfully-designed
graphics, and animations
to convey meaning
Visuals can sometimes
and more clearly than text.
Icons can help save space
to display everything
But be mindful that some
understood or could
So you want to look for icons
across regions and cultures,
to be clear to the
And short, meaningful
to complement text and to
And graphs and other data
for a more interesting visual
in far more meaning
But there's more to consider
of your notifications.
You also need to think
and when you're sending them.
Getting a notification
at the wrong time can be just
If you got a notification
so annoyed unless it was about
than being here right now,
which is completely
Now, because Apple Watch
on their wrist when they
notifications are
If your app sends
that are not genuinely useful,
people are likely to just
to send notifications
So, how do you know why and
Well, the best approach is to
to the people who use your app
and intelligently
for when they're
Now I have two really
I have two really
The first is from the
Dark Sky notifies people
about significant
such as when it's
or when rain is about to stop.
Now, in the case of Dark
by contextual factors.
Notifications are sent based on
to an approaching or
And notifications are sent early
to get the umbrella out
down raining cats and dogs.
Now, because these notifications
and timely, they
Knowing that it's about to
to get ready to go for a run.
to walk to my couch
Now, in addition to contextual
and patterns can provide
into what people want to know
and when they want
Now, to explain, let's
Streaks is an app that helps
and also just won an
People can pick up to
to do on a daily basis.
Now, as the name suggests,
on streaks of daily tasks
because doing something
to become a routine.
So, if you want to
of doing core-strengthening
Which I should be doing or
or remembering to refill your
for a walk, Streaks is going
My dogs have never been
They don't realize it, but
Of course, the whole point
that people want to
but just can't seem
So Streaks uses notifications
But these reminders are
at just the right time.
They should arrive close to
to take action.
Or, put another way, when
But how does Streaks
Well, at first, they don't.
To explain what it does, let's
Now I'm trying to get into
And at a somewhat randomized
I'll get a reminder
It doesn't arrive so late
to play guitar or that
But it's not so early that
So, for simplicity's sake,
let's say I get the
Now, that's a bit early.
So I can tap a 30-minute
and delaying that notification
until I'm finally
And when I play guitar,
as complete in the app.
Streaks takes note of this time.
Day after day, each time I
Streaks gets an increasingly
of when I typically play guitar.
Streaks uses that time
to automatically arrive
It's such a simple
The actual timing
because obviously I can't just
of a hat and start
However, automatically
and notifications might not
Some tasks you want to do
and Streaks gives you
Or maybe you don't want
you just want one
So Streaks gives
And you can disable
or turn off notifications
So by smartly choosing when
and giving users full
like to be notified,
that Streaks sends are less
ignored, and unwelcome.
Now the notifications
that Streaks sends
as they remind people to
physical task.
But making notifications
literally adding actions
Now I encourage you to explore
that you send actionable.
Being able to quickly triage
from your wrist is a
Notifications can push
who use your app, and they're
of engagement to people
of their day.
Now you can have up to four
And be sure to only show
to the content of
Make sure that actions are
and use action-oriented verbs.
And try to focus on actions
in one tap just one
However, sometimes one
or two additional steps
Now multi-step flows will
and that used to be
because apps would take a
But in watchOS 3, when your
your app will be launched
This gives you an opportunity
to make sure your app's data is
for people to show up.
So don't shy away from
if that's what's necessary.
Now, speaking of taking
it's time to talk about apps.
watchOS 3 will profoundly
and interact with apps.
Let's take a look at the
and what they'll mean to you.
Let's start with the new Dock.
People can put up to 10 of their
and every app in the Dock is
from the Dock into an app fast.
And what's shown are
These snapshots should
to be informative
And snapshots from your app
to keep them current.
Apps in the Dock are
at least once an hour.
This lets you fetch new
and request that the
of your app if it's necessary.
And when your app is viewed in
that it can update its
Now when someone puts
you should be flattered.
Being in the Dock means that
that people want to be
Because of this, it's
of your app are not only
Now, in some situations,
that they saw when they were
that relevant.
Fortunately, watchOS 3 provides
to a different screen
that they were last looking at.
So, for instance,
that shows a list view of
And of course, each of these
to a detail screen
Okay. Now, imagine yourself
The last time you were in
at this particular game.
And when you exit out and
you probably expect to continue
to see the details
And when the game
You probably still expect to see
But after a little while,
the details about this
and less relevant.
You may have learned
from a notification the app
on Twitter, in the news.
At some point, the content here
You're not interested
Perhaps you're going
in seeing the next
Or if your favorite team is
already started,
to see the details
Now these are the sorts
to be asking about your app.
And as you do so, I want you
to consider the following
First and foremost,
to proactively anticipate
Put yourself in their
Graphing events onto a timeline
for doing this.
Plot out significant events
"How do these events influence
In the hypothetical baseball
I speculated that people will
or during the times where
While, at other times, those
about the overall
However, this is probably
Individual preferences
on what's most relevant
For instance, a fair-weather
about one team might expect to
than a hardcore baseball fanatic
And for other apps, other
of day and location
on what people want to see.
Now, as a general rule,
when an app changes
and the state isn't saved.
And it can be confusing
So if you choose to navigate
you want to do so in a way
The hope is that
to realize what's going on.
But if they do, they
to make some really accurate
of your app's UI changes
And I would also recommend
against making the snapshot
from your app.
This can make your app a
and may be harder to find.
Now it's totally fine to just
or maybe hide some stuff
when your app is
But, you know, if you want
of certain things for
But don't make it look
Now next, avoid showing
or confirmation dialogues, or
When seen out of context,
these sorts of screens
And in fact, they might
or make no sense at all.
So, depending on the situation,
consider programmatically
after some period of time.
And lastly, optimize your app
in a miniaturized form.
Now, in the Dock, apps
and this is, like, just
but 62.4851% of their
You'll want to avoid
from becoming illegible
Now for this very reason, the
and a lot of text in the
from regular to medium.
At smaller sizes, bolder
And for really key information,
This may require removing some
to make space, but that's not
Now, by following these
as glanceable as
And speaking of glanceable,
some of you may be
Glances were designed to be a
and contextually-relevant
from the user's favorite apps.
Not coincidentally, the Dock
purpose while simplifying the
In a way, Glances
And the Dock, in turn, made
So they were removed
With that said, the time and
into designing your Glances is
about how to design your app
Okay. So, the next big change
but powerful improvement to how
Most existing Apple Watch apps
Basically, a top-level list
Now that's not so
to organize data hierarchically.
Unfortunately, navigating
between those screens can
to return to that top-level
So, for example, if I want
I select an item,
select another item,
So forth and so on.
It's kind of like being in a
to get to the room
But in order to get there, you
and then back down
It'd be so much more efficient
if there was just a
So in watchOS 3, we now
It's now possible to navigate
to another by swiping vertically
Think of it like vertical paging
Now if your app is already
you should really consider
But one thing to point out is
that this behavior
when the detail screens are
So with the previous
the 10-day forecast made
It was accessed by scrolling
In the new version of Weather,
to a child view so that
on screen at once.
So if you want to opt into
to refactor your design
And for those of you
now is a really good time
or to consider doing so.
Navigating with the Digital
than swiping horizontally
And page-based apps do
Obviously, that's not
And having a top-level
of detail items can
By moving from a page-based
our Weather App can
and low temperatures for
This is very handy.
Okay. Now, the third
on watchOS 3 relates
Now besides just being
stickiness describes how
in the foreground.
On watchOS 3, apps can
which is quite a bit
So when someone is
and then drops their wrist,
your app will be the
when they raise their
as they do so within 8 minutes.
In fact, with every
that timer gets reset
Now making apps stickier is
Apple Watch apps are intended
that can occur over many
But during those periods, the
for many minutes at a time.
So, one example might
When shopping, most of your
reading labels, inspecting
trying to avoid crashing
and trying to look cool.
There are so many activities
They're what we might
or session-based activities.
Cooking dinner, playing sports,
These things all take
in which people will
to stay on task.
Stronger stickiness puts you
where you left off, which
Okay. Now, the fourth
for apps involves
when it's okay to
When people initiate
they expect to get
Did the task succeed
Unfortunately, providing
conformation of success or
Slow networks, weak
and long Bluetooth ranges might
or remote delays.
Apps that allow people to
like garage doors or window
to provide completion feedback
until those devices have
And some services
or ride-ordering apps
with other people.
And as we all know, people
to you promptly.
Now on an iPhone or a Mac,
you would ordinarily
with your app while
that confirmation feedback.
Progress indicators are a way
They make people
They basically say,
I'll be right with you."
But, however, it might
All the while, the person
wrist raised.
Their shoulder starts
Seconds start to
It really starts to slow down.
So, to avoid this
you should use an NSURL
to communicate with your server.
This does two things.
First, it helps to make sure
to your server before
And second, when
Apple Watch will
And then, in turn, you can
and do something like
which is also new to watchOS
to the person who's
So, for example, say you're
When someone places a
to make sure that the
and provide an estimated
You wouldn't want people to keep
these things out.
Instead, it's way better to
that their order has been
You can also let people know,
That once the restaurant
and provides an estimated
you'll send a final
that the order has been
Now, if you've done this
to drop their wrist, trusting
to complete the task that
And if all goes well, you send
to let them know that the
and it is on its way.
And if there's a problem,
and help people address
with minimal additional
Now, the key to making
People need to trust that your
and that you'll make sure
about whether the task
And related to trust, you
into thinking that a
if it's actually
That's basically lying, which
Okay, so that was a lot
And there's still a little bit
to pause here for a
We looked at the new Dock
as glanceable and
We saw how the Digital
between detail screens
and hierarchical apps
We learned how session-based
from changes to app stickiness.
And we just saw how the ability
to schedule local notifications
in the background
who use your app the
to keep interactions quick.
Now we think that
to watchOS will empower you to
that shorten user
Now, if the Apple Watch
this would have been a
I would have had plenty to
But they did not stop there.
They're like a bunch
The kind of people who made me
In watchOS 3, there's
and frameworks to let you
For starters, watchOS 3 now
our 2D and 3D graphics
SpriteKit and SceneKit let you
They let you make elements
or to animate things
And you can implement
I mean, it's crazy.
Force fields, detect
Now you might think about these
for games, but you can
And watchOS 3 has
Up until now, touch input
The controls and views that you
to touch events on your behalf.
Now, you have the ability to
So you can do something
or pan, or long press.
This one takes a
Okay, in watchOS 3,
to raw Digital Crown events.
You can use this data to
and other visual
Or, you can use the
for changing selection
So, what can you do with
Well, for starters,
to visualize data
With SpriteKit, you
like this programmatically so
between any two arbitrary
You can use the default
which provides a really
Or, you can do something
for a bouncy animation,
of animation that you'd like.
There's a ton of open
by the very generous people
in the SpriteKit
And you can even do things
of the rings to reflect
Data visualization, like charts
to life with animation.
By drawing this chart
we can animate the built-in
or we can use animation
to a particular part
SpriteKit properties
so you can easily
to display different
Or, perhaps you want
to let people inspect
with a pan gesture.
Totally. Or, better still,
you can let people
to do the same thing.
Or, let people zoom
Or, maybe let people scroll.
And since you have full
and how the graph responds,
or slowly things happen
Now, I could go on.
This is a lot of fun to just
but that would take all of
Now, I encourage you to
and SceneKit, and experiment
to create richer and more
But just remember,
with increased freedom comes
Animating something just because
good reason.
When used well, animation
quickly, and thereby
Similarly, making a graph
richer and more informative
and ideally reduce the need for
Okay. So, we've covered a lot
to leave you with
about designing your watch app.
Making a great Apple Watch
things simple.
But making something simple
And bonus points if you
Keeping things simple
about what your app will do.
It means saying no to a lot
of really interesting-sounding
But just because you can
that you should.
Keeping things simple
about the journey that people
of their day.
People will experience
And the way that you design
of this.
Think less in terms of
in terms of user flows.
Account for the fact that
uninterrupted experiences.
People will drop in at arbitrary
And when they do, they'll always
and relevant to their
Your app should anticipate
at any given moment, and attempt
and functionality that's
and timely.
Now doing that right
Designing for Apple Watch
for an iPhone, an
What we know about
for these devices has
about how complex apps should
and how much time they're
Try to recognize and
deeply-rooted assumptions.
This is easier said than done.
I know. But this is a crucial
great watch app.
Now, for Apple Watch,
that I can offer you
of features and not apps.
Making something great for Apple
one feature.
Just Press Record is
The complication is
and the app is the recording
It works great.
And I literally just described
Two seconds goes by in a flash.
There's nothing simple
for such brief interactions.
But I hope the concepts
that we discussed today will
And I'm really excited to
of the new capabilities
A lot of people worked
and all of that work was in
to build more innovative,
and platform-defining
Okay. So for more information
please check out the video page
where there's a ton
Again, definitely go and check
out the watchOS Human
There's a ton of really
And we're going to continue
so check in regularly.
We also have a lot of great
I would definitely
out SpriteKit one and watching
that have already happened.
And this year, we had a lot of
Some of them are still to come.
I highly recommend Inclusive
to design for accessibility
for people around the world.
I also recommend the
about Typography and Fonts.
And there's one more
about Iterative UI Designs
and refine them and come up with
With that, thank you
[ Applause ]