[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everyone.
Wow it's loud.
Thank you all for coming.
We're really excited to be here.
My name is Ryan Olshavsky.
And with me down
We're designers on an
where we make the Numbers,
for Mac, iOS, and iCloud.
Jon and I have been
for quite a while both
And if there's one thing
of our years of experience, it's
And I know that sounds like
because it's good
if everybody believes this.
And maybe some of you have seen
well that doesn't look too hard.
And you're right a lot of times
or effortless.
But what makes design difficult
to answer to do it well.
Questions like, what
Who is it for?
Does it actually work?
And did we get it right?
These questions do not
And they're always
for the most experienced
And if you're a solo developer,
on your team, or if you just
before, trying to answer
daunting task.
But we do it anyway, because
it's important and it can have
of your app and on
A poorly thought out design
and obvious interaction
and potentially embarrassing
A great design, on
can transform an
into something simple,
Even when it's based
on something extraordinarily
Now unfortunately there are
There's no magic button you
of disparate features
and successful product.
Design is not effortless.
It takes time, commitment,
But the good news is there are
There are tools, techniques
to mitigate uncertainty
to a great design sooner.
So today, Jon and I are going to
and methods that we use on our
to help you find answers
Specifically, what
Where do we start?
And what's the right design.
So first, what are we making?
We're going to start
because if you can answer this
questions a lot easier.
So maybe you have a bunch
but can't decide which
Or maybe you've identified a
but don't know exactly what
in that audience want or need.
Or maybe you've built a
but don't know who
A powerful way to answer those
That is, take all the things you
Identify the features that
who will use your
that serve your own
in order to determine
So as an example, throughout
to pretend to design an app.
And how many of you here
Great. Well, if you haven't
down in Apple Headquarters
It has a rotating menu
and most Apply employees
But a lot of people walk down
order their food, pay for their
to their desk and eat there.
So to make it a little
we're going to design
that lets employees order a meal
and have it delivered
Which is pretty cool.
So, fair warning, you're
of food coming up, so if you
or a snack before the
So, let's go through the
So like I said first,
and collect all the features
So you want to include
So we're pretty sure we'll
details about those entrees
But you also, and include
Capture all the features
and your audience might
So in our case we might want
see ratings, quickly
Maybe we could offer
And so on.
There aren't any good or bad
to include anything you want.
And then once you have
to set it aside for a little bit
to do is figure out
for and what they need.
Now this can often be
because it's not uncommon
to have completely
about who is going
But without a shared
of who your user is, and what
up with a hodgepodge of features
you might spend a lot of time
that nobody knows about because
So let's start with a
First, you are not the user.
You might be a user of your app,
you risk building in
about the user experience
that might be completely
For example, I'm an Apple
of the Caffé Macs app
but I almost exclusively
And if I were to design the
I'd put the burger of the
and that would be it because
And that would be great for me,
who prefer salad, or who like
that normal people eat.
Designing for yourself
from what matters
But the opposite is also true.
Your audience should
because this is too
to draw any meaningful
about what would be most
to the real people
Instead you need to focus on
of your target audience.
And one way to do that is
to image you're interviewing
to use your app to
and what they don't like,
In our case, we might ask our
meal, or something
Do they like to take
or just grab something
Do they get the same
Or do they like to try
And do they prefer
Or do they just pickup
Try to capture a range
in a few questions like these.
And then pick the answers that
to serve with your app.
You can use your instinct
and if you have user
you can use that to
In our case, it's already pretty
and get a premade
So, instead, we want to focus
for a quick interesting, fresh,
Once you know the
of your customer, you
as a set of goals.
So, our customer goals
eat quickly, or sorry.
Enjoy a fresh meal, eat
and make healthy choices.
Articulating your
like this will help you focus
on their needs throughout
But what about you?
What about your goals as an app
Maybe you want people to
Or maybe you want it to be a
Or maybe you want it
You want to capture those
as app goals that describe what
like, how it should feel
and what makes it
So our app goals might be
to provide a convenient
so people don't have to walk
We want to highlight
so customers know
that are available to them.
And we want Caffé Macs
so they keep coming back.
Now, note that this list
be profitable, or earn a
or optimize food costs.
While those are important goals
they don't really provide
for the design.
And that's because business
to get out of your app
App goals on the other
of experience you want
You need to understand both
But it's your app goals that
to design and build
All right so finally, to figure
out what exactly
we need to consider all those
in step one from the perspective
of our customer goals
So, here's our list again.
And by looking at each one
of our goals, you can pretty
that are appropriate
So, in addition to the
we can also include an
that serves our customers'
and interesting to eat.
And a feedback link
of making diners happy
to let us know if
By the same method we
that do not serve our goals.
Now this isn't to say
or that they're not
they just don't fit our
So we can set them aside
to them in a future release.
All right, check this out.
Now that we actually
and we know what we're making.
We have a nice succinct
on a solid understanding of
and what's going to matter to
And so now to tell
to actually start
I'm going to hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Ryan.
So now that know
let's start designing our app.
But where do we start?
Well what I like to do is I
You might not know how all
or work yet, but
or two things you
and you can start
For example, if you're designing
to start by designing
because you know that's where
to be spending their time.
Or, if you're designing a
by designing the profile
that that's going to be a
In our case, I'm designing
So I don't know much
but I know at the very least,
so that people can
So I'll start by
So for this demo, I'm going
You might already know Keynote
but it's also a great
It creates layouts very easily,
you can try out different
You can even make
that you can load
In our group, we like Keynote
of our apps using Keynote.
In fact, even Keynote was
Think about that.
[ Applause ]
That shouldn't even be possible.
But it is because
So, let's start drawing UI.
UI is made up of a
It's made up of shapes and lines
and I can insert those
I can just tap to
I can tap to insert a line.
UI also has text.
And I can insert
on this and get a textbox.
And UI also has images.
On my desktop I have
and I can just drag
And I can resize that.
Great. So to start, I'm just
I'm going to copy
I'm going to change its
because this is the
And I'm going to make it white
So in just 30 seconds I've
iPhone app.
It's a flashlight.
Ha,ha [laughter].
I'm just kidding.
So I'm going to draw a menu
like to do is I like to take
and use them as references.
So here I have a screenshot
So I'm just going
It comes in a little large
So I'm just going to resize it.
And I'm going to put this next
And now that I have
to what I'm drawing, I
So I'm going to start by
out the layout of my screen.
So I'm just going to resize
I turned on my accessibility
in system preferences so I
and make sure that
Okay. I'm going to do
I know that this
Again, I'm going to zoom
in to make sure it is
Great and now I'm just going
to start duplicating this
I don't really care where
I can be a little bit sloppy,
because I'll clean
The only one I do care
I want to make sure that
where I want it.
Great, because now I can
and space them out evenly,
So that was a really quick way
to just get all my lines
Oh, okay. That was not
So now I want to change
and I can do that here.
I can make it gray.
Or if I wanted to
I could use the system
and use the eyedropper tool.
This turns my mouse
and now I can click on a
and it will use that
And now I'll do the same
I'll get this light gray.
So I've already got the outline
of the screen that
So the next thing I want
So I'm going to take this
to match the style of the
So I can start by just typing in
You can see that the font
I know that iPhone system
So I can set it to
And I'm just going to
It looks like what I'm trying
And I could actually
and make sure that it is exact.
Great. So it looks like
I can do the same
Close enough.
Okay. So now I've got my
on my screenshot, and
maybe like it's gray so I'm
So now the next thing I want
to do is start putting
I've got this text file
of different entree
So I'm just going to copy and
Resize this.
Great. I also want to get
So I'll try to match that.
This looks like it's
That's great.
Stick this in the center.
And I'll call this Caffé Macs.
Okay. So now I've got some
The next thing I want to
I'm going to take my picture
Now I want to get the
So what I'm going
to use a shape and
So I'm going to just make this
And now, if I select
I can crop the image
Going to nudge it a bit.
Excellent.
And now my picture of fish
I can mask images in other ways.
I want to get the status
I don't want to draw it.
So I'm just going to
double click the mask it
and just grab the bar
I saved myself a
And the last thing I want,
I've got this other trick.
I can actually take a
of my screen using the
control, shift 4.
It's hard to remember,
When I do that it turns my
And now I can just draw
And it's copied to my clipboard
So that's a not well
Great. So now I've got one row.
So I'm going to group
And again, I'm going to do the
The only one I care about
because I can just
space them out and align them.
Great. And now the
to do is replace these images
in there to get it
To save some time I've actually
So it looks something
out all of the content.
So in just I don't know, three
[ Applause ]
So I want to talk a little bit
in the last couple minutes.
I started by using
to match colors,
I also used screenshots
of UI that I wanted to use.
I drew a bunch of squares and
and I zoomed in and
that they were pixel perfect.
And I used believable content
and texts to make my UI
I think with a little
and effort these steps
that anyone here can
So now I'll hand
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jon.
Great work as always.
All right so here's our
And we're done.
Right? This seems good enough.
Meets all the functional
Looks great.
It's tempting to just
onto the next feature
But how do we actually know
if this first design
Well, I can tell you from
And that's because you can't
if you try only one idea.
Instead you need to look at
and iterate on your design to
that you might miss otherwise.
Basically, you want to look
what could we do differently?
So here's our design again,
Well, in our case, it's based
so one thing you can do is just
Here by making the rows taller,
but we can make the
And you can also increase
of information that's
so here we've added the prices.
You can consider different
of white space between
That's the space around
that are on your screen.
So here we've added margins
up the UI a little bit.
You can also try
For example, here we're using
for the names, and we've
to make them stand out on
You can also just go where
So, we wondered, what it the
of food, because why not?
It's worth a try.
But what we found is that
on each row, we needed to
and bolder, which gives
And note that I'm not
of these designs yet.
We're just really brainstorming
of shake out new ideas.
So another technique you
So while this design
what about one that's
So we have a grid
It kind of looks like a
You can also think about the
and what shapes suit
So while these photos
maybe wider landscape
You can also look at different
Here each entrée is
which helps them feel more like
Think about how you use
these photos are edge-to-edge,
which makes the most
And in this layout to
we superimposed them
to create a different
And remember you
to a uniform grid
You can play with the size and
to create completely
You can combine ideas
So, here we took the
and merged it with the list
Think about how immersive you
These larger photos
which encourages the viewer to
And if your text is critical
to how readable it is.
Can somebody with
or color blindness make
And finally what if we took this
so that the image takes up
Here scrolling vertically
so instead we're using a
so you just swipe
So, consider how your
by different navigation schemes.
All right so here
to our original design.
These were all drawn
And you want to basically
do differently?
Until you've come
as many interesting alternatives
And again you can do that
into different layouts,
color, weight, and font.
Experimenting with proportions
and decreasing the amount
of information that's
Doing 180s and pushing
And considering different ways
of navigating through
So the next question is,
will any of these designs
We don't know yet.
This is a step when
to actually judge your designs.
This can be the fun part.
So you want to set aside
and forget all the time you
And instead pretend you're a
to evaluate and critique your
and weaknesses, and
So to do that you have to
and ask some tricky questions.
Things like, how well
audience's goals?
How well does it address
And does it fit the
Does the design provide people
Is there enough detail
Is it readable?
Is the design intuitive?
Are you using interface controls
And are you using terminology
given their context
And finally, does the
Even if it meets all
and it's objectively
does it feel the
Does it have the personality and
That's just as important
These questions are
And you will most likely
with your teammates and even
But asking these
to answer them honestly
to the right design.
So to demonstrate what
and I are going to now critique
of you, to find the one that
So let's take a second
All right what do you think Jon?
&gt;&gt; Looking at them side by
that some are better than others
and eliminate a couple
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; Let's get rid of A,
It's pretty good, but it's
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt; Let's get rid of D,
it doesn't have any photos,
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; A food app, we need photos.
Let's also get rid of E.
Yeah that one has
It feels so crowded
that much information.
&gt;&gt; True. I think we
It has a little bit
but I think the visual layout
and the entree names are getting
&gt;&gt; That's a good point.
&gt;&gt; I think we can get rid
of those photos are
but you can't really see
if it looks good or not.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; And then option L, even
I think paging through 12
or 15 different entrees
to be too tedious so I think we
&gt;&gt; I agree.
&gt;&gt; All right now we're down
All right [laughter].
Didn't take very long at all.
All right so let's look
in a little more detail.
So between these two,
they're very functionally
I would say that maybe option B
maybe more what people expect
And I actually like the
I think that's a nice look.
&gt;&gt; You know I actually
It's a little bit
I like how the topography
I think that's really hip now.
It's also cool how all
of the information is
It's really each to just scan
And I sort of like the
and feeling a little
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think, yeah
Thank you.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; You've convinced me.
All right let's get
This is totally ad lib
&gt;&gt; Okay these two look
they both have edge-to-edge
G has more of a grid layout,
while H looks more
I really like, I really like H.
You know there's a lot of
It feels really fun.
&gt;&gt; [Sigh] Yeah H looks cool,
which is that some of these
than others.
Like, we really want you
to buy grilled mahi-mahi
And that's not really the case.
These should all
I think if we like this style,
with balancing this
with the actual functional
&gt;&gt; I still really like
but I think you make
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; I think we should go with G.
&gt;&gt; All right fair enough.
All right so between these
like I've said the edge-to-edge
And I love that this reminds
which I think is a
&gt;&gt; Ryan, we are not designing
we are designing a delivery app.
You can't even see
I like how K has a better
Because it just seems more
&gt;&gt; All right I see
You gave me H, so
All right.
&gt;&gt; Okay, good.
&gt;&gt; Compromise.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right now we're
what do you think?
&gt;&gt; They look pretty good,
by side, I think it's
that G is not that great.
These descriptions are
of tell people what the food is.
And G just seems really
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Seeing them all
Even though I love the
having the descriptions,
the more information really
so I guess we'll get rid of G.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; All right now
in just a few minutes
down to just two options
These two are also very
They both look great I think.
They do have pretty
I don't actually, I
of these two, how about you?
&gt;&gt; Well [laughter], oh
They both look pretty good.
&gt;&gt; All right.
Well we were actually
And so maybe all
So given all of the, now you've
and given the goals and the
by round of applause, please
who thinks option C
[ Applause ]
Okay now, who thinks option
[ Cheering ]
All right well I think
which is pretty convenient
All right so our
Good job. So we've determined
that option K is the
of functionality, efficiency,
and the general feel we'd
So now have we actually
Well, we're on our way, right,
We now actually have to figure
So to tell you more about that,
I'm going to give
&gt;&gt; Thank you [applause].
We need to design a workflow.
A workflow is a set of steps
In my case the task
So let's go back to the
I think I'll take my
with what I know here.
I don't know much about
but I do one thing,
of those entrees I probably
about that.
So I'll go ahead and I'll
And maybe it looks
Okay. So now that I'm here,
I probably need a
So I'll put in an Order button.
And maybe it will just go on the
Excellent.
And now what happens if I
Well, I don't know.
Maybe I'll just finish the order
and let the user know
So, I've designed a workflow.
It looks pretty good.
I think it gets the job
But you know now
I think there's some problems.
It's actually missing a
that we talked about before.
You can't actually change order
or when it's going to come,
And now that I look at it, the
After I hit the order button,
There's probably
that says you shouldn't do that.
So I think there's
that maybe this workflow
so let's try that again.
So, in a couple apps I've
So I think I'm going to
So in the upper right hand
cart icon.
And now if I tap in food
And now I could tap that,
the button will say it's
And my icon will
that there's something in it.
It seems like a pretty
so that's really nice.
I think people will
And now if I tap on the shopping
summary of their order.
And from here they could maybe
to get a confirmation
about to spend 11.68 for food.
And now if they tap Place
that the orders complete and
So, now my work flow
It addresses the problems
It lets me know the
and it does not make the
It lets the user know
so I think that's really nice.
But you know I don't think this
it's actually a whole lot of
as ordering a sandwich.
So I think we can
And I actually noticed,
that the menu screen
of giving people
and they might not have
to actually figure out
So maybe the user can determine
to order the food right
So let's try this again,
let's try to make
So here, I put the Buy buttons
because that seems like
And now if the user taps
maybe we keep the shopping cart
in the corner, it's
that comes up on bottom.
Here, I could actually show
and even let them
from the menu screen.
If they want to I guess, they
and see the full
and the different options.
But I think for the most part,
for someone to figure
to complete this order.
And I could actually extend
on the Order button, I could
and show the confirmation
So now, the workflow
It's three steps, but
because all that's
And it still has all
as the previous design, but
under the tray rather
to be a mandatory
So that's really nice.
So I think this workflow
I think it gets the job
and I think it does
Notice how to design this,
that we talked about before.
I started with what I knew and
on all my designs until I ended
up with something
So now to wrap things up, let
[ Applause ]
Thank you, Jon.
I can't wait to use
All right so to wrap up, we
I hope we've been able to convey
First, good design is not easy.
It can be a lot of fun,
and thoughtful deliberation.
But by using the methods
it can be a little bit easier.
If you're trying to figure out
Define your audience's goals
And then use those to
that best serve everyone's
If you know what
but don't know what
or feel like, just
Start with what you do
It's okay if you don't have
out ahead of time.
And it's our completely unbiased
we think you might like it.
And finally to find the right
Don't settle for
or what might be good enough.
Then critique your
which options best suits
and your app goals.
Keep iterating and evaluating
So, we hope you'll
and methods back
Give yourself the time
and critique your designs.
We think you'll find
You can find more information
Please also check out
They're all awesome.
I think they're all online now.
Thank you everyone for coming.
[ Applause ]