[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
I'm Jacob Xiao and I'll be
joined later by Kyle Macomber.
We're so excited to show you
SwiftUI, a revolutionary new way
to build better apps faster.
We think the best way to learn
about Swift UI is to see it in
action by building an app.
Using SwiftUI feels like magic,
but to make it clear that I
don't have anything up my
sleeves, I want to go through
the entire process of creating
an app in SwiftUI starting from
scratch.
So what kind of an app are we
going to make?
Well, let me set the stage for
you.
Anybody here hate meetings?
Yeah? Well, so do we.
But Kyle and I have found
something that makes meetings
more bearable, and that's having
them in amazing, fancy
conference rooms.
So we've been making a list of
all of the best conference rooms
we can find and we want to make
an app for it.
So let's dive in.
Okay. I'll start by creating a
new project.
And we'll call it Rooms.
And I'll make sure that Use
SwiftUI is checked.
Now Xcode has started us off
with a view, with the view that
we can use to start building our
UI.
Our code is over here on the
left.
And on the right is the Canvas.
And if you're familiar with
Interface Builder or
Storyboards, you may think that
there's nothing new here.
Some code on one side and a
visual Canvas on the other,
right?
Well, there's a very important
difference.
With Storyboards, you need to
choose between the benefits of
using a visual editor, or the
benefits of creating your UI in
code.
And if you choose one and change
your mind later, then you have
to start all over again.
But with SwiftUI, that problem
is gone.
Now your view definition is
always Swift's code and you can
always choose to edit the code
directly or to use the visual
editor.
And you can always go back and
forth.
So if we select something in the
Canvas, then that selection is
reflected in the code as well.
And if you change something in
the code, then that change is
reflected in the Canvas as well.
They work together seamlessly.
So let me tell you a little more
about how it works.
The Canvas shows us previews of
our view code.
And it even helps us edit and
learn about that code.
Xcode shows these previews by
compiling our real code and
running it to generate a result.
But one of my favorite things
about previews is that they're
also created using SwiftUI code.
In this case, the code right
here.
And later on, we'll see how that
gives us a lot of power to
customize our previews.
Now our app is going to show a
list of conference rooms, so
let's make the cell for our
list.
I'm going to add another piece
of text under this one to show
more detail about each room.
And I'm going to add it by just
dragging it out onto my Canvas.
And Xcode even shows me what
will happen when I place it at
different locations.
Now when I drop it in, the
preview updates to show my new
text, but even better, Xcode has
actually edited my code to add
that text.
Xcode has embedded these views
into a Vstack to get the layout
that I want.
Now a Vstack or vertical stack
is one of the common layout
elements in SwiftUI.
It lets you stack views
vertically.
And there's also an Hstack that
stacks views horizontally.
And these stacks are containers.
I can place any views that I
want inside of them.
Now I'm going to replace this
placeholder that Xcode has given
me with some more information
about the room.
We'll show the number of people
that it can hold.
And for now, let's just use a
hard-coded value.
Next, let's add an image next to
our text.
I can make edits in the code
just as easily as in the editor.
So let's embed our view in an
Hstack.
I can Command-click on my view
and choose Embed an H Stack.
And Xcode has updated the code
to do just that.
Now I can add an image next to
my Vstack.
We'll add some assets in a bit,
but for now I'll just use an SF
symbol image to get something up
and running.
SF symbols are new in iOS 13.
They're a rich set of
Apple-provided images that you
can use in your app.
And already we have a basic
version of our cell.
Now, I'll use the Canvas to
style the cell the way I want.
I can Command-click on my stack
and choose Inspect to see some
of the properties that I can
change for this stack.
I'm going to set its alignment
to be leading.
And, once again, Xcode has
updated my code to make that
change.
Now, I can also Command-click on
my text to inspect that as well.
And let's change this to be a
smaller font.
I'm going to use sub-headline.
And one of the great things
about Xcode modifying my code is
it helps me to learn about
SwiftUI.
For example, here it's added
this code to change the font.
We call these kinds of methods
modifiers and they're used in
SwiftUI to customize the way
your views look or behave.
I'm going to add another
modifier in code to set the
foreground color to be a
secondary color.
Okay. Now that I have my cell,
let's put it into a list.
To do that, I'm going to
Command-click on our cell and
just choose Convert To List.
This wraps my cell in a list and
shows five iterations of it.
[ Applause ]
It's great to be able to do this
so easily.
And this code is all that I need
to show a list in my app.
There's no delegates or data
sources necessary, just views
inside of a list.
Next, let's hook this up to some
data.
I'm going to drag in some assets
and a model file that I created
earlier.
Now my model has a few fields of
information that we'll use.
And to use this in a list in
SwiftUI, I just need to make
this type identifiable.
This lets Lists know which items
are coming and going.
And all I need is an ID property
which we already have.
Now this model file also
includes some test data that I
can use for debugging my app.
Now let's go back to our view
and let's pass in our data.
I'll add a property for my
rooms.
And one of the great things
about previews is that they can
use their own test data.
So I'll just pass in my test
data right here.
Now you may have noticed that
this banner appeared above my
preview.
When I make larger changes to my
types like adding this rooms
property to our view, Xcode
pauses the previews until I'm
ready to have them resume
updating.
And I can just click button to
resume.
Next, let's use our data to
drive the list.
We'll pass in our rooms to the
list and then I'll update our
text to show the room's name.
And we'll also use the real
capacity right here in our text.
And now that we have real
images, let's also use our Rooms
thumbnail for the image.
Great.
[ Applause ]
And you may have noticed the
subtle change that happened to
our list when we did this.
When we started, our cells were
the standard 44 points tall.
But when we changed to these
larger images, the cells
automatically expanded to make
sure those images fit without
any extra work.
[ Applause ]
It's pretty cool.
And now that I have these images
in context, they look a little
bit sharp.
So let's add a corner radius to
our image using another
modifier.
And if you're not sure about
what modifiers are available,
you can view and filter a list
of them right here in the
library.
Let's find Corner Radius and
we'll just drag it onto our
image.
[ Applause ]
Then we can tweak the values.
That looks a little bit too big.
Great.
And now that our cells and our
lists are looking good, the next
thing that we need is to be able
to tap on a cell to see more
details.
To support this, let's wrap our
list in a navigation view.
A navigation view shows a
navigation bar and also has a
stack to push views onto.
Let's also set a navigation bar
title and we'll just use some
text that says Rooms to show
Rooms in our navigation bar.
Now let's set up our cell to
push onto this stack.
To do that, I'll wrap our cells
content in a Navigation button.
A Navigation button takes a
destination which is a view that
will push onto the stack.
And to start with, we'll just
use some text that shows the
room's name.
Then we'll put all of our cell's
content inside of that
navigation button and we're
ready to go.
And notice that our UI has
updated to automatically show
these UI indicators.
SwiftUI handles details like
this for me automatically so
that my UI automatically looks
right by default.
Now let's also check that the
cell behaves correctly.
I can just click on this play
button in my preview, which
takes me into Live Mode.
And when I do this, Xcode is
compiling my code, sending it
over to the Simulator, running
it for me and showing the result
of all of that right here in the
Canvas, which means I can
interact with my view.
So I can tap on a cell to make
sure that everything pushes and
pops as I expect.
And if I swipe to pop, you'll
notice an advanced behavior that
SwiftUI has given me
automatically.
Our cells stay highlighted, and
as I swipe, they are
interactively un-highlight it
without us doing any extra work.
[ Applause ]
Okay, so we've got our list and
it's working with its cells.
But this view code is a little
bit large now.
And I'd really like to factor
the cell out to be its own view.
And Xcode helps me do this with
one simple operation.
I can just command click on the
view that I want and choose
Extract Subview.
[ Applause ]
It's fantastic.
All of my view code gets
extracted out down here and I
even get to choose the name for
my new view.
Let's call it Room Cell.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Now, let's also add a property
for our room.
And we'll pass it in right here.
This is a fantastic workflow
improvement.
And with SwiftUI, views are
really lightweight so you don't
have to worry about creating
extra views to better
encapsulate or separate your
logic.
Okay, next let's build our
detail view.
I'm going to create a new view
and make sure to use the SwiftUI
Template.
And let's call this new view
Room Detail.
Xcode has automatically given me
a new ViewStruct and also the
preview code to create it.
Now since I want this detail
view to show more information
about my room, I'll add a
property for the room.
And just like I did before, I'll
update my preview code to pass
in one of our rooms from their
test data.
Then let's build our UI.
We use an image and we'll show
the room's image name.
Okay, now we're showing our
image but it's a little bit too
large for our view.
By default, SwiftUI shows all
images at the size of their
contents to prevent visual
artifacts from scaling the image
up or down.
But for photos like this one, we
want to be able to resize them
down.
And we can use an image-specific
modifier called Resizable to do
that.
So I'll just drag this onto our
view and all right, now it's
resizing to fill the size that
we have.
But really we want it to
maintain this original aspect
ratio.
And we can do that with another
modifier, this time aspect
ratio.
And the aspect ratio modifier
lets me choose between .fill,
which expands the image to take
up its entire frame, or .fit,
which makes sure the image fits
within the frame.
And previews let me really
easily see and understand the
difference between these
different modes.
For now, let's use Fit so we can
see the full image.
Now let's go back to our list
and update our cell to push our
new detail view.
We'll create our Room Detail
view and we'll just pass in the
current room.
Now I'll switch my preview back
into live mode.
And I can tap on my cell to see
our image.
But now that I'm previewing it
here, I can see that I forgot to
set the title in the navigation
bar.
So let's go back to our detail
view and fix that.
Just like before, I can use the
navigation bar title to set our
title and we'll pass in our
room's name as the title.
But in the preview that I have
here, we're only seeing the view
itself and I'd really like to be
able to quickly verify my
change.
Well, since previews have all
the power of SwiftUI's views
available, we can do just that.
I can set up my preview to be
inside of a navigation view
using the same code that I would
anywhere else.
And now my view's preview is
inside of a navigation bar.
[ Applause ]
And now that I'm seeing it here,
this large title looks like a
little bit too much for our
detail view.
So let's update our navigation
bar title to set the display
mode to be inline.
Much better.
Now when I'm picking a good
conference room, there's one
thing that's very important to
me.
The room has to have a good
table.
I just can't focus on what
anyone is saying if the table
isn't of the highest quality.
[ Laughter ]
And I can see that there's some
kind of table in this room, but
I really can't see its details
well enough.
But when the image was in Fill,
I could see it nice and close.
Look at that wood grain.
So I'd like to be able to change
back and forth between Fill to
see the details of the room and
Fit to see everything at once.
But how do I actually change
this aspect ratio's content mode
from within my view?
Well, to understand how to do
this, we really need to know
more about how views work in
SwiftUI and why.
And so I'm going to invite Kyle
to the stage to talk about that.
Kyle?
&gt;&gt; Well, hello, WWDC.
[ Applause ]
What does everyone think of
SwiftUI so far?
[ Applause ]
Yeah, I'm pretty excited too.
It's a little magical though.
And so before we go any further,
we're going to take a step back
and talk about the way views
work and why in SwiftUI.
So we left off here implementing
Room Detail view.
In SwiftUI, a view is a struct
that conforms to the view
protocol, rather than a class
that inherits from a base class
like UI view.
This means your view doesn't
inherit any stored properties.
It's allocated on the stack and
it's passed by value.
Room Detail just stores a room,
so it's the size and weight of a
room.
No additional allocation or
reference counting overhead.
Behind the scenes, SwiftUI
aggressively collapses your view
hierarchy into an efficient data
structure for rendering.
Because of this, we make liberal
use of small single-purpose
views in SwiftUI, and you should
too.
What I want you to take away
from the last couple slides is
that views in SwiftUI are
incredibly lightweight.
As Jacob said, you should never
hesitate to refactor your
SwiftUI code because extracting
a subview has virtually no
runtime overhead.
Yeah, you can clap for that,
it's pretty great.
[ Applause ]
So a view in SwifthUI and a view
in a traditional UI framework
fulfill the same primary role.
They define a piece of UI.
The view protocol only has a
single requirement: a body
property, which is, itself, a
view.
You build bigger views in
SwiftUI by composing together
smaller views.
We built Room Detail by
composing together image, a view
of an image at its native
resolution, resizable which
opted it into stretch in either
dimension; and aspect ratio, a
view that proportionally scales
its child.
The rendering of any view you
build is just the rendering of
its body.
So if you set a break point and
the debugger stops there, it
means the framework has decided
it needs a fresh rendering of
your view.
Tada.
All right.
So the framework knows when to
fetch a new rendering of a view
because in addition to defining
a piece of UI, in SwiftUI, a
view defines its dependencies.
Let's extend Room Detail to
allow the user to toggle between
fitting into and filling up the
available space so Jacob can get
a good look at that wood grain.
So, the first thing we'll need
is a property, but it's a
special property.
It's a state property and it
says whether or not the image is
zoomed.
When SwiftUI sees a view with a
state variable, it allocates
storage for that variable on the
view's behalf.
In this Memory diagram, the
green is your app's memory, and
purple is memory SwiftUI is
managing.
And so this value of the zoom
variable, we got you covered.
So if you decide to fill or fit
based on that variable, then
we've got a view that renders
like this when it's zoomed and
like this when it isn't.
So, now, all we need is a
tapAction to toggle back and
forth between the two states.
And then on tap, the image will
zoom to Fill and shrink to Fit.
[ Applause ]
So what actually is happening
when we tap here?
Well, one of the special
properties of state variables is
that SwiftUI can observe when
they're read and written.
Because SwiftUI knows that Zoom
here was read in body, it knows
that the view's rendering
depends on it, which means when
the variable changes, the
framework is going to ask for
body again using the new state
value.
So it can refresh the rendering
this time with a different
content mode.
So, traditional UI frameworks
don't distinguish between state
variables and plain old
properties.
But I've found this distinction
to be incredibly clarifying.
In SwiftUI, every possible state
your UI might find itself in,
the offset of a scroll view, the
highlightedness of a button, the
contents of a navigation stack.
It's derived from an
authoritative piece of data,
often called a Source of Truth.
Collectively, your state
variables and your model
constitute your Source of Truth
for your entire application.
Earlier, I mentioned that this
call to aspect ratio makes a
view.
Its definition looks something
like this, where content mode is
a plain old Swift property.
You can neatly classify every
property as either a source of
truth or a derived value.
The Zoom state variable is a
Source of Truth.
The Content Mode property is
derived from it.
Recall SwiftUI can observe when
state variables are read and
written.
So when one changes, it knows
which renderings to refresh.
The framework refreshes the
rendering by asking for a new
body, making a new aspect ratio
view from scratch, thereby
overriding the Content Mode and
any other stored properties.
This is the mechanism by which
all derived values in SwiftUI
are kept up-to-date.
So we've seen how we can declare
a Source of Truth using a state
variable, and that every plain
old property is a derived value.
We're not going to see an
example in this talk, but Swift
gives you a tool called Binding,
which is great for passing
read/write derived values.
And technically any constant can
serve as a perfectly good
read-only Source of Truth as we
saw with the test data driving
our previews.
Now there's one more I want to
call out, and I mentioned a
second ago that collectively
your state variables and your
model constitute the Source of
Truth for your entire app.
And so we have this bindable
object protocol Jacob used
earlier to teach SwiftUI about
how to observe changes from our
model.
This might be a lot really
quickly, and so we have an
entire talk later this week
dedicated to developing your
intuition about these different
flow primitives.
All right, let's step back and
take stock.
This is really different from
what you do in a traditional
life framework where the views
themselves persist and you try
your hardest to keep them all up
to date.
You may not think about it this
way when you use a traditional
UI framework, but every time a
view reads a piece of data, it's
creating an implicit dependency.
It's a dependency because when
that data changes, the view
needs to update to reflect the
new value.
And when it fails to, that's a
bug.
SwiftUI automatically manages
dependencies on your behalf by
recomputing the appropriate
derived values so this never
happens again.
[ Applause ]
Of course, we don't just manage
a single dependency at a time in
our apps.
Our apps are big.
They're complicated.
When it comes to how much you
have to hold in your head and
how easy it is to make a
mistake, the way we manually
manage dependencies today, it's
really hard.
Despite my best efforts, every
update to every app I've ever
shipped has had UI bugs.
Every one of these lines is a
dependency.
And it's just the start.
The thing I find the hardest
about managing the complexity of
my views is dealing with all the
possible orders the different
callbacks can get called in.
So here's an old version of the
room detail view that was
implemented in UIKit.
It had the same features as the
one we've seen so far has, but
it had one more.
Every once in a while, when we
zoom in on a conference room
image, it was too blurry to make
out the wood grain on the table.
And so we decided to add a
special feature using neural
networks and machine learning so
we could tap to enhance the
image on a background thread and
thus choose the right conference
room.
All right, yeah.
Over-engineering, right?
So there's only one problem with
this feature and that's it had a
bug.
We got a report of a stray
activity indicator that never
stops spinning.
How'd this happen?
Well, it turns out if the events
fired in a specific order, we
forgot to clean up that activity
indicator.
In this case, if the user zoomed
out and tapped the enhance
button as it was animating away,
the activity indicator would get
stuck.
These kinds of mistakes are easy
to make when you mutate your
subviews directly from event
handler callbacks rather than
updating your Source of Truth
and deriving your UI from that.
Now we make this mistake because
when we're coding this code,
it's really easy to only think
about the happy path.
Those are the ones that come
easily to mind.
And it's really easy to overlook
the unhappy ones that don't.
The problem is that as the
number of possible events our
view can respond to grows, the
number of unhappy paths
explodes.
Assume you get all four of these
events, how many different
possible orders are there that
they could come in?
Well, there's actually 24
different orders for any four
events.
And in practice, it's even worse
than that because every event
can come in more than one time.
Say for example a user is
mashing the enhance button.
The challenge of managing this
should be familiar to anyone
who's ever implemented an
interruptable animation where
the completion handler can come
in at a really unexpected time.
If I could tell myself from five
years ago anything about my job,
it would be that UI programming
is really hard.
Like log-free concurrency hard.
How many of you have written
multi-threaded code?
Probably all 2,000 of you, yeah.
So no one pretends that's easy.
It's taken me months to shake
out all the bugs in some of my
multi-threaded code, and even
then I wasn't 100% confident in
its correctness.
A lot of UI code is actually
just like that, only instead of
a crash, your view ends up in
the wrong place, or it's
missing.
This is because race conditions
and UI inconsistencies share the
same underlying source of
complexity.
These easy-to-overlook
orderings.
Many of the views we all work on
have way more than four events.
You know, like model
notifications, delegate methods,
target actions, completion
handlers.
They're all events.
A view with 12 would roughly
equate to 12 factorial possible
orderings.
That's almost half a billion.
We've all worked on views with
12 event handlers.
So you can only fit so much in
your head at a time.
Yeah. This dotted line is one of
the views in your app.
What do people think the
difference between those two
dots is?
Anyone? Those are the bugs, yes.
So as we add features, the
number of possible orderings we
have to think of increases
exponentially.
And the chance we overlook one
-- it's the same.
It's inevitable.
So I imagine many of you
instinctively have reached for a
way to handle this complexity in
UIKit or AppKit when you program
today, which is to collect all
your view update code in a
single method.
And then from these event
handler callbacks, you call that
one method.
It's a really great way for the
complexity to not explode on
you.
Well, SwiftUI was heavily
inspired by this best practice.
When you are trying to implement
a view this way in UI today,
there's all these tricky cases
you need to think about like
adding or removing a subview
from the view hierarchy, or
pushing and popping off the
navigation stack.
Or performing updates to a table
view.
I was never able to figure out
all of those cases all on my
own.
Well, we've spent all the time
and done all the work and we've
codified this best practice into
SwiftUI on your behalf.
The view protocol only has a
single requirement: body.
A single entry point that the
framework calls.
That means there's only one
possible order it can ever get
called in.
[ Applause ]
Because of this pattern of
simply fetching new views for
the parts of the UI that
changed, SwiftUI scales with
your brain, virtually
eliminating UI inconsistencies.
All right.
[ Applause ]
Let's get back to the demo and
finish the Room Detail view.
Jacob?
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's finish this app.
Now, we know how to set up our
view to zoom in.
We'll add a state property.
And we'll call it Zoomed and
we'll default it to false.
Then in our aspect ratio we'll
use the Zoomed property to
change between Fill when we're
zoomed and Fit otherwise.
And finally, we'll add our
tapAction to toggle that Zoomed
property.
Now let's try it out in Live
Mode.
Great, we can switch between
these two different modes.
But there's something missing
here.
Does anybody see it?
That's right, it needs an
animation.
And with SwiftUI, animation's
really easy to add.
I can just wrap my change in a
call to WithAnimation.
And now my change is animated.
[ Applause ]
And not only that, the animation
is fully interactive and
interruptible so I can always
change between the different
states and it always ends up in
the right place.
[ Applause ]
Yeah, it's great.
Now I would add the Enhance
button next, but it turns out
that the way Kyle trained the
model, it only ever worked on
that one image that he showed.
So I'm going to add something
more useful.
One of our coworkers is in
London so we often want to know
which rooms have video
conferencing.
So let's show an icon for that
on top of our detail view.
I can use a Zstack to show views
stacked on top of each other.
So I'll put our existing image
inside of that Zstack and then
I'll add another image to show
an icon for whether the room has
video or not.
I'll just use a symbol image and
we'll use Video.fill.
Okay, we have our icon here, but
it's a little bit small.
But symbol images automatically
use the current font to size
themselves, so I can easily
change to a larger font with a
modifier.
We'll just drag this into our
code and apply it to the image.
And Title sounds good.
Now we've got our larger image.
Next, I want this image to be in
the top-left.
So let's set our Zstack's
alignment to be topLeading.
Okay. Next let's add some
padding so that this is not up
against the edge here.
Again, we can use a modifier to
do this.
And we'll just drag it in onto
our system image.
And All Edges seems like a good
choice here.
Okay, this is close, but I
really want to have this icon
all the way at the top of our
view area.
And we can get our video icon
there by putting our room image
inside of a flexible frame.
The frame will stretch to fill
the whole screen.
And when it has extra space, it
will center its contents inside
of it.
This means that our room image
will still be at the right
place.
So I'll add our flexible frame
to our image.
And we'll use a minimum width of
zero and a max width of
infinity.
And we'll do the same thing for
our height.
There we go.
And if you're curious to learn
more about how layout works in
SwiftUI, check out the Building
Custom Views in SwiftUI session.
Now we have our icon.
But we only want it to appear
when a room has video
conferencing.
So how do we do that?
Well, the declarative syntax
that we're using makes that
really easy.
We can just use an if.
So I'll add an if and we'll
check whether our room has
video.
And we'll only show our image
when that's true.
Now we can check if this is
working by changing our preview
data to a room that doesn't have
video, which is nice.
But even better, we can actually
set up our previews to show
multiple versions of our views
at once.
To do that, I'm just going to
embed this view inside of a
group.
And now I can have multiple
views here.
So let's create a second version
using different test data.
Now we have one version of our
view with video conferencing,
and another version without.
[ Applause ]
Now let's go back to live mode.
Now when I'm in the Zoom state,
having that icon on top of my
image is a little distracting.
So let's update it to also
disappear when we're zoomed.
We can do that just by updating
our condition.
Now the icon automatically shows
and hides as we zoom in and out.
But even better, it animates,
fading in and out.
And we can also customize that
animation behavior by setting it
to a different transition.
So let's try .move and we'll use
the leading edge.
Now our icon slides out and
slides back in.
[ Applause ]
And let me also make this a
longer animation by specifying a
custom animation with a duration
of two seconds.
Now we can see our animation in
more detail and we can also see
what happens if we tap on it
while the animation is still
going.
It turns around and comes right
back.
Again, our animation is always
interactive and we can always
tap on it and it will end up in
the right state.
So that's our detail view.
Now let's review what we just
built.
Our detail view is configured
with a room to show and remember
that that's a derived value
passed in by the parent of the
view.
And we also have our state
property which controls whether
this view is zoomed in or not.
And this is persisted by the
framework and controls the
aspect ratio.
Then we also have our video icon
and that's only shown for views
that have video conferencing and
only when they're not zoomed.
And we're also specifying this
transition to make the icon
slide in and out.
But what's actually happening
during that transition?
Well, when this icon is removed,
the view gets animated to a new
position and SwiftUI waits until
it finishes that animation to
actually remove the view from
the hierarchy.
And the when it's coming back,
SwiftUI inserts it off-screen
and the moves it back in with an
animation.
I've wanted to be able to do
AddSubview and RemoveSubview
with an animation for a really
long time, so I'm really excited
to finally have it.
[ Applause ]
And recall that this animation
is always interactive right out
of the box.
This is where being data-driven
instead of event-driven really
shines.
All those events that Kyle
talked about can happen while
this is animating.
And animations beginning and
ending are even more events.
It's incredibly difficult to
build something like this in an
event driven world.
But in SwiftUI it's just one
line of code.
Now let's go back to our list of
rooms and finish up this app.
Over time, we need to be able to
change our list of conference
rooms, so let's add some editing
support.
And while we're at it, let's
also make our data model a
little more real.
Right now, the data in our app
is completely static.
We have this array of rooms and
whatever we start with is what
we'll always have.
So let's update our model to
have a root store object that
will contain our rooms and will
be able to change over time.
I'm going to drag in a prebuilt
model file with our room store.
Notice that our store is a
mutable object which contains
the rooms that we need.
And all we need to do is tell
SwiftUI when it changes.
To do that, I'm going to conform
it to the bindable object
protocol which requires me to
have a DidChange property.
Now new this year is the Combine
framework which includes a large
number of components you can use
to connect your data together.
Here we use the pass-through
publisher, a pass-through
subject from Combine which gives
us a local object that we can
subscribe to and send updates
to, similar to a notification
center.
Then we'll just update our rooms
to have a DidSet so that we can
notify our subject when our
rooms change.
And if you're interested to
learn more about Combine, there
are two sessions this week to
take you through all of the
details.
Now let's go back to our view
and update it to use our store.
We'll change from this Rooms
property to a Store property.
And we'll make it an object
binding to tell SwiftUI to
listen to changes for this
property.
And again, the Data Flow Through
SwiftUI session that Kyle
mentioned earlier has a lot more
information about how object
binding and these other pieces
work.
Let's also update our preview to
create our new store type.
Using our test data.
And we'll also update our list
to pull the rooms from out of
the store.
Great.
Now we're using our new model
and whenever it updates, our
view will create a fresh
rendering.
This means we're ready to add
our editing support.
Let's start by adding a button
to our list to add new rooms.
Right now, we're using a single
collection to drive the list
which is great for lists that
are entirely data-driven.
But when I need more, SwiftUI
also lets me mix static and
dynamic content in lists and
other containers.
So I can replace this list using
the collection with a ForEach.
A ForEach creates a view for
each item in its collection.
So now I can add a static
element right alongside this
ForEach.
I'll just go to the library and
find a button.
And then I can just drag it into
my code to add it to our list.
Let's update its text to show
Add Room.
And let's add a method to add
that new room.
Okay, we'll tell our Store to
append a new room.
And let's just use the room that
we're in.
It's called Hall 2 and I think
there's what, about 2,000 of
you.
And finally, let's update our
button to use our new Add Room
method.
Okay, now let's go to Live Mode
and try out our new button.
There it is, right next to all
of our data.
And when I tap it, we get our
new room.
Great.
[ Applause ]
So just like that, we were able
to add this single static
element alongside our
data-driven collection.
SwiftUI lets us easily describe
these powerful combinations
which makes it so much easier to
build complex list UI's.
No more off by one index path
errors.
But I want to style this to look
even better.
Let's put the Add button and all
of our content into separate
sections.
We can change our list style to
be grouped, which gives us this
nice grouped appearance.
Then we'll add a section
container around our button.
And another one around our
ForEach.
Great, now we have our separate
sections.
Next, let's hook up deletion for
our list.
We'll add a method to delete a
set of rooms and we'll pass in
some offsets for where to remove
them.
Then we'll just tell our store
to remove the rooms that those
offsets.
Then we can add a modifier onto
our ForEach called OnDelete.
And we can pass in our delete
method to that modifier.
Now if we go back into Live
Mode, we can swipe on one of our
rows and delete it, just like
that.
[ Applause ]
This ForEach is now configured
to call into our callback
whenever items get removed from
it.
And then our callback calls into
the Store to remove those items.
And then our view updates.
Okay.
Now we want to be able to take
our list into Edit Mode in
addition to just allowing swipe
to delete.
So let's set a navigation bar
item, and we can do that the
same way we set this navigation
bar title-- with another
modifier.
And to create an Edit button, we
just create an Edit button.
And there it is in our UI.
And while we're at it, let's
also add reordering support.
Again, I'll just add a simple
method to move items.
And we'll move it from a source
to a destination.
And again, we'll just call into
our Store's Rooms and tell it to
move.
Okay.
Then just like before, we'll add
another modifier, this time on
Move, and tell it to call into
the method that we just added.
Now let's try our app again.
We can toggle Edit Mode for our
list.
And notice that all of our data
rows have editing controls but
the button does not.
SwiftUI automatically shows the
right editing controls in the
places that need it, without us
having to do any extra work.
[ Applause ]
Yeah, it's cool.
And of course now we can drag to
reorder and tap on items to
remove them.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So let's quickly review what we
just added.
We customized our list to show
multiple sections, and by
setting its list style to
grouped.
And we mixed this static button
together with our data-driven
collection from our Rooms.
And we also saw how we can
quickly add editing operations
to our list with just these
modifiers and a few functions to
modify our data.
And remember how we made our
room type identifiable earlier?
Well, ForEach automatically
watches for changes to its
collection and synthesizes the
correct insertions, deletions,
and changes for us, so we no
longer need to tell the list to
add and remove rows, which means
we no longer have to worry about
getting data source
inconsistency exceptions.
[ Applause ]
Yep, that's right.
So that's our list.
And we made this whole
sophisticated list UI with just
this really minimal view code.
Okay, now we were able to build
this app up really quickly.
But you might be thinking that
there's still a lot more work we
need to do to get it ready for
customers.
These days, support for dynamic
type, dark mode, accessibility,
localization -- these are all
just expected for an app.
But with SwiftUI you get a lot
more support for these behaviors
automatically.
And we can use previews to
really quickly test all of
these.
So let's go to our preview and
add some more views.
Again, I'll add a group to let
us have multiple children.
And then I'll add another
version of our view.
And this time we'll change the
environment to use a size
category that's a much larger
size.
Let's go see how it looks.
And everything automatically
works great.
Now --
[ Applause ]
Yeah. It's great to get this for
free.
Now the environment is a way
that you can set contextual
information about your views
that flows down the view
hierarchy and changes different
aspects of any contained views
all at once.
It's great for making changes to
a large set of views and it's
also great for customizing your
previews to see your view in
different contexts.
So let's add another version of
our view and update the
environment to set its color
scheme to be dark.
And once again it all just
works.
[ Applause ]
And finally, let's also see how
our app works with other
languages.
I have some English string files
that I'll drag into my app.
And I'll tell Xcode to localize
them.
Then I'll go to my project file
and I'll import a localization
that I have for Arabic.
Now let's go back to our view
and add one more preview.
Now, if we first set the layout
direction to be right-to-left,
we can see that this
automatically works without any
extra work.
But if I also set the locale to
be an Arabic locale, you can see
that everything gets localized.
[ Applause ]
And even better, if we look back
at our code, we didn't do
anything extra to support these
features.
To get our text localizable, we
didn't have to mark up which
strings should be localizable or
not.
SwiftUI automatically infers
that.
For text using string literals,
it's localizable by default.
And for text that's created by
getting passed a string, it
defaults to getting used as-is.
This means that all of our app
text like Rooms and Add Room
gets localized.
But all of our content like
these room names still gets
passed right through.
But even better, you can finally
use string interpolations and
have them localized correctly.
[ Applause ]
I love string interpolations.
They're great.
We're really excited for you to
start building apps with
SwiftUI.
When you get all of these
behaviors for free, you can
concentrate on the unique parts
of your app and build better
apps for your customers even
faster.
Now we built an iPhone app here,
but you can use these same APIs
and techniques across all of
Apple's platforms.
And you'll get these kinds of
automatic behaviors across all
of them.
Okay, let's take one last pass
through our app to review what
we built and make sure
everything is working right.
I'm a big fan of dark mode, so
let's use that version.
Okay, we have our list of rooms
and we can tap on one of them to
see more information.
And in our detail view we can
tap to zoom to full screen which
hides our video icon with a
transition, and that animation
is always interactive.
And we can also edit our list to
make changes.
Let's move this one down, and I
don't think anyone really wants
to use the dungeon conference
room.
Actually, I'm also not sure why
Kyle added this room that has an
elephant.
Let's get rid of that one too.
And finally, let's add our
conference room.
Great.
That's our app.
[ Applause ]
But there's one last thing that
I want to point out and it's
something that we didn't see.
We just built up this entire
application and tested all these
rich behaviors without ever once
building and running our app.
Xcode previews let us view,
edit, and debug our application
way faster than was ever
possible before.
So thank you very much.
I hope you enjoy using SwiftUI
as much as I do.
It's a lot of fun.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So our goal with this SwiftUI
is to give you the shortest path
to a great app that's going to
reach the widest audience.
We saw four of SwiftUI's key
design principles at play today.
We saw its declarative syntax,
which will evoke the actual UI
you're building and take care of
those imperative details like
adding and removing subviews on
your behalf.
We saw the compositional pieces
and how you can combine together
pieces of content, modifiers and
containers to build exactly the
UI you're looking for.
We saw all the automatic
behaviors you get by saying less
and letting the framework take
care of more.
We talked about how SwiftUI
keeps your views in a consistent
state so you never end up with a
view missing or in the wrong
place.
And of course we played with
SwiftUI's awesome interruptal
animations, which is one of my
favorites.
I always felt like before I had
to trade between having flashy
animations and the crushing
complexity that could come with
it.
But no longer.
The goal with SwiftUI -- wait,
we didn't look at it again.
It's so cool, right?
All right, the goal with SwiftUI
is for us to take care of these
basic features that every app
needs on your behalf.
Because when you're building an
app, it's not just the basic
features you add.
You've got all your special,
unique features that make your
app yours.
And the goal is for us to bear
more of this burden, the burden
for all those things that you
need to have to have a great app
and let you spend more of your
time focusing on things that
make your app special.
So I hope you all enjoyed your
introduction to SwiftUI.
Come find us in the labs.
We'll be there this afternoon
and throughout the week.
And we called out to a couple
sessions, Data Flow Through UI,
and Building Custom Views.
Your next stop in learning
SwiftUI should be the SwiftUI
Essentials talk where we're
going to go into every piece of
syntax and all the pieces that
you can compose together to make
views what they are.
So I hope to see you there.
Have a great WWDC and I hope you
enjoy SwiftUI.
[ Applause ]