[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome everyone.
My name is Gaurav and today
we're going to talk about What's
New in Machine Learning.
Machine Learning is used by
thousands of apps.
The apps that you are making are
amazing.
They're touching every aspect of
a user's life.
In hospitals, doctors are using
apps such as Butterfly iQ to do
medical diagnostics in real
time.
In sports, coaches are using
apps such as HomeCourt to train
their players.
In creativity, apps such as
Pixelmator Pro are helping other
users to augment their
creativity using ML.
These are just a few examples,
and we would like all of these
apps you guys should also make
these kind of apps.
So now the question is what's
new?
Let me begin by saying a lot.
We have so much material that we
can hardly cover it one session
or two sessions.
We need ten sessions to cover
the entire material.
We also have a session
intersecting the design in
machine learning.
We also have Daily Labs where
you can meet and discuss your
ideas with Apple Machine
Learning engineers.
All of us are here to remove any
roadblocks that you might be
facing while integrating Machine
Learning in your app.
In all of these sessions, you
will see that we follow simple
principles.
We want Machine Learning to be
as easy to use as possible.
We are laser focused on doing
that.
We want to make it flexible so
you can do it by variety of
tasks, and we want to make it
powerful so you can run state of
the art Machine Learning models
on your devices.
It is truly Machine Learning for
everyone whether you are a
researcher or someone new to
Machine Learning.
With Create ML app you can
make state of the art,
task-focused ML models.
The next big pillar of our
offering is Domain APIs.
Domain APIs allow you to
leverage Apple's built-in
intelligence and models.
So you don't have to worry about
collecting the data and building
the model.
Simply call the API and be done.
This year we are significantly
expanding our Domain APIs.
We have Domain APIs in Vision,
Text, Speech and Sound.
Now let's take a sneak peek of
some of these APIs.
Let's start with Vision.
Vision allows you to reason
about the content of the image.
One of the new features this
year is Image Saliency.
Image Saliency can help you
identify the most relevant
region in your image.
In this case, the region around
the person.
You can use it to generate
thumbnails or to make image
cropping, generate memories,
guide camera et cetera.
Another big feature we are
introducing this year is Text
Recognition.
You can now take a picture of
the document, perform
perspective correction, lighting
correction and reorganize the
text on the device.
[ Applause ]
This is huge, but that's not
all.
We have Image inbuilt
classifier, human detector, pet
detector, and we are going to
cover them in detail in our two
Vision sessions.
Next domain is Natural Language.
Just like you use Vision to
reason about images you can use
Natural Language to reason about
the text.
New this year is inbuilt
Sentiment Analysis.
So you can use to analyze the
sentiment of the text in real
time on the device in a privacy
friendly way.
So, for example, if somebody
types something like this I was
so excited about the season
finale that's a positive
sentiment, but it was a bit
disappointing at the end it's a
negative sentiment.
So you can provide this kind of
feedback in real time.
For the first time we are also
exposing inbuilt Word
Embeddings.
Word Embeddings can allow you to
find semantically similar words.
So, for example, the word
thunderstorm is very close to
cloudy but it is very far away
from shoes and boots.
One of the big use case of Word
Embeddings is semantic search
and we are going to give you an
example soon.
Natural Language will be
discussed in detail in Advances
in Natural Language Framework
session.
The third way user interacts
with your app is through speech
and sound.
Now we have an on-device speech
support so you can transcribe
the text on the device so you no
longer have to rely on the
network connection, and we also
have new Voice Analytics API
that can tell you not only what
is spoken but how it is spoken.
So you can differentiate between
a normal voice and a high
jittery voice.
We also have a brand-new Sound
Analysis Framework, that we will
discuss in Create ML session.
There's a lot more in each of
these domains and another thing
you can do to combine these
domains almost seamlessly.
Let me show you an example.
Let's just say you want to build
a feature that does Semantic
Search on Images.
That's a very complex feature.
So if a user searches for
thunderstorm, you want to
provide them the results not
only for thunderstorm but also
for sky and cloudy.
Now, you can combine Vision with
Natural Language to implement
this feature in very few lines
of code.
This is how you will do it.
You will run your Image
Classifier on images or you can
have them use inbuilt Image
Classifier to generate the tags.
When the user types the word
something like thunderstorm, you
can use Word Embeddings to
generate similar words and find
the images that matches these
tags.
And that's not all.
You can also combine the custom
models that you made using
Create ML with Domain APIs, and
we are going to show an example
of that in our Creating Great
Apps Using Core ML and ARKit
session.
So to summarize, Domain APIs
allow you to leverage Apple's
built-in intelligence and model
using API so you don't have to
collect the data and make the
models.
And this year we have a
significant expansion in our
Vision Natural Language and
Speech and Sound APIs.
Now let's talk about Core ML 3,
the third big pillar of our
offering.
Core ML is now supported across
all our platforms.
All the work is done on the
device so user's privacy is
maintained.
Core ML is hardware accelerated
so you can do, you can use it
for realtime Machine Learning
and you don't need a server and
it always available.
Core ML has always supported a
wide variety of Machine Learning
models ranging from classical
generalized linear models, tree
ensembles and support vector
machines as well as neural
networks such as Convolution
Neural Network and Recurrent
Neural Networks.
New in Core ML is model
flexibility and model
personalization.
So let's take a look at both of
them.
Core ML has expanded support for
Data Neural Networks and we have
added a support for more than
100+ Neural Network layers.
This means that you can bring
almost, you can bring the most
cutting-edge Machine Learning
models into your app such as
ELMo, BERT, Wavenet.
What does that mean?
Let's just say you have an app
and you want to integrate a
state of the art Question and
Answer system in your app so
that when a user asks a question
how many sessions will there be
at WWDC this year?
You can do it by using BERT
model.
So the model can analyze the
statement and gives feedback the
result over 100 is the answer.
Besides Natural Language you can
also run the latest advances in
Vision such as Instance
Segmentation as well as latest
advances in Audio Generation.
And to take full advantage of
this expanded support of Core
ML, we are updating our
converters.
So we will have a brand new
TensorFlow Core ML converter and
ONNX support ML converter will
be coming soon.
We are also updating our Model
Gallery importing some of these
research models on our Model
Gallery so you can start using
them immediately.
So Core ML 3 with this new model
representation and embedded
converters with Model Gallery
can help you bring the cutting
edge ML research into your app.
Now a big feature, Model
Personalization.
So let me explain what it is.
So up to now you have seen, you
have used Create ML to build the
models and Core ML to deploy the
models, but new in Core ML 3 is
On-Device Model Personalization.
You can fine tune the model on
the device.
And we use this kind of
technology in Face ID and
setting Watch Face.
So this is how it happens.
Today you have data, you make an
ML model, you ship it to your
app and all of your users
download the same model.
And this is great because now
users don't have to upload their
photos.
You can directly take photos,
run through the model on the
device and get inference such as
dog.
But what if you are trying to
deal with a concept that is
unique to each user?
Say the concept of My Dog.
You might want users to find
pictures of their own dog in the
photo library and not all dog
photos they've taken.
And each user's dog looks
different.
For example, someone may have
Golden Retriever, someone may
have this Bulldog, ah, and this
is my crazy dog.
So, how do we do that?
So what we want is for user 1 we
need image classifier that takes
this dog and says it's their
dog.
For user 2, that's the English
Bulldog and this the third dog.
So in order to do that, one
approach would be to use Server
Based Approach.
So you may ask each of your
users to upload the photos in
the Cloud.
Server generates model for each
of the users and then sends it
back.
Unfortunately, this approach has
privacy concerns.
Your user may not be very happy
uploading their photo to your
server and you may also not be
okay taking their photo.
You have to setup the server so
there is some cost involved.
Let us say you have a million
users, which we sincerely hope
you do, you have to make
millions such models and keep
track of them over time.
With Core ML 3 you can do more
personalization on the device.
So if you have a training data
on the device, you can just
simply use it to fine tune the
model on the device.
So previously you take LMH and
you do the inference and now you
can take the label data feedback
from the user, provide some kind
of training data and fine tune
the model on the device.
[ Applause ]
You have a personalized model
for each user.
We respect user's privacy and
you don't need to put server.
So Core ML 3 supports On-Device
Personalization for Neural
Networks.
We're also supporting Nearest
Neighbor and you can do it in
the background at night.
So to summarize and end our
session we saw Create ML a brand
new app to build ML models, we
have a significant expansion in
our Domain APIs and Core ML is
much more flexible and now
supports On-Device
Personalization.
You can find more information on
our Developer Website Session
209 and we hope you are as
excited about these technologies
as we are.
I look forward to seeing you in
the labs.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]