[ Music ]
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Good afternoon.
My name is Ken Ferry from iOS
System UI, or Springboard if you
know that name.
And today, myself, and Steve
Holt, and James Savage are going
to talk to you about multiple
windows on iPad.
So what are we talking about?
Well, on iOS 12 and before, if
you swipe up in the switcher,
you got this nice little grid,
you can tap on things, gets you
to applications, it's great.
On iOS 13, it looks pretty much
the same, but those are no
longer applications.
Those are Windows, or as you'll
see it's called the in API
scenes.
So that's what we're going to
talk about today.
We're going to talk about what
does this mean for your app.
And it's an introductory talk so
we're going to do it really from
top to bottom.
We're going to start out with
design issues.
So, just what are you going to
want to be thinking about doing
at all in your app for multiple
windows?
We'll go on from there to the
how of multiple windows,
starting out with application
lifecycle, which is the biggest
change to the application
programming model.
That's like foreground,
background and active.
Go on from there to drag and
drop, which is how you mostly
make windows.
And then, James will walk you
through next steps of further
adoption that you might want or
need to do in your app in order
to be a good multiple window
app.
So let's get started.
We're going to talk about these
design issues.
And, first, we just want to talk
about what these windows or
again scenes are.
It is -- there's really kind of
two questions we want to try to
answer here, is first, does it
make sense for my application to
support windows at all, multiple
windows?
And then, if it does, what would
those windows be?
Like how do they act, what are
they, you know, how does the
user think of them?
We'll answer those questions by
looking at examples from Apple's
own apps and generalizing to how
it might apply to yours.
So that's what you're going to
be thinking about.
So we'll start out with Safari.
Safari is a poster child for
this kind of multitasking, that
it was kind of already there.
This is actually a screenshot
from iOS 12 where Safari already
supported the split-screen view.
In iOS 13, it looks like this,
or iPadOS, it looks like this,
which is not really that
different.
That's because it was just so
important that we did it in
Safari even before we could --
we brought it to a whole rest of
the operating system.
For generalization purposes,
though, what is it that we want
to be thinking about here?
The first thing to be realizing
is that every -- there's only
one kind of window in Safari.
They're all the same as each
other.
They're just kind of clones of
the interface.
And each one can do everything
in the application.
That's important because for --
on the iPad, the user should be
able to do everything from just
one window if they want to.
They should be able to create
more windows f they think that's
useful.
But if your application requires
multiple windows to you -- to
work, then something has gone
wrong.
So, it's not important that it
always be quite like this where
they're all just clones of each
other, but it is important that
the first window that the user
create be able to do everything.
Now, that said, in this case,
they are all the same.
And you'll actually see that in
most of Apple's apps, that's
what we've done.
So, and that's -- so that's not
a bad thing.
That's the easiest thing for you
to do and it very well might be
the right thing.
We'll look at the examples.
Though before I go on, I just
want to note that like because
we did adopt, you know, the
system-wide support for this, it
did get better in Safari.
Now, you can like tear off one
of these things and throw it off
to the side and concentrate on
something else for a little
while.
You know, it's fancy.
Going on, document-based apps.
Here, we're looking at pages.
And in any document-based app
really, the user would have the
expectation that they're able to
view documents in different
windows at the same time.
So you're definitely going to
want to support that.
But there's something you might
or might not be a little bit
surprised by here.
If you look at the top left,
there's a button there that says
documents on both of those
windows.
Each of these windows is
actually a full browser.
You can go back from the
document you're looking at and
look at a different one.
So it's actually the same case
as Safari.
There's only one kind of window
and pages.
That's not necessarily going to
be the case in every document,
not even necessarily in every
document-based app I think.
But in here, it does make sense.
And we'll look at cases where it
doesn't going on.
Maps also is -- there's only one
kind of window.
But the reason I still want to
-- we still want to talk about
it is because it illustrates
something to that other point of
should my application even
support multiple windows.
That's because at first, this
didn't necessarily seem like
that attractive of a case
because it seems like you just,
you know, you open maps, you go
somewhere and then you close it.
And that's how it works.
That's actually not the case.
If you're planning an evening
here, you might be going to
dinner and then after dinner,
you're going to a show.
It's really useful to be able to
do each of those two legs in a
different window.
So you can think about them or
change them without losing all
your state in between.
And that seems specific to maps,
but the reason to bring that up
is that we've pretty much always
found that.
So, for all the cases where we
weren't sure if multiple windows
would be useful or not, we
pretty much came around to that
it is.
So, I'll go through more
examples of cases where it is,
but be thinking about that when
you're when you're doing yours.
Oh, and, you know, because it is
using the system multi-window,
that does mean that once you
want to focus on one of them,
say where I'm going to dinner,
you know, I can rearrange my
spaces and pull out notes and do
things that you otherwise
wouldn't be able to do if it was
just inside of one application.
So, Mail is the first case where
there are different kinds of
windows that we've looked at.
Craig showed this in the
keynote, but when you reply to a
message, that brings up this
modal interface same as it
always has, but you can tear it
off.
And then you might even want to
use your slide over stack as
almost like a to-do list of
actions that you are pended and
still need to perform.
So in this case, if you look at
the window again, look at the
top.
There's a Send button, that's
the blue arrow, and there's a
Cancel button.
But there's no way to get back
from here to see the rest of
your mailboxes or anything like
that.
These windows are dedicated.
And then, when you and -- so
when you hit one of those
buttons, it will close the
window.
So I think Craig showed sending
in the keynote, so I'm just
going to show dismissing.
If you first click to get out of
the slide overview to just view
one of them and then click
Cancel, it looks like that.
And all those animations are
available in your app too.
They're talked about in some of
the later talks.
Messages also has different
kinds of windows, but it's not
just like a to-do list.
It's not just like a transaction
or an action like in the other
case.
Here, when you pull off a thread
into its own window, that's just
a dedicated window that pertain
-- that is only for that one
thread.
And you can see it as a Done
button at the top from when
you're finished with it.
That's more of an organizational
tool, but it's a very handy
organizational tool.
And then going back for a minute
to that question of should my
applications support multiple
windows, here in Messages, using
this, I found it incredibly
useful to be able to look at one
conversation and scroll up and
find some information and
reference it while I talk to
someone in the other window.
And I can tell them, and if they
have more questions, I don't
have to somehow go back and
forth.
I've still got it there.
So, in general, I think the
generalizable principle there is
being able to refer to
something, being able to see one
thing while you're acting in a
different window.
The last example of an Apple app
I want to talk about today is
Calendar.
What's interesting here is that
Calendar supported drag and drop
for events already.
But by adopting multi-window,
now, if you view say two
different weeks at the same time
in Calendar, you can drag and
drop from one of those weeks to
the other.
And that didn't require any
additional changes in Calendar
to support that.
That's just the drag and drop
they already had.
So if your app supports drag and
drop by supporting multiple
windows, also you can kind of
magnify the power of both of
those features working together.
So, yeah. And so like I said,
pretty much what we found when
we looked at this is that any
app of sort of reasonable
robustness pretty much benefits
from it.
So, you know, I can't completely
answer the question for your
apps.
You'll have to think about it.
But hopefully some of these
examples will help you think of
those cases where it would be
useful for your users.
Last thing I wanted to note here
before we go on to the next
topic is, you know, we talked
about iPad apps on the Mac this
year.
And Mac apps have windows and
without all this API, you
couldn't make new ones, so it's
going to be kind of a weird Mac
app.
But now you can.
So do that.
Alright. So that's everything
about what are these windows at
all.
But now, still from a design
perspective, what interactions
do you want to enable in your
app so that the user can create
new windows?
We're going to explore that by
first showing what the system
can do for you for free, and
then extrapolating to what users
would expect to be able to do
based on what is already there.
So for starters, Craig showed
App Expose already.
And in App Expose, there's
always this little button in the
top right, and that that little
button is make new window.
So that's something that's
completely for free.
If your app supports
multi-window, that will make new
windows.
There's only one other thing
that we can really do for all
applications, but this is the
one that kind of becomes the
foundation for everything.
If you're already looking at
your application and you grab
the application icon and drag it
over to the edge, that seems
like it's really explicitly
saying, I want to make another
window right here.
Just what else could that mean?
And we have all the contexts
that we need to make that work,
so it does.
But given that, now if the user
picks up something else, say a
tab in Safari and they do that
drag, they're also going to
expect that to work, and that
the system can't just do it for
you.
It's not a lot of work to adopt
the API to do that, but you do
have to actually adopt something
to make that work.
And that really extrapolate --
that extends to all drag and
drop.
Pretty much if the user can pick
something up and it makes any
kind of sense for that to result
in a new window, they're going
to expect that it can.
And you should enable that.
A really common case for that is
any kind of master detail view.
So here in message -- in Mail,
you know, there's this left-hand
table view that represents --
each cell represents a message.
And if you tap on the cell, then
you see the whole thing, right?
So the user is going to expect
that if you drag out of the
table view that that's going to
pull out a window for a message.
OK. So mostly drag and drop.
You can also create windows
through explicit action.
So in an application like Safari
or really anything that has
links at all, you might want to
support that if you press and
hold on a link that that might
pull up a popover and the
popover might have a button that
says Open in New Window.
And that is the case in Safari.
You can do that.
And that's how it reads, it says
Open in New Window.
So that pretty much implies that
there must be -- we are, there
is an API in UIKit that just
whenever you call it, it will
open a new window.
So, you could do a lot with
that, you know.
You could set up like a voice
recognition thing so that like
whenever I sneeze, it like
creates like a new sneeze window
like for analyzing my sneeze
like kind of like Shazam or
something like that.
But -- you could do that, but it
would be weird.
So you shouldn't.
The -- though it actually sounds
kind of fun, but you know.
As we were saying before, the
user should not be forced into
using multiple windows.
That should always be an action
they take for themselves.
So it always needs to be
something that they recognize as
very explicitly creating a new
window like this Open in New
Window.
So -- but that's just -- that's
design level.
So that's something you have to
do for yourselves in your own
applications.
Anyway, that is everything we
have to say about design and the
what.
So to talk about how you can go
adopting this, I'm going to turn
it over to Steve Holt.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Thank you, Ken.
My name is Steve Holt and I'm an
engineer in the UIKit Team.
And hopefully, you've seen some
great examples of how to adopt
this new feature in your
applications.
And you're probably wondering,
how do you actually adopt it in
your applications?
That's great because we're going
to talk about that right now.
So there are two classes you
need to know about in general to
work with this new feature on
iOS and iPadOS, which is
UIWindowScene and SceneSession.
You might be familiar with how
UIs in UIKit are structured
today.
You have a screen, you have all
window or maybe multiple windows
depending on your application.
And then you have your views
contained inside that window
alongside your view controllers.
UIWindowScene inserts itself
right in between the screen and
your windows.
This lets you contain your
windows to a single instance of
user interface without forcing
you to change your application
or user interface structure too
much from what you already
should have today.
So basically, a scene, it
contains your user interface,
and the system will create an on
demand for you.
Whenever the user performs a
drag and drop interaction,
requests a new window opened up
through your own interfaces or
however that's achieved, the
system will ask you to put UI
onto the screen.
And then, if that scene should
go background and it's not being
interacted with anymore, the
system can decide that it's just
kind of hanging out there, we
don't need it anymore, and we
may destroy that scene.
So, if we're going to take that
scene away, but clearly the user
thinks something is there.
I mean your application is still
in the switcher right where it
was before.
You need a way to understand
what is actually in the switcher
without having to rely on the
actual concrete interfaces being
suspended out of your
application.
And that's where SceneSession
comes in.
The SceneSession represents the
persisted interface state that
the user of your applications
were doing last.
Now, they have a defined system
role.
This could be a standard
application interface that you
interact with on the display of
the actual device, or could be
for an external display.
And every time a new window gets
created on the system, your
application is informed through
the application delegate that a
new session has been made.
And every time one has been
destroyed by the user, either
through interactions with our
APIs, or because they swiped up
in the switcher and destroyed
that space, you get informed
that that session has been
destroyed.
And your UI scenes from the
previous slide connect and
disconnect from these sessions
over the lifetime of your
application.
Now, this has some interesting
effects with your application
lifecycle as you might expect.
To represent that, there is a
handy chart we made up.
We have three sessions in our
application, which represents
three different spaces in the
system that my application is
showing its interface.
And right now, they're
disconnected.
They're below that background
line.
So, my application just reports
that its application state is
background.
Now, if I should activate one of
the spaces that my session is
on, the application state will
go up and go all the way up to
foreground active along with
that connected scene.
When I send that scene back to
the background, the application
state descends down with that
scene.
If I were to switch to any of
the other two sessions, then my
application state would remain
at the foreground active state
to represent the fact that the
overall state of the application
hasn't changed.
When it comes to your
application class and your
application delegate class, we
used to put the combination of
the interface with the rest of
the system, and the lifecycle in
that ApplicationDelegate and
Application object.
This doesn't really work too
well anymore.
So, we split it up.
We have your application which
still represents the state of
the system as a system process,
and the ApplicationDelegate
which gets events and delegate
notifications about processes,
things, and launching and
terminating the app as a
process.
But now your scene actually
encapsulates the UI state and
full.
Any questions you have about the
status bar, you ask those to the
scene now.
And your SceneDelegate gets
informed about opening up URLs
in a particular context,
returning from the background,
going to foreground, et cetera.
And of course, you have
SceneSession which represents
that persisted UI state.
Now, you might think that this
is a lot of complicated API.
So, if you have code like this
in your application right now,
you're going have to make a
really big change and move your
implementation of these methods
into these methods.
For the most part, we've kept it
as similar as we could.
Application didn't finish
launching, becomes willConnectTo
session.
EnterForeground is enter
foreground.
It's just on the scene now
instead of the application, and
so on.
Now, there is a hitch here with
state restoration.
It's going to be really
important.
So, your users can look at the
state of the switcher, go to a
particular space, and then have
their information come back
exactly as they left it.
So to help you with that, we've
borrowed a little bit of API
from the Handoff.
And we represent
stateRestoration as an
NSUserActivity now.
You can put whatever information
you wanted.
And at various points in the
lifecycle, you like, it will
request that user activity from
the SceneDelegate.
And then, when you're seeing
restores, will pass it right
back in as the connection
delegate callback.
And should no scene actually
exist for that particular
session, you can access the
stateRestorationActivity
directly on the session so that
should you do a background fetch
and need to update a particular
one, you can go and find which
one you'd change data for.
So, I'm going to give you a
quick demo to show you what it's
like to adopt this new API in
your application.
So, I have an application here
and it was authored by a good
friend of mine and colleague on
my team, John Ham.
And he wrote what is, to me, one
of my favorite apps ever.
You'll see it in just a second
when the simulator comes up, but
it's fantastic.
What you'll see when this boots
is a fantastic gallery app that
exercises all of collection view
flow layout.
But it's going to show a really
important point.
It's a nice charming
application.
And we're going to go from
having just a single instance of
it and bring multiple windows.
Because when I use this
application, I really want to be
able to see more than one photo
at a time.
So we're just going to wait a
little bit more for the
simulator to boot up here.
And here we go.
[Applause] We can launch apps.
As you can see, it is a
marvelous application.
And I can step in and view any
of these photos and pop back
out.
Now, I can bring it up, and if I
try to go into App Expose, I
can't right here.
And that's because this
application doesn't have
multi-window.
So, the first step to
implementing this is to go into
Xcode.
Right here in the General tab,
we have this nice new checkbox
labeled Supports multiple
windows.
You can take a guess what
happens when I check this.
We make a little edit in our
info.plist, and if we jump to
it, we can see that we have this
new entry here called the
Application Scene Manifest.
This tells the system that the
application supports the new
lifecycle interfaces, and we can
declare statically what
interfaces for which type of
roles we want to use.
Now in this case, I've prebaked
a info.plist entry for you.
So we're going to get rid of
that.
And now we have this right here.
So, we've made this and this has
already moved over our existing
storyboard.
And we've had a very, very basic
SceneDelegate class that we have
right here.
And all this does is declare
just a window, a really, really
basic template class.
We build and run.
And we're right back where we
started, which is good.
But now --
So if I could access the icon in
the dock, I will be able to drag
it up and move it over to the
side of the iPad interface and
create a new window, which is
what that info.plist allows us
to do.
But unfortunately, if I were to
go back to the home screen, let
the application terminate, and
then launch it again, we don't
quite get the same level of
state restoration we did do
before as you can see right
here.
So to get that back, we need to
implement a few things, which is
OK.
Now, like I said, to implement
stateRestoration here, we need
to take our existing
stateRestorationActivity that we
have.
Windows return it from the new
stateRestorationActivity for
scene, delegate call.
And way deep in the
implementation here, we've been
setting it on the application
instance, which is not really
what we want anymore.
We want to set it on to local
windows scene like so.
And then clear it out where we
cleared it out before.
So now, we're returning our user
activity so we can do
stateRestoration.
Let's try it.
So what you'll notice here is
that we're not quite done
implementing the
stateRestoration just yet.
We need to do one more thing
when our scene connects.
When the scene connects to the
SceneSession, we get options and
we get the session reference.
Now, in this template that I
pulled out, we're already
looking for any user activities
that we have gotten through
Handoff or any other system
facilities that vend us user
activities.
We want to prefer those user
activities because that's what
the user actually did.
But the stateRestorationActivity
is special and it's on the
session.
So if you don't have one of
those activities, we want to use
our stateRestorationActivity.
So now, when we build and run,
we restore back when the
application is relaunched.
So that's how you adopt multiple
windows in your application.
It's pretty straightforward.
You can use most of your
existing application delegate
logic and just move it to the
scene, and it will run there.
Now, as Ken mentioned, the
preferred way of interfacing
with these drag and drop items
is with drag and drop.
And there are a couple of ways
we can achieve this if you use
existing universal links or
references to file URLs that
your application declares its
own in info.plist, those will
just work.
But if you want to do something
more custom, once again, you can
use NSUserActivity.
You can include that in your
existing DragItem's
NSItemProvider as a different
object representation.
When you drag it off to the rest
of the system, you'll get hit
targets and drop points at
system defined locations just
like any other app icon drag.
And now to talk about the next
steps is my colleague James.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Steve.
So to wrap up this talk, I have
just three more things to talk
about.
The first is going to be a
deeper look at the
UISceneSession API.
Next, we're going to cover some
case studies about common issues
that we think you might see when
you start duplicating your
application's interface.
And lastly, I just want to talk
briefly about some of the
deprecations that we've added to
UI application to support this
new lifecycle.
So let's get started by going
over what a scene session is.
Going back to this diagram from
earlier, you can see in the App
Switcher, we have four windows
of our application.
And that is how the user will
think about this, as four
windows.
But I want to encourage you as
developers to think about these
as scenes and scene sessions.
And that distinction is
important because while the
windows that the user sees in
the App Switchers will always be
there as snapshots, the scenes
themselves may not be loaded in
your application.
They can come and go as needed,
but the sessions will always be
available to you.
And because of this, we use the
session for programmatic control
over the windows.
So I think these are some of the
most exciting API that we're
adding to multitasking this year
because they allow you to create
new windows programmatically,
update the snapshots in the App
Switcher, and close them on
response to things like a user
gesture, or if the document that
they represent has expired in
some way.
So to go over when and how you
would use these, let's look at
some sample code.
The first of these is the
requestSceneSessionActivation
API.
And what this lets you do is
bring forward either an existing
or a new scene of your
application.
In this example, I'm trying to
open a document.
And I first check if the
document has an existing scene
somewhere in my application.
And if it does, I pass it to
this API and it will be brought
forward.
But if this document isn't open
yet, I can create an
NSUserActivity that references
the context I need to open it
later and pass nil to create a
new scene.
Next is the
requestSceneSessionRefresh API.
You'd want to use this in the
context where you may be
received a push notification
about a new message or in an app
like Calendar when an event has
changed.
When you call this method, UIKit
will schedule an update at some
point in the future where it
will connect your scene in the
background.
You'll have a chance to update
the UI, a new snapshot will be
taken, and then that will be
saved into the App Switcher for
later.
You can also use this to update
the stateRestoration user
activity that Steve talked
about.
Lastly, is the
requestSceneSessionDestruction
API, which you can use to close
a scene.
What's really cool about this is
that it also comes with the
scene -- this options object
that lets you pick a semantic
animation for how the scene
should be closed.
You can see this in Mail with
the Compose window.
When the user sends a message,
the sheet animates up off
screen.
And if the user saves it as a
draft, it'll slide down to
remind them that it's been saved
for later.
You can use these same
animations with your scenes and
your apps.
Now, window management isn't all
that the session can do.
We've also added state
restoration to it, as shown with
the NSUserActivity for
stateRestoration.
We think for lots of apps, this
is going to be a really simple
and easy way to start saving
your state, especially if you've
already invested in technologies
like Handoff.
But we also realize that many of
you have apps with existing
state restoration logic and
maybe you don't want to work to
integrate it with
NSUserActivity.
And for that, we have a
persistentIdentifier property.
Now, all this is is a string
that is generated by the system.
You can feel free to write it
down into any databases or any
files in your apps container
that you use for state
restoration.
And it will be the same
identifier for the same scene
every time your app is launched,
even across backups and restores
of devices.
Lastly, there's a userInfo
dictionary, which is great for
storing small amounts of data,
such as per scene
customizations.
You might use this for something
like whether a sidebar is being
shown, or the last used color at
an ink picker.
Really a great way to find
things to put in this might be
to go over data that you're
already storing in your user
defaults, because some of those
things you might not actually
want to be global to your whole
app.
So, that's the new API for
UISceneSession.
But next I want to talk about
what your next step should be
after you built and ran your app
with Xcode supporting multiple
scenes.
And that's of course debugging
it.
Now, there's lots of code in
your app that is very custom,
and we've done our best to make
the framework help you along the
way.
But we can't really predict if
there's any changes you'll need
to make or what they might be.
But we think that there probably
are.
And we do want you to think
about the code that you've
written in the past.
Adopting this new lifecycle and
especially adopting multiple
scenes might have changed
assumptions that you made about
how your application functioned.
There's no longer just one
interface, and there might no
longer be just one instance of a
view controller.
Of course, if you have automated
test, that's great.
Those tests might continue to
pass though, even when your
users might see real bugs.
And that's again because of
these changes to the assumptions
that you might have made.
So the best way that you can
find these problems before your
customers do is just to play
with your app, play with it,
you're having two copies of it
out at once.
And it's a really great way to
very quickly see when something
doesn't quite line up like you
meant it to.
Now, I've prepared a couple of
case studies to highlight
prototypical bugs that you might
see.
But there's this common theme to
both of them, and the theme is
state, specifically, shared
state.
Now, I'm willing to bet that
almost all of you have used one
of these classes in an
application before because
they're really common and really
useful Cocoa classes.
And they're also really
convenient because of that
singleton property.
You can go be in a model object
deep in your app and reach up to
the UI device singleton and read
off some configuration about
what kind of device you're
running on, and that's really
powerful.
But this pattern also can have
problems.
Because of that loose coupling
between layers and data, you can
kind of lose track of where data
is flowing in your application,
who is reading it and how.
But like I said, these are very,
very powerful patterns because
they're so convenient.
And in fact, I expect most of
you have written your own
singletons at some point.
You might be using something
that isn't quite a singleton
like a global variable, or maybe
you're piggybacking on an
existing singleton in the kit.
Or maybe you're using the file
system, which is itself just one
big vault of data that's shared
by your app.
Now, I'm not here to tell you
that you need to get rid of all
your singletons or that shared
state is bad, but I do want to
encourage you to think about how
you're sharing it, and whether
you should be sharing that.
There's lots of other advantages
to factoring your data out, such
as an easier time with unit
tests.
So let's get into those case
studies.
The first one rolls around a
state restoration.
And to work on it, I came up
with this sample app before the
talk.
Now, it's just a nice little
sketch pad editor.
You can type some texts into it,
you quit and relaunch it, and
you see it again.
And I follow the steps from the
demo and I enabled support from
multiple screens, and it's
looking pretty good.
But when I quit and relaunch the
app, this happens.
I now I have the same content in
both sides of my application and
that's not really what I wanted.
So I took a look at my database
and the problem was pretty
straightforward really.
I was saving out this text file
as a file in my apps container,
but I was only saving it to one
location.
So every time either side of my
application saved data, it
overwrite whatever the other one
had saved.
Now, there's nothing that you
UIKit can really do for free
here because this is code in my
app.
So I had to go and do two
things.
I had to correlate that
persistent identifier for the
scene session with the note for
the right scene.
And then I had to update my
logic so that I could save
multiple files instead of just
one.
Now if you're going this route
and doing manual state
restoration, there's just one
more thing I want you to think
about and that's cleaning up the
data.
When UIKit manages that
NSUserActivity for you, it will
take care of where to write it
in once you remove it for you.
But if you're receiving other
large files tied to the lifetime
of a scene in your app, then
you'll want to clean them up
using the new UI application
diDiscardSceneSessions API.
This gets called with a set of
sceneSessions.
And it's a great time to remove
any data that really doesn't
need to exist anymore.
And a document-based app like
pages, you wouldn't want to
delete the document.
That stays in the file system.
But configuration or preferences
aren't needed anymore.
This method will be called
immediately when the user swipes
up on -- in scene of your app in
the App Switcher if your
application is running.
Otherwise, you might receive a
set of multiple sessions
sometime after your next launch.
For our next case study, I want
to look at UserDefaults, which
is another really common and
super useful class for
applications.
UserDefaults are great for
storing settings.
And that's exactly what I'm
using them for here.
I have this toggle for a word
count bar in my app.
And when I switch it on, a word
count bar appears at the bottom
of the screen.
But unfortunately, it only
appeared on the screen where I
had the settings view controller
is showing.
It didn't appear in both windows
and that's not what I wanted.
I want this to be an application
global preference.
And when I looked at why this
was happening, it was again
pretty straightforward.
I had a settings view controller
and a settings view controller
delegate.
Whenever the setting changed, I
told the delegate, which was the
text editor view controller
behind, which then updated its
UI.
That's a very self-contained
process.
And at no point is the second
scene in my application ever
informed that anything is
updated.
There's a couple of ways that we
can solve this, but a really
elegant way is using key value
observing.
And I can do this in two steps.
The first is to define a
property on UserDefaults via an
extension.
This will give me a key path
that I can use for key value
observing.
Here, I have my isInfoButton --
or, sorry, isInforBarHidden
Boolean property, and I
implement it in terms of the
existing get and set methods on
UserDefaults.
Next, I go over to my view
controller where I register an
observation on the standard
UserDefaults.
It takes that key path that I
just defined in my extension and
the change handler which
encapsulates for the work that I
want done anytime that value
changes.
Importantly, I've also passed
the option initial to this
registration.
What this does is really cool.
It calls my change handler once
for free when I set it up, which
means that I don't have to have
this code duplicated anywhere
else.
I don't have to remember to call
one method when my view is
loaded and another when I
receive this update.
There's just one source of truth
for whether or not that's being
shown right now.
It's a really great way to make
sure that your app's interface
is consistent.
Now, everything looks great.
So we hope that those give you
some ideas about things to look
for in your applications.
If your application is already
using best practices, you might
already be doing some of these
and have nothing to change.
But speaking of best practices,
I want to talk about these new
deprecations on UIApplication.
As Steve mentioned, we've split
out the responsibilities for
user interface state and process
lifecycle from the
UIApplicationDelegate.
And to go along with that we've
also split them out of
UIApplication.
Now that you can have multiple
scenes of your application
visible at the same time, you
could have a one with a light
status bar content and one with
a dark status bar content.
And it doesn't make sense for us
to be able to return just one
value to you for this.
So because of that, we are
deprecating these properties on
UIApplication and giving you new
ones on the window scene.
We encourage you to adopt these
new properties even if you're
not planning to adopt support
for multiple windows this year
because it will put you in a
great place if you consider
doing it later.
We've covered a lot today.
So I just want to go over a
brief summary.
Earlier, Ken helped you envision
your applications using many of
the new powerful features that
we've added to multitasking this
year.
We think that users are really
going to come to expect these
out of apps because they're so
useful and convenient.
So we really want to encourage
you to adopt them.
We've made this API easy to
adapt for existing applications.
And we're also pushing it as the
best practice for new
applications.
In fact, this is going to be the
default template for new Xcode
projects using this UI scene
lifecycle.
I also want to encourage you,
because while there might be
some issues when you adopt these
new lifecycle changes, they
usually have fairly simple
solutions, including just the
best practices that we've talked
about in previous WWDCs.
And lastly, I want to encourage
you to move off of the
deprecated UIApplication
properties and onto
UIWindowScene.
These are available to you
anytime you're running on iOS 13
or iPadOS, and you don't need to
adopt multiple windows to take
advantage of them.
We have a couple more talks
later in the week about advanced
topics in multitasking, and also
some labs this week, including
ones focused specifically on
multitasking on Thursday.
I want to thank everyone for
coming out today and hope you
have a great week.
[ Applause ]