[ Music ]
[ Cheering and Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Luke Spicer and today
my teammate Divya and I are very
excited to show you how
HealthKit has expanded our data
representations in iOS 13.
As many of you already know,
HealthKit provides a centralized
data store for health and
fitness data while also
providing interoperability for
health and fitness apps and
experiences.
If you're not already excited
about using HealthKit, let me
remind you that there are over
70,000 apps in the health and
fitness category on the App
Store and all of them can
benefit from the
interoperability and
functionality provided by
HealthKit.
Today, we're going to show you a
few things related to data
representations in HealthKit,
starting with a review of the
HealthKit data model.
Then I'll go into some specific
APIs focused on quantity data.
Later, Divya will come out to
show you beat-to-beat
measurements, heart rate events,
and the brand new API's focused
on hearing health.
Let's jump right in and start
with the HealthKit data model.
In HealthKit, we represent our
data-- in HealthKit we represent
our data with samples, which are
measurements taken at a
particular time that span some
time interval.
Most of these measurements are
simple measurements, like the
heart rates measured with Apple
Watch or body mass measurements
taken with a connected Bluetooth
scale.
Other measurements are more rich
and complex, like workouts or
the clinical health records that
can be downloaded directly to
iPhone.
All of these rich complex data
representations share a common
structure; a top-level sample
that's backed by some
specialized data representation.
For example, a blood pressure
measurement can be represented
with a correlation sample, an
allergy resource by clinical
record, and a workout route by a
series sample.
All of these are examples of
specialized sample types that
all have their own unique
backing data format.
For example, the blood pressure
correlation is a set of blood
pressure measurements.
The allergy resource is backed
by a file resource, and the
workout route is an array of CL
location data.
And just as HealthKit provides
these specialized data
representations for these
special types of measurements,
we've also expanded our data
representations for our most
common type of measurement,
which are for quantity data.
So, let's continue by talking
about quantity data.
To quickly review, quantity data
in HealthKit applies to some
very commonly-measured concepts,
like walking distance, body
mass, and heart rate.
All of these concepts we refer
to as quantity types and they
have measurements that look
something like this, where each
of these measurements consists
of a quantity that is a value
and a unit as well as a date
interval that tells us the
interval over which the
measurement was taken.
We call each of these
measurements a quantity sample.
Throughout this presentation,
we're going to talk about
quantity types and quantity
samples specifically focused on
how we can efficiently represent
large numbers of quantities, but
if you'd like more of an
introduction to these concepts,
you can always refer back to our
2014 presentation, Introducing
HealthKit.
To forward our discussion of
quantity data, I'd like to
describe a scenario.
If you would, please imagine
that together we're working on a
brand-new app.
This app connects to a
never-before-seen heart rate
sensor that's been built right
into a video game controller.
Our task is to take measurements
from this heart sensor and save
them to HealthKit so that our
users can see what their heart
rate was when they play any
particular game.
The heart rates that we're
receiving from the sensor might
look something like this; a
sequence of measurements that
are coming into our app over
time while the user plays.
And we have to decide how we
want to represent this data so
that we can save it to
HealthKit.
One approach that we could take
would be to use a single
quantity sample and that might
look something like this.
This single quantity sample
spans the entire measurement
interval, that is the entire
duration of the game, and
represents all of the
measurements we received from
our sensor with a single
quantity.
Maybe an average.
This representation gives us an
object to represent the
measurement we took, which was
the heart rate during this game,
but if later we want to see
changes in heart rate over the
game, we won't have the
resolution to do that with this
representation.
Another representation we could
take is to use multiple quantity
samples and that might look
something like this, where every
measurement is represented by a
different quantity sample.
This representation will allow
us to keep the full resolution
measured by our sensor, but it
is not an efficient
representation of this data
because we have redundancy.
All of these quantity samples
have identical metadata and
device information and we no
longer have that single
convenient object that
represents the measurement that
we actually took, which was the
heart rate during the game.
Thankfully, we have a third
approach that we can take that
we call quantity series.
The quantity series
representation looks something
like this.
Again, a single quantity sample
that spans our entire
measurement interval, but in
this case, instead of holding a
single quantity, it can be
backed by multiple quantities.
This representation gives us the
best of both of the previous
approaches; a single object to
represent our measurement that
keeps the full resolution
measure-- taken by our sensor.
And notice that we've moved
those redundant pieces of
information that were previously
on the individual quantity
samples, so we only store a
single copy at the quantity
series sample level.
We all want to be respectful of
our users' device storage and
device performance and this
representation allows us to do
that.
Because a quantity series sample
is a quantity sample, we need a
way to represent the sequence of
quantities with a single value
and in HealthKit we do that
through a technique called
aggregation.
We have two primary aggregation
styles; cumulative and discrete.
The cumulative aggregation style
applies to some very common
quantity types, like distances,
calories, and steps.
All of these quantity types are
constantly being accumulated by
our users who are taking more
steps and burning more calories
and moving more distance and a
natural way to accumulate-- to
aggregate multiple quantities
for these types is with a sum.
On the other hand, we have some
other common quantity types for
which a sum doesn't make sense.
For example, heart rate, body
mass, and height won't mean
anything when summed together.
If you take multiple heart rates
over a day and add them up,
you'll get a nonsense value.
It's much more natural to
aggregate quantity types like
this with an average and maybe
some other aggregating
statistics, like minimum,
maximum, and most recent value.
Again, we can see that a
sequence of cumulative
quantities can be represented
and aggregated by a sum and a
series of discrete quantities
like heart rates are going to be
aggregated to produce some
rising statistics, like minimum,
maximum, average, and most
recent value.
In HealthKit, we use quantity
aggregation style to tell us the
aggregation style for a
particular quantity type.
And in iOS 13, we've decided to
deprecate the discrete
aggregation style in favor of a
new discrete arithmetic
aggregation style.
We've done this to make clear
that the average calculated for
this aggregation style is the
simple arithmetic mean.
We've also introduced a couple
of new aggregation styles,
starting with
discreteTemporallyWeighted, a
special aggregation style that
uses a time-weighted average
that we apply when aggregating
heart rate quantities.
We've also added
discreteEquivalent
ContinuousLevel, a special
aggregation style that gets
applied to audio exposure
quantities.
Divya's going to go into more
detail about audio exposure
later on.
Now that we know how to
aggregate multiple quantities to
produce some rising statistics,
we need somewhere to store this
information on our quantity
sample.
And we've done this in iOS 13 by
introducing two new quantity
sample subclasses, starting with
cumulative quantity sample,
which has a sum property, and
discrete quantity sample, which
has a average, minimum, maximum,
and most recent quantity
properties.
We've also made quantity sample
an abstract base class, which
means that from now on all
instances of quantity sample
that you interact with will be
one of these two quantity sample
subclasses, depending on the
quantity type's aggregation
style.
And also I want to note that all
quantity samples can be thought
of as quantity series, some of
which just happen to have a
count of 1.
We've also introduced
corresponding predicate keypaths
for both of these new sample
types so that you can query for
corresponding properties of both
of these samples.
Going back to our quantity
series sample example, we can
see that quantity series sample
can be summarized with our
aggregating statistics, average,
min, max, and most recent value.
Now I'd like to show you how we
go about building this quantity
series.
We're going to start our
quantity series at the time that
our measurement starts.
In this scenario, it's at the
start of a game.
Then, we'll receive measurements
from our sensor which we can
insert into this quantity series
and we can continue to take
measurements from our sensor and
insert them into the quantity
series as long as the game is
being played.
Finally, when we're done
measuring, we can end the
quantity series and get back the
summarizing quantity series
sample.
Now let's see what this looks
like in code.
Our first step, as with all
HealthKit interaction is to
request authorization for the
data types that we plan to read
and write.
In this case, we're going to
request authorization for heart
rate.
Once we've requested
authorization, we can create our
quantity series sample builder
with our healthStore, the data
type, the start date of
measurement, and an optional HK
device.
Then, as long as we're receiving
measurements from our sensor, we
can insert those into our
quantity series sample builder.
And, finally, at the end of the
game, we can finish our quantity
series sample builder with
optional metadata and the end
date for our measurement.
Now that we've thought about how
we can efficiently represent
quantity data and save it to
HealthKit as a quantity series,
we can think about the
experiences we can bring to our
app with the data once it's
saved to HealthKit.
Maybe we want to give our app
the ability to record calorie
information in addition to heart
rate so that we can show our
users the total calories that
they burned in some time
interval or just present some
amazing graphs and charts that
highlight and help them
visualize their data.
Or we want to point out averages
that have been recorded over a
time period.
Or help users see the minimum
and maximum value that they hit
during a particular game.
Or we just want to keep our UI
live and up to date as new data
is being recorded as it's
received from our sensor.
We can do all of this and more
with a single HealthKit query.
HKStatisticsCollectionQuery.
Many of you are already familiar
with StatisticsCollectionQuery,
but it's pretty amazing, so I
just wanted to reiterate what
it's capable of.
StatisticsCollectionQuery can
help you calculate multiple
statistics that can be separated
by the source of data and you
can receive updates to those
statistics as new data is saved
to HealthKit.
And if that wasn't enough, we've
also updated
StatisticsCollectionQuery to
support all of our new
aggregation styles and to
automatically include all of the
backing quantity data that is
stored in quantity series
samples.
If you want more information on
StatisticsCollectionQuery and
HKStatistics, you can always
refer back to Introducing
HealthKit.
Even though
StatisticsCollectionQuery should
be our go-to tool to efficiently
interact with quantity data
that's been saved to HealthKit,
sometimes we really do want to
enumerate every single quantity
that are stored in quantity
series.
For example, if we want to do
something like plot every single
heart rate that was measured by
our application while a user
played the game.
We can do this with
QuantitySeriesSampleQuery.
In iOS 13, we've enhanced
QuantitySeriesSampleQuery by
replacing the quantity sample
argument with a quantity type in
NSPredicate.
Now, instead of simply
enumerating the quantities for a
single quantity sample, you can
enumerate multiple quantity
samples and all of their backing
quantity data.
We've also updated the date
parameter with a date interval,
so you get the full date
interval for every single
quantity while it's being
enumerated.
And we also have an optional
quantity sample parameter which
can give you the quantity series
sample that is currently being
enumerated.
This query is best explained
visually, so I'd like to show
you this.
Here we have two quantity series
samples.
The first quantity series sample
consists of quantities that were
measured with the heart sensor
built into our video game
controller.
And the second series consists
of quantities measured on Apple
Watch.
Because our user happened to be
using both devices
simultaneously, these series
overlap each other in time.
By default, the
QuantitySeriesSampleQuery is
going to enumerate all of the
quantities from both of these
quantity series in the
quantity's start date order.
Like this.
And note that at the end of the
quantity series, the done
parameter is set to true.
If you need access to properties
on the quantity series samples
themselves, like device
information, source, revision,
or metadata, you can set include
sample to true on the query
before executing it.
And notice that, in this case,
while enumerating these quantity
series you can get the
corresponding quantity series
sample in the quantities
handler.
Now that we've seen how we can
efficiently interact with
quantity data using quantity
series, I'd like to show you how
easy it is to add support for
this to the game that we've been
talking about in this
presentation.
Follow me over to Xcode and I'll
show you a brief demo.
What I have here is our game in
its current form.
I don't actually have a heart
rate sensor that's been built
into a video game controller,
but if any of you want to make
one, come find me after.
I do have another external heart
sensor that I can use to get
information into this app.
And remember the quantity series
can be applied to any quantity
type, not just heart rate, and
the data can come from an
external sensor, an external
database, a file on disk, or
just be directly entered by your
app.
In this game, we have two tabs.
First, the Play tab brings up
the PlayViewController where we
can play our game.
And the second tab, the Last
Game tab, brings up the
ResultsViewController, which
will show us the heart rates
that were measured during the
most recently played game.
I'm going to go ahead and switch
back to the PlayViewController
to show you what a round of the
game looks like.
In this game, I'm trying to
click these hot dogs and not hit
the broccoli.
Might seem a bit backwards for a
health app, but this is what I
have.
Every hot dog that I get scores
another point and my heart rate
has a tendency to increase while
I play.
If I switch back to the Last
Game tab, I can see we don't yet
have any heart rate data being
measured while I played that
last game.
We'd like to add that support to
our app now.
Our first step is going to
have-- be to have our app
request authorization, just like
we saw in the presentation.
And because our app is all about
writing and reading heart rate
data while users play, I want to
do this request for
authorization as soon as my app
finishes launching, so I'm going
to add this in application
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions in
my app delegate.
Here I'm requesting-- I'm
creating a set of quantity types
specifically for heart rate so
that I can request authorization
within HK healthStore for these
sample types.
After we request authorization,
we can get measurements from our
sensor and save that data to a
quantity series.
I've already created a class
that encapsulates the connection
to my external sensor and, if
you want to see how that works,
you can always check out the
sample project associated with
this session.
I'm going to switch over to the
PlayViewController now because
we want to add the connection to
record heart rate while the user
plays a game.
I'm going to open the project
navigator and switch over to our
PlayViewController.
In the PlayViewController, I
have a function, startNewGame,
that's called whenever that
Start Game button is pressed in
our app.
This is a great place for us to
create a connection to our
external heart sensor and start
our quantity series-- our
quantity series sample builder.
First, I'm going to create the
connection to my sensor.
This HeartSensorSession is the
class that I mentioned earlier
that I wrote that encapsulates
the connection to my sensor and
I'm setting the
PlayViewController itself as the
delegate of the
HeartSensorSession.
Now I can start my quantity
series sample builder for heart
rate.
Here I'm creating a quantity
series sample builder with my
healthStore for the heart rate
type where the start date of
measurement is the current date
and I'm getting my HK device
information from the
HeartSensorSession.
The HeartSensorSession
communicates to the
PlayViewController through its
delegate protocol,
HeartSensorSessionDelegate,
which has these two methods;
sessionDidReceiveHeartRate and
sessionDidEnd.
With sessionDidEnd--
DidReceiveHeartRate,
HeartSensorSession provides
heart rate measurements to its
delegate and this is a great
place for us to take these
measurements and insert them
into our quantity series sample
builder.
Here I'm inserting the heart
rates and date intervals that
I've received from the
HeartSensorSession into my
quantity series sample builder.
And, finally, sessionDidEnd is
called by the HeartSensorSession
when a HeartSensorSession ends
at the end of a game.
This is the perfect place for us
to end our quantity series
sample builder to persist the
heart rate quantities that we've
inserted to HealthKit.
And we can also associate the
quantity series that we've
created with metadata.
In this case, I'd like to use
metadata to associate these
heart rates with the game
session that we just played, so
that in the
ResultsViewController we can
query for the heart data
associated with the most recent
game.
Here I'm creating a metadata
dictionary using the
MetadataKeyExternalUUID, which I
am setting to the heart sensor's
UUID string.
And finally, I am finishing my
quantity series with that
metadata and the end date of
measurement that we receive from
the HeartSensorSession.
Now that we've saved our heart
rate data to HealthKit, we want
to-- we want to display that
data to the users in the
ResultsViewController.
So, let's move over to the
ResultsViewController now.
In the ResultsViewController
viewDidLoad function, I have a
utility function,
loadHeartRateQuanitites, that's
going to query for the heart
rate data associated with the
most recent game session and
generate a string representation
of each of these quantities that
can be displayed in a table
view.
Let's go ahead and start this by
adding a quantity series sample
query for heart rate associated
with our most recent game, if we
have one.
Here I'm guarding against the
case that no game has yet been
played.
If we have a game identifier, we
can go ahead and create a query
predicate for the
MetadataExternalKeyUUID using
that game identifier.
Remember, we use this metadata
so that we would later be able
to query for the heart rate data
associated with our most recent
game.
Then, I can create my quantity
series sample query for the
heart rate type using the
predicate we created above.
Inside of the query's handler,
I'm going to be enumerating the
quantities and date intervals
associated with this-- with this
latest game and I'm going to
create a string representation
for each of them.
Let's go ahead and create an
array of strings we can use to
store these result strings.
And then we can use this in our
query handler.
First, I'm going to guard
against errors that might have
been returned during
enumeration.
And if I don't have any errors,
I can go ahead and create a
heartRateDetailsStrings using
the enumerated quantities and
date intervals and I'll append
these detail strings to my
heartRateStrings array.
Finally, when enumeration is
complete, the done parameter
will be set to true and this is
the perfect place for me to
dispatch back to the main queue
to reload our
ResultsViewController to display
these strings.
Now I'd like to re-run the app
to show you what this looks like
now that we've added support for
writing and reading heart rate
data.
Remember, the first thing we're
going to see when our app
launches is that request for
authorization.
I'm going to go ahead and turn
on authorization to read and
write heart rate data.
And now I'll play another round
of our game.
Remember, I'm trying to hit the
hot dogs and miss the broccoli.
Oh, scored zero.
Let me play another round.
Oh, scored two, but we can still
see what my heart rate looked
like.
There we go.
We have some heart rates that
were measured during this most
recent game.
[ Applause ]
What we just saw was how easy it
is to efficiently save quantity
data with a quantity series
sample builder and how we can
query for that data using
QuantitySeriesSampleQuery.
Now I'd like to invite up my
teammate Divya, who is going to
show you how HealthKit has
expanded our representations in
the area of heart and how we've
moved into the brand-new health
domain of hearing health.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, my colleague Luke just
described to you the new
efficient way to store HK
quantities now in iOS 13 and
HealthKit has become a
repository for more and more of
our users' daily health data.
And in addition to storing more
and more data, we're also
storing more kinds of data.
This year, we're adding on to
our existing support for heart
health and adding new support
for hearing health.
Our users have been interacting
with heart-related features
since iOS 8, where they've been
able to get heart rate from
Apple Watch, or from sensors
connected to apps created by
developers like you, and view
that data all together in the
Health app.
HealthKit has always had heart
rate support, so if you had a
heart rate reading like the one
here, you could determine that
over a five-second period that
the average heart rate was 68
beats per minute.
And in HealthKit, you would save
that as an HK quantity sample.
In iOS 11, we introduced heart
rate variability SDNN.
Heart rate variability is a
measurement of the variation in
the time intervals between
heartbeats and SDNN stands for
standard deviation normal to
normal.
So, Apple Watch would take the
same heart rate reading and take
the time intervals between each
beat to calculate a standard
deviation and save that as a
quantity sample to HealthKit.
Heart rate and heart rate
variability are both important
metrics for cardiovascular
health and our users have loved
looking at these at a glance
throughout the day or in more
detail, like when they do a
workout.
So, let's take a look at this
same heart rate reading one more
time.
Thus far, I've described to you
ways in which we can summarize
this heart rate data, but
sometimes you want the actual
underlying data itself.
So, let's say that I want the
time-- to know the times at
which each heartbeat occurred.
And returning to our scenario,
let's say that our game
controller has a sensor capable
of telling us any time a new
beat comes in while the user is
playing a game.
So here, the first heartbeat
occurs at 0.5 seconds from the
start point of data collection,
the second at 1.49 seconds, and
we can get-- we can continue to
get the rest of the times that
these beats occurred since the
start of data collection.
So, you'll notice that each beat
happens at a certain point of
time and put together they form
a series of heartbeats.
To save this data to HealthKit,
we have an
HKHeartbeatSeriesSample that
stores a series of heartbeats by
the time stamps at which they
occurred.
Now, you might notice that this
feels similar to the series API
that Luke showed to you before,
but it's important to note that
heartbeat series samples
encapsulate a type of data that
deviates from our other sample
types in HealthKit.
There are no values or units
like the HK quantities that are
the underlying data behind a
quantity series, and therefore
we can more efficiently just
store a series of timestamps to
represent a heartbeat series.
But because we're still storing
a series of data that could get
potentially large, we have in--
we have designed the API to be
familiar to the quantity series,
so we've equipped this
HeartbeatSeriesSample with its
own builder and custom query.
Like quantity series samples,
heartbeat series samples get
created with a builder and
finished when you're done saving
data.
So, let's build one in code.
Our first step, as always, is to
request the proper
authorizations.
For this, you'll need to request
the new heartbeat series type as
well as the quantity type
heartRateVariabilitySDNN
introduced back in iOS 11.
You'll need to request
authorization for both of these
types since heart rate
variability is a metric that can
be directly derived from
heartbeat series and this way
your users have a clear
understanding of exactly the
kind of data they're sharing
with you.
Once we've requested
authorization, we can initialize
a heartbeat series builder with
a healthStore, gameDevice, and
the gameStartDate that will
indicate when we're starting
data collection.
And while the game is ongoing
and our user is playing the
game, we'll add heartbeats with
the time interval since the
series start date to our
builder.
But you might enter a case like
this where your sensor goes down
and here we have a gap in data
collection between seconds two
and three.
Now, it might look like there is
a 1.99 second gap between beats
two and three that could lead to
erroneous interpretation of this
user's heart data.
In order to account for this,
we'll set precededByGap to YES,
which you can set for each beat
that you add if you're aware
that there was a gap in data
collection from a sensor going
down.
Now I can add metadata to my
builder like I would to any
other HK sample.
And when I'm done saving data,
I'll finish the series, which
will save the Heartbeat series
sample to HealthKit.
Now we've added support for
beat-to-beat measurements to our
game and we're ready to start
querying for the underlying beat
measurements.
Like what Luke described to you
before, we can interact with our
normal HK queries to fetch the
high-level samples and then use
the custom queries to interact
with the finer-grain data.
So, my first step will be to run
a normal HK sample query to
fetch my heartbeat series sample
of interest.
And once I've done that, I'll
initialize a heartbeat series
query with that sample, which
will let me enumerate over the
times for each beat.
And finally, I'll execute my
query.
Now, heartbeat series are a
powerful addition to HealthKit,
but that's not all we have
related to heart features.
Back in iOS 12, Apple Watch
started notifying users with
heart alerts.
A low heart rate alert when
Apple Watch detected a heart
rate below a given BPM
threshold, a high heart rate
alert for when heart rate rose
above a given BPM threshold, and
an irregular heart rate alert
for when Apple Watch detected a
rhythm that could be indicative
of AFib.
Well, in HealthKit, these alerts
now come in the form of three
new category types that will get
saved to HealthKit any time
Apple Watch detects an alert.
Now, in addition to all this
great heart support, there's
also this new area that we're
exposing in iOS 13 and I'm
excited to share with you that
hearing health has found its
place in HealthKit.
At some point in your life, you
might remember getting a hearing
test where you put on a pair of
headphones and listened to a
series of sounds and would raise
your hand as soon as a single
sound was loud enough for you to
hear it.
Well, this was an example of a
pure tone hearing test, where a
pure tone is a sound with a
single frequency.
Pure tone testing helps identify
the quietest sound that you can
hear at a set of different
frequencies and it can provide
assessment on the kind of
hearing impairment or loss that
you might have.
The results of pure tone testing
most commonly get displayed in
graphs called audiograms.
This here is an example of an
audiogram for someone with mild
hearing impairment and let's
just zoom into this graph to get
a better idea of the kind of
data that is stored in an
audiogram.
So, here you'll see two lines,
one corresponding to the pure
tone hearing test results from
the left ear and one for the
right ear.
And let's just take a look at
the first two data points at the
125-hertz line.
This shows that for this user to
hear a sound at a 125-hertz
frequency, they need around 11
decibel hearing level units in
their left ear and 31 in their
right.
The decibel hearing level unit
measures the intensity of a
sound relative to the quietest
sound that a young, healthy
individual would be able to
hear.
So, we can get the rest of the
data points associated with this
audiogram and in order to store
this data in HealthKit, we're
introducing an HKAudiogramSample
that stores an array of hearing
sensitivity points associated
with a hearing test.
So, let's create an audiogram
sample and code.
Our first step is to create an
HKAudiogramSensitivityPoint that
encapsulates the intensity of a
sound required for both ears to
hear a given frequency.
So, I'll create a frequency
quantity with my new HK unit
hertz unit and a left-ear and
right-ear sensitivity quantity
with my new decibel hearing
level unit.
Now I'm ready to create an
audiogram sensitivity point.
Once you've created an array of
audiogram sensitivity points,
you can store that in an
audiogramSample.
Now, you'll need to make sure
that the array of sensitivity
points are all unique and in
order, since that's how you
should expect to interact with
this data later on in analysis
or charting.
And finally, I'm ready to store
that data to HealthKit.
And that's how easy it is for
you to start creating audiogram
samples and to start building
hearing health apps with
HealthKit.
But an audiogram sample only
represents the health of your
ears at a given point of time
when you're taking a hearing
test.
Most of the day, we're exposed
to sounds through our headphones
or while we're walking down the
street in the environment and
all of that can impact our
hearing health for life.
To keep track of the audio
exposure that you're exposed to
through your headphones, we have
a read-write quantity type,
headphoneAudioExposure.
And for the rest of the day,
when we're walking down the
street exposed to construction
work sounds or traffic, Apple
Watch is capable of capturing
that environmental audio
exposure data and saving it to
HealthKit, and for that we have
an analogous read-write quantity
type,
environmentalAudioExposure.
And for times when environmental
audio exposure gets too high,
Apple Watch will generate an
audio exposure alert to make
sure that you're aware of the
possible impact that can have on
the health of your ears.
And it will save this as a
category sample using the new
audioExposureEvent category type
identifier.
So, we've covered a lot about
the new data representations now
available with HealthKit and iOS
13, from new efficient series
representations to the new
support with hearing health.
Now you can officially store
large numbers of HK quantities,
the most abundant kind of data
stored in HealthKit.
And you have the opportunity to
represent even more rich data
representations related to heart
and hearing health.
For more information as well as
our sample code projects you saw
here, you can visit our session
link listed or come talk to us
right after this session at the
Health and Fitness Technologies
Lab.
Thank you and have a great rest
of your WWDC.
[ Cheering and Applause ]