[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
Sound has long been an
incredible part of creating a
truly great app.
Whether that's creating an
atmospheric sound bed for your
games or drawing attention to an
important alert or notification.
The addition of haptics adds a
whole new dimension to this
experience -- touch.
Today's session is a story in
two parts, design and
development.
And first, I'd like to start by
introducing Hugo and Camille and
ask them to come to the stage
for their insights and guidance
on designing great haptic
experiences for your apps.
[ Applause ]
[ Cell Phone Vibration ]
&gt;&gt; I'm sure you're familiar with
that sound.
It's been part of our life for
years.
In 2019 though, I think we can
do better.
I'm Camille Moussette,
interaction designer on the
Apple design team.
&gt;&gt; And I'm Hugo Verweij, sound
designer on the design team.
This session is about designing
great audio haptic experiences.
Our goal with this talk is for
you to be inspired and leave you
with practical ideas about how
to design great sound and
haptics when used to together in
the right way can bring a new
dimension to your app.
During the next 30 minutes,
we'll talk about three things.
First, we'll introduce what is
an audio haptic experience.
Then we'll look at three guiding
principles to help you design
those great experiences.
Lastly, we'll look at different
techniques and practical tips to
make those experiences great and
truly compelling.
So, what is an audio haptic
experience?
Well, let's start by listening
to a sound.
[ Beeping Sound ]
Okay. Now let's lower this
sound.
[ Beeping Sound ]
What happens if I lower it even
further?
[ Beeping Sound ]
Whoa. It's so low I can't hear
it anymore.
You know, our ears just don't
register it anymore.
But, if you would put your
finger on the speaker, you could
still feel it move back and
forth.
We designed a taptic engine
specifically to play these low
frequencies that you can only
feel.
Here it is in the iPhone and
next to it the speaker module.
The haptic sensations from the
taptic engine are synchronized
to the sounds coming from the
speaker, and the result is what
we call an audio haptic
experience.
But haptic sensations are meant
to be felt, so because we are
presenting this on stage, and on
screen we need your help in
imagining what this would feel
like.
We'll do our best to help you by
visualizing the haptics like
this
or by playing a sound that
resembles the haptic, like this.
[ Drumming ]
We will also visualize these
experiences on the timeline, and
Camille will tell you some more
about how that's done in a quick
haptics design primer.
&gt;&gt; IOS 13 introduced a new API
for designing your own custom
haptics.
It's called Core Haptics.
This new API allows you
developers to use the taptic
engine fully in iPhone.
The taptic engine is capable of
rendering a wide range of
experiences and can generate a
custom vibration like this, it
looks like this, and it should
sound and feel like this
[beeping sound].
So, as you've seen, we're using
a wave form and sound to
represent haptics.
As Hugo said, you need to
imagine this in your hand as a
silent experience.
This should be felt and not
heard.
So, we can play these continuous
experiences.
We can also have something
that's more shorter and compact.
It's a single cycle, and we call
this experience a transient.
It's much more momentary, and it
feels like an impact or a strike
or a tap.
[ Drumming Sound ]
Very momentary and then we
actually can refine it further.
Moving forward, we'll use basic
shapes to represent haptics in
different patterns.
So, our transient becomes a
simple rectangle, and because
our taptic engine is an
exceptional piece of haptic
engineering, we can modulate the
experience in different ways.
First, we can modulate the
intensity or the amplitude.
We can also make it feel more
round or soft.
At the other extreme, we can
make it more precise and crisp.
So this experience is possible
with the taptic engine.
So, in the end, this completes
our quick introduction to haptic
design and what Core Haptics API
is all about.
We have one intensity you can
modulate and another design
dimension, haptic sharpness,
that you can, you are in control
for two types of event,
continuous and transient.
Now, let's look at the three
guiding principles that we want
to share with you today.
First is causality.
Then we have harmony and lastly
we have utility.
These concepts or approaches are
used throughout the work that we
do at Apple, and we think they
can help you as well in your own
app experience.
For each of them, we'll look at
the concept and explain through
a few examples.
Let's get started.
Causality.
Causality is about for feedback
to be useful it must be obvious
what caused it.
&gt;&gt; So, imagine being a soccer
player kicking this ball.
What would the experience feel
like?
There is a clear, a clear
relationship, an obvious
relationship between the cause,
the foot colliding with the ball
and the effect, the sound of the
impact and the feel of the
impact.
Now, what this experience sounds
and feels like is determined by
the qualities of the interacting
objects, the material of the
shoe, the material of the ball.
And then the dynamics of the
action.
Is it a hard kick or a soft
kick?
And the environment, the
acoustics of the stadium or the
soccer field.
Because we are so familiar with
these things, it would not make
sense at all to use a sound that
is very different.
Let's try it out and take it way
over the top.
[ Glass Breaking ]
Very strange, that doesn't
really work.
Now when designing sounds for
your experiences, think about
what it would feel and sound
like if what you interact with
would be a physical object.
As an example, let's look at the
Apple Pay confirmation.
We wanted the sound and the
haptics to perfectly match the
animation on screen, the
checkmark.
So, where do we start?
Well, what sounds do you
associate with making a payment?
What does money sound like?
And what is the interaction of
making a payment using Apple
Pay?
And of course we have to look at
that animation of the checkmark
on screen.
It should feel positive, like
confirming a successful
transaction.
Here are a few examples of
sounds that were candidates for
this confirmation.
This is the first one [beeping
sound].
This one is very pleasant, but
it sounded a bit too happy and
frivolous.
Now the next one worked really
well with the checkmark of the
animation [beeping sound].
But we felt that its character
wasn't really right.
It was a little too harsh.
And then there is this one, the
one that we chose in the end and
that you all know.
It's not too serious, and it's
clearly a confirmation [beeping
sound].
Okay, so we've got our sound.
Now, onto the haptics.
Our first idea was to mimic the
waveform of the sound because it
matches perfectly, but after
some experimentation, we found
that two simple taps actually
did a better job.
I like to see these as little
mini compositions where we have
two instruments, one that you
can hear and one that you can
feel, the haptics.
They don't always necessarily
have to play the same thing, but
they do have to play in the same
tempo.
Here they are together.
Notice the lower sound
indicating the haptics [beeping
sound].
Okay, and this is then the final
experience with the animation.
Again, imagine feeling the taps
in your hand when you pay.
[ Beeping Sound ]
Next, let's look at our second
guiding principle, harmony.
Harmony is about things should
feel the way they look, the way
they sound.
In the real world, audio haptics
and visuals are naturally in
harmony because of the clear
cause and effect relationship.
In the digital world though, we
have to do this work manually.
New experiences are created in
an additive process.
The input and output need to be
specifically designed by you,
the developer.
Let's start with creating a
simple interface with the
visual.
We have a simple sphere dropping
and colliding with the bottom of
the screen.
Next, let's add audio feedback.
[ Beeping Sound ]
Now, we choose a sound that
corresponds to the physical
impact or the bounds of the
sphere.
It needs to be short and precise
and clear, but we also modulate
the amplitude based on the
velocity of the hit.
Now, let's do additional work
and introduce the third sense,
haptic feedback [beeping sound].
So imagine feeling that hit in
your hand.
Again, we're trying to design in
harmony the sphere hitting the
bottom of the screen, so we
choose a transient event with
high sharpness.
We also modulate the intensity
to match the velocity of the
bounce.
We're not done yet.
Because it's really important to
think about synchronization
between the three senses.
That's where the magic happens.
That's where the illusion of the
real ball colliding with the
wall takes shape.
So here's an example where we
broke the rules, and we
introduced latency between the
visual and the rest of the
feedback.
[ Beeping Sound ]
It's clearly broken, and the
illusion of a real bouncing ball
is completely not there.
So, harmony requires great care
and attention from you but when
done well can create very
delightful and magical
experiences.
Let's look at different harmony
in terms of the notion between
interaction, visuals, audio and
haptics, in terms of qualities
and overall behaviors.
We'll look at a simple green dot
on screen that will animate and
think through what kind of
audio, what kind of haptics
makes sense with that green dot.
So if we add a snappy pop or a
different pulse, what kind of
audio, what kind of haptics work
with these visuals?
What if we have a large object
on screen?
Does it sound different?
Does it feel different than a
tiny little dot?
If we add different dynamic
behavior, a different energy
level, a pressing, pulsating dot
that really calls for attention
might want a different sound,
different haptics.
And lastly, something that feels
calm or like a heartbeat warrant
different type of feedback.
So, think about the pace, the
energy level, and the different
quality that you're trying to
convey in your app.
Design feedback that tell the
consistent and unified story.
&gt;&gt; Now I'll illustrate how the
harmony principle helped us with
designing sound and haptics for
the Apple Watch crowd.
We were all used to our phones
and their old school vibes
coming from them.
When the Apple Watch came out as
the first device with a taptic
engine, it was the first device
that could precisely synchronize
sound and haptics.
Now for Series 4, haptics and a
very subtle sound were added to
the rotation of the crown.
Remember the sharp and precise
haptic that Camille described
earlier?
That was the one that we used
for the crown.
But it was scaled down to match
the small size of the crown, and
so the haptics are felt in the
finger touching the crown rather
than on the wrist.
For sound, we looked at the
world of traditional watch
making for inspiration.
We listened to and recorded all
kinds of different watches, some
of which sounded quite
remarkable, like this one
[clicking sound].
And then there are other
physical mechanical objects in
the real world with a similar
sound like bicycle hubs
[clicking sound].
We wanted to find a sound that
would feel natural coming from a
device like this.
We took these sounds as
inspiration before we started
crafting our own.
And then this is the result.
On your wrist, it sounds very
quiet, just like you would
expect coming from a watch.
[ Clicking Sound ]
The perfect coordination between
sound and haptics creates the
illusion of a mechanical crown,
and then to match this
mechanical sensation, our motion
team changed the animation so it
snaps to the sound and the
haptics when using the crown.
Let's look at that [clicking
sound].
And I'll play it again.
Look at the crown visualizing
the haptics [clicking sound].
The result is a precise
mechanical feel, which is in
perfect harmony with what you
see and what you hear.
&gt;&gt; Next, let's look at our third
guiding principle, utility.
Utility is about adding audio
and haptic feedback only when
you can provide clear value and
benefit to your app experience.
Use moderation.
Don't add sound and haptics just
because you can.
Let's look at a simple AR kit
app that we made to illustrate
this point.
In this app, we place a virtual
timer in the environment, and
then the interaction is
dependent on the distance of
that virtual timer.
Let's look at the video first.
[ Clicking Sound ]
So, in this app, we purposely
designed audio and haptic
feedback to complement the AR
interaction and the most
significant part of the user
experience, meaning moving
closer to the timer or moving
away from the timer modulate the
audio haptic experience.
The three senses are coherent
and unified.
We refrain from adding other
sound effects or haptic feedback
to interacting with the
different elements or other
minor interaction in the app.
&gt;&gt; It's often a good idea not to
add sound and haptics.
So, start by identifying
possible locations in your app
for audio haptic feedback, and
then focus only on the elements
where it can enhance the
experience or communicate
something important.
And then, are you tempted to add
more?
But maybe don't.
It will overwhelm people, and it
will diminish the value of
what's really important.
So, to recap, here are the
guiding principles one more
time.
We spoke about Causality, how it
can help to think about what
makes the sound and what causes
the haptics.
About Harmony, how sound,
haptics, and visuals work
together in creating a great
experience.
And Utility.
How looking at the experience
from the point of view of the
human using your app.
&gt;&gt; Next, let's look at the
techniques and practical tips
that we can use with these three
guiding principles to create
great audio haptic experience.
First, a small recap about the
primitives available in Core
Haptics.
We have two building blocks that
you can work with.
The first one is called
transient, and it is the sharp
compact, haptic experience that
you can feel like a tap or a
strike.
The second one is a continuous
haptic experience that extends
over time.
You can specify the duration how
long it should last.
For transient, there are two
design dimensions that is
available and under your
control.
We have haptic intensity, and we
have haptic sharpness to create
something more round or soft at
the lower value and something
more precise, mechanical, and
crisp at the upper bound.
Intensity changes the amplitude
of the experience as expected.
For continuous, we have the two
similar design dimensions.
We have sharpness and intensity,
and we're able to create more
organic or rumble-like
experience that extends over
time or something that is more
precise and more mechanical at
the upper values of sharpness.
So there are many more details
and capabilities in the Core
Haptics API.
Be sure to check out the online
documentation.
&gt;&gt; Now, when designing sounds,
keep in mind what will work best
with these haptics.
For a sharp transient, a chime
with a sharp attack will
probably work really well
[chiming sound].
But if we have a sound that's
much smoother, using those same
haptics, it's probably not such
a good idea [music].
So, for something like this, a
continuous haptic ramping up and
down probably works better.
[ Music ]
But these are not hard rules.
There is a lot of room to
experiment, and sometimes you
may find out that the opposite
of what you thought would work
is actually better, and this was
the case for the Apple Watch
alarm, that sounds like this.
[ Chiming Sound ]
For a sound like this, you may
want to add a haptic like this
because it pairs together
perfectly
[chiming sound].
But can we make it better?
Can we keep experimenting?
Maybe flip it around and change
the timing?
[ Chiming Sound ]
This creates anticipation by
ramping up the haptics and then
quickly putting it off and
playing the sound.
There was a clear action
reaction, and the sound plays as
an answer to the haptic.
This work really well for the
Apple Watch alarm.
Next, it's pretty common to have
a number of events back to back
to convey a different type of
experience.
In this case, we have four
transient events, and we notice
that when we present this to
different people, they don't
necessarily feel the first one.
We have a first ghost haptics.
[ Drumming Sound ]
So the sequence of four taps is
actually reported as a triple
tap only.
This could be a problem or an
opportunity.
We could use this effect of
ghost or not perceiving the
first one completely as a
priming effect.
Let's look at the example of a
third-party alert on watchOS.
This is the sound and the
haptics of that third party
notifications.
[ Chiming Sound ]
So this is a really important
notification that we want to
make sure that the user
perceived and acknowledged
clearly.
So in this case, we use our
ghost effect or a primer in this
case to wake up the skin and
make sure that it's completely
ready to feel what's to come.
Let's listen and feel it.
[ Drum and Chiming Sound ]
So, in this case, we have clear
presentation and recognition of
our main notification
experience.
Next, we can also create
contrast between very similar
experiences.
Here is the sound for the left
navigation cue on watchOS.
It sounds like this
[beeping sound].
With our harmony guiding
principles, we end up with
really nice haptics that pairs
very well with that sound.
So we have a series of double
strikes that sound and feel like
this.
[ Beeping Sound ]
Now if we look at the right cue,
we have a similar sound but
slightly different.
[ Beeping Sound ]
So we can notice the little
difference between the left and
the right on the audio, but if
we continue to follow our
harmony principle, with the
haptics we end up with an
identical pattern between the
left and the right experience.
In this case, we want to add
haptics.
We double up the haptics from
the double strikes, and then we
have true contrast between left
and right.
Let's listen and feel what, this
experience [beeping sounds].
Again, we have contrast between
the left and the right for very
similar audio experience.
&gt;&gt; So, by now you have quite a
few tools to create your own
experiences.
We would like to show you one
more example illustrating the
points we made.
This is a full screen effect in
messages.
[ Popping and Crackling Sound ]
The sound and haptics are
perfectly synchronized to the
animation, and it's a delightful
moment for a special occasion.
Let's look at it one more time.
[ Popping and Crackling Sound ]
Now, if you haven't yet, I
encourage you to try this out on
your own iPhone to experience
the haptics yourself.
And now, a few more thoughts to
consider in addition to the
guiding principles that we
shared.
The best results come when
sound, haptics, and visuals are
designed hand in hand.
Are you an animator?
Collaborate with the sound or
interaction designer and vice
versa.
It's the best way to come to a
unified experience.
Imagine using your own app for
the very first time.
What would you like it to sound
like or feel like?
And then imagine using it a
hundred times more.
Does it still help you to hear
and feel these things or are you
overwhelmed?
Experience it and take away all
the things that don't feel
compelling or that are not
useful.
And don't be afraid to
experiment.
Try things out.
Prototype.
We've seen that you may just
come across something amazing by
trying something new.
We're looking forward to seeing,
hearing, and feeling what you
will come up with in your own
apps.
See this URL for more
information.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thank you Hugo and Camille.
So, now that we have a better
idea of how to design our haptic
experiences for our apps, now
let's understand how we're going
to take these principles and put
them into practice in code.
And to do that, Michael and Doug
are going to walk through how we
can take advantage of the new
Core Haptic APIs.
And to start that off, I'd like
to introduce Michael to the
stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good evening.
I'm Michael Diu from the
interactive haptics team, and
I'm looking forward to sharing
the many advances in haptics in
iOS 13 with you.
Let's take a look at our agenda.
First, we'll find out where we
can use Core Haptics, how it
fits in with other audio and
haptic APIs.
We'll talk about the two groups
of classes in the API and the
basic dimensions and descriptors
that we will use to describe our
haptics and audio content.
We're going to walk through the
basic recipe to start playing
out that content, and then we're
going to move onto introducing
dynamic parameters.
And dynamic parameters are a way
that you can customize your
haptic patterns at playback
time, in response to your user
or your app's behavior.
And, we're going to explore a
new way to express, store, and
share your audio haptics
contents, a new file format
we're calling the Apple Haptic
Audio Pattern or AHAP.
So let's get to it.
First, what is Core Haptics?
We can think of it as an
event-based audio and haptic
rendering API or synthesizer for
iPhone.
We can continue to use our other
audio and haptics and feedback
APIs like AV Audio Player and
UIKit's UIFeedback Generator in
parallel with Core Haptics.
You might be wondering, which
iPhones can I use this on.
With just one API and one file
format, we will be able to
access hundreds of millions of
taptic engine equipped iPhones
starting from iPhone 8 onward.
And we've taken care that your
haptic patterns will have the
same feel across all of these
products, so much so that you're
going to be able to prototype
and release just using one
product.
And these iPhones aren't
equipped with just any old
commodity actuator.
They all have the Apple-designed
taptic engine, which offers you
that unique combination of
power, a wide expressive range,
and an unmatched precision and
control and subtlety.
Next, I'd like to talk about
those of you who have already
started adopting haptics on
iPhone with UIKit's Feedback
Generated APIs.
Now, Core Haptics is not a
replacement for this API.
In most cases, you want to keep
on using Feedback Generator
especially for UIKit controls
and adding haptics to that.
With that API, you indicate the
design intent for your event,
whether that's a selection, an
impact, or a notification, and
you let someone else, Apple,
worry about developing a
vocabulary to express that and
mixing the right modalities like
audio, haptics, animation to
communicate that message.
Now this API is also being
improved in iOS 13.
So please check out its
documentation for more details.
In contrast, Core Haptics is
good when you want to be your
own sound and haptic designer.
With it, you developed your own
patterns, and you can have a lot
more control over exactly what
time it gets played, so you can
synchronize with other APIs like
an animation from Core Animation
or a sound event from AV Audio
Engine.
You have a much richer set of
playback and modulation
controls.
Now, UIKit is built on top of
Core Haptics, so both APIs share
the same low latency performance
characteristics.
Now, designing your own haptic
patterns is going to take more
time, but when it allows you to
do something that you couldn't
otherwise do, and when it allows
you to differentiate your app,
then it's worth thinking about.
Now, next I'd like to talk a bit
more about those audio
capabilities.
So, Core Haptics is also an
audio API, and so that allows
you to play short, synthesized,
or custom waveform audio in
synchronization tight sync with
your haptics.
This type of audio haptic
duality has been crucial to many
of Apple's own haptic
experiences like the haptic home
button in iPhone 7, the haptic
crown in Series 4 Watch, and the
UIDatePicker, those scrolling
wheels that you use to select
dates and times and alarms and
calendars.
And, you may not have realized
that.
You may not even have noticed
that there was audio in these
experiences, but if you were to
cover up that audio once you
take it away, you'll realize
that it's an inseparable and
integral part of that
experience.
So now, you can do the same with
Core Haptics in your own apps.
And I want to talk about some
categories of apps, one huge
category in particular, where
you might want to think about
Core Haptics, and that's games.
So, imagine we are at the
racetrack.
We want to go into turbo mode.
Let's imagine [rumbling sound].
When you've got the brute force
message to deliver, think about
using synchronized haptics and
audio in your app to generate
those visceral explosions and
rumbles.
Now, another very nice
application is simulate physical
contact, to make your
applications feel more
realistic.
Think about a tennis game.
You could have audio and haptic
components where the pitch of
your audio, the intensity of
your haptics are proportional to
how fast your swing is or how
centered the ball lands in the
middle of the racket.
And you can even control how
long the strings your racket
will resonate for after the
impact.
So, another great area to think
about using Core Haptics is in
augmented reality apps.
And there, if you're working in
this space, you're already
familiar with the benefits of
having high visual fidelity
paired with 3D audio, working in
concert.
Now, we can reach for that next
level of emersion by considering
how custom haptic feedback can
ground our user gestures or
respond to app, device, and AR
object events.
For example, moving your device
around or moving your entire
users around.
As an inspiration, this year
we've enhanced the swish sample
code by using haptics that are
modulated based on how fast you
pull back the sling, how fast
you pull back your phone.
You're going to feel the tension
building up as you stretch it
back, and then the very
satisfying thunk as you release.
I'd like to show you a video of
this, and I'm going to use audio
to represent just the haptics
that you're going to feel.
They're going to sound like this
[chiming sound].
Now, we're going to see the
whole thing together, visuals
and haptics, no regular audio.
[ Chiming Sound ]
So that was an example of how we
can use haptics, sound, and
visuals all synchronized
together to enhance our AR
experience.
Now, these are just a few
categories of apps, games, and
AR that are ripe for creative
explorations with haptics and
their corresponding sounds.
I'm sure you're going to think
of many, many more.
So, now let's get into how we
can start expressing our content
with Core Haptics.
There are just two groups of
classes in Core Haptics.
There's those to represent your
content and those to play back
that content.
Let's take a closer look at the
content side first.
The basic indivisible content
element in Core Haptics is
called a CH Haptic Event.
Now each event has a type and a
time, and optionally parameters
that will customized its feel.
These events can overlap each
other, and when they do, they
mix.
And all events are grouped into
a pattern.
Next, I'd like to talk about
those types of events.
Our first type is called the
Haptic Transient.
The Haptic Transient, I think of
it as a gavel, it's a tricking
motion.
It's momentary and
instantaneous.
And then we have two continuous
types.
We have Haptic Continuous and
Audio Continuous.
And there, I think of, for
example, bowing a stringed
instrument.
It is longer than a transient.
It can be, for example, used as
a background texture, and you
have a much richer set of knobs
that you can use, for example,
to modulate the resonance of it.
Lastly, we have the Audio Custom
type, and the Audio Custom, as I
mentioned earlier, is where you
can provide your own audio to be
played back in sync with the
haptics.
Next, let's talk about some of
those optional parameters.
Our first event parameter is
called haptic intensity, and it
has an audio analog, audio
volume, which you're probably
already familiar with.
Now, with this parameter, you go
from no output as you turn, and
as you turn the knob from 0 all
the way up to 1, you go to
maximum output of the system.
Our next parameter is called
haptic sharpness.
Now, haptic sharpness is a new
concept.
There's no physical analog to
this, and there's also no audio
analog.
In this world, I want you to
instead think of moving along in
a perceptual space from a very
round and organic feel at 0 all
the way to a more crisp and
precise feel at 1.
And to help ground that a bit
further, I'm going to use some
examples from iOS 12.
The flashlight button on your
lock screen is an example of a
very high sharpness haptic, and
the app switcher, that swipe up,
that's an example of a more
round, a lower sharpness haptic.
As for the why, why were those
two types of experiences, you
know, sharp and not sharp, I'm
going to refer you to our talk
on audio haptic design.
Now, we have several more types
of event parameters, for
example, that apply to audio,
like pitch and pan, and for
haptics, we have things that let
you change those resonance and
so forth.
But these two, intensity and
sharpness, will be enough to get
us going.
Now, to develop a feel for that
dynamic range and precision of
intensity and sharpness, we've
got a sample code, the Palette,
which allows you to try out
these experiences for yourself.
As you move, as you tap or you
drag your finger around, you'll
be accessing the sharpness axis
as well as the intensity axis,
and it's going to play out the
corresponding continuous or
transient haptic, as you do
that.
This will help you get that
intuition.
So, that was an introduction
about where we can use Core
Haptics and also how to specify
our content.
Now, let's invite Doug Scott,
our Core Haptics architect, to
get us started with playing back
Core Haptics, playing back those
patterns, and integrating Core
Haptics into our apps.
Please welcome Doug.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Michael.
Good evening everyone.
I am thrilled to be here to talk
to you about integrating the
Core Haptics API into your
applications.
Before I show a demo and dive
into the code, let's walk
through the basic steps that
your application will follow
when you want to play a haptic
pattern.
Creating your content is the
first good step because this can
be done at any point prior to
the point where you need to use
it.
In this example, with load an NS
dictionary into a haptic
pattern.
The dictionary might have been
something that we stored in our
application as part of our
resources.
As we will see later, patterns
can also be created right before
they are to be played if they
need to vary interactively in
response to changes in your
application.
The next step is to create an
instance of the haptic engine.
This should be done as soon as
your application knows that it
will be making use of haptics.
Next, you create a haptic player
for your haptic pattern.
Each player is associated with a
single pattern and a particular
haptic engine.
Starting the haptic engine tells
the system to initialize the
audio and haptic hardware in
preparation for a request to
play the pattern.
At the moment that your
application wants the pattern to
play, you start the player.
This can be done in two modes.
The first, which we could call
immediate mode, tells the system
that you wish this pattern to
play at the soonest possible
moment with minimal latency.
The second, in scheduled mode,
you handed a absolute timestamp,
which tells the system that you
want to synchronize this event
with some other system, such as
another audio player or a game
event or a graphics event.
If you want to know when your
pattern is finished playing, you
can have the haptic engine
notify you via callback when
your player or players are done.
Here, the engine calls back to
the application, and the
application can now choose to
stop the haptic engine or can
turn you on with the next haptic
pattern.
Those are the basic steps.
Now, let's see and example of an
application which uses this
system.
But before we do, we need to let
you in on a secret.
Demonstrating the use of an API,
which generates tactile feedback
presents a unique problem.
You in the audience can't feel
it.
The way we handled this was by
adding an audio equivalent for
each haptic event into the
output, which will let you hear
the effect of the haptics.
This application uses a simple
physics engine to move the ball
around the screen in response to
the accelerometer.
It generates haptic and audio
feedback when the ball impacts
the edges of the screen.
The user has the sense they are
feeling the impacts through the
edges of the game wall as well
as hearing them.
The harder the ball hits the
edge, the more intense the
haptic and the louder the audio.
Okay. Let's look at the code for
this example to see how to
integrate the Core Haptics API
into your application.
We'll see how event parameters
are used to produce changes in
haptics and audio.
The example here, all this code
is taken from the sample code on
the website, but it's been
edited down to show the
important points.
First, we important the Core
Haptics module along with the
other modules we need for the
application.
The CHHaptic Engine is declared
as a member variable of our view
controller, because we want to
be able to control its lifetime
and have it exist for the
lifetime of the application.
As discussed in our flow chart
earlier, we set up the haptic
engine in advance of when we
want to use it.
Here, we call a helper method at
the point that the view has
loaded.
In the helper method, we began
by creating the instance of the
haptic engine and check for
possible errors.
The engine is assigned to our
member variable so we can keep
it around.
It is optional but extremely
useful to assign a closure to
the engine's stop handler
property.
This will be called if the
engine is stopped by some action
other than the application
itself asking it to.
Some possible reasons that this
might happen are an audio
session interruption or the
application being suspended.
We finish this method by
starting the haptic engine and
checking for possible errors.
The engine will continue to run
until the application or a
possible outside action stops
it.
Note that the application tracks
whether or not the engine needs
to be restated.
Typically, you might leave the
engine running for the entire
time that you have any view
visible on the screen, which has
haptic interaction.
Here's the location in the
application where the simple
physics engine let's us know
that the ball has collided with
the wall.
In this example, we want to
generate our haptic and audio
pattern to interactively track
the velocity of the ball.
So the pattern player and its
pattern are created at the
moment they are needed.
This method is responsible for
creating the pattern to be
played in response to the ball
collision.
In here, we will create a
pattern with two events, one
haptic and one audio.
We create a haptic event of type
haptic transient to produce that
impactful feel, and we give it
two event parameters, which
configure the event's sharpness
and intensity, which you've
heard about already, based upon
the velocity of the ball.
Then, we create the audio event,
we type audio continuous, with a
set of event parameters for
volume and envelop decay, also
calculated from the ball's
velocity.
The sustained parameter here
assures us that the intensity of
this event will die off to zero
instead of continuing on for the
length of the event.
We create a pattern containing
these two events, synchronized
in time.
Finally, we create the pattern
player from this pattern and
return it to this layer, back in
the method that responds to the
collision.
The final step is to start the
pattern player at time
CHHapticTimeImmediate, which
indicates to play it back as
soon as possible with minimal
latency.
Notice that the app does not
hold onto the instance of this
player.
Its pattern is guaranteed to
continue playing until it is
finished so the application can
simply fire and forget it.
And that's the basic recipe for
playing your content using a
pattern that is created
programmatically within your
app's code.
Again, because this app is
continuously interactive, we
don't stop the haptic engineer
until the game screen is not
longer visible.
Now, let's take a moment to talk
about one of the most powerful
capabilities of Core Haptics,
Dynamic Parameters.
Dynamic Parameters let's you
increase and decrease the value
of the existing event parameters
for all active and upcoming
events in a pattern as it plays.
Dynamic Parameters take effect
at the time stamp you provide.
You can adjust multiple
different parameters at the same
time or with any arbitrary time
relationship.
You can include dynamic
parameters when you create your
pattern or send them to your
player in real time during
playback.
This allows you to use a single
pattern to generate an infinite
number of haptic and audio
variations by adjusting the
pattern dynamically.
Let's take a look at an example.
In this diagram on the bottom we
have a haptic pattern that was
designed with all haptic event
intensities set to their maximum
value.
First half are haptic
transients.
Second half is a haptic
continuous.
We'd like to reduce the
intensity of all the game's
haptics temporarily, for
example, if a character was
speaking in the game.
I send a dynamic parameter for
intensity with a value of 0.3
that takes effect at time 0.5
seconds.
You can see that it reduced the
intensity of the event at that
time significantly to about a
third of what it was unmodified.
Finally, let's look at another
way to create patterns.
So, what exactly is AHAP.
The Apple Haptic Audio Pattern
is a specification for
describing a Core Haptics
pattern in a text-based format.
It is built from nested key
value pairs, which become quite
familiar to you once you start
working with the classes which
make up the Core Haptics API.
It is the schema for the widely
established JSON file format,
which means you have already
quite a number of different
frameworks, which can read,
write, and edit these, including
such things as the Swift Codable
Framework.
AHAP makes it easy to share and
edit haptic patterns because it
is a format that all developers
can agree on.
Loading your haptic patterns
from external AHAP files allows
you to separate your content
from your application code.
Using the magic of a slide deck,
we're going to create a simple
AHAP file here.
We start with a version string,
which indicates which version of
the system this pattern was
designed for.
Next, we add the key for our
pattern, which will be an array
of dictionaries.
We add our first event
dictionary to our pattern array.
This event has two required key
value pairs, a time in seconds
at which the event should happen
relative to the start of the
pattern and the type of event.
This is a haptic transient event
starting as soon as the pattern
starts.
To this event, we add event
parameters, which will effect
only this event.
These are stored in their own
array of dictionaries.
We add an event parameter to
control the intensity of the
event and another to control its
sharpness.
We can add a second event in the
same fashion.
This one starts at an offset of
0.5 seconds from the first and
is of type Haptic Continuous.
For the event parameters, we use
the same as we had for the first
event.
Events of type Haptic Continuous
and Audio Continuous require an
event duration in addition to
the time and event type.
This duration value is always
specified in seconds.
Here is a visual representation
of the pattern we just created.
You can see the two type of
events, the Haptic Transient at
the very beginning, the
continuous later, with their
relative timing and duration and
their intensity and sharpness
parameter values.
That was a quick tour of AHAP.
This diagram shows a summary of
the AHAP file structure, a
single pattern consisting of an
array of event dictionaries,
optional dynamic parameters, and
optional use of parameter
curves, which are an extension
of dynamic parameters, which you
can read about more with the
information we have on the
website.
You can find a full link to the
AHAP specification on our
sessions page.
Also, on our sessions page,
you'll find a code example that
shows how to create, load, and
play the patterns described by
AHAP files.
This haptic sampler app includes
a range of patterns that
highlight the subtlety, dynamic
range, and audio haptic sync
that's possible with the Core
Haptics API.
Thank you very much and now I'd
like to return the stage to my
colleague, Michael.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Doug.
So, although we covered a lot of
ground today, there is still
much more to discover with Core
Haptics.
Check out the online reference
for details.
Once you're up and running with
the basics of specifying
contents and playing that
content, you'll probably be
wondering about the design
principles for these joint
haptic audio patterns.
You'll be wondering, do the
rules, the guidelines for sound
design carry over to haptic
design?
What are some common pitfalls I
should be aware of?
The good news is that our audio
and haptic design teams have
been doing this for years, and
they've helped put together some
advice and guidance in an
updated human interface
guidelines or HIG for Haptics as
well as in the accompanying talk
in WWDC this year.
Check it out.
So, let's recap.
Today we talked about where
haptics can help you reach for
that next level of emersion and
make your app interactions more
effortless.
Having synchronized and
complementary audio and haptics
together is a particularly
effective combination, but there
haven't been APIs that allows
you to actually do this.
With iOS 13, we now have the
necessary ingredients to create
these rich multimodal
experiences.
We have the vocabulary to
describe haptics and audio
events and a file format, AHAP.
We've got a new performant API,
Core Haptics, which is designed
for low latency and real-time
modulation.
We've put together sample code,
sample patterns, design
guidelines and support from
Apple.
And lastly, you've got an
incredible audience, incredible
hardware, where you can feel
your haptics as you intended.
A huge installed base of taptic
engines that give you the most
powerful, expressive, and
precise haptics hardware
available.
So, please come on down to the
labs on Thursday and Friday
where you can check out some of
these haptics samples that we
showed today and discuss your
own ideas for your apps.
You'll also find all of these
guidelines and reference online
at our sessions page.
I know you're going to have a
lot of fun creating and using
these haptic patterns in your
apps.
We can't wait to hear and feel
what you come up with.
Thank you and good night.
[ Applause ]