[ Music ]
Good afternoon.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to session 225.
My name is Brad Ford.
I work on the Camera Software
Team.
Thank you for hanging in there
till the bitter end.
I know it's been a long day.
We appreciate you staying with
us for The Late, Late Show.
And as 5:00 o'clock sessions go,
this is a pretty good one.
We'll be introducing two
exciting additions to the iOS
Camera Stack today.
I'll spend the first 40 minutes
or so talking about Multi-Camera
capture.
And then I'll invite Jacob and
David up to talk about Semantic
Segmentation.
So first up, Multi-Camera
Capture, or as we like to call
it internally.
MultiCam.
MultiCam is our single-most
requested third-party feature.
We hear it year after year in
the labs.
So what we're talking about here
is the ability to simultaneously
capture video, audio, Metadata,
depth, and photos from multiple
cameras and microphones
simultaneously.
Third parties aren't the only
ones who benefit from this,
though.
We've had many and repeated
requests from first-party
clients as well for MultiCam
Capture.
Chief among them is ARKit.
And if you heard the keynote,
you heard about the introduction
of ARKit 3.
These APIs use front camera for
face and pose tracking, while
also using the back camera for
World tracking, which helps them
know where to place virtual
characters in the scene by
knowing what you're gazing at.
So we've supported MultiCam on
the Mac since the very first
appearance of AVFoundation, way
the heck back in Lion.
But on iOS, AVFoundation still
limits clients to one active
camera at a time.
And it's not because we're mean.
There were good reasons for it.
The first reason is hardware
limitations.
I'm talking about cameras
sharing power rails.
And not physically being able to
provide enough power to power
two cameras simultaneously full
bore.
And the second reason was our
desire to ship a responsible
API.
One that would help you not burn
the phone down when doing all of
this processing power with
multiple cameras simultaneously.
So we wanted to make sure that
we delivered something to you
that would help you deal with
the hardware, thermal, and
bandwidth constraints that are
reality in our world.
All right.
So great news in iOS 13.
We do finally support MultiCam
Capture.
And we do it on all recent
hardware, iPhone XS, XS Max, XR,
and the new iPad Pro.
On all of these platforms, the
aforementioned hardware
limitations have been solved,
thankfully.
So let's dive right into the fun
stuff.
We've got a new set of APIs for
building MultiCamSessions.
Now, if you've used AVFoundation
before for Camera Capture, you
know that we have four main
groups of classes: Inputs,
outputs, the session, and
connections.
The AVCaptureSession is the
center of our world.
It's the thing that marshals
data.
It's the thing that you tell to
start or stop running.
You add to it one or more
inputs, AVCaptureInputs.
One such is the
AVCaptureDeviceInput, which is a
wrapper for either a camera or a
microphone.
You also need to add one or more
AVCaptureOutputs to receive the
data.
Otherwise, those producers have
nowhere to put it.
And then the session
automatically creates
connections on your behalf
between inputs and outputs that
have compatible media types.
So note what I'm showing you
here is the traditional
AVCaptureSession, which on iOS
only allows one camera input per
session.
New in iOS 13: We're introducing
a subclass of AVCaptureSession
called AVCaptureMultiCamSession.
So this lets you do multiple ins
and outs.
AVCaptureSession is not
deprecated.
It's not going away.
In fact, the existing
AVCaptureSession is still the
preferred class when you're
doing single cam capture.
The reason for that is that
MultiCamSession, while being a
power tool, has some limitations
and I'll address those later.
All right.
So let me give you an example of
a bread and butter use case for
our new
AVCaptureMultiCamSession.
Let's say you want to add two
devices-- one for the front, and
one for the back camera to a
MultiCamSession; and do two to
VideoDataOutputs simultaneously,
one receiving frames from the
back camera, one from the front.
And then let's say, if you want
to do a real time preview, you
can add separate
VideoPreviewLayers; one for the
front, one for the back.
You needn't stop there, though.
You can do simultaneous
MetadataOutputs, if you want to
do simultaneous barcode scanning
or face detection.
You could do multiple
MovieFileOutputs, if you want to
record one for the front and one
for the back.
You could add multiple
PhotoOutputs if you want to do
real-time capture of photos from
different cameras.
So as you can see, these graphs
are starting to look pretty
complicated with a lot of arrows
going from a lot of inputs to a
lot of outputs.
Those little arrows are called
AVCaptureConnections, and they
define the flow of data from an
input to an output.
Let me zoom in for a moment on
the device input to illustrate
the anatomy of connection.
Capture inputs have
AVCaptureInput ports which I
like to think of as little
electrical outlets.
You have one outlet per media
type that the input can produce.
If nothing is plugged into the
port, no data flows from that
port, just like an electrical
outlet.
You have to plug something in to
get the electricity.
Now, to find out what ports are
available for a particular
input, you can query that
input's ports property and it
will tell you, "I have this
array of AVCaptureInput ports.
So for the Dual Camera, these
are the ports that you would
find.
One for video, one for depth,
one for Metadata objects such as
barcode scanning and faces, and
one for Metadata items, which
can be hooked up to a
MovieFileOutput.
Now whenever you use
AVCaptureSessions addInput
method to add an input to the
session or addOutput to add an
output to the session, the
session will look for compatible
media types and implicitly form
connections if it can.
So here, we had a
VideoDataOutput.
VideoDataOutputs receive video,
accept video.
And we had an electrical plug
that can produce video.
And so the connection was made
automatically.
That is how most of you are
accustomed to working with
AVCaptureSession, if you've
worked with our classes before.
MultiCamSession is a different
beast.
That is because inputs and
outputs-- You have multiple
inputs now with multiple
outputs.
You probably want to make sure
that the connections are
happening from A to A and B to
B.
And not crossing where you
didn't intend them to.
So when building a
MultiCamSession, we urge you not
to use implicit connection
forming.
But instead use these special
purpose adders,
addInputWithNoConnections, or
addOutputWithNoConnections.
And there are likewise ones that
you can use for
VideoPreviewLayer, which are
setSessionWithNoConnections.
When you use these, it basically
just tells the session: Here are
these inputs, here these
outputs.
You now know about them but keep
your hands off them.
I'm going to add connections as
I want to later on manually.
And the way you do that is you
create the AVCaptureConnection
yourself by telling it, "I want
you to connect this port or
ports to this output."
And then you tell the session,
"Please add this connection."
And now you're ready to go.
That was very wordy.
It's better shown than talked
about.
So I'd like to bring up Nik
Gallo.
Also from the Camera Software
group, to demonstrate
AVMultiCamPiP.
Nik?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Brad.
AVMultiCampPiP is an app that
demonstrates streaming from the
front and back cameras
simultaneously.
Here, we have two video
previews; one displaying the
front camera and one displaying
the back camera.
And when I double tap the
screen, I can swap which camera
appears full screen and which
camera appears PiP.
[ Applause ]
There we go.
Now, we can see here that Brad
is live at Apple Park.
And before I ask him a few
questions, I will press the
record button here at the bottom
to watch this conversation
later.
Hey, Brad.
So tell me how's it going over
at Apple Park?
&gt;&gt; Nik, it's pandemonium here at
Apple Park.
As you can see in front of the
reflecting pool, there's all
kinds of activity happening.
I hear a rushing of water.
It sounds like I'm about to be
drenched at any moment.
I hear wild animals behind me,
like ducks or something.
I honestly fear for my life
here.
&gt;&gt; Well, Brad, that seems
absolutely terrifying.
Hope you stay safe out there.
&gt;&gt; Okay, thanks.
&gt;&gt; Got it.
So now that we finished
recording the movie.
Let's go take a look at what we
just recorded.
Here we have the movie.
As you can see, when I swap
between the two cameras, it
swaps just like we did when
using the app.
And that's AVMultiCamPiP.
Back to Brad.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Nik.
Awesome demo.
All right, so let's look at
what's happening under the hood
in AVMultiCamPiP.
So we have two device inputs:
One for the front camera, one
for the back camera, added, with
no connections, as I mentioned
before.
We also have two
VideoDataOutputs, one for each.
And two VideoPreviewLayers.
Now to place them on screen,
it's just a matter of taking
those VideoPreviewLayers and
ordering them so that one is on
top of the other and one is
sized smaller.
And when Nik double tapped on
them, we simply repositioned
them and reversed the Z
ordering.
Now there is some magic
happening in the Metal Shader
compositor code.
There it's taking those two
VideoDataOutputs and compositing
them so that the smaller PiP is
arranged within one frame.
So it's compositing them to a
single video buffer and then
sending them to an AVAssetWriter
where they are recorded to one
video track in a movie.
This sample code is available
right now.
It's associated with this
session.
You can take a look and start
doing your own MultiCam
Captures.
All right.
Time to talk about limitations.
While AVMultiCamSession is a
power tool, it doesn't do
everything.
And let me tell you what it does
not do.
First up, you cannot pretend
that one camera is two cameras.
AVCaptureDeviceInput API will
let you create multiple
instances for say the back
camera.
You could make ten of them if
you want.
But if you try to add all those
instances to one
MultiCamSession, it will say,
uh-uh.
And it will throw an exception.
Please, only one input per
camera in a session.
Also, you're not allowed to
clone a camera to two outputs of
the same type.
Such as taking one camera and
splitting its signal to two
VideoDataOutputs.
You can, of course, add multiple
cameras and connect them to a
VideoDataOutput each, but you
cannot fan out from one to many.
You're also not allowed-- The
opposite holds true as well.
AVCaptureOutputs on iOS do not
support media mixing.
So all the data outputs only can
take a single input.
You can't, for instance, try to
jam two cameras sources into a
single data output.
It wouldn't know what to do with
the second video since it
doesn't know how to mix them.
You can, of course, use separate
VideoDataOutputs and then
composite those buffers in your
own code, such as the Metal
Shader Composite that we used in
MultiCamPiP.
You can do that however you
like.
But as far as session building
is concerned, do not try to jam
multiple cameras into a single
output.
All right.
A word about presets.
The traditional AVCaptureSession
has this concept of a session
preset, which dictates a common
quality of service for the whole
session.
And it applies to all inputs and
outputs within that session.
For instance, when you set the
session preset to high, the
session configures the device's
resolution and frame rate, and
all of the outputs so that they
are delivering a high-quality
video experience such as
1080p30.
Presets are a problem for
MultiCamSession.
Think again about something that
looks like this.
MultiCamSession configurations
are hybrid.
They're heterogeneous.
What does it mean to have high
quality for the whole thing?
You might want to do different
qualities of service on
different branches of the graph.
For instance, on the front
camera, you might want to just
do a low res preview, such as
640x480, while also
simultaneously doing something
really high quality, 1080p60,
for instance, on the back.
Well, obviously, we don't have
presets for all of these hybrid
situations.
We've decided to keep things
simple in MultiCamSession.
It does not support presets.
It supports one, and one preset
only, which is input priority.
So that means it leaves the
inputs and outputs alone.
When you add them, you must
configure the active format
yourself.
All right, onto the Cost
Functions.
I mentioned at the beginning
that we took our time with this
MultiCam support because we
wanted to deliver a very
responsible API, one that could
help you account for the various
costs that you incur when
running multiple cameras and
lighting up virtually every
block on the phone.
So this is trite but true.
There is no such thing as a free
lunch.
And so this is the part of the
session where I become your
father and I'm going to give you
the Dad Talk.
In the Dad Talk, I will explain
how credit cards work, and how
you need to be responsible with
your money and live within your
means, and, like, such things.
So it's a fact of life that we
have limited hardware bandwidth
on iOS.
And though we have multiple
cameras-- so we have multiple
sensors-- we only have one ISP,
or image signal processor.
So all of those sensors, all the
pixels being -- going through
those sensors need to be
processed by a single ISP.
And it is limited by how many
pixels it can run per clock at a
given frequency.
So there are limiters to the
number of pixels that you can
run at a time.
The contributors to the
HardwareCosts are, as you would
expect, video resolution.
Higher resolution means more
pixels to cram through there.
The max frame rate.
If you're delivering those
pixels faster, it's got to do
more pixels per clock as well.
And then a third one, which you
may or may not have heard of, is
called Sensor Binning.
Sensor Binning refers to a way
to combine information in
adjacent pixels to reduce
bandwidth.
So for instance, if we have an
image here, and we do a 2x2
binning, it's going to take 4
pixels in squares and sum them
into one so that we get a
reduction in size by 4X.
It gives you a reduction in
noise.
bandwidth.
It gives you 4X intensity per
pixel.
So there are a lot of great
things about Sensor Binning.
The downside is that you get a
little reduction in image
quality.
So diagonal lines might look a
little stair stepped.
But their most redeeming quality
is that binned formats are super
low power.
In fact, whenever you use ARKit
with the camera, you are using a
binned format because ARKit uses
binned formats exclusively to
save on that power for all the
interesting AR things that you'd
like to do.
All right.
How do we account for cost?
Or how do we report those costs?
MultiCamSession tallies up your
HardwareCost as you configure
your session.
So each time you change
something, it keeps track of it.
Just like filling up a shopping
cart, or going to an online
store and putting things into
the cart before you pay for
them, you know when you're
getting close to your limit on
your budget.
And you can kind of try things
out, and then put new things in
or move old things out.
You see the costs before you
have to pay.
It's the same with
MultiCamSession.
We have a new property called
HardwareCost.
And this HardwareCost starts at
zero when you make a brand new
session.
And it increments as you add
more features, more inputs, more
outputs.
And you're fine as long as you
stay under 1.0.
Anything under 1.0 is runnable.
The minute you hit 1.0 or
greater, you're in trouble.
And that's because the ISP
bandwidth limit is hard.
It's not like you can, you know,
deliver every other frame.
No.
This is an all-or-nothing
proposal.
You have to either make it, or
you don't.
So if you're over 1.0, and you
try to run the
AVCaptureMultiCamSession, it
will say, "Uh-uh."
It will give you a notification
of a Runtime error, indicating
that the reason it had to stop
is because of a HardwareCost
overage.
Now, you're probably wondering,
"How do I reduce that cost?"
The most obvious way you can do
it is to pick a lower
resolution.
Another way you can do it is if
you want to keep the same
resolution, if there was a
binned format at the same
resolution, pick that one
instead.
It's a little bit lower quality
but way lower in power.
Next, you would think that
lowering the frame rate would
help, but it doesn't.
The reason is that
AVCaptureDevice allows you and
has allowed you since, I think,
iOS 4, to change the frame rate
on the fly.
So if you have a 120 fps format,
and you say, "Set the active
format to 60," you still have to
pay the cost for 120, not 60.
Because at any point while
you're running, you could
increase the frame rate up to
120.
We must assume the worst case.
But good news.
We're now offering an override
property on the
AVCaptureDeviceInput.
By setting it, you can turn a
high frame rate format into a
lower frame rate format by
promising that you will go no
higher than a particular frame
rate.
Now, this is a point of
confusion in our APIs.
We don't talk about frame rates
as rates.
We talked about them as
durations.
So to set a frame rate, you set
one over the duration.
That's the same as the frame
rate.
So if you want to take a 60 fps
format and make it into a 30 fps
format.
You do that by making a CMTime
with 1 over 30, which is the
duration.
And then set that deviceInputs
videoMinFrameDuration override
to 30 fps.
Congratulations.
You've just turned a 60 fps
format into a 30 fps format.
And you only pay the hardware
cost for 30.
I should also mention that there
is a great function in the
AVMultiCamPiP app that shows how
to iteratively reduce your cost.
It's a recursive function that
kind of picks things that are
most important to it and it
throttles down things that are
less important until it gets
under the HardwareCost.
Now next up is System Pressure
Costs.
This is the second-big
contributor that we report.
As you're well aware, phones are
extremely powerful computers in
little, bitty, thermally
challenged packages.
And in iOS 11, we introduced
camera system pressure states.
These help you monitor the
camera's current situation.
Camera system pressure consists
of system temperature.
That is, overall OS thermals.
Peak power demands.
And that has to do with the
battery.
How much charge does it
currently have?
Is it able to ramp up its
voltage fast enough to meet the
demands of running whatever you
want to do right now?
And the infrared projector
temperature.
On devices that support
TrueDepth Camera, we have an
infrared camera as well as an
RGB camera.
Well, that generates its own
heat.
And so that's part of the
contribution to system pressure
states.
We have five of them.
Nominal all the way up to
Shutdown.
When the system pressure state
is nominal, you're in great
shape.
You can do whatever you want.
When it's Fair, you can still
almost do whatever you want.
But at Serious, you start
getting into a situation where
the system is going to throttle
back.
Meaning you have fewer cycles
for the GPU.
Your quality might be
compromised.
And, at Critical, you are
getting a whole lot of
throttling.
At Shutdown, we cannot run the
camera any longer for fear of
hurting the hardware.
So at Shutdown, we automatically
interrupt your session.
Stop it. Tell you that you're
interrupted because of a system
pressure state.
And then we wait for the device
to go all the way back to
Nominal before we'll let you run
the camera again.
That was all iOS 11.
Now, in iOS 13, we're offering
you a way to account for the
system pressure cost up front,
okay?
Instead of just telling you
what's happening right now,
which may be influenced by the
fact that you played Clash of
Clans before you started the
camera, we now have a way to
tell you what the camera cost as
far as system pressure is,
independent of all other
factors.
So the contributors to this cost
are the same as the ones for
hardware, along with a lot of
other ones.
Such as video image
stabilization, or optical image
stabilization.
All of those cost power.
We have a Smart HDR feature,
etc. All of those things listed
here are contributors to overall
system pressure cost.
MultiCamSession can tally that
score up front, just like it
does for hardware, and it will
only account for the factors
that it knows about.
So if you're going to be doing
some wild GPU processing at the
same time, the score won't
include that.
It will just include what you're
doing with the camera.
Here's how you use it.
By querying the
systemPressureCost, you can find
out how long you would be
runnable in an otherwise
quiescent system.
So if it's less than 1.0, you
can run indefinitely.
You're a cool customer.
If it's between 1.0 and 2.0, you
should be runnable for up to 15
minutes.
2.0 to 3.0, up to 10 minutes.
And higher than 3.0, you may be
able to run for a short little
bit.
And, in fact, we will let you
run the camera, even if you're
over 3.
But you have to understand that
it's not going to stay cool very
long.
And once it gets up to a
Critical or Shutdown level, your
session will become interrupted.
So we'll save the hardware, even
if you don't want to.
But hey, it's great.
If you can get what you need to
get done in 30 seconds of
running at a very, very high
system pressure cost, by all
means, do that.
Now how do you reduce your
system pressure while running?
I'm not talking about while
you're configuring your session.
I'm talking about once you're
already running and you notice
that you're starting to elevate
in system pressure.
The quickest and easiest way to
do it is to lower the frame
rate.
Immediately.
That will relieve system
pressure.
Also, if you're doing things
that we don't know about, such
as heavy GPU or CPU work, you
can throttle that back.
As a last resort, you might try
disabling one or more of the
cameras that you're using.
AVMultiCamSession has a neat
little feature that, while
running, you can disable one of
the cameras without affecting
preview on the other.
We don't shut everything down.
So if for instance, you're
running with the front and the
back.
You notice that you're way over
budget, and you're soon going to
go critical, you could choose to
shut down the front camera.
The back camera will keep
previewing.
It won't lose its focus,
exposure, or white balance.
And when you shut down the last
active input port on the camera
that you want to disable by
setting its input ports enabled
property to false, we will stop
that camera streaming and save a
ton of power and give that
system a chance to cool off.
All right.
So I just talked about two very
important costs, hardware and
system pressure.
There are other costs that we
are not reporting.
I didn't want to trick you into
believing that there aren't
other things at work here.
There are, of course, other
costs, such as memory.
But in iOS 13, we are
artificially limiting the device
combinations that we will allow
you to run, the ones that we are
confident will run, and that
will not get you into trouble.
So we have a limited number of
supported device combinations.
Here, I'm listing the ones that
are supported on iPhone XS.
This is kind of an eye chart.
I don't expect you to remember
this.
You can pause the video later.
But there are six supported
configs.
And the simple rule to remember
is that you're allowed to run
two physical cameras at a time.
You might be questioning like,
"Brad, what about config number
one there?
There's only one checkbox."
That's because it's the Dual
Camera.
And the Dual Camera is a
software camera that's actually
comprised of the wide and the
telephoto.
So it is two physical cameras.
How do you find out if MultiCam
is supported?
Like I said, it's only supported
on newer hardware.
So you need to check if
MultiCamSession will let you run
multiple cameras or not on the
device that you have.
There's a class method called
isMultiCamSupported, which you
can right away decide yes or no.
And then further, when you want
to decide, "Am I allowed to run
this combination of devices
together?"
You can create an
AVCaptureDeviceDiscoverySession
with the devices that you're
interested in.
And then ask it for its new
property,
supportedMultiCamDeviceSets.
And this will produce an array
of unordered sets that tell you
which ones you're allowed to use
together.
Next up is a way that we are
artificially limiting the
formats that you're allowed to
run.
The supported formats, last I
checked on an iPhone XS, there
were more than 40 formats on the
back camera.
So there are tons to choose
from.
But we are limiting the actual
video formats allowed to run
with MultiCamSession because
these are the ones that we can
comfortably run simultaneously
on end devices.
So, again, this is a bit of an
eye chart, but I'm going to draw
your attention to groups.
First group is the binned
formats.
Remember low power?
Yay. These are our friends.
At the sensor, you're getting
that 2x2 binning.
So you're getting a very low
power.
All of these are available up to
60 fps.
You've got choices from 640x480
all the way up to 1920x1440.
Next group is the 1920x1080 at
30.
This is an unbinned format.
And this is the same as the one
you would get if you chose the
high preset on a regular
traditional session.
This one is available for
MultiCam use.
The final one is 1920x1440
unbinned at 30 fps.
This is kind of a good stand-in
for the photo format.
We do not support 12 megapixel
on end cameras.
That would certainly do bad
things to the phone.
But we do allow you to do
1920x1440 at 30 fps.
And notice it still allows you
to do 12 megapixel high res
stills.
So this is a very good proxy for
when you want to do photography
with multiple cameras
simultaneously.
Now, how do you find out if a
format supports MultiCam?
You just ask it.
So while iterating through the
formats.
You can say isMultiCamSupported?
And if it is, you're allowed to
use it.
In this code here, I'm iterating
through the formats on a device
and picking the next lowest one
in resolution that supports
MultiCam, and then setting it as
my active format.
Last way that we're artificially
limiting is because we need to
report costs, and those costs
are reported by the
MultiCamSession, we're
specifically not supporting on
iOS multiple sessions with
multiple cameras in an app.
And we're also not supporting
multiple cameras in multiple
apps simultaneously.
Just be aware that the support
on iOS is still limited to one
session at a time.
But of course, you can do -- run
multiple cameras at a time.
Thus concludes the Dad Talk.
Okay?
Write good code.
Be home by 11:00.
If your plans change, call me.
All right.
All right, now back to the fun
stuff.
Synchronized Streaming.
I talked a little bit about
software cameras.
Dual Camera, for one, was
introduced on iPhone 7 Plus.
And it's now present on the
iPhone XS and XS Max as well.
And the TrueDepth camera is also
another kind of software camera
because it's comprised of an
infrared camera and an RGB
camera that is able to do depth
by taking the disparity between
those two.
Now, we've never given these
special types of cameras a name.
But we're doing that now.
In iOS 13, we're calling them
virtual cameras.
DualCam is one of them.
It presents one video stream at
a time and it switches between
them based on your field -- your
zoom factor.
So as you get closer to a 2X, it
switches over to the telephoto
camera instead of the wide
camera.
It also can do neat tricks with
depth because it has two images
that it can use to generate
disparity between them.
But still, from your
perspective, you've only been
able to get one stream at a
time.
Because we have a name now, they
are also a property in the API,
which you can query.
So as you're looking at your
camera devices, you can find out
programmatically is this one a
virtual device?
And if it is, you can ask it,
"Well, what are your physical
devices?"
And in the API, we call this its
constituentDevices.
Synchronized streaming is all
about taking those constituent
devices of a virtual device and
running them synchronized.
In other words, for the first
time, we're allowing you to
stream synchronized video from
the wide and the tele at the
same time.
You continue to set the
properties on the virtual
device, not on the constituent
devices.
And there are some rules in
place.
When you run the virtual device,
the constituent devices aren't
allowed to run willy nilly.
They have the same active
resolution.
They have the same frame rate.
And at a hardware level, they
are synchronized.
That means that they are reading
out.
The sensor is reading out those
frames in a synchronized
fashion.
So that the middle of -- middle
line of the readout is exactly
at the same clock time.
So, that means that they match
at the frame centers.
It also means that the exposure,
white balance, and focus happen
in tandem, which is really nice.
It makes it look like virtually
it is the same camera.
It just happens to be at two
different fields of view.
This is best shown rather than
talked about.
So, let's do a demo.
This one's called AVDualCam.
There we are.
Okay, AVDualCam lets you see
what a virtual camera sees by
showing you a display of the two
cameras running synchronized.
And it does this by showing you
several different views of those
cameras.
Okay, here I've got the wide and
the tele constituent streams of
the Dual Camera running
synchronized.
On the left is the wide.
And on the right is the tele.
Don't believe me?
Here.
I'm going to put my finger over
one side.
Ooh. I'm going to put my finger
over the other side.
See? They're different cameras.
[ Applause ]
All I've done with the wide is
zoom it so it's at the same
field of view as the tele.
But you can notice that they're
running perfectly synchronized.
There's no tearing.
There's no weirdness in the
vertical blanking.
Their exposures and focuses
change at the same time.
Now we can have a little bit
more fun if we change from the
side-by-side view to the split
view.
Now, this is a little bit hard
to see.
But I'm showing the tele-- the
wide on the left and the tele on
the right.
So I'm only showing you half of
each frame.
Now if I triple tap, I bring up
Distance-o-meter, which lets me
change the plane of depth
convergence for the two images.
This app knows how to register
the two images relative to one
another.
So, it lets me play with the
plane at which the depth
converges.
Kind of like with your eyes.
When you focus on something up
close or far away, you're kind
of changing that depth plane of
convergence.
So for instance, up close with
my hand, I can find the place
where the depth converges
nicely.
There we go.
Now I've got one hand.
But that's not right for the car
behind me.
So I can keep going further --
be further away.
There we go.
And that's not right for the car
behind it.
So now I can pull that guy back
too.
And that's Dual Camera
streaming-- Synchronized from
the Dual Cameras.
[ Applause ]
Here's a diagram showing
AVDualCam's graph.
Instead of using separate device
inputs, it just has one.
So it's using a single device
input for the Dual Camera.
But it's sourcing wide and tele
frames in a synchronized fashion
to two VideoDataOutputs.
You'll notice that there is a
little object, a little pill at
the bottom called the
AVCaptureDataOutputSynchronizer.
I don't want to confuse you.
That thing is not doing the
hardware synchronization that I
talked about.
It's just an object that sits at
the bottom of a session if you
desire, which lets you get
multiple callbacks for the same
time in a single callback.
So, instead of getting a
separate VideoDataOutput
callback for the wide and the
tele you can slap a
DataOutputSynchronizer at the
bottom and get both frames for
the same time through a single
callback.
So it's very handy that way.
Now below it, there's a Metal
Shader Filter / Compositor
that's doing some magic.
Like I said, it's knowing how to
blend those frames together.
And it decides where to render
those frames to the correct
places in the preview.
And it also can send them off to
an AVAssetWriter to record into
a video track.
Now recall my earlier diagram.
I showed you a close-up view of
the AVCaptureDeviceInput,
specifically the Dual Camera
one.
The ports property of the Dual
Camera input exposes which ports
you see there.
Anybody see two video ports
there?
I don't see two video ports.
So how do we get both wide and
tele out of those input ports
that we see here?
Is that one video port somehow
giving us two?
No.
It's not giving us wide or tele.
It's giving us whatever the Dual
Camera decides is right for the
given zoom factor.
That's not going to help us get
both constituent streams at the
same time.
So how do we do that?
Well, I'll tell you.
But it's a secret.
So you have to promise not to
tell anybody.
Okay?
Virtual devices have secret
ports.
Okay?
These secret ports, previously
unbeknownst to you, are now
available.
But you don't get them out of
the ports array.
You get them by knowing what to
ask for.
So, instead of just getting an
array of every conceivable type
of port including ports that are
not allowed to be used with
Single cam session, you can ask
for them by name.
So here we have the
dualCameraInput.
And I'm asking for its ports
with source device type
wide-angle camera and source
device type telephoto camera.
It goes, aha.
Those are the secret ports that
I know about.
I'll give them to you now.
Once you've got those input
ports.
You can hook them up to a
connection the same way that you
would when doing your own manual
connection creation.
Then you're streaming from
either the wide or the tele or
both.
Now in the AVDualCam demo, I was
able to change the depth
convergence plane of the wide
and tele cameras with the
correct perspective.
And you saw that it wasn't kind
of moving and shaking all over.
It was just moving along the
plane that I wanted it to.
It was just along the plane of
the baseline.
And I was able to do that
because AVFoundation offers us
some homography aids.
Homography is, if you're
unfamiliar with the term, it
just relates two images on the
same plane.
They are the basis for computer
vision.
They are common for such tasks
as image rectification, image
registration.
Now camera intrinsics are not
new to iOS.
We introduced those in iOS 11.
They're presented as a 3x3
matrix that describes the
geometric properties of a
camera, namely its focal length
and its optical center seen here
using the pinhole camera where
you can see where it enters
through the pinhole and hits the
sensor, and that being the
optical sensor, and the distance
between the two being the focal
length.
Now you can opt-in to receive
per-frame intrinsics by
messaging the
AVCaptureConnection and saying
you want to opt-in for intrinsic
delivery.
Once you've done that, then
every VideoDataOutput buffer
that you receive has this
attachment on it.
CameraIntrinsicMatrix, which
again is an NS data wrapping a
matrix float, 3x3, which is a
SIMDI type.
You'll get -- when you get the
wide frame, it has the matrix
for the wide camera.
When you get the tele frame, it
has the matrix for the tele
camera.
Now new in iOS 13, we offer
camera extrinsics at the device
level.
Extrinsics are a rotation matrix
and a translation vector that
are kind of crammed into one
matrix together.
And those describe the camera's
pose compared to a reference
camera.
This helps you if you want to
kind of relate where the two
cameras are, both their tilt and
how far away they are.
So AVDualCam uses the extrinsics
to know how to align the wide
and the tele camera frames with
respect to one another so it's
able to do those neat
perspective shifts.
That was a very, very brief
refresher on intrinsics and
extrinsics.
So I described them in
absolutely excruciating detail
two years ago in session 507.
So I'd invite you to review that
session if you have a very
strong stomach for puns.
[ Chuckling ]
Okay, the last topic of MultiCam
Capture is Multi-Mic Capture.
All right.
Let's review the default
Behaviors of a microphone
capture when using a traditional
AVCaptureSession.
The mic follows the camera.
That's as simple as I can put
it.
So if you have a front-facing
camera attached to your session
and a mic, it will automatically
choose the mic that's pointed
the same direction as the front
camera.
Same goes for the back.
And it will make a nice cardioid
pattern so that it rejects audio
out the side that you don't
want.
That way, you're able to follow
your subject, be it back or
front.
If you have an audio-only
session, we're not really sure
what direction to direct the
audio.
So, we just give you an
omnidirectional field.
And as a power feature, you can
disable all of that by saying,
"Hands off, AVCaptureSession.
I want to use my own AV audio
session and configure my audio
on my own."
And we'll honor that.
So now comes the time for
another dirty little secret.
There is no such thing as a
front mic.
I totally just lied to you.
In actuality, iPhones contain
arrays of microphones.
And there are different numbers
depending on the devices.
Recent iPhones happen to have
four.
iPads have five.
And they are positioned at
different strategic locations.
On recent iPhones, you happen to
have two that point straight out
the bottom.
And at the top, you have one
pointing out each side.
All of them are omnidirectional
mics.
Now, the top ones do get some
acoustic separation because
they've got the body of the
device in between them, which
acts as a baffle.
But it's still not giving a nice
directional pattern like you
would want.
So what do you do to actually
get something approximating a
front or back mic?
What you do, it's called
Microphone Beam Forming.
And this is a way of processing
the raw audio signals to get
them to be directional.
And this is something that Core
Audio does on our behalf.
Here, we've got two blue dots,
which represent two microphones
on either side of an iPhone.
And the circles are roughly the
pattern of audio that they are
hearing.
Remember, they're both
omnidirectional mics.
If we take those two signals,
and we just simply subtract
them.
We wind up with a figure eight
pattern, which is cool.
It's not what we want, but it's
cool.
If we want to further shape
that, we can add some gain to
the one that we want to keep
before subtracting them.
And now we wind up with a little
Pac-Man ghost.
And that's good.
Now we've got rejection out the
side that we don't want.
But unfortunately, we've also
attenuated the signal.
So it's much quieter than we
want.
But, if after doing all that, we
apply some gain to that signal,
we get a nice, big Pac-Man
ghost.
And now we've got that beautiful
cardioid pattern that we want,
which rejects out of the side of
the camera that we don't want.
Now, this is extremely over
simplified.
There's a lot of filtering going
on to ensure that white noise
isn't gained up.
But essentially that is what is
happening.
And, up to now, only one
microphone beam form has been
supported at a time.
But the good folks over in Core
Audio land did some great work
for this MultiCam feature.
And as of iOS 13, we now support
multiple simultaneous beam
forming.
[ Applause ]
So going back to the
AVCaptureSession, when you get a
microphone device input, and you
find its audio port, that port
lives many lives.
It can be the front, back, or
omni depending on what cameras
the session finds.
But when you're using the
MultiCamSession, the behavior is
rigid.
The first port, the one -- the
first audio port you find is
always for omni.
And then you can find those
secret ports that I was talking
about to get a dedicated back
beam or dedicated front beam.
The way you do that is by using
those same device input port
getters; this time; by
specifying which position you're
interested in.
So you can ask for the front
position or the back position.
And that will give you the ports
that you're interested in.
And you'll get a nice back or
front beam form.
Here's for the front.
And here's for the back.
Now going back to the
MultiCamPiP demonstration we had
with Nik.
We stuck to the video side while
we were showing you the whizzy
part of the graph.
Now I'm going to go back and
tell you what we were doing on
the audio side.
We were running all the time a
single device input with two
beam forms, one for the back and
one for the front.
And we were running those to two
different audio data outputs.
This slide should say audio data
outputs.
And then choosing between them
at Runtime.
So depending on which is the
larger of the two, we would
switch to back or front and give
you the beam form that we
desired.
There are a couple of rules to
know about multi-mic capture.
Beam forming only works with
built-in mics.
If you've got something external
USB, we don't know what that is.
We don't know how to beam form
with it.
If you do happen to plug in
something else, including
AirPods, we will capture audio
of course.
But we don't know how to beam
form.
So we'll just pipe that
microphone through all of the
inputs that you have connected.
Thus, ensuring that you don't
lose the signal.
And that's the end of the
Multi-Camera Capture part of
today's talk.
Let's do a quick summary.
MultiCam Capture session is the
new way to do multiple cameras
simultaneously on iOS.
It is a power tool.
But it has some limitations.
Know them.
And thoughtfully handle hardware
and system pressure costs as
you're doing your programming.
And if you want to do
synchronized streaming, use
those virtual devices with
constituent device ports.
And lastly, if you want to do
multi-mic capture, be aware that
you can use front or back-beam
formed or omni.
And with that, I'm going to turn
it over to Jacob to talk about
semantic segmentation mattes.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, I'm Jacob.
I'm here to tell you about the
semantic segmentation mattes.
So first, I'm going to go
through what are these new types
of mattes.
And then David is going to talk
you through how to leverage Core
Image to work with these new
mattes.
So remember, in iOS 12, we
introduced the portrait effects
matte.
So this was a matte designed
explicitly to provide effects
for portraits.
So we use it internally to
render beautifully looking
portrait mode photos and
portrait lighting photos.
So in taking a closer look at
the portrait effects matte, you
can see how it -- that clearly
delineates the foreground
subject from the background.
So this is beautifully
represented here as a black and
white matte.
So values of one indicating
foreground and values of zero
indicating background.
In iOS 13, we're taking this a
step further with semantic
segmentation mattes.
So we're introducing hair,
-- skin, and teeth.
So taking a closer look at the
hair matte, for instance, you
can see how this is beautifully
separating the hair region from
the non-hair regions.
So we get great hair details
against the background.
And we get great separation
between the non-hair regions and
the hair.
Similarly for the skin regions
where now we have alpha values
indicating how much of a pixel
is of type skin.
So an alpha value of .7, for
instance, would indicate that a
that a pixel is 70% of type
skin.
So we hope these new three types
of -- three new types of mattes
will give you the creative
freedom to render some cool
effects and beautiful-looking
photos.
So a few things to notice-- That
the mattes are half size of the
original image.
That means they're half in each
dimension of the original image.
And that means quarter
resolution.
So another thing to remember is
that that these segmentation
mattes can actually overlap.
So this is particularly true for
the portrait effects matte and
the skin matte that will
inherently overlap.
So these mattes do not come for
free.
So we heavily leverage the Apple
Neural Engines for machine
learning spectral graph theory
and looking a bit under the
hood, what we do is we take the
original size image.
We feed it through the Apple
Neural Engine.
And together with the
original-sized image, we render
these high-resolution,
high-quality, and with
high-consistency segmentation
mattes.
These are then ready to be
embedded into the HEIF or JPEG
files as you know them, together
with the original size, the
image, and the depth as you know
from iOS 11.
So there are two distinct ways
to generate these new types of
mattes.
So one is that they're embedded
in the old portrait mode
captures.
So you can grab them from those
files.
Or even better, you can write
your own capture app and opt-in
to these mattes on capture.
So if you have files with the
segmentation mattes in them, you
can work with them through Core
Image and Image IO.
David is going to talk more
about that.
But first, I'm going to talk you
through how to capture with the
AVFoundation API.
There are four phases we're
going to go through here that
relates to the extension.
So, the first is when we set up
the AVCapturePhotoOutput.
Second is when the capture
request is being initiated in
any point in the life cycle of
your app.
Then two of the callbacks.
So one is when the settings are
resolved for your capture.
And the final one is the one the
photo did finish processing.
So, for full details on this,
please refer to Brad's 2017 talk
on this exact topic.
Yeah, let's go through the how
to set up the
AVCapturePhotoOutput.
So this usually happens when
you're setting or you are
configuring your session.
So you're already, at this
point, done session that begin
configuration.
You've set your presets.
You've added your device inputs.
You add your
AVCapturePhotoOutput.
At this point is when you tell
the API what superset of
segmentation mattes are you're
going to ask for at any point in
life cycle of your app.
When you actually want to
initiate your capture requests,
you need to specify the
AVCapturePhotoSettings.
So this is where you tell the
API, "This is what I really want
in this particular capture."
So, here again, you can specify
all the ones that you already
enabled.
Or you can specify a subset, say
hair or skin.
Now you initiate your capture
request.
So you give it the
AVCapturePhotoSettings.
And you give it the delegate
where you want to have your
callbacks.
So time passes.
And soon after, you will get
that -- get a will begin capture
for callback.
This is when the API tells you
you may have asked for
something, but this is what
you're actually going to get.
So this is important for the
portrait effects matte and the
semantic segmentation mattes.
Because if there are no people
in the scene, you'll actually
not get a matte here.
So you need to check for the
dimensions of the semantic
segmentation mattes.
There will be zero in such case.
More time passes.
The photo did finish processing.
So this is when you get the --
your AV semantic segmentation
matte back.
This is the variable matte in
this case.
So this new class had the same
type of methods and properties
as you know from the portrait
effects matte.
That means you can rotate
according to EXIF data.
You can get your
CVPixelBuffer reference.
Or you can get a dictionary
representation for easy file IO.
So for full walkthrough of the
lifecycle of how to make these
captures, please refer to the
AVCam sample app.
It has been updated with the
semantic segmentation mattes and
will take you through all these
different steps.
I'm going to hand it over to
David, who going to talk about
the Core Image.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Thank you very much.
Now that we've learned how to
capture images with semantic
segmentation mattes, we get to
have some fun and learn how we
can leverage Core Image to apply
some fun effects.
Now, I'm going to have a demo
next.
But I should warn you if --
there's clowns in this image.
So if you have any coulrophobia,
or irrational fear of clowns,
you know, avert your eyes.
All right, so here we have an
image that was captured in
portrait mode on a device.
And what we can see in this
application is that we can now
very easily see all the
different semantic segmentation
mattes that are present in this
file.
We can use the traditional
portrait effects matte.
Or we can also see the skin
matte.
Or we can see my-- the hair
matte or the teeth matte.
And it's also possible to use
Core Image to combine these
various mattes into other
mattes, such as this one I've
synthesized by using logical
operations to create a matte of
just eyes and mouth.
If we go back to the main image,
however, we see this is a
picture of me In Apple Park.
And one of the great things you
could do with semantic -- with
portrait effects mattes is you
could add a background very
easily.
And as you can see here, we can
put me in a circus tent.
And while that really does look
like a circus tent, I don't look
like I fit in.
So now we can use some fun
effects.
For example, we can make it look
like I've got some clown makeup
on.
Or if we want to go a little
further, we can give myself some
green hair.
And lastly, we can use some of
these other mattes to give
myself some makeup.
So that's what I'd like to talk
to you about today is how we can
do these kind of fun effects in
your application.
[ Applause ]
All right, so most of the clown
references are gone now.
So it's safe to look back.
All right, so we're going to be
talking about three things
today.
One is how you create matte
images using Core Image, how you
can apply filters to those
images, and lastly, how you can
save these into files.
So firstly, let's talk about
creating matte images using Core
Image.
There are two ways.
One is you can create matte
images by using the
AVCapturePhoto APIs.
And then, from that, you can
create a Core Image.
So, the code for this is very
simple.
What we're going to be doing is
using the
semanticSegmentationMatte API
and specifying that we want to
do the hair or the skin or the
teeth.
And that returns an
AVSemanticSegementMatteObject.
And from that, it's trivial to
create a CIImage where we can
just instantiate a CIImage from
that object.
The other common way you're
going to want to create matte
images is by loading them from a
HEIF or JPEG file.
These files have a main image
you're familiar with, a typical
RGB image.
But they also have auxiliary
images, such as the portrait
effects matte, as well as the
new mattes that we're talking
about, the skin segmentation
matte, and the hair, and the
teeth.
The code for this is very
simple.
The traditional code to create a
CIImage from a HEIF file is just
to say CIImage and specify a
URL.
To create these auxiliary
images, all you do is make the
same call and provide an options
dictionary, specifying which
matte image you want to return.
So we can specify the auxiliary
segmentation hair matte.
Or if we want, we can get the
mattes for the other semantic
segmentations.
So very simple, just a couple
lines of code.
The next thing we want to do is
talk about how you can apply
effects to these images.
So, I showed a bunch of effects.
I'm going to talk about one in a
little bit of detail.
What we're going to do is we're
going to start with a base RGB
image, and then we're going to
apply some effects to that.
Let's say we want to do the
washed-out clown white makeup.
So, I'm going to apply some
adjustments to that.
Those adjustments, however,
apply to the entire image.
So we want those to be limited
to just the skin area.
So, we're going to use the skin
matte.
And then we're going to combine
these three images to produce
the result we want.
Let me walk you through the code
for it because it's actually
quite simple.
But first, I want to talk about
the top feature requests we've
had for Core Image, which is to
make it easier for people to
discover and use the 200-plus
built-in filters we have.
And that is the new header
called
CoreImage.CIFilterBuiltins.
And these allow you to use all
of the built-in filters without
having to remember the names of
the filters or the names of the
inputs.
[ Applause ]
So [chuckles] it's really great.
So let me show you some code
that will use this new header.
So the first thing we're going
to do is create the base image.
And we're just going to call
image with contents of URL.
And that will produce the
traditional RGB image.
Now, we're going to start
applying some effects.
So the first thing I want to do
is I'm going to convert it to
grayscale.
And I'm going to use a filter
called the maximum component.
And I'm going to give that
filter an input image of the
base image.
And then I'm going to ask for
that filters output, and that
produces an image that looks
grayscale like this.
This doesn't look quite bright
enough to look like clown
makeup.
So we're going to apply an
additional filter.
We're going to say use the gamma
adjustment filter.
And the input to this will be
the previous filter's output,
and then we're going to specify
the power for the gamma
function, and ask for the output
image.
And you'll notice it's now very
easy to specify the power for
the gamma filter.
It's a float rather than having
to remember to use an NS number.
So that's the first part of our
effect.
The next thing we want to do is
start by getting the skin
segmentation matte.
So again, as I described
earlier, we're going to start
with a URL to specify that we
want the skin matte.
However, when we get this image,
you notice it's smaller than the
other image.
As we mentioned before, these
are half size by default.
So we need to scale that up to
match the image, the main image
size.
So we're going to create a
CGAffineTransform that scales
from the matte size to the base
image size.
And then we're going to apply a
transform to the image.
And that produces a new image,
which, as you expect, matches
the correct size.
The next step we're going to do
is start combining these two.
And we're going to use the
blendWithMask filter.
And this is great.
And we use this throughout the
sample I just showed.
We're going to specify the
background image to be the base
RGB image, which looks like
this.
Next, we're going to specify the
input image, which will be the
foreground image, which is the
image which has the white makeup
applied.
And lastly, we're going to
specify a mask image, which is
the image that I showed
previously.
Given these three inputs, you
can ask the blend filter for its
output.
And the result looks like this.
Now, as you can see, this is
just the starting point.
And you can combine all sorts of
interesting effects to produce
great results in your
application.
Once you're done applying these
effects, you want to save them.
And most typically, you want to
save them as a HEIF or a JPEG
file, which supports saving
auxiliary images as well.
So, in addition to the main
image, you can also store the
semantic segmentation mattes so
that either your application or
other applications can apply
additional effects.
The code for this is very
simple.
You use this Core Image API
writeHEIFRepresentation, and,
typically you specify the main
image, the URL that you want to
save it to.
And then the pixel format that
you want it to be saved as.
And the color space you want it
to be saved as.
And what I want to highlight
today is another set of options
that you can provide when you're
saving the image.
So, for example, you can specify
the key semantic segmentation
skin matte.
And specify the skin image, or
the hair image, or the teeth
image.
And all four of these images
will be saved into the resulting
HEIF or JPEG file.
Now there's an alternate way of
getting this result, which is if
you want, you can save a main
image and specify the
segmentation mattes as
AVSemanticSegmentationMatte
objects.
This again, the API is very
simple.
You specify the URL, the primary
image, the pixel format, and the
color space.
In this case, if you want to
specify these objects to be
saved in the file, you just say
AVSemanticSegmentationMattes,
and you provide an array of
mattes.
So, that's what you can do using
Core Image with these mattes.
What I've talked about today is
how to create images for mattes,
how to apply filters, and how to
save them.
I will however, mention that the
sample app I showed you has been
written as a Photos app plugin.
And if you want to learn about
how you can do that in your
application so that you can save
these images not just to HEIFs
but also into the user's photo
library, I recommend you consult
these earlier presentations,
especially the introduction to
the photos frameworks from WWDC
in 2014.
All right, and thank you all
very much.
I really look forward to seeing
what you do with these great
features.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]