[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to making apps with Core
Data.
I'm Scott Perry.
I work on the Core Data team.
And today, we're going to have
an accelerated refresher with a
focus on best practices.
We'll talk about how to get up
and running with Core Data, how
to set up an app's controllers
for success.
And as well as how to use
multiple coordinators and
scaling involving that.
Then we'll wrap up with some
useful testing tips.
So let's get started.
This year, we released a new
sample app.
You may have already seen it in
Session 202.
It starts out with a list of
posts.
We can add a new post by tapping
on the Plus button at the top.
And have a closer look in
DetailViewController.
So you can here -- see here that
this is like a blogging app.
It's supposed to support a
title, content, multiple tags,
as well as multiple media
attachments where you can see
the thumbnails down here.
Let's change the title and then
also add a tag.
Hello.
Great.
We'll save that and head back to
the ListView.
Now let's look at the
TagManager.
You can see here that we only
have one tag, called Demo, and
it has three posts.
So let's add two more, one named
Cats.
And another one named Dogs.
All right, we'll dismiss this
and then go back into our little
toolbar here and add 1000
randomly-generated posts.
Here we go.
And if we go back to our tag
list, we can see Dogs are more
popular than Cats.
It's science.
[ Chuckling ]
So now that we've seen our app,
let's think about the shape of
its data.
The most obvious type is posts.
So we'll start with that.
But since we support multiple
media attachments, that's
another type.
And then we'll also need a tag
type for the same reason.
But since attachments might be
quite large, we'll want to store
that data separately.
After all, the list view only
needs to show thumbnails, so we
can keep the larger data
elsewhere.
Now that we've organized the
shape of our data, it's a pretty
straightforward process to
transliterate it into a Core
Data model using the Model
Editor and Xcode.
Here, we define the members of
our modeled types, as well as
the relationships between them.
For example, the relationship
between attachments and their
data is one-to-one.
That is, an attachment can only
be backed by one image data, and
an image data can only represent
one attachment.
We can also tell our Core Data
in the model that if the
attachment is deleted, then its
image data should be cleaned up
automatically.
This is called a cascade
deletion rule.
Meanwhile, the double arrow
heads signify a too-many
relationship.
Here, a post may have many
attachments, but an attachment
will only ever belong to one
post.
And finally, the post may have
many tags.
Tags may be on many posts.
This is a many-too-many
relationship.
So now, we've defined a managed
object model.
But there are a few more Core
Data types that we need to get
familiar with before we're ready
to build our app.
The model is required by a
PersistentStoreCoordinator,
which as the name implies, is
responsible for managing our
persistent stores.
Most of the time, this is a
database that lives on the file
system, though it's possible to
have many stores at once,
including our own custom made
types that derive from
NSPersistentStore.
Finally, the type that we'll
spend the most time with is the
ManagedObjectContext.
Core Data uses the command
pattern, which is really a fancy
way of saying that you need a
context to get anything done.
If you want to execute a fetch
request, you need a context.
Dirty-to-managed object, the
context knows about it, and will
save it on your command.
Contexts needs to know a
coordinator in order to do their
work.
And as I mentioned earlier, the
coordinator has to know about
the model to make sense of
stores.
The types are all sufficiently
interdependent.
But coordinator provides one
type that encapsulates them all
and represents the entire stack,
called a persistent container.
Using a persistent container, we
can set up a stack in just a few
lines of code, especially if the
model lives in our bundle.
All we need to do is refer to it
by name, and the persistent
container will load it for us.
If the model is generated in
code, or we need to use the same
model with multiple containers,
there's another initializer that
gives us the control we need.
Once we have a container, we
tell it to load our persistent
stores.
The completion block gets called
once per store with a nil error
parameter on success, after
which is time to shift our focus
to managed object contexts.
Contexts provide us with
seamless access to managed data,
and they have a few options that
can make them even more useful
to certain use cases, such as
driving our views.
The first of these is support
for query generations.
Query generations provide a
stable view of the stores data,
allowing safe and consistent
access to objects, even if
they're changed or deleted by
another actor.
To enable this, set the
context's query generation to
current.
Current is a floating meta
version.
The context's query generation
will get pinned to a concrete
point in time on the next access
to the store.
[Chuckles]
Now the context has a stable
view of the data in the store.
What about keeping it up-to-date
with the latest changes?
Well, in the Stone Ages, we
would register for context and
save notifications.
But contexts can also be
configured to keep themselves
up-to-date as changes are saved
by their siblings.
Just that automatically emerges
changes from parent to true.
Okay, so now all of our stack
types are configured to our
liking, how do we use them in
our app?
The most important thing to
remember when using a context is
that all store requests and
interactions with managed
objects must be done in the
context queue.
Background contexts each have
their own queue.
So using them requires the
perform API's.
There's a blocking invariant, as
well as an asynchronous version.
But for truly asynchronous work,
the container offers a
convenience method for
performing background tasks that
creates a background context for
you, and disposes of it
automatically when your block
returns.
So now, how do we add data to
our app?
Well, if we only need a couple
of objects, it's easy to use the
initializer provided by the
managed object sub classes that
were generated for us from our
model by Xcode.
If the subclass is only used by
one model, then it already knows
which entity it represents.
So we can use in it with
context.
Once it's been registered with
the context, then we can
configure it, treating it like
any other instance variable.
Once it's set up to our liking,
we call the contextSave method
to persist it to storage.
But what if we need more data?
Most apps aren't content with
inserting a handful of objects
at a time.
Chances are good, you've got a
server component that sends
objects back by the hundreds or
thousands.
We can save these to the store
one at a time, like we were just
doing for a couple objects.
But it's a lot of boilerplate to
write, not to mention a lot of
resource overhead, to have all
of those in-memory at once.
Enter batch insertions, the
first of many new features we'll
be talking about today.
This code fragment is worth 1000
objects.
And it all starts with your
de-serialized payload in the
form of an array of dictionaries
that have string keys.
These keys need to line up with
the names of your attributes in
the model.
It's okay to leave some out if
they're not required by
something like a unique
constraint.
If you've configured default
values in your model, then Core
Data will use those.
In this case, we have three
dictionaries that each cover a
different set of content and
title attributes.
Going back to our code, we
create a batch insert request
with our array of dictionaries,
as well as the objects model
entity, which is also available
through a method on the managed
object subclass that was
generated for us by Xcode.
Then we execute the request, and
the context returns a response,
which wraps a Boolean, that
tells us if the operation
succeeded.
We're getting a lot for free
here.
And I know you're thinking.
What's the catch?
Well, there's not really many
sharp edges here.
And a lot of this is going to
sound familiar if you've used
batch updates or batch
deletions.
If you have unique constraints
than any existing objects
matching the dictionary will be
pulled out of the database and
updated with new values instead.
Attributes that are optional or
configured with default values
can be omitted from the
dictionary as well.
In the case of updating an
object with unique constraint,
the existing values will not be
changed.
This goes for relationships as
well.
Batch insertions can't be used
to set relationships.
But if a batch insert updates an
existing object due to a unique
constraint, the existing
relationships will be left
alone.
And finally, like the other
batch operations, batch
insertions do not generate a
contextDidSaveNotification, so
you'll have to manage that on
your own.
Now that we have some data,
let's talk about how to satisfy
the needs of our controllers.
The first thing that a
controller needs to be able to
do, is fetch and present data.
So let's look at that.
We use a fetch request to get
objects out of the store.
And just like getting the entity
when we created new objects,
there's a method on the managed
object subclass type generated
by Xcode, that will give us a
preconfigured fetch request.
Adding a predicate to the
request allows us to refine our
results, in this case, so we can
fetch a tag by its name.
Once we've executed the request,
you pluck the results out and
use it to configure our views.
This works well for immutable
data.
But what if the tag's name or
color changes while our view is
up?
Our managed object context will
make sure that the objects'
properties get updated.
But we haven't done any of the
plumbing here necessary to
observe those changes.
As many of you know, managed
objects have supported key value
observations since the dawn of
time.
But the combined framework,
announced this week, makes KVO
much easier to use in Swift.
We get a publisher out of the
object for each property we want
to wire up, and sync the data
flow into an assignment
subscriber on the view.
In the case of the tag's color,
we have an extra map step in the
middle to make the types lineup.
This is all the code we need to
write.
And our ViewsContents will
automatically get updated now
whenever the underlying object
changes.
[ Cheering and Applause ]
Yeah, Combine is great.
And this is barely scratching
the surface of the framework.
It provides a lot more, very
powerful, data flow
functionality.
And to learn more, I encourage
you to check out Session 721.
Now there is a deceit you may
have noticed to this evolution
of our code, and it's that
DetailViews almost never
actually have to fetch the
object that they're presenting.
Usually this kind of view is
pushed from a parent that
configures it with a managed
object.
So normally, the code we'd write
would actually look like this.
The Parent to our DetailView is
usually some kind of list view,
like a Collection or a
TableView.
It also gets its objects from a
fetch request.
But there are a few more
properties that we haven't
talked about that are important
when fetching a bunch of
objects.
The first is the
requestSortDescriptors.
These define the order of the
results.
In this case, we're sorting our
tags by name.
But if names weren't unique
enough, we'd want to add another
descriptor to the end of the
array to break any ties.
Another useful option is
batching.
If our fetch request is going to
match 14 million objects, we
don't want them to all get
loaded into memory at the same
time.
Even if we had the memory for
that, which we probably don't,
it would take a long time.
Instead, we configure a fetch
batch size to tell the context
how many objects should be
loaded from the store at a time.
This makes a big difference on
our app's responsiveness.
But it only works when
interacting with the result as
an MS Array.
Swift's array bridging defeats
this optimization.
So with this knowledge, it's
pretty easy to set up a fetch
request that will fetch all the
tags that we want to see.
But what if one gets changed?
Just like with the properties of
an object that we're displaying
in a detailed view, we need some
way to keep up with the objects
as the career changes.
Luckily, Core Data supports live
queries in the form of a Fetch
Results Controller.
Here we've configured a request
to fetch all posts ordered by
title, 50 at a time.
This fetch request is joined by
a context to configure a type we
haven't talked about yet called
a fetchedResults Controller.
It communicates changes to the
fetch requests through a
delegate protocaller and starts
working as soon as you tell it
to perform the fetch.
Now the Fetch Results Controller
is probably well known to many
of you already.
The delegate protocols change
reporting callbacks include a
method to tell you when changes
are going to begin coming in.
Another to tell you when a
section changed in some way.
And another tell you for each
object that changed, how it
changed.
And finally, a method to tell
you that we're done.
And you know everything.
These methods were originally
designed to line up closely with
UITableView's API, but there was
still a fair amount of glue code
to write matching the career
query results to the table
redrawing.
Furthermore, newer collection
views don't support this change
callback pattern.
So I'm very happy to announce
that the Fetch Results
Controller has learned some new
tricks this year.
The first is a delegate method
that vends an instance of
NSDiffableData SourceSnapshot.
[ Applause ]
It sounds like a lot of you
already know what this type is.
But in case you don't, it's a
new type in UIKit MapKit that
represents the structure of a
collection or TableView.
To use one, you configure your
TableView's data source to be
one of the DiffableDataSource,
also new this year, and feed it
snapshots.
You can learn more about these
types in Session 220.
But for all our purposes, all
you need to know is that you can
use them to keep your collection
views up-to-date in a single
line of code.
And that code fits in the
remainder of the slide.
This used to be a lot of
boilerplate.
All we're doing here is feeding
the Snapshot to the
DiffableDataSource.
The data source diffs the
snapshot against the previous
view state that it has, which is
what makes it a
DiffableDataSource, and then
uses it -- uses the computer
difference to update the view.
[ Applause ]
This has been a long time
coming.
[Chuckles]
The DiffableDataSource Snapshot
works great for wholesale
control of the collection view.
But if you're looking for
something that allows more
customization, or you're
managing the state of types
other than Table and Collection
views, we have another delegate
method you may be interested in.
Like with Snapshots, this method
also gives you a summary of all
the changes to the Fetched
Results in one shot.
But it uses a different type,
also new this year, called
CollectionDifference.
Like the name implies, a
CollectionDifference encodes the
difference between, and can be
generated from, two collections.
Collection diffing in the Swift
standard library was introduced
in Swift Evolution Proposal 240.
But it also exists in
Foundation.
And you can learn more about
that in Session 711.
For our purposes, it's a
one-dimensional type.
So it's only supported when
you're not using section
fetching.
And like the SnapshotDelegate
method, it's mutually exclusive
with the legacy change reporting
methods.
So if you want to drive multiple
things from a Fetched Results
Controller, you should use
multiple Fetched Results
controllers.
So let's take a quick look at
how we can drive a single
section of a collection view
using these differences.
Here's our Delegate method.
And at the very top, we start by
kicking off a batch update, and
looping over the changes in the
diff.
CollectionDifferences support
two kinds of changes, Insert and
Remove.
And two changes of opposing
types may refer to each other
through association.
So in the first case, we have an
insertion that has an associated
removal.
This means the object has moved,
or at least changed.
It may not have actually moved
logical position.
But it doesn't matter, because
the CollectionView is smart
enough to tell the difference.
And as long as we give it the
right original and destination
IndexPaths, then it will do the
right thing.
In the second case, we have an
insert of an object that was not
previously part of the Fetched
Results.
So we tell the CollectionView to
add it.
Finally, we match all removes
that weren't part of an
associated move by filtering for
new associations, and then
remove those from the
CollectionView.
And that's it.
And you'll notice that this code
composes well.
So it's a good candidate for
factoring into a function to
further reduce your boilerplate,
because all the state you need
is the CollectionView and the
difference.
So we think people are really
going to love these new delegate
methods.
But the old ones find new life
this year as well.
The Swift UI framework
introduces first-party support
for declarative interfaces, but
it can't be driven with
Snapshots or diffs.
But this model type can be
derived from our list of Fetched
Results.
Conveniently, the existing
controller,
didChangeContentDelegateMethod
will tell us every time an
updated set of Fetched Results
is ready to update our views.
So it's easy now to apply
Fetched Results to our views.
But what if the results
themselves were difficult to
fetch?
What if we wind up being unable
to build a fetch request to
fetch our data?
Or what if we wind up with
performance problems when we
execute our fetch requests?
At a certain point, the needs of
the controller outweigh the
needs of the model, and we have
to give up some modeling purity
in order to accomplish our
goals.
We do this with denormalization.
We talked a bit about
denormalization during WWDC 2018
in Session 224.
But to recap, denormalization is
when we keep copies of our data,
so access can be more efficient.
This comes with the price of
some additional overhead
maintaining that extra data.
But there are a lot of
circumstances where this
tradeoff is a no-brainer.
Databases indexes are a good
example of this.
In exchange for maintaining a
copy of all of our indexed
columns, were rewarded with
lightning-fast queries when they
depend on those columns.
Looking back at our app,
denormalization is also a useful
way for us to keep track how
many posts are using each tag.
All we need to do is add an
integer attribute to the tag
type named postCount.
Now all we have to do is make
sure that this new postCount
attribute gets incremented every
time a post is tagged and
decremented every time a tag is
removed from a post.
Surely, this code will be bug
free, and our data consistent
forever, right?
[ Chuckling ]
Right? [Chuckles] No, enter
derived attributes.
[Chuckles] Derived attributes
are normalized metadata that's
maintained for you by Core Data.
And it's not just for counts.
There's a bunch of supported
functions that you can find in
the documentation.
Derived attributes are defined
in the managed object model.
The Model Editor in Xcode has a
new interface for this.
Or you can define derived
attributes in code using the new
type,
NSDerivedAttributeDescription.
And finally, derivation
expressions can refer to any of
the properties of an entity, one
level deep.
Derived attributes make
denormalization super easy.
And I'd love to take a moment
now to show you how to adopt
them.
Here we have our app, just as
before.
And if we look in our Tag
Manager here, we can see that we
have three tags and a whole
bunch of posts.
But the view code that's driving
this here is actually traversing
the relationship posts and
getting its count, which faults
in the relationship when we do
it.
So if we had many orders of
magnitude more data, this could
wind up being a performance
problem for us.
So let's fix that by using
derived attributes in our model.
Here's our model editor.
And we're looking at the tag
type right now.
So we're going to go in here and
add a new attribute called
postCount.
And we're going to make that an
integer type.
Now if we go over to the
inspector here, we can see a new
checkbox that says derived.
And if we click it, we wind up
with a space for a derivation
expression.
So here, we're basically moving
our code from the view into
here.
Let's say posts.
@counts, since we're using an
aggregate function.
And then that's it.
If we rebuild, Xcode will
rebuild our managed object sub
classes.
And when we go back to the view,
here, we will find a new
instance variable called
postCount, but it's not
optional.
So we get to delete even more
code by getting rid of this
conditional.
If we build and run, we should
see that nothing changed.
[ Chuckling ]
Except it's way faster and
better.
And we don't have to keep
anything up-to-date.
And sure enough, there it is.
[ Applause ]
The complete set of supported
derivations is available in the
developer docs.
But generally speaking, they
come in four classes.
The simplest is outright
duplication, like keeping a copy
of an attachments identifier and
the image data that backs it.
The other kind of derivation is
a simple transformation of the
fields, such as lower casing a
tag's name, or canonicalizing
some Unicode string.
We just saw an example of an
aggregate function across a too
many relationship in the demo.
And lastly, there are global
functions such as now that take
no parameters at all, which are
useful for things like keeping
track of when an object was last
updated.
So now that our controller is
want for nothing, it's time to
talk about some more advanced
topics and scaling.
PersistentHistory was introduced
in 2017 as a tool to help you do
things like process data added
by an importer, or maintain data
consistency across multiple
active coordinators that are
using the same store.
New this year, we've recruited
fetch requests to make it easier
to look up only the history
you're interested in.
Maybe you want to look up the
changes made by an extension, or
only changes that affect posts,
or only history within a certain
range of time.
I think what is the power of the
fetch request applied to your
PersistentHistory.
Now and
NSPersistentHistoryTransaction
and NSPersistentHistoryChange
are not modeled types, but
they've both sprouted some new
cross-methods to make them work
with fetch requests.
If you squint, the new methods
look similar to what you would
find generated by Xcode for your
managed object subclass types.
They include accessories for an
entity description corresponding
to the type, as well as a method
that produces a new
preconfigured fetch requests
that will return instances of
the type, either
NSPersistentHistoryTransaction
or NSPersistentHistoryChange
when executed.
You configure the fetch request
to the predicate, just like your
fetching managed objects.
But instead of executing the
fetch requests directly against
the context, the fetch request
gets used as part of a
PersistentHistoryRequest.
There's a new convenience
initializer on
NSPersistentHistory
ChangeRequest for creating a new
instance with a fetch request,
as well as immutable property
you can use for post-talk
configuration.
Harnessing fetch requests for
PersistentHistory provides a lot
of granularity to our
application.
But there's still the question
of how do we know when history
gets made?
There are a lot of ways we could
do this, but they all have
drawbacks.
We could pull the store for
changes every so often.
But it's hard to tune that kind
of solution for the right
compromise between wasted effort
and delays before changes are
noticed.
File System monitoring systems
like Dispatch Sources, or
FSEvents, are useful, but they
only work with file back stores,
they're not trivial to adopt.
And it's likely that you'll get
a lot of notifications that
don't actually correspond to
changes being committed to the
store.
So there's still a lot of wasted
effort there.
While useful as Band-Aids, these
approaches are all imperfect
solutions to the problem of
knowing when other coordinators
change the store.
This year, we're introducing a
new kind of notification.
You can think of it as a
cross-coordinator save
notification, but the events are
delivered asynchronously.
So the really like
cross-coordinator change
notifications, we call them
remote change notifications.
To turn on remote change
notifications, there's a new
PersistentStore option called
NSPersistentStore
RemoteChangeNotification
PostOptionKey.
[Chuckles] Set it in your store
description before loading the
PersistentStore into the
coordinator, and the coordinator
will listen for remote changes
to the store.
This option also tells the
coordinator that it should send
remote change notifications
whenever it makes any changes.
So if you want change
notifications, you want to use
NSPersistentStore RemoteChange
NotificationPostOptionKey on all
of your coordinators, not just
the ones that want to consume
changes.
You also probably want to be
turning on PersistentHistory,
because sure.
Remote change notifications can
tell you which store changed
with the NSPersistentStore URL
key in the notification's user
info dictionary.
But if you have
PersistentHistory enabled, it
also includes the new history
token created by that
transaction.
This is especially useful when
combined with the new
PersistentHistory fetching
features that we were just
talking about a second ago.
Because remote change
notifications work kind of like
push notifications, sometimes
changes make it collapse
together if there are many at
once.
And only the last would get
delivered.
If we free launch our app, how
do we know what the current
PersistentHistory token is?
Well, we can get it with a new
method on the persistent store
coordinator for -- called
CurrentPersistent HistoryToken.
All of these new pieces together
can be used to solve puzzles
that weren't possible before.
Not only can we keep up a state
in a timely manner, but
PersistentHistory can also be
pared down to only the changes
that affect our work.
Now I think the best way to show
that to you is with another
demo.
So let's see what that looks
like in our app.
So here, we have a controller
that has the responsibility of
keeping the view context
up-to-date whenever a
coordinator changes.
So we've already registered this
method, storeRemoteChange, to be
called whenever we get a remote
change notification.
Once we're in it, we can pull
out the new PersistentHistory
token that was saved out of the
user info dictionary.
And we'll grab the context that
we want to update and hop into
perform block.
The first thing we want to do to
reduce the PersistentHistory to
only what we're interested in,
is to build predicates based on
the last history token we saw,
which in the case of what our
app just launched, was the
current PersistentHistory token.
And get all transactions before
or equal to the new history
token that we just got in the
notification.
If we're using transaction
authors, and we should, then we
can also create a predicate that
allows us to look at only
transactions that were created
by other coordinators other than
our own.
So then, we can build the
history fetched requests to get
transactions, and configure it
with a predicate that's a
compound and predicate of other
predicates we just built.
So now we're only going to get
transactions authored by other
coordinators between the last
one we saw, and this new one
that just got posted inclusive.
We create an NSPersistentHistory
ChangeRequest, and you configure
it with this fetched requests
you've just built, and then
execute it against the context.
The result is a list of
transactions that we're not
up-to-date on.
So for each of them, we can pull
out the objectIDNotification
userInfo dictionary, and then
pass that into the
ManagedObjectContextMethod
mergeChanges
fromRemoteContextSave, that we
announced in 2017.
Once all the transactions have
been processed, our view is now
up-to-date with the latest
on-disk data in the store.
And it's done in pretty close to
real time since the push
notifications locally are very
fast.
Finally, just to make sure we
don't do any unnecessary work
next time, we remember the last
PersistentHistory token that we
processed.
And now, we're ready for another
remote change notification.
Alright, and that is
PersistentHistory fetching and
remote change notifications.
[ Applause ]
Ah, finally, I wanted to spend a
bit of time talking about
testing.
While hopefully everyone here is
running their tests in multiple
configurations with desanitizers
as well as in release, I wanted
to start some advice that
focuses a bit more on Core Data.
Number one is to know what your
performance goals are.
A Contacts app should be testing
with at least tens of thousands
of objects.
But with that kind of
performance goal, a linear
algorithm might actually be
acceptable on desktop hardware
some of the time.
The Photos app, on the other
hand, should have tested to
validate everything works
correctly when there are
millions of objects.
At that scale, anything slower
than logarithmic time is enough
to hang the app.
And so it's really important to
test like you fly by running all
of your integration tests with
the performance data set.
But the integration tests should
also get running configurations
optimized for detecting and
surfacing other kinds of issues
as well.
For applications using Core
Data, that should include taking
advantage of the Framework's
built-in concurrency debugging.
You can enable it by going into
the Scheme Editor and setting
com.apple.CoreData
ConcurrencyDebugged1 in the
process arguments list.
Running integration tests in
multiple configurations can take
a lot of time.
And likewise, unit tests need to
be as fast as possible.
So it's good idea to use
in-memory stores when test
runtime is important.
In this case, I specifically
mean the SqLightStores in-memory
mode.
SqLightStore has long supported
in-memory mode.
To take advantage of it, in
between creating a persistent
container and loading its
stores, we can pull out the
store description and set its
URL property to point to
dev/null.
This creates an extremely
performance stack.
But this in-memory store can't
be shared between coordinators.
So to validate all that remote
change notification work we just
did, we want to take advantage
of named in-memory stores
instead.
A named in-memory store is
defined by adding a path
component after dev/null.
And any other SqLightStore with
that URL in the same process
will connect to the shared
in-memory database.
Different coordinators sharing
the same in-memory store will
also dispatch remote change
notifications to each other,
which allows us to test all of
our logic.
Finally, use the sanitizers.
Each of these has saved me at
least once.
I've seen the trust sanitizer
instantly identify a one byte
buffer overflow that would have
taken months to isolate.
Similarly, thread sanitizer
understands critical sections
and can tell you about threading
races that are impossible to
reproduce in-house.
And finally, UBSan lets you fix
bugs before they happen by
identifying undefined behavior
that may change in the future.
So today we've seen how to get
set up with Core Data, about how
to take advantage of new and
existing APIs to write compact,
seamless, and robust integration
between the model and controller
layers.
We've explored keeping things in
sync between multiple
coordinators, and we've
characterized our needs and
written tests around them, so we
can ship with more confidence.
As always, we'd love to hear
what you think, so please let us
know using Feedback Assistant.
For more information, please
check out the developer website.
This session's page will include
links to the other sessions
mentioned here today.
We'll see you in the labs
tomorrow.
Thanks for coming.
[ Applause ]