[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and good afternoon
everyone.
Welcome to our session on
Natural Language Processing.
I'm Vivek, and I'll be jointly
presenting this session with my
colleague, Doug Davidson.
Let's get started.
As you know, text is ubiquitous.
You see it everywhere.
If you think of how users
interact with text in apps,
there are two primary modes in
which they interact.
One, is through Natural Language
input, wherein the user is
writing text or generating text
within the application.
For instance, the user may be
typing text on the keyboard
inside the app.
Examples of apps are, for
example, messages where you're
writing text and sharing it with
other people, notes, or any
productivity app where you're
writing text as part of the
application.
The other sort of user
interaction with text in apps is
through Natural Language output
wherein the app presents the
text content to the user, and
the user is consuming or reading
this text.
If you think of an application,
like Apple News, the information
or text is presented to the
user, and the user is reading
this information.
So, both in cases of text input
and text output, in order to
extract actionable intelligence
out of raw text, Natural
Language processing is really
important.
And last year, we introduced the
Natural Language Framework.
The Natural Language Framework
is the NLP workhorse for all
things across all Apple
platforms.
So, we provide several
fundamental NLP building blocks
such as language identification,
tokenization, part of speech
tagging, and so on, and we
present these functionalities
and provide this across several
different languages.
And we do this by seamlessly
blending linguistics and machine
learning so that you can just
focus on building your apps by
using these APIs, and we do all
of the heavy lifting under the
hood.
Now, if you step back and look
at all of these functionalities,
actually if you look at most NLP
functionalities, they can be
broken down into two broad
categories of tasks.
One is text classification.
And the objective in text
classification is given a piece
of text, and this text can
either be a sentence, can be a
paragraph, or a document, you
would like to assign labels to
this piece of text, and these
labels can be sentiment labels,
topic labels, or any labels that
you want to assign.
The other category of tasks by
NLP is called word tagging.
And the task here or the
objective here is given a
sequence of words or what we
call is tokens, we would like to
assign a label to every token in
this sequence.
And this year, we have exciting
new APIs in both text
classification as well as word
tagging.
Let's start off with the first
one, which is sentiment
analysis.
Sentiment analysis is a text
classification API, this is a
new API, and it works this way.
What you do is you bring your
text, and you pass your text to
this API, and the API analyzes
the text and gives you out a
sentiment score.
Now this sentiment score
captures the degree of sentiment
that is contained in your text.
You provide a sentiment score
from -1 to +1, which indicates
the degree of sentiment.
For instance, if you have -1, it
indicates a very strong negative
sentiment, and +1 indicates a
very positive sentiment.
So, essentially we provide the
score and let you calibrate the
score for your application.
As an example, if you had a
sentence such as we had a fun
time in Hawaii with the family,
the API might give you a score
of 0.8, which shows that this
sentence is a positive sentence.
In contrast, if you had a
sentence such as we had a not so
fun time in Hawaii because mom
twisted her ankle, well that's
not positive, so you get a score
of minus 0.8, and you can
calibrate that to be a negative
sentiment.
This is great; how do you use
it?
It's really simple to use.
So those of you who are used to
using NaturalLanguage, this is
extremely easy.
You import NaturalLanguage.
You create an instance of
NLTagger and all that you do now
is specify a new tag scheme.
And the new tag scheme is called
sentiment score.
Once you do this, you attach the
string that you want to analyze
to the tagger, and you simply
ask for the sentiment score
either at the sentence level or
the paragraph level.
Now let's see this in action.
So what we have here is a
hypothetical app.
It's a cheese application.
And as part of this application,
users can do a bunch of things.
They can write notes about
cheese.
They can write reviews, express
their opinions about different
kinds of cheese.
So, even though this application
is about cheese, there's nothing
cheesy about it.
It really deals with the finer
points of cheese.
And what I'm going to show you
here is a user writing a review,
and as the user is writing the
review, the text gets passed to
the sentiment classification
API, we get a score, and we
color the text based on the
sentiment score.
So, let's see, if you were to
type something like fantastic
taste, really delicious, you can
see this is a positive
sentiment.
In contrast, if you said great
at first but a horrible
aftertaste, you see that this is
a negative sentiment, right.
And what you also realize here
is all of this can be happening
in real time.
That's because the API is
extremely performing.
It uses a Neural Network model
underneath, and it's hardware
activated across all Apple
platforms, so essentially, you
can do this in real time.
And we support the sentiment
analysis API in seven different
languages, English, French,
Italian, German, Spanish,
Portuguese, and simplified
Chinese.
I think you're really going to
like this.
[ Applause ]
And, of course, all of this is
happening completely on device,
and the user data never has to
leave the device.
We bring all that power on
device to you.
I like to just spend a brief
moment on language assets.
As I mentioned, the NLP
functionalities are quite
diverse, and we provide this in
several different languages.
Now, for users of our
applications, we make sure that
they always have the assets in
the language they're interested
in.
But for you, for development
purposes, you might be
interested in getting assets on
demand.
This is in fact a very common
request that we've heard from
several of you, and we're
introducing a new convenience
API called Request Assets.
So, you can trigger off a
download for a particular asset
on demand.
You just specify the language
and the tag scheme that you're
interested in, and we'll fork
off a download in the
background, and the next
opportune moment you're going to
get the assets on your device.
So, this is really going to help
you with development and
increase your productivity as
you're building your apps.
So, we talked about text
classification.
Now let's shift our attention to
Word Tagging.
To just refresh your memory,
Word Tagging is a task where
given a sequence of tokens we'd
like to assign a label to every
single token in the sequence.
As an example here, we could
assign a bunch of tokens
different labels.
Timothy is a person name.
Switzerland is a location, and
we have a bunch of nouns here in
this sentence.
Now, this is great.
If you're just looking to do
named entity recognition using
our APIs or part of speech
tagging using our APIs, this is
fine, but there are several
instances where you want to do
something that's more customized
to your task.
You don't want to know just
Gruyere cheese are two nouns,
but what you want to do is you
want to know that it's Swiss
cheese.
Of course, we are building a
cheese application, you want to
get this information out.
But, the default tagger doesn't
have any information about
cheese, so how are we going to
provide this information?
So, we have a new functionality
in Natural Language Framework
that we call a Text Catalog.
A Text Catalog is very simple.
What you do is you provide your
custom list, and this can be a
very large list of entities.
For each of the entities in your
list, you have a label.
In practice, these lists can be
millions or even like, you know,
a couple of hundred millions.
What you do is you pass this
sort of a dictionary into Create
ML, create an instance of
MLGazetteer, and Gazetteer is
just a terminology that we use
interchangeably with Text
Catalog, and what you get as an
output is a Text Catalog.
Now, this is an extremely
compressed and efficient form of
the input dictionary that you
provided.
It's very simple to use.
What you do is you provide this
dictionary.
As I mentioned, we can't show
your million entries here.
We're just showing as an example
a few entries, but this can be
an extremely large dictionary.
Once you do that, you can create
an instance of MLGazetteer, pass
the dictionary, and you write it
out to disc.
It looks really innocuous.
You might be thinking, I'm just
writing a dictionary to disc.
What are you doing here?
Something magical happens when
you make the right call.
Create ML calls Natural Language
under the hood, and Natural
Language takes this very large
dictionary and compresses it
into a bloom filter, which is an
extremely compact
representation, and what you get
as an output is a Text Catalog.
In fact, we've used this to
create effect internally.
We've been able to compress
almost all the person,
organization, and location names
in Wikipedia, which is almost
two and a half million names,
into two megabytes on disc.
Sort of implicitly you've been
using this model.
When you call the named entity
recognition API in
NaturalLanguage, in conjunction
with the statistical model,
you're using this bloom filter
and Gazetteer and now we are
bringing that power to you.
Once you create a Gazetteer or a
Text Catalog, using it is
extremely easy.
You create an instance of
MLGazetteer by specifying the
path to the Text Catalog that
you just wrote out to disc.
You can work with your favorite
tag scheme here.
It can be lexical class.
It can be name type, any tag
scheme, and you can simply
attach your Gazetteer to this
tag scheme.
Once you do this, every time you
have a piece of text, this
customized Gazetteer is going to
override the default tags that
NaturalLanguage provides.
Consequently, you can customize
your application.
Now, if you go back to the
cheese application, and if you
have a sentence such as lighter
than Camembert or Vacherin, you
can use your Text Catalog for
cheese and identify that one is
a French cheese, and the other
is a Swiss cheese, and you can
perhaps hyperlink it and create
a much more cooler application
out of this.
So that's one way to use Text
Catalog in a word tagger in
NaturalLanguage for this
release.
So we've talked about text
classification.
We've talked about word tagging.
But the field of NLP has moved
significantly in the past few
years, and there have been the
without catalysts for this
change.
One is the notion of Word
Embeddings, and Word Embeddings
are nothing but vector
representation of words.
And the other one is the use of
Neural Networks in NLP.
We are delighted to tell you
that we are bringing both these
things to your apps in
NaturalLanguage this year.
So, let's start off with Word
Embeddings.
Thank you.
Before we jump or dive into Word
Embeddings, I'd like to spend a
couple of slides talking about
what an embedding is.
At a conceptual level, embedding
is nothing but a mapping from a
discrete set of objects into a
continuous vector
representation.
So, you have these bunch of
discrete objects.
Each object in this set can be
represented by some sort of a
finite vector.
In this example, we're showing
it with a 3-dimensional vector.
Three dimensions because it's
easy to plot and visualize, but
in reality, these vectors can be
of arbitrary dimensions.
You can have 100 dimensions, 300
dimensions, or in some cases
even 1000 dimensional vector.
Now, the neat property about
these embeddings is that when
you plot these embeddings,
objects that are similar
semantically are clustered
together.
So, in this example, if you had
to look at the paint can and the
paint roller, they are clustered
together.
Or, if you had to look at the
sneakers and the high heels,
they are clustered together.
So, this is a very neat property
of embeddings.
And this property of embeddings
is not only proof of words but
actually across several
different modalities.
You can think of image
embeddings.
When you take an image and pass
it through a VGG network or any
sort of a convolution Neural
Network, the feature that you
get as an output is nothing but
an image embedding.
Similarly, you can have
embeddings for words, for
phrases, and when you work with
recommendation systems where
you're working with song titles
or product names, they are
represented by using a vector.
So, they are nothing but just
embeddings.
So, in summary, embedding is
nothing but a mapping from a
string into a continuous
sequence of numbers or a vector
of numbers.
We've actually used these
embeddings very successfully in
iOS 12, and let me tell you how
we use this in Photos.
In Photos search, when you type
a particular term that you're
looking for, maybe pictures of a
thunderstorm, what we do
underneath the hood is all the
images in your photo library are
indexed by using a convolution
Neural Network.
And the output of the
convolution Neural Network is
fixed to some certain number of
classes, perhaps to 1000 classes
or 2000 classes.
Now, if your convolution Neural
Network doesn't know what
thunderstorm is, you will never
find the pictures that were
indexed because they didn't have
the term thunderstorm, but with
the power of Word Embeddings, we
know that thunderstorm is
actually related to sky and
cloudy, and those are labels
that your convolution Neural
Network understands.
So, by doing this, in iOS 12,
you're able to enable fuzzy
search in Photos search by using
Word Embeddings.
So, as a consequence of this,
you can find the images through
the power of Word Embeddings.
In fact, it can be applied to
any search application.
If you want to do fuzzy search
and you have a string, you can
use the Word Embedding to get
neighbors related to that
original word.
Having said that, what can you
do with an embedding?
There are four primary
operations that you can do with
Word Embeddings.
One is, given a word, you can
obviously get the vector for
that word.
Given two words, you can find
the distance between two words
because for each of those words,
you can look at the
corresponding vectors.
So, if I say dog and cat and ask
for the distance, I'm going to
get a distance, and that
distance is going to be pretty
close to each other.
If I say dog and a boot, those
are fairly distant in the
semantic space, and you're going
to get something that's much
higher distance.
The third thing that you can do
is get the nearest neighbors for
a word, and this probably is by
far the most popular way of
using word embeddings, and the
Photos search application that I
just showed you was doing
exactly that.
Given a word, you're looking for
nearest neighbors of a word.
Last but not the least is you
can also get the nearest
neighbors for a vector, so let's
assume that you have a sentence,
and you have multiple words in
the sentence, and for each of
the words in the sentence, you
can get the word embedding, you
can sum it up.
So what you get is a new vector,
and given that vector, you can
ask for all the words that are
close to that vector.
That's a neat way of using Word
Embeddings too.
So a lot of stuff about Word
Embeddings, but the most
important thing is we are
providing this easy for you to
use on the OS.
So, we're delighted to tell you
that these Word Embeddings come
on the OS in seven different
languages for you to use, and
all of the functionalities I
just mentioned, you can use it
with one or two lines of code.
So, we're supporting it in seven
languages from English, Spanish,
French, Italian, German,
Portuguese, and simplified
Chinese.
Now, this is great.
The OS embeddings are generally
framed on general corpora, large
amounts of text, billions and
billions of words.
So, they have a general notion
of what a relationship with a
particular word is.
But many a time, you want to do
something that's even more
custom.
So, perhaps you're working with
different sort of domains,
something in the medical domain
or the legal domain or the
financial domain.
So, if your domain is very
different, and the vocabulary of
words that you want to use in
your application is extremely
different, or maybe you just
want to train a word embedding
for a language that's not
supported on the OS, how do you
do that?
We have a provision for that
too.
You can use and bring custom
word embeddings.
So, those of you who are
familiar with word embeddings
and have seen this field evolve,
there are many third-party tools
to train your own embedding such
as word2vec, GloVe, fasttext.
So, you can bring your own text
or you can even use a Custom
Neural Network that you train
in Keras TensorFlow or PyTorch.
So, go from raw data, you can
build your own embeddings, or
you can go to any one of these
websites and download their
pretrained word embeddings.
Now, the challenge there is when
you download any of these
embeddings, they are very, very
large.
They're 1 gigabyte or 2
gigabytes in size.
But you want to use it in your
app in a very compact and
efficient way, and we do just
that.
When you bring these embeddings
from third-party applications
and they're really large, we
automatically compress them into
a very compact format, and once
you have this compact format,
you can use it just like how you
use the OS embeddings.
But to tell you how you use
these embeddings, both the OS as
well as the custom, I'm going to
turn it over to Doug, who is
going to do a demo and then walk
you through the rest of the
session.
Over to you, Doug.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
So, let's go over to the demo
machine here, and let's see some
of this in action.
So, the first thing I've done
here is to write a very tiny
demo application that helps us
explore Word Embeddings.
So, I type a word in here, and
it shows us the nearest
neighbor, nearest neighbors of
that word in embedding space.
Let's start by using the
built-in OS Word Embeddings for
English.
So, I type a word like chair,
and we see the nearest neighbors
of chair are words that are
similar in meaning to chair,
sofa, couch, and so forth, or I
could type in something like
bicycle.
And the nearest neighbors, bike
and motorcycle and so forth,
these are words that are close
in meaning to bicycle or maybe
book.
And we get words that are
similar in meaning to book.
So, what we can see from this,
we can understand that the
built-in OS Word Embeddings
represent the ordinary meanings
of words and the language and
recognize the similarity of
meanings as expressed in general
text in that language.
But, of course, what I'm really
interested in here is knowing
what do these embeddings
understand about cheese, because
we're dealing with a cheese
application here.
So, let me type in a cheese
word.
And take a look here, and what I
can see right away is that these
built-in embeddings do know what
cheese is, but I'm very
disappointed.
I can see these embeddings know
nothing about the finer points
of cheese.
Otherwise, they would never have
put these particular cheeses and
cheese-related things together.
They don't go together at all.
What I really want here is
something that understands the
relationships of cheeses.
So, I've taken the opportunity
to train my own custom cheese
embedding that puts cheeses
together based on their
similarity.
And let's switch over to it.
So, here are the neighbors of
cheddar in my own custom cheese
embedding.
This is much better.
We can see that it puts near
cheddar, it puts some fine
cheeses that are similar to
cheddar in texture like our
Lancashires, Double Gloucester,
and Cheshire.
So this is something that we can
use in our cheese application.
So, let's take a look at the
cheese application now.
So, I've been trying out some
ideas for our cheese
application.
Let's see how this looks.
So, when the user types
something in, the first thing
I'm going to do is get a
sentiment score on it to see and
check does this represent a
sentence with a positive
sentiment, and if it does, then
I'm going to go through it using
my tagger using, of course, our
custom cheese Gazetteer to see
whether the user mentioned any
cheeses in it.
And so I'll look for a cheese,
and if the user did mention a
cheese, then I'm going to pass
it through my custom cheese
embedding to find similar
related cheeses.
Sounds plausible?
Let's try it out.
Let's bring up our cheese
application, and so I visited
the Netherlands last year, and I
fell in love with Dutch cheeses,
so I'm going to tell my app
that.
So, this is a certainly a
sentence with a positive
sentiment, and it does reference
a particular cheese.
So, I go through, and now my app
can make recommendations of
cheeses that are similar to the
one that I mentioned here.
So, this shows of the power of
Word Embeddings, but even more
than that, it shows how the
natural, various NaturalLanguage
APIs can come together for
application functionality.
[ Applause ]
So, now, let's go back to the
slides, and I want to review
briefly how this looks in API.
So, if you want to use a
built-in OS Word Embedding, it's
very simple.
All you do is ask for it.
Ask for the word embedding for a
particular language, and we'll
give it to you.
Once you have one of these NL
embedding objects, there are
various things you can do with
it.
You can, of course, get the
components, the vector
components, corresponding to any
particular entry.
You can find the distance
between two words, be it short
or far, in embedding space.
And as we saw in our cheese
application, you can go through
and find the nearest neighbors
of any particular item in this
embedding space.
If you want to use a custom word
embedding, then to create it,
you go over to Create ML, and
you need, of course, all of the
vectors that represent your
embedding.
I can't really show them all to
you right here in the slide
because there are 50 or 100
components long, but here's an
example of what they look like.
In practice, you're probably
going to be bringing them in
from a file using the various
Create ML facilities for loading
data from files.
And then you just create a word
embedding object from it and
write it out to disc.
Now, what's going on when you do
this?
Well, in practice, these
embeddings tend to be quite
large, hundreds of dimensions
times thousands of entries.
It could be huge, and they could
take a lot of space on disc,
naively and be expensive to
search.
But when you compile them into
our word embedding object, then
under the hood what we do is we
use a product quantization
technique to achieve a high
degree of compression, and we
add indexes so you can do fast
searching for nearest neighbors,
as you saw in our examples.
Just try this out.
We took some very large
embeddings that are readily
available as open source.
This is some GloVe and fasttext
embeddings.
These are a gigabyte or 2
gigabytes in uncompressed form.
When we put them into our NL
embedding compressed format,
they're only tens of megabytes,
and you can search through them
for nearest neighbors in just a
couple of milliseconds.
Closer to home--
[ Applause ]
For an example, closer to home,
Apple does a lot with podcasts,
so our podcast group, we talked
to them, and they, as it
happens, have an embedding for
podcasts that represents the
similarity of various podcasts,
one to another.
So, we thought we'd try it out
and see what would happen if we
took this embedding and put it
into our NL embedding format.
So this embedding represents
66,000 different podcasts, and
source form is 167 megabytes,
but we compress it down to just
3 megabytes on disc.
So what NL embedding does is it
makes it practical to include
these embeddings and use them on
, on the device, in your
application.
All right.
So, next I want to switch and
talk about another thing that's
related to Word Embeddings, and
that is Transfer Learning for
Text Classification.
So, I'd like to start by talking
a little bit about what we do,
what it is we do when we train a
text classifier.
So, when we're training a text
classifier, we give it a set of
examples for various classes.
You can pass that in to Create
ML.
Create ML will call on Natural
Language.
We will trained a classifier and
out will come a Core ML model.
And what we hope is that these
examples will give sufficient
information about the various
classes that the model can
generalize to classify examples
that it hasn't seen.
And, of course, we have already
shipped this last year, and we
have algorithms for training
these models, most notably our
standard algorithm is what we
call the maxEnt algorithm, based
on logistic compression.
It's very fast, robust, and
effective.
But one thing about it is it
doesn't know anything except
what it learns from the training
data that you give it.
So, you have to make sure that
the training material you give
it covers essentially all of the
sort of things that you expect
to see in examples in practice.
So, in some sense, we've done
the easy part of creating the
algorithm and left you the hard
part of producing the training
data.
But, wouldn't it be nice if we
could take advantage of prior
knowledge of the language and
then maybe use that in
conjunction with some smaller
amount of training material that
you have to provide in order to
train a model that would combine
these two and so hopefully
understand more about the
examples it's going to see with
less in the way of training
material.
And so this is the promise of
Transfer Learning.
This is a highly active research
area in NLP, and I'm happy to
say we have a solution for this
that we're delivering now.
Again, NaturalLanguage trains a
model, and the outcome is a Core
ML model.
But how are we going to
incorporate previous knowledge
of the language?
Where are we going to get it?
Well, Word Embeddings provide a
great deal of knowledge of the
language.
In particular, they know quite a
bit about the meaning of words.
So, our solution uses Word
Embeddings, takes the training
material you provide, puts them
through the Word Embeddings, and
then on top of that we train a
Neural Network model, and that
is what we provide as a Transfer
Learning Text Classification
model.
Now, there's a lot of work going
on here, but if you want to use
it, all you have to do is ask
for it.
You just change one parameter in
the specification of the
algorithm that you want when
training a Transfer Learning
model.
Now, there are a few different
options here.
So, the first one, most obvious
is, you can use the built-in OS
Word Embeddings that represent
the ordinary meaning of words,
and if you have a custom Word
Embeddings, you could also use
that as well.
We know that a given word can
have very different meanings,
depending on how it appears in
the context of a sentence.
So, for example, Apple in these
two sentences has very different
meanings.
So, what we'd like is to have an
embedding for Transfer Learning
purposes that gives different
values for these words depending
on their meaning and context.
And, of course, an ordinary word
embedding, it just maps words to
vectors, and it will give the
same value for the word no
matter how it appears.
But, what we have done is
trained a specialized embedding
that gives different values for
the words depending on their
meaning and context.
Now, to give you some idea of
how fast the field is moving,
this is something that was just
researched a year ago, and we're
delivering it now.
And again, if you want to use
it, you just ask for it.
You specify the dynamic
embedding.
So, the dynamic embedding
changes the value of the
embedding for words depending on
their sentence context, and this
is a very powerful technique for
doing Transfer Learning for Test
Classification.
Well, let's see it.
All right.
So, here what I have is some
fairly standard code for
training a Text Classifier using
Create ML, and what I'm going to
be training, this is based on a
dataset using an Open Source
encyclopedia called DBpedia.
It has short entries about many
different topics.
Some of them are people,
artists, writers, plants,
animals, and so forth, and the
task here is to determine from
the entry what the
classification is, whether it's
a person or writer or artist,
etc.
And there are 14 different
classes here, and I'm going to
try and train a classifier using
only 200 examples.
So, it's a fairly difficult task
here, and so let's just-- let's
try it with our existing maxEnt
model.
So, I'll fire it off.
It starts, and it's done.
Very fast and easy, and on our
training-- if we take a look at
our performance on our test set,
we see it got 77% accuracy.
That's okay, but can we do
better?
Well, let's make one little
change to our code here.
Instead of using the maxEnt
model, we're going to use the
Transfer Learning with Dynamic
Embeddings, and let's start it.
Now, as I mentioned, this is
training a Neural Network model,
so it takes a little bit longer,
so while it's training, let's
just take a little closer look
at the data that we're training
on.
As it turns out, when you're
training Neural Network models,
it's important to pay close
attention to the data that you
train it on.
So, notice that this data is a
random sample across the various
classes, and I've arranged it so
that they're roughly the same
number of instances for each
class.
It's a balanced set.
This is our training set.
In addition, we also have a
separate validation set that is
similarly a random sampling of
examples across classes, maybe
not quite as large as the
training set, but balanced.
And the validation set is
particularly important in this
kind of training.
Neural Network training has a
tendency to over fitting, where
it more or less memorizes the
training material and doesn't
generalize.
The validation set helps keep it
honest and make sure it
continues to generalize.
And then, of course, we also
have a separate test set that's
similarly randomly sampled and
balanced, and of course there
can't be any overlap between the
training validation test sets.
That would be cheating.
And the test set we need to see
how well we're doing, in
particular in this case, we need
it so that we can see whether
the Transfer Learning model is
doing better than our maxEnt
model.
And it looks like it's finished
now, so let's take a look and
see.
And we can see here that the
Transfer Learning has achieved
an accuracy of 86.5%, much
better than our maxEnt model.
[ Applause ]
So, how does this apply to our
cheese application?
Well, what I've done is I've
taken my cheese tasting notes,
and I labeled them each by the
cheese that they referred to,
and I use that to train a cheese
classifier model.
And so my cheese classifier
model can take a sentence and
try to classify it and determine
which cheese it most closely
refers to.
And I put that into my cheese
application, and so, what I'm
going to do in the cheese
application is if the user
didn't refer to a specific
cheese, then I'm going to try to
figure out which cheese they
might want.
And all I do is ask the model
for the label for the text.
And very simple.
Let's try it out.
So, I'm going to type in
something here.
And we'll let the cheese
classifier work on it.
And so the cheese classifier
determined that this is most
closely resembling Camembert,
and then my cheese embedding has
recommended some other cheeses
that are very similar, Brie and
so on and so forth.
Or, maybe I say--
Something firm and sharp and it
recognizes that as resembling
cheddar, and it recommends some
similar cheeses to us.
[applause]
So, this again shows us the
power of Text Classification in
combination with the other
NaturalLanguage APIs.
So, I'd like to finish off with
some considerations for the use
of the Text Classification.
First of all, we need to note
the languages that are supported
for transfer learning, either
via Static Embeddings or the
special Dynamic Embeddings that
take context into account.
And then I want to talk a bit
about, more about data.
So, the first commandment when
dealing with data is that you
need to understand the domain
you're working with.
What kind of text do you expect
to see in practice?
Is it going to be sentence
fragments, full sentences,
multiple sentences, and make
sure that your training data is
as similar as possible to the
text that you expect to see and
try to classify in practice.
And covers as much as possible
of the variations that you're
likely to see when you encounter
this text in your application.
And, as we saw in our DBpedia
example, you want to make sure
that you have randomly sampled
as much as possible distinct
sets for training, for
validation, and tests.
This is basic data hygiene.
And how do you know which
algorithm will be best for your
case?
Well, in general, you'll have to
try it, but some guidelines.
You can start with the maxEnt
classifier.
It's very fast.
It will give you an answer.
But what does a maxEnt
classifier do?
A maxEnt classifier works by
noticing the words that are used
most often in the training
material.
So, for example, if you're
trying to train positive and
negative, it might notice words
like love and happy are
positive, hate and unhappy
negative.
And if the examples you
encounter in practice use these
same words, then the maxEnt
classifier is going to work very
well.
What the Transfer Learning does
is it notices the meaning of
words.
So if the examples you encounter
in practice are likely to
express a similar meaning with
different words, then that is
the case where Transfer Learning
shines and it's likely to do
better than the simple maxEnt
model.
So, to summarize, we have new
APIs available for Sentiment
Analysis, for Text Catalogs with
MLGazetteer, for Word Embeddings
with NL embedding, and we have a
new type of text classification,
a particularly powerful new type
that takes advantage of Transfer
Learning.
I hope you'll take advantage of
these in your applications, and
there's much more information
available online, and there are
other related sessions that you
can take a look at.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]