[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name is Frank Doepke and I'm
going to talk to you about Text
Recognition in the Vision
Framework.
Now, for those of you who are
familiar with Vision, you'll
know that we already had the
VNDetectRectangleRequest that
tells you where there is text in
an image.
For some mysterious reason, we
always got the question, "What
is the text?"
So, we needed a little bit of
extra code.
It arrayed over your results,
and then you need to train
basically a Core ML model that
actually can read this stuff.
Next, you run the Core ML model.
You filter out the bad
characterization.
You take all these characters,
put them into a string, and then
come up with some heuristics
that actually form the really
sentences and words out of this.
So now you know why we need a
full session to talk about Text
Recognition.
But today, I want to make this
easier.
And we have something new, and
that is the
VNRecognizedTextRequest.
And just that little bit of text
that you see here [applause],
this allows you to take you from
an image like this into
recognized text like this.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Okay, so what are we going to
cover today?
First we're going to talk a
little bit about how Text
Recognition works.
We have a number of example
applications and they're also
all attached to the session so
you can download the sample
code.
And last but not least, we're
going to go over some best
practices on how to use our Text
Recognition.
So, how does Text Recognition
work in Vision?
We have two paths to choose
from.
The fast path, and the accurate
path.
The fast path works just
actually on what Text Detector
did before by finding characters
and then advance a small machine
learning model to actually
recognize those characters,
character by character.
The accurate path, on the other
hand, uses a state-of-the-art
neural network to recognize text
by first finding it in terms of
strings and full lines.
And then recognizing it as words
and sentences.
So, it requires a deep learning
model which will take a little
bit more time to compute, but it
reads much more as we humans
actually read our text.
We don't read character by
character.
We look at words.
And this helps us to get about,
you know, there are certain
characters that might be a bit
like, you know, hard to read.
And this is also the same reason
when we try to proofread our
text, that we don't see typos,
because our brain interpolates
over some of these mistakes.
And we use the same kind of
technique here in the accurate
path to help us get past some of
the recognition errors.
Both stages afterwards can
actually go through a language
correction phase which helps us
to again eliminate some of the
typical misreadings.
And out we get our results.
So, this is a complex machinery,
you might think.
But all of this happens on the
device.
[ Applause ]
So, let's look at what the
difference is between fast
versus accurate.
So, I did a little screen
recording of reading this
document.
And I did this on a relatively
old MacBook Pro.
So, the times that you see are
not necessarily representative,
but I wanted to give you a feel.
So let's look first at how fast
is fast.
And we're done.
Now, let's look at how long does
accurate takes.
And you see the progress?
It took a little bit longer.
And as I said, the numbers are
not representative for
everything, but it gives you a
feel of the delta.
The other part that you see is
that accurate is actually much
better in reading the whole
text.
The fast path has a little bit
of a problem with the stylized
font on the top.
So there are some tradeoffs
between these two paths.
Let's look at these tradeoffs.
The fast path is meant for
real-time reading and it's
optimized for that.
But the accurate path is more
likely to be used in an
asynchronous fashion.
In terms of memory budget, the
fast path also uses less memory
because it doesn't need to run a
large neural network.
But when it comes to rotated
text or perspectively misaligned
text, the accurate path gives
you much broader support.
And when it comes to style or
fonts and as you saw already in
the example, when it comes to
stylized text, there's again
much broader support in the
accurate path.
And last but not least, when it
comes to the real reading of
natural language, the accurate
path is what we would recommend
because it performs best on that
part.
So, how do you choose between
those two?
The use cases that you have are
the important part that will
actually drive how you want to
use the request.
You need to think about a few
things.
So, what is my input?
Am I working off a camera or do
I already have images from my
photo library that I want to
process?
What are my processing
constraints?
So, how much time can I spend on
the request?
And how much memory do I have
available?
Some of the processes might be a
bit more memory constrained.
And last but not least, what am
I going to do with the results?
Am I using them to transcribe?
Or for search?
Or just do a, perform an action
based on what I read through the camera.
So, let's talk about the camera
capture in a few more details.
The camera capture can be used
as a live capture.
So, you actually want to use now
the string reading live and keep
up with the frame rate.
In this case, the fast path is
most likely the one that you
want to use.
But there's also the way of
opportunistic capture.
What do I mean with that?
It's like for instance you take
a photo and there's text
somewhere in the photo and you
want to process that.
So, you don't need to keep up
with the frame rate of the
camera, but you actually want to
use this to read the text and
the accurate path will most
likely give you better results.
One more thing to think about
when we talk about camera is I
need to design which resolution
do I want to use in my
application, and the text size
will actually drive this.
If for some mysterious reason
you want to read the fine print
of a legal document where you
might actually have to increase
the resolution of the camera, or
when you read a billboard with
large text, you can actually
turn down the resolution and
work with less memory it
actually will be faster as well.
Now, when it comes to post
processing, so we already have
the image in a file.
Most likely you want to favor
the accurate path, because you
can actually use the better
accuracy and speed is not as
important.
Next, let's talk a little bit
about language processing.
As I mentioned, language
processing is one of the stages
that you can use in the text
recognition.
It helps us to get past some of
the typical missed readings that
can happen when you read the
text, but it can also get in the
way.
When I want to read codes or a
serial number, think of the
serial number like C001 that can
very easily be misconstructed as
cool.
Also, this language correction
does not come for free.
It does take some processing
time and of course it uses a
little bit of memory.
So now that we have some of the
fundamentals out of the way,
let's talk actually how we can
perform Text Recognition.
Everything in Vision starts with
an image RequestHandler.
Then I create my request.
I set my completionHandler on
it; that's where actually I deal
with the results.
Then I set the recognitionLevel.
As I said, I can switch between
the fast and accurate.
Next, I would recommend that you
actually set the revision.
The revision, of course here
there is only one, but down the
line we will come up with
improved versions and you might
have tuned your algorithm to a
specific behavior that we have.
And if you otherwise don't
specify a revision, you will
always get the latest and that
might appear with some
surprises.
So, I would recommend getting to
the behavior of using a
revision.
And I can turn on and off the
language correction and last but
not least, of course, I need to
perform my request.
When we perform it, and we get
our results back.
These come back as
VNRecognizedTextObservations,
and we get them pretty much in
terms of lines and strings that
we find.
So, we need to iterate all of
these results.
And when we want to get the text
out, we actually have multiple
candidates.
We'll talk about some of the
candidates later.
Here to make it simple, I just
get my top candidate and I have
my text.
And I can get to the bounding
box which actually helps me
where all this text is on screen
or in the image, the image
onscreen.
But now when I want to use
search, and so for instance the
user types in a word that you
read in the document, and we
want to find actually where is
this again in the image, I can
actually ask the candidate for
where is the bounding box for
this string that I actually see
in my results.
Now, after all this theory,
let's go into some example, and
we want to do some real-time
Text Recognition.
So, that's when we want to use
the fast path.
The use case here is I want to
read something like a serial
number or a code.
The serial number that I'm using
here actually is a phone number
because it's the easiest for
everybody, easiest to understand
here.
And I want to read them really
just like a barcode reader.
With that, I can constrain
actually how the camera should
actually look for the text, but
interactivity is key because it
should be snappy.
It should be fast, so that the
user can be guided, and it reads
the text right away.
So, that's why I'm choosing the
fast path here.
And with that, let's look at the
demo.
All right.
The sample code that I have here
and which as I said is also
attached to this session, allows
me to read phone numbers.
So, when I'm scanning over this
text here, you see a little
white box.
That means I find text, but I'm
not reading it because it's not
a phone number.
Even the zip code here.
But the moment I find a phone
number, it reads it and stops
the scanning.
Let me show that once more.
[ Applause ]
You see it feels interactive.
It's easy for me as a user to
use this, even though my hands
are shaking here.
So, how does this look in code,
because that's what's really
interesting part here.
So, I start by creating my text
request.
And as I said, I'm going to use
the fast path here.
I disabled the language
correction because I know I'm
looking for codes.
I'm not looking for natural
text.
And then I'm using the
regionOfInterest.
Now, this is a concept
envisioned and generally
available.
You'll notice that in my app I
have this little box that kind
of guides the user of like where
he wants to frame the text, but
I also use this area as my
region of interest which crops
Vision to only work on that
specific subject.
That helps me to A, get rid of
all the noise that's surrounding
it and because it's less data
that I have to process, it
enhances the performance.
So, now I have my request and
I'm using an AVCapture session
here.
So, my capture output, all I
have to do is that I get my
image from the session, create a
RequestHandler, and perform the
request.
And then this is mostly the
drawing of the boxes.
That's not the interesting part.
The interesting part happens in
our string utils.
As I said, we turned the
language correction off.
So, I'm now left on my own to
kind of correct some of those
results, but I can do this
because I actually have
intrinsic knowledge of what I
need to solve here.
And I know I'm looking for phone
numbers, and this means I know
I'm not looking for any
characters.
I'm only looking for numeric
paths.
So, I can simply say if it reads
something like an S, which would
be a 5, or if I get an L, this
should be a 1, I'm using my
domain knowledge of kind of
correcting for some of the
typical mistakes that can
happen.
So, that's helped us to not
probably get any characters
through, but then comes the next
part.
How did I difference it between
zip code and a phone number?
Well, I knew the structure.
The structure of an American
phone number is very simple, and
I'm using that knowledge again
to filter out results that I
don't want.
Last but not least, let me find
this as well, is our string
tracker.
And now I'm using a little trick
here.
If you ever dealt with reading
something live from a camera
feed, you will realize that very
often from frame to frame you
get different results.
They slightly fluctuate because
of noise, lighting and so on.
But it would be bad if I flicker
out the wrong phone numbers.
So, what I try to avoid is to
show incorrect results.
What I'm using here is a
technique where I actually look
over multiple frames and build
evidence over time.
This building of evidence over
time means I simply store the
phone numbers and at the very
end, all that I'm doing is very
simple.
If the same number showed up in
10 consecutive frames, I know
I've read it and actually
propagated up to the user.
Now, 10 was an empiric number
that we picked, but it worked
really well for us.
And with that, I basically
filter out all the noise that I
would otherwise have.
And that is all that we needed
to do to get our demo to run.
Let's go back to the slides.
So, let's quickly recap.
I use the fast path to keep up
with the frame rate of the
camera.
I was able to guide the user how
to use the camera.
I use the region of interest to
crop down to really what I only
want to read to get rid of the
noise surrounding it and enhance
the performance.
I turned off the language
correction because I knew I'm
reading actually code.
And I use my own domain
knowledge, and this is like the
same thing as you as app
developers would do of this
phone numbers to actually read
them correctly.
And last but not least, I use
this building of evidence over
time to actually help to reduce
some of the noise.
Next, I would like to introduce
the Document Camera.
The Document Camera was already
introduced two years ago by
Notes.
And it's a really great
companion when you don't need to
use a live stream to capture.
This year, you've seen it in
Notes, Mail, Files, and
Messages.
And it already is perfect for
reading a document.
Because as you can see here, it
finds the document, crops it
out, and now I could just simply
pipe it into my text recognition
request.
This is a great companion
because what it does is already
just a prospective correction of
these scans for you and it
evenly lights also the image.
That makes it much easier to
process afterwards.
So, how does this look in code?
First, I need to bring in
VisionKit as this is a new
framework and then I create the
VNDocumentCameraView Controller.
I present it on the screen and
my camera is running.
So, once the user is done, in my
delegate I get the results back.
Now, there's one thing to keep
in mind.
We can actually scan multiple
documents at once, so they come
back as pages.
From each of them, I simply take
my CG image and pipe them into
my Vision Request, and I get my
results out of it.
And now to get to some of the
best practices, I would like to
introduce my colleague Cedric
Bray onstage, who will give you
some more information about
that.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Frank.
I am super excited that we have
Text Recognition coming into the
Vision Framework this year.
And to help you take best
advantage of this new API, we're
going to talk about best
practices.
So, in this section, you will
learn about language knowledge,
how to leverage language
knowledge for getting the best
results.
You will learn how to tune for
better performance in your
application.
And you will learn a bit more
about how to process your
results in the most effective
way.
So, the image that you are
processing maybe are in a
language that you have
identified.
And if there are, in this
particular language, then you
want to take advantage of this
information.
To do so, you enable
language-based collection.
First you have to set the
language that you are targeting.
For this we will support
English.
And once language-based
correction is enabled, it will
improve the transcription of the
results by using on-device
language models.
On-device language models are
great.
They have large generic
coverage.
But you may have domain-specific
words, domain-specific
vocabulary like medical terms or
business-specific codes or
references that appear in the
documents.
And so we can, you can specify
this information, this
vocabulary, by passing a custom
lexicon to the Text Recognition
request.
When you do so, this custom
vocabulary will complement the
language-based correction to
give you the correct
transcription, even in cases
where the images are more
challenging.
So, let's see how this looks in
code.
First, a prerequisite, you need
to check the languages that are
supported by language-based
correction.
And so this list of supported
languages is defined for a
combination of recognition level
and for the API version that you
are targeting.
Enabling language-based
correction is simple.
Just set the corresponding
property to true on the Text
Recognition request.
Initialize custom words.
You can specify this list of
words as an array of strings
that you pass to the custom
words property on the text
recognition request.
So, this is great for optimizing
for accuracy, transcription
accuracy.
But what about performance?
And there's a very common case
where you're probably not
interested in smaller
text that is in the
image.
So for that case, we recommend
that you adjust the
minimumTextHeight.
And the way it works is that
when you set up these
minimumTextHeight, all text that
is smaller than the height that
you specify will be ignored.
It won't be processed.
It won't be part of the results.
And the input image will be
downsized, and the execution
time will be smaller.
Recognition will go faster.
And the memory usage will go
down.
One important note about this
property is that it is expressed
as a fraction of the image
height.
As you can see in this example.
If I said 0.5, it means that the
text that is bigger or same size
as half of the height of the
image will be returned.
So, this is a case when you want
to make text recognition faster.
But what if text recognition is
not the highest priority task in
your application?
Maybe you have other higher
priority tasks to run, like an
ARKit view running in foreground
might be the case for you in
your app.
Or Cam AR Frames that you are
running and processing in real
time.
So, in the case of background
task, we allow you to run text
recognition on the CPU only, so
you can leave GPU resources and
optionally the neural engine, to
higher priority tasks for your
application.
You do that using the
usesCPUOnly property.
It's a property that is
available for other VN requests,
for all other VN requests and
Text Recognition support that as
well.
So, that's the case when you
will have Text Recognition
running slower on purpose.
But there are also cases where
the image is just very big and
there's a lot of text and Text
Recognition will be, will take
longer and your user might be
confused unless you provide
progress management.
And we highly recommend that you
focus on progress management in
your application.
This is a new concept in Vision
for this year and Text
Recognition fully implement
that.
It comes in two ways.
First, you can set a
progressHandler on your request.
And when you do so, you get the
progress ratio as in true
parameter in the progress
handler.
And you can also support
cancellation in your app.
For example, if you want to
provide a button to the user so
they can cancel a Text
Recognition that's running in
front of them.
So, that's a bunch of concepts
and to illustrate them, I would
like to show you a demo of a
sample app that we're making
available with this session as
well.
It's called My First Image
Reader.
So, let me give you a tour of
this app.
So, as you will see with this
sample code, My First Image
Reader as the main window.
As you can see here.
And a transcript panel.
The main window will show the
image and the geometry of the
results.
The transcript window will show
the text.
If I take a closer look at the
top of this window, at the
toolbar, you'll see that you can
choose between accurate and
fast.
So, that's in fact a very nice,
simple app for you to experiment
with this mode.
But also with other setting that
we have just talked about.
Performance setting, minimum
text height, I'll get back to
that later, and in this view,
you also have access to the
language settings, setting,
enabling the language model,
sorry.
And the custom words.
Let me show you quickly with a
crafted example how this looks
like.
If I take one image that I
created and say that's a book
cover and happens to have very
small text and happens to be my
name.
You see that you get very small
text, my name here, located and
recognized.
And same obviously for the very
large text.
Now let's say I have a bunch of
those and I just want to index
the titles of these images.
I wouldn't care so much about
the small print, in particular
my name on it.
So, I will adjust the minimum
text height to make the
recognition run faster.
You can just set it to 0.1, so
the text has to be at least 90
percent of the image height.
And that's the case for the
large text, Desert Dunes, here.
So, setting these back to 0, let
me show you the language
settings, in particular the
impact of custom words.
If I drag this flyer here, it's
for a project called Hill Side.
It also has a probable number,
which is a reference number.
It happens to be HI11.
So, there's possible confusion
here.
So, let me show you the
transcription results.
You see that the code is in fact
misrecognized here.
So we're changing.
So if I specify HI11 as custom
word, because it's part of my
known references, then the
custom, the list of custom words
and this one in particular we
complemented by this correction
and give us the correct
transcription for that
reference.
Back to the slide.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So, quick recap.
You need to choose the
recognition level that is the
best fit for your use case for
your application.
Fast, accurate, it needs to be
the right one.
For the language settings, we
recommend that you check based
on the type of documents that
you have.
If there's an obvious language,
a neighbor languages correction,
and if you have a
domain-specific vocabulary,
enable custom words, specify
your custom words.
And also, very importantly, you
need to support progress update
in your app for the best user
experience.
Now, even if you follow this
recommendation, there's still
one very important aspect to be
aware of.
You need to process your results
and you need to provide a
recipe, have your own recipe for
presenting your results to your
users.
And the recipe you want to have
is probably not alphabet soup.
What I mean by that is that you
need to process your results in
the most effective way for the
best user experience.
So, let's check how to do that.
One very important statement
first.
You should expect ambiguity in
the input.
This is computer vision.
This is an open-ended problem.
And our terms of excellent
parameter that will influence
the content of the images that
you are processing.
In fact, the case of house
number is quite interesting
here.
Because some of them are very
stylized.
And when you run the generate
Text Recognizer on those, it has
no clue that they should be
numbers, right?
And instead of getting 101, you
get lol or you might get the
ASCII art for the happy
guy raising hand, meaning this
case.
So, in that case, have you heard
it before but we're insisting on
that you need to leverage the
candidate list, the list of top
candidates that you have for,
from the observations.
So, take this candidate list and
if it makes in for your
application, take a look at this
top one, top two, top three
results or more.
There's a typical example where
you want to index the content of
the images and so if you want to
increase the recall, you can
index more candidates for each
of the results.
Of course, at the cost of
precision.
Right? So, this candidate list,
we need to dive into that, but
that's just one dimension.
That's the scale of prediction
confidence.
What about other dimensions?
What about image space?
We recommend that you evaluate
and in fact reconsider using the
geometry to map your results.
You have the salvation bonding
box.
It gives you spatial information
and you can map these results
together using the position, the
scale of the results, but also
the rotation.
And the example that we are
showing here, in case, in the
case of the receipts, you can
probably map the item name to
the price.
So, that's for the geometry.
But for each result in
isolation, you also have the
opportunity to use parsers and
try to make sense of each of
these results in isolation.
And in this case, Data Detector
is your best friend.
It's initiate NSDataDetector for
the types that you're interested
in.
As you probably know, it
supports addresses, URLs, dates,
phone numbers.
In the example of my business
card, I can use that to make
sense of some of the results.
But if that's not sufficient,
then you can obviously use your
own domain-specific features,
have your own vocabulary that
you match the strings against,
or use your own regular
expression.
So, to illustrate these
principles, we have another
sample app, an iOS app this
time, called Business Companion.
In fact, if you're sitting in
this room because you have the
idea receipt scanner.
Receipt scanner, anyone?
Maybe? Or a business card
reader?
People interested in business
card?
Then this app is something you
really take a look at, because
it mixes the two flows into the
same app flow.
Let me show you how.
First, it has document category
picker.
It gives you some - You see soon how it works,
It is just the first screen.
That way you pick the document
type you're interested in.
And from there, you go to the
Document Camera that you heard
about before.
And from the Document Camera, we
run text recognition and from
the recognized result, we
perform some analysis to make
sense of these results, and
that's what really matters here.
Because based on this analysis,
we'll be able to get some data
model for receipt business card.
In this case, we have a fall
back on the type of documents.
And from this results analysis,
given that you make sense of the
data, you can also visualize the
result more appropriately in the
case of the receipt which shows
to display in a table view.
And if we have a business card,
we show mini contact card.
So, let me show you this app.
Switching to the iOS device
here.
So, this is Business Companion,
and as I was telling you, we
have here a choice between
receipt, card, and other type of
document.
Let's just start with receipts.
And first the Document Camera.
We have some challenging light
in here.
As the document gets captured
and processed, yes, our results
structured.
You see the item name.
You see the category names and
the value for each section.
Now, if I look at a business
card.
Similarly I get each field of
the business card analyzed
[applause], and this is my mini
business card.
Thank you.
Like I said, this is nice but
look at this front screen.
You still have to choose
manually the document type.
It's not really seamless.
You can make that more seamless,
right?
Actually, we've done that.
And I'm going to show you a
better version of this app.
It's called Better Business
Companion.
And what we've done, in fact, is
that we've trained a classifier
model using Create ML and we're
using this classifier as a first
step so that you don't have to
specify the document type.
It will be selected
automatically.
Enough talking.
Let me show you.
So, very obviously, first
button, big button, very small
button.
You only have the scan button
here and you can see that
similarly I get my receipt here.
Get processed as a receipt
[applause] without having the
user specify the document type.
Just to show you how it works
with business cards, with my
business card again.
And yes, we get the business
card correctly processed.
[ Applause ]
So, I told you we integrated the
Core ML model for this but I
would like to show you how.
So, let's go into Xcode here and
this is the code, in fact this
is the code we modified from
Business Companion.
And we added the insertion of a
Core ML model that is actually
here.
So, we inserted this Core ML
model to set out the request
with a completionHandler.
And as part of the handler, you
see that we processed the top
observation and date of the
identifier, sorry, of this top
observation.
We set up the scan mode for the
application that will determine
the flow for the rest of the
app.
So, we encourage you to think
about how you can improve your
application flow using Text
Recognition but, and processing
the results appropriately but
also leveraging ML models, like
this.
All right.
Back to the slides.
Just for a quick recap.
As I mentioned, we encourage you
to use geometry information when
it makes sense.
Parse your results, make sense
of them by using Data Detectors
or your own parsers.
And most importantly, you know
what you're building.
You know what type of data that
you have to look at.
And so we recommend that you
leverage your domain knowledge
for the best user experience.
So, we hope that gave you good
reference point for starting
integrating Text Recognition
into your app.
I can't wait to see all the
fantastic app that you're going
to create using this technology.
If you have question, you can
visit the machine learning lab.
There's one more tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]