[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everyone, my
name is Michael Gorbach and I'll
be presenting today with my
colleague John Nefulda from
Apple's Accessibility team.
I'm sure all of you are excited
about SwiftUI and how it can
help you build better apps
faster and easier.
I am also really excited about
SwiftUI and specifically, I'm
excited about its potential for
Accessibility.
We're going to tell you today
how SwiftUI can help you build
the next generation of apps for
all of your users.
We're going to kick it off with
a quick introduction to
Accessibility and our
Accessibility technologies on
our platforms.
Then talk a little bit about how
SwiftUI make your -- makes your
apps more accessible by default.
John is going to come in and
take us through the
Accessibility API that we are
introducing today.
And, also take us through the
Accessibility Tree that SwiftUI
generates for us in our
applications.
So, let's start with that
introduction.
What do we mean when we throw
around this word Accessibility
today?
Well, all of you have put a ton
of work into your applications
to make them fun and functional,
helpful and a joy to use.
Given all of that work you want
your apps to be useable by all
of your potential customers.
Not just some of them.
That's really what Accessibility
is all about.
It's about giving customers with
disabilities full access to the
value that your app provides.
And that means more happy
customers for you.
It is also especially great for
your customers with
disabilities.
On our various devices like Macs
and iPhones, Watches and
HomePods, Apples technologies
enable people with disabilities
to live fuller lives.
They open up possibilities for
them that did not exist just a
few years ago.
A huge part of how that happens
in practice is through your
applications.
Yes, your apps can change
people's lives.
But for that to happen you need
to do a little work to make them
fully accessible.
When folks with disabilities
interact with your applications,
they will generally use Apple's
built in Accessibility features.
We've got a whole array of these
shipping across our many
platforms.
I'm going to focus on one of
them first called VoiceOver.
VoiceOver is a screen reader
available across all our
platforms.
It's a product that lets folks
with low to no vision use their
Apple devices without needing to
see their screens.
The way it does this is by
reading to you.
VoiceOver lets you step through
the elements on your screen,
taking each one of them in turn,
and reads information to you
about those elements like the
titles of buttons, the names of
images, and the values of text
fields.
It also lets you use gestures on
iOS or keyboard keys on the Mac
to interact with those elements
and kick off their associated
actions.
Here's VoiceOver on the Mac
interacting with Calculator.
VoiceOver is reading to us here
and it's showing what it's
reading in the bottom right as
well.
There are also two really cool
new items in this long list this
year.
The first is Voice Control.
I'm sure you all have seen the
amazing demos.
The second -- yes, it is
amazing.
The second is Full Keyboard
Access.
Totally new on iOS this year and
greatly enhanced on the Mac.
Full Keyboard Access lets you
use your Mac of iOS devices
entirely with just a keyboard.
It is a great, fast and fluid
way to get things one on your
Apple devices.
We are confident that this
feature is really going to get
used not just for accessibility
purposes, but also just by folks
looking to be extra productive
on their Apple devices.
Move around screens, kick off
commands.
Here's Full Keyboard Access
interacting with the Calculator
on iOS.
Notice the highlighted 8 key
showing us where the keyboard
focus is.
These two great features are
perfect examples of something
we've learned on our team time
and time again.
Accessibility is for everyone.
Not just for people with
disabilities.
That is why the little bit of
work you do on your app for
Accessibility has such a broad
impact.
Now, one of the best things
about our platforms is that many
of the features on this slide,
including all the ones we just
discussed, use the same
underlying technologies.
If you implement Accessibility
in your app well it will work
great with all of them.
All these features ultimately
rely on information that your
app exposes to our platforms.
The better this information, the
better these features are going
to work.
We call this information your
apps Accessibility User
Interface.
What actually goes into one of
these?
Well, let's take a quick look at
Calculator just as a simple
example, and take it apart.
The Accessibility User Interface
your app exposes to us consists
of Accessibility elements.
Each view in Calculator forms
one Accessibility element here.
In this case, most of these
Accessibility elements are
buttons.
So, let's take a look at one of
them in particular.
Here is the X button on the left
and its Accessibility element on
the right.
Notice that it's got a label for
VoiceOver to read.
You're going to want a label
like this for all of your
elements so a VoiceOver knows
where they are in your app.
In this case, the developers of
the Calculator app have
customized the default label
from the simple X to the text
multiply.
This element also has a type.
On iOS that's described using
traits and on macOS it's
described using roles.
That type here is button.
And finally, this button element
has a default action.
Press on macOS or tap on iOS.
A VoiceOver user can use this
action to interact with the
element.
Let's take a look at one more.
This is the display at the top
showing us the results of our
calculation.
We can see that the developers
have given it a label named
display.
It is also exposing another
important piece of information
called a value, that holds the
current text its showing.
It has no default action since
you can't right now interact
with this element.
Default actions though are not
the only way your Accessibility
customers are going to interact
with your app and its elements.
You can add custom named actions
to any Accessibility element in
your app.
For example, we could add a
Custom Action on this one called
clear, which would clear the
display.
So that is Calculator's
Accessibility User Interface.
Your app has one too.
A lot of it is going to get
created for you automatically,
but with a little bit of work
you can make it a whole lot
better.
You relentlessly polish the
visual user interfaces on your
apps.
In a similar way you should
polish your Accessibility User
Interface as well.
Here are three key things to
look for which we're going to
show you how to do today.
First, your Accessibility
elements should be
understandable.
They should have reasonable
labels, values, and other
describing information.
An example of this is how
Calculator changed the label of
the X button to multiple so it's
easier to understand.
Your elements should also be
interactable.
That means, appropriate default
actions and Custom Actions
wherever they are needed.
Adding that clear action to the
main display as we just talked
about is an example of this.
And finally, your elements
should be navigable.
Carefully thinking through the
ordering of your Accessibility
elements and grouping them as
needed will really make your app
more useable with our
Accessibility features.
So, if you're interested in how
to do all this fun stuff with
AppKit or UIKit we have some
great sessions for you, but not
this one.
Today we are going to talk about
SwiftUI.
At Apple we have always deeply
believed in the importance and
power of Accessibility.
That is why we all work
extremely hard to make
frameworks that let you folks
make accessible apps easily and
even automatically wherever
possible.
Today, because of the high level
of declarative nature of SwiftUI
and the way that it understands
your state, we can take
automatic Accessibility to a
whole new level with this new
framework.
SwiftUI can make your apps more
accessible by default and it
also gives us a powerful
foundation to do more of your
Accessibility work for you going
forward.
SwiftUI is going to generate
your Accessibility elements for
you, just like it generates
NSView and UIViews for you.
Let's take a look at this simple
SwiftUI code.
It's creating a vertical stack,
in that stack is a button, and
it is sandwiched between some
text.
SwiftUI is going to create three
Accessibility elements for you
here.
One for each of the two texts
and of course one for the
button.
Keep in mind, the Accessibility
elements that SwiftUI creates
here are not UIViews or NSViews.
Instead, they are SwiftUI's own
Accessibility elements.
We have all worked hard to make
sure that SwiftUI's standard
controls are as Accessible as
possible by default.
Notice that although these
elements are simple, they
already have all the important
information we need.
They're understandable because
they have labels.
They are intractable, the button
has an action.
And they're navigable because
they're in the correct order.
As I mentioned though, SwiftUI
does have an Accessibility API
to customize the elements it
generates for you.
Before we get into that though,
I wanted to talk to you about
the great Accessibility you get
with SwiftUI before you write
any Accessibility specific code.
One thing you get for free in
SwiftUI is notifications to help
keep our Accessibility features
like VoiceOver up to date
regarding what is going on in
your app.
Remember, the Accessibility
features I talked about earlier
are all based on the
Accessibility elements that your
app exposes.
While running, VoiceOver's going
to ask your app for that list of
Accessibility elements.
For example, when the user opens
Calculator it'll ask Calculator
for the elements on screen and
Calculator's going to respond
with those buttons we talked
about earlier.
It's also going to send the
element for the main display.
It'll send a value with that.
In this case, that value is 5.
So, what happens if this
information changes?
For example, what happens when
Calculator has gotten a press of
the equals button and has
updated the value of that main
display?
Let's say that value is now 10.
Well, VoiceOver needs to know
that the value of that element
has changed.
That's why our frameworks
support Accessibility
notifications.
Your app can tell VoiceOver,
hey, the value here has changed.
We have been talking to you all
conference about how SwiftUI is
state driven.
Well, this is where there are
some huge benefits for
Accessibility.
Because SwiftUI really
understands your state and is
tracking when it changes, you
never need to worry about
Accessibility notifications
again.
Not even for custom controls.
Yes, exactly.
SwiftUI will track the state
that you're using for your
Accessibility and send them for
you.
Let's take a look at how this
happens.
We have a toggle here and a
button that are linked to a
single piece of state.
It's a Boolean and we've called
it Enabled.
You can see there are two
Accessibility elements created
for us here.
In this case, we'll have an
Accessibility element for that
toggle.
It's got a correct label and
type.
Its value is going to start off
as 0.
When you click the button the
value of that Boolean enabled
state is going to change.
It'll go from 0 to 1 or 1 to 0.
That's why we've called that
button Flip.
So, what happens here with
Accessibility?
Well, the Accessibility value of
that toggle has now changed.
So, we need to let VoiceOver
know.
Because it understands that that
value's changed, SwiftUI will
automatically send a
notification to VoiceOver
telling it exactly what
happened.
Notice, there's no Accessibility
specific code needed here.
You don't need to worry about
Accessibility notifications in
SwiftUI, because we send them
for you.
Another area SwiftUI really
improves on is Custom Controls.
Often when you're designing your
app, you may want to customize
the look and feel of your UI.
Maybe you want your app to have
a unique visual style or you
need to fit with a company
theme.
If you have done Accessibility
work in the past you know that
oftentimes the more custom your
controls in this way, the more
Accessibility work you have to
put into them.
Well, SwiftUI's control styles
let you have complete control
over the look and feel of your
UI while still getting great
accessibility out of the box.
That means you can finally
easily make custom controls that
are beautiful and unique, but
still immediately accessible
just like the system ones.
Here's an example of a custom
button style built using
SwiftUI.
This API is giving us the style
of the button including its
label and whether it is pressed.
Given that, we need to let the
style know how we want this
button to draw.
So, let's go ahead and put that
label within a rounded rectangle
and set some background and
foreground colors that are going
to depend on whether we're
pressed.
We're also going to add a tiny
bit of padding and set a nice
big font and color as well.
So, you can see the result here
on the right.
Now that we've defined this
beautiful custom drawing, we of
course need to use it.
All we need to do is create a
normal button and then use the
button style modifier function
to set the way we want the
button to draw.
This is going to create an
Accessibility element for us,
which you can see in the top
right here.
Notice that despite the totally
custom drawing here this
Accessibility element is good to
go.
It has a label, it's got the
right type, and it has an
action.
Once again, we're doing this
without writing any
Accessibility specific code.
SwiftUI also provides better and
more intuitive Accessibility for
your images.
Specifically, I want to talk to
you about illustrations and
glyphs which often form
important parts of our UI's.
Imagine you have an app with a
sign-up flow that ends in a
green checkmark like this.
Here are some simple SwiftUI
code you might start with to
create such a view.
In this case, it's just a
vertical stack with an image in
it.
After completing this sign up a
sighted customer would look at
this and say, oh sweet, that
means I'm done.
Great. But, a customer with
VoiceOver will hear,
CheckmarkGlyph.
That is not super useful.
That is your developer created
name for the image.
I don't know what a glyph is or
what it's supposed to mean.
As a VoiceOver user I'm
confused.
Am I finished or not?
Was there an error?
This is not understandable for
me.
The reason for that is that this
image is not explicitly labeled.
Here's the Accessibility element
that's created by SwiftUI, which
you can see it's got the right
type but no label.
What SwiftUI is going to have to
do here is pull the label from
the filename of the image or the
name of the asset.
That isn't really something we
want to rely on.
Because that name is for you the
developer, not your customers.
With SwiftUI you can label your
images now with localizable
accessibility information right
as you create them, like so.
All we need to do is use the
Label Based Initializer to
image.
That way there's no need to
remember to do this afterwards
in some separate code.
This is going to create an
Accessibility User Interface
that is understandable.
Notice that this updated
Accessibility element is now
properly labeled.
When I land on this image
VoiceOver reads, sign up
complete.
On the other hand, sometimes
your VoiceOver users don't need
to land on an image.
For example, maybe this
checkmark is really just
decoration and you've already
got text below it that says,
sign up complete.
The SwiftUI code might look
something like this.
A vertical stack with an image
and two lines of text.
In this case, the image is
really just decorative.
You could create it like so,
telling SwiftUI that with the
right initializer.
Now, VoiceOver users aren't
going to land on this image.
If we look at the Accessibility
elements, we've got two for the
text, but none for the image.
This is now more navigable
because your VoiceOver users
aren't going to land on useless
elements.
There is one last area where
SwiftUI can make your life
easier with Accessibility.
And that is labels.
Let's take a look at this
control which is actually in our
System Preferences.
Its purpose it to let you pick a
voice.
You can see the Accessibility
element here in the top right.
It has no label and a value of
Alex.
So, this is not understandable
to me as a VoiceOver user.
Because VoiceOver is going to
read, Alex, and nothing else.
Who is Alex and why do I care
about him?
If I'm using VoiceOver I don't
know.
I would have to scan around the
rest of this screen to try to
find some context.
Let's take a look at the SwiftUI
code instead for such a control.
Here, we are using a standard
SwiftUI picker which is being
rendered as a popup button.
Now, SwiftUI's picker has a
built in label we can use.
In this case, we've set System
Voice.
Many of SwiftUI's controls have
labels like this and the rest
will soon.
Let's take a look at the
appropriate Accessibility
element.
This time it's got a label.
And if we look at what VoiceOver
reads; we have Alex System Voice
pop up button.
In an upcoming seed of SwiftUI
you'll be able to do even more
here.
What if you want one single
label to show for all of your
customers, regardless of whether
they're using Accessibility?
Well, you will be able to
configure that label to show
visual -- let's say on the left
here, and when you do so we will
set up Accessibility for you.
Specifically, we will set up a
connection between the label on
the left and the popup button on
the right.
They'll each be their own
Accessibility element, but
VoiceOver will know that they're
linked.
And so, VoiceOver's going to
read, Alex System Voice pop up
button.
So, here is what SwiftUI can do
for you automatically.
There are two things to
highlight about all of these
items.
First, they're all consistent
across SwiftUI's platforms.
And second, to get all of this
you don't need to write any
Accessibility specific code.
Sometimes though, no matter how
good our automatic Accessibility
might be, it might not be
enough.
That's why we provide an
Accessibility API for you to
use.
I'm going to hand the show over
to John now to take you through
it.
John.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Michael.
So, we've shown you all of the
great built-in Accessibility
that SwiftUI provides.
It was designed to give everyone
a good experience out of the
box.
But we understand that this
alone isn't enough to be a
complete experience.
This SwiftUI Accessibility API
allows you to modify and
ultimately create an even better
experience for everyone.
So, I want to start off by
showing a couple simple use
cases for the API.
And let's go back to the
Calculator example that Michael
showed earlier.
We'll start with the multiply
button, which by default will
read X.
To change the label, I'll use
the Accessibility modifier
function with the label
parameter.
And with this change the button
will now read, multiply.
We also want to provide
VoiceOver for the selected state
of the button.
Visually the button becomes
white when selected.
We have an Accessibility trait
that can help out with this.
And if you're not familiar,
traits are a set of things that
describe what your element is
and what it can do.
Buttons for example, will
automatically have the isButton
trait by default.
VoiceOver will read, button,
after reading out the elements
label.
For this example, we can add the
isSelected state using the
Accessibility function and add
traits as the parameter.
VoiceOver will now read,
selected, when the button is in
this state.
So, let's see how we can improve
the Accessibility of the result
view.
We'll change the label to result
and add an Accessibility value.
You can use Accessibility value
to provide VoiceOver with a
readable description.
You might choose to include
units or other additional
context.
But for our purposes, the number
itself is sufficient.
Finally, we'll add a Custom
Action using the Accessibility
action function.
Using the name parameter, we'll
create a Custom Action called
Clear.
VoiceOver will read that there
are actions available when
focused on this element.
And this was just a quick
overview of how to add
Accessibility in SwiftUI.
The Accessibility function adds
information and the
Accessibility action function
allows you to add actions.
But I want to talk a little bit
more about when to use this API
and how you can identify the
areas of need within your app.
And this comes back to what your
customers need your apps to be.
Understandable, interactable,
and navigable.
And here are a few questions to
help you evaluate this.
Do the displayed strings provide
enough information?
Will a Custom Action simplify
the interaction?
And can you speed up navigation?
So now I'll show you a video of
VoiceOver moving through an app
that I created.
And as it does, try to keep
these three questions in mind.
So, this is an app that
calculates the contrast ratio
between text and its background
color.
At the top you can see the
current value of the ratio and
at the bottom there are two
areas where you can adjust the
red, green, and blue values of
the background color and the
text color.
I've also added a double tap
gesture on the top view to swap
the two colors.
So, let's see how VoiceOver uses
that by default.
:50
&gt;&gt; 11.7 1.
11.7 1. 11.7 1.
Reset colors button.
Background.
Red 76. 30 percent.
Adjustable.
Green 217.
85 percent.
Adjustable.
Blue 100. 39 percent.
39 -- 100 percent.
&gt;&gt; So, there were a couple of
things in the video that stood
out to me with the label at the
top.
First, there was a symbol that
wasn't read out.
VoiceOver doesn't always read
out your punctuation depending
on settings.
And in a situation like this,
where the punctuation represents
that this is a ratio, we should
pass that information on to
VoiceOver.
So, 11.7 1 should read 11.7 to
1.
And secondly, the numbers were
spoken without any context.
It's probably a good idea to
give this a proper label to
describe its value.
So, we can use contrast ratio.
And we'll do this by calling the
Accessibility function twice on
a contrast ratio view.
Once for the label and another
to add the value.
Another thing that stood out to
me was the information provided
by the slider.
The value of the slider was a
percentage, but in this case, it
actually represents the color
components value from 0 to 255.
We can also hide the label above
the slider and expose that
information through the slider
instead.
So that'll group all the
information into one element.
So first let's hide the label.
We'll call the Accessibility
function with visibility as the
parameter.
Passing in .hidden will hide the
element and any children that it
may have.
Next, we'll add the information
of the label onto the slider.
We'll give it the label of the
color that it will modify and a
proper value between 0 and 255.
We also have a double tap
gesture on the view.
Gestures on iOS can be
challenging to perform for
customers who use our
Accessibility products.
Some of our products have a
built-in gestures menu to help
perform some of the more complex
gestures.
But we can do better here.
An easy simplification for this
is to create a Custom Action for
the gesture.
This helps in two ways.
First, the name of the action
will help describe what will
happen when you activate it.
And second, actions are
available everywhere in iOS and
they're discoverable in all of
our Accessibility products.
So, let's add the swap colors
action to our contrast ratio
view by calling the same
Accessibility action modifier
function.
And finally, can we speed up
navigation here?
Looking at the view it can be
divided into three main spaces;
the contrast ratio, the
background color, and the text
color.
So, these are good candidates
for the isHeader Accessibility
trait.
This trait's used by VoiceOver
to navigate quickly between
different header elements in
your app.
So, let's add the trait to the
contrast ratio view and the two
text views in each of the color
picker sections.
So, let's take a look at the
results of the changes that we
made, starting off with the top
view.
&gt;&gt; Contrast ratio 11.7 to 1.
Heading.
&gt;&gt; So, the element now provides
context and a proper description
for the value.
Let's move onto the sliders and
we'll adjust the blue sliders
value.
&gt;&gt; Reset colors button.
Background.
Heading. Red 76.
Adjustable.
Swipe or down with one finger to
adjust the value.
Green 217.
Adjustable.
Blue 10. Adjustable.
Swipe -- 100.
255.
&gt;&gt; And finally, let's use the
VoiceOver rotor to navigate by
headings and swap the colors
using the Custom Action that we
created.
&gt;&gt; Adjust value.
Headings. Text.
Heading. Background.
Heading. Contrast ratio 13.0 to
1.
Heading. Actions.
Swap colors.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, with just a few tweaks we
were able to greatly improve the
Accessibility experience of this
app.
And these are just the basics of
the API.
But I want to move onto
something a little bit more
conceptual.
The Accessibility Tree.
And you've seen how
Accessibility elements are
created from your views.
But I want to go in a bit
further and talk about this tree
structure of these elements and
how you can manipulate the
structure to provide a better
experience.
So, we'll start with how this
tree's created.
Starts off with your view tree
created directly from your code.
On the left here is SwiftUI code
for a table cell view.
It has one label, a spacer, and
two buttons.
Arranged horizontally inside of
an HStack.
And this directly translates to
the view tree structure on the
right where the HStack is the
parent node and the label,
spacer, and buttons are its
children.
Because of our built in
Accessibility, this view tree
will create three Accessibility
elements.
One from the text and two from
the buttons.
These elements will become
children of your platforms
hosting view and that's passed
on to our Accessibility
products.
This subtree may also be a part
of a larger Accessibility Tree,
mixed in with UiKit or AppKit
elements.
The SwiftUI tree can even be a
parent of other platform
elements bridged over using a UI
or NSViewRepresentable.
And you'll notice the levels of
hierarchy in this tree and you
might be thinking about how
quickly this can become complex.
But I'll show you how creating
hierarchy in this tree can
actually improve navigation.
So, let's take a look at our
example again.
The table cell itself has three
Accessibility elements.
VoiceOver will navigate these in
order and this works great if
you have only one cell.
But it's more likely that you'll
have hundreds of these in your
app.
And as you can see, there are a
ton of elements in this tree.
And it doesn't seem very useful
to have a lot of repetitive
information with the follow and
share buttons.
If you landed on this follow
button, how would you know if it
was for person 5 or person 6?
There's no context here unless
you look around.
But we can make this a lot
simpler.
And we'll do this by creating an
Accessibility element at a
higher level than in the view
tree.
We can find a view that is a
parent of our Accessibility
elements and create a new
element there.
In our case, we'll use the
HStack.
We can use the Accessibility
element function on our HStack
to create a new element.
Specifying .combine will merge
the Accessibility provided by
the children into one element.
In this case, the text view will
provide the elements label and
the two buttons will
automatically be converted into
Custom Actions.
And now, VoiceOver will see just
one element here which will read
the person's name and that there
are actions available.
[ Applause ]
And with these changes we've
significantly reduced the number
of elements in this tree.
You can navigate the cells one
by one as expected.
You can access the buttons
through Custom Actions.
So, grouping related UI like
this is a simple yet great way
to improve navigation in your
app.
Another important component of
navigation and Accessibility is
ordering.
There may be situations where
you find that the default
ordering isn't giving you the
experience that you'd expect.
So, you may have noticed from
the video earlier that the reset
colors button was actually the
second element in the swipe
order.
The two elements are arranged in
a ZStack which orders elements
from back to front by default.
Visually though, the button
appears above the contrast
ratio.
So, in this case we might want
to swap that.
To customize this order, we can
use sortPriority.
So, all elements have a default
sortPriority of 0.
And elements in a container are
sorted from highest to lowest
priority.
So, we can set the sortPriority
by calling the Accessibility
modifier function with the
sortPriority parameter.
So, we'll give our button a
sortPriority of 1 and since the
contrast ratio has a priority of
zero, the button will be scanned
first and the ratio will be
scanned second.
So, the Accessibility API helps
you make your apps more
understandable.
It lets you add context by
adding labels, values, and hints
using the Accessibility
function.
You can use the Accessibility
action function to add actions
and make your apps more
interactable.
And finally, you can use the
Accessibility element function
to group your elements together
and improve navigation.
With built in Accessibility and
simple enhancements with the
Accessibility API, SwiftUI lets
you make your apps accessible,
faster and easier than ever.
Now, back to Michael.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, so let us close
things up here.
One last thing before we do
that.
If you have put in all of this
work into the Accessibility of
your app, how do you know you're
actually being successful?
Well, we have two pieces of
advice for you here.
First, there is no substitute
for using your app.
That means trying it out with
our real Accessibility features
like VoiceOver, Full Keyboard
Access, and Voice Control.
For example, if you're using
your app with VoiceOver and
there's something you can't do
with just your voice or you --
there's something that you need
to look at the screen for, you
have some work to do.
Or if you're using your app with
Voice Control and there is
something you can't do with your
voice.
Or you're using your app with
Full Keyboard Access and there's
something you can't do with your
keyboard; you have some work
left to do.
Second, there is the
Accessibility Inspector.
This is a product that ships
with Xcode and can help you dig
deep into the Accessibility of
your app.
The Accessibility Inspector
doesn't replace testing your app
with our real Accessibility
features, but it can be a
powerful tool to understand your
Accessibility Tree and the debug
when things go wrong.
There are some great sessions
about the inspector on this
slide.
So, a few points to summarize
what we've talked about today.
We have worked super hard at
Apple to build SwiftUI so it can
make your apps as accessible as
possible by default.
And we've designed SwiftUI with
Accessibility in mind from the
very beginning.
We've talked today about what a
great Accessibility User
Interface is.
I know we've been drilling it
into you, but remember,
understandable, interactable,
and navigable.
To go beyond the basics and add
polish, SwiftUI has a powerful
Accessibility API for you to
use.
And that API is now finally
unified across all our
platforms.
So, you only have to learn it
once.
[ Applause ]
Two useful references going
forward.
First, we will be releasing
sample code for the session.
You can find it at the link
above.
And second, we have an
Accessibility lab coming up
immediately after this session.
Come join us to meet us, talk
about SwiftUI, and
Accessibility.
We are looking forward to
meeting all of you.
We're super excited of the new
era of accessible apps that you
folks will create with SwiftUI.
Thank you for listening.
[ Applause ]