[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello and welcome.
I am Stephane, an engineer in
the maps team, and together with
my colleague, Mithilesh, we are
going to talk about adding
indoor maps to your app and
websites.
In iOS 11, we introduced indoor
maps as a part of Apple maps.
We provide beautiful and
detailed floor plans for venues
such as airports and malls.
Indoor maps is a great way for
you to view, search, and find
your way inside of indoor
spaces.
Using the level picker, you can switch
between floors, and each of
these venues have indoor
location similar to GPS or
better.
Today, we will talk about how
you can display indoor maps
inside your own applications
along with indoor positioning.
We'll start by talking about the
Indoor Mapping Data Format.
Then, we'll introduce some of
the tools available to you as a
part of the Indoor Maps Program.
We'll then show you how you can
display indoor maps inside your
iOS and web applications.
Let's get started.
IMDF, which stands for the
Indoor Mapping Data Format, is a
specification for modeling
indoor spaces.
But before going into more
details, let's step back a bit
and take a closer look at what
an indoor map is in general
terms.
An indoor map, like your regular
map, is comprised of many
layers, and each of these layers
may contain several features.
Let's break this map, for
instance.
The base of an indoor map is the
building footprint.
Then we get a level.
On that level, we can find
units, such as rooms and
walkways.
Units have doorways, and we can
also have kiosks that you often
see in malls.
We have labels for rooms and
kiosks, such as the name of a
business occupying a room, and
also icons that mark the
location of amnities of
interest like elevators or
restrooms.
And finally, there is also a
virtual boundary enclosing an area
with multiple units.
Okay, so these are some of the
layers that make an indoor map.
However, in order to be able to
accurately describe-- in order
to be able to create and display
such a map, we need a way to
accurately describe its
contents.
That's where IMDF comes into
play.
IMDF is a specification for
modeling indoor spaces.
It is a 2D GeoJSON based data
format that's not only easy to
create and understand but also
easy for applications to use.
An IMDF archive is a set of JSON
files.
More specifically, it consists
of a manifest JSON file and
several GeoJSON files, each
containing a collection of
features of the given IMDF
feature type.
An IMDF feature is a regular
GeoJSON feature.
It has a type feature, may have
a geometry, and has a set of
properties.
The IMDF specification also
requires an ID to present, which
is a UUID and an additional
field called feature type, which
represents the indoor concept
being modeled.
Let's take a look at some of the
main feature types of IMDF.
Levels model the location and
physical extent of floor areas.
A level has a full name, like
parking level one, a short name
like P1, and a reference to the
building features it belongs to.
It also has an ordinal, which
represents the level's position
within the total range of floors
in a building.
Ground levels have an ordinal
equal to 0, subterranean levels
have negative ordinals, and, of
course, above-ground levels have
positive ordinals.
A level is paved with units.
A unit models the location
and extent of a space, like a
room, a walkway, a stairwell, or
an elevator.
Openings model entrances such as
door.
They may also define interesting
properties like the type of
accessibility or the kind of
access control systems.
Kiosks model pieces of furniture
that may be used to provide
services or distribute products,
like information desks or
vending machines.
We can also add businesses to
our map thanks to the occupant
features.
An occupant provides information
about a business like the name,
the phone number, and opening
hours.
They don't have a geometry, but
we can get their display point
and address through their associated
anchor.
Anchors represent a curated
point used as a peripheral
display location in a unit.
They may also have a reference
to an address.
Anchors play a key role in IMDF
since other features like
occupant, unit, or kiosk may be
linked to addresses through
them.
We may also want to add
amenities.
Amenity features can model
permanent equipment or other
convenience of interest like a
photo booth, and ATM, or an
exhibit in that case.
Section features may be used to
describe the extent of an area
with a particular theme on the
level like a food court in a
mall or a post-security area in an
airport.
Sections do not need to be
materialized by a physical
boundary.
Buildings describe physical
building structures.
They may have a name and also
refer to an address.
However, they don't have a
geometry, but defer job of
describing their extent to
another feature called
footprint.
And there are three types of
footprints.
Aerial footprints capture the
maximum extent of the levels
above ground.
Ground footprints capture the
maximum extent of the ground
levels, and subterranean
footprints capture the maximum
extent of the floors below
ground.
Okay.
So this was just a quick
overview of the main features of
IMDF.
Thanks to IMDF, we can describe
indoor spaces data in a formal
yet flexible way.
But, of course the specification
covers a lot more.
You can check it out at
register.apple.com.
Apple works with many of the top
platforms' providers for
geospatial tooling that support
IMDF.
You can work directly with them
to create an IMDF archive for
your venue.
You can use that archive right
away and display it in your apps
as we will demonstrate later in
this session.
But what if you also want to
enable indoor positioning?
Well, that's where the indoor
maps program comes in.
By participating in the indoor
maps program, you can take
advantage of some of the tools
that Apple provides to visualize
and validate your data.
Even more interesting, you can
add indoor location capability
or the blue dot to your venue.
And optionally, you can also
allow Apple to display your
venue inside of Apple Maps.
You can sign up for the indoor
maps program at
register.Apple.com/indoor.
Signing up is very
straightforward and easy.
You just need to provide some
basic information about yourself
and your organization such as
the name, the location, and
address.
Once Apple has reviewed and
approved your application, you
can start working with your
geospatial tool provider to
create an IMDF archive.
And now that you have it, you
are ready to validate it with
the IMDF Sandbox.
The IMDF Sandbox is a tool that
allows you to visualize and
validate your IMDF data.
Most of the issues it reports
can be addressed right away with
a few clicks.
Some errors might require more
work, and, in that case, you may
want to take your data back to
the mapmaker to fix them.
When the IMDF Sandbox reports no
errors, you may submit your data
for more exhausting validation
tests.
If no issues are detected, you
can proceed to the next step,
which is enabling indoor
positioning for your venue with
the indoor survey app.
The indoor survey app is your
companion to enable indoor
positioning on iOS.
You survey a place by collecting
radiofrequency fingerprints of
your venue.
Surveying relies on the fact
that the radiofrequency patterns
emitted by fixed WiFi access
points inside a building are
unique depending on your
location.
Once surveying is complete, the
survey data is uploaded to Apple
servers and processed.
And, if no issues are detected,
your venue is made live for
indoor location.
You can use a survey app to test
the accuracy of indoor location
afterwards.
Performing a survey is very easy
and intuitive.
We have some guidelines in place
so that you can get the best
results out of it.
Alright.
So, you have created your IMDF
archive and validated it, and
you may also have enabled indoor
positioning.
The next step is to display it
in your app or website.
I'll now hand over to Mithilesh,
who will show you how you can
display an indoor map inside an
iOS application.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Stephane.
Hello everyone.
My name is Mithilesh, and I'm an
engineer on the maps team.
I'm here to show you how you can
use IMDF data to display an
indoor map in your iOS
application.
We'll build a simple app for
visitors of a dinosaur museum.
We call this app Dinoseum.
The app displays a map of a
museum with different exhibits,
restaurants, shops, and more.
The various areas of the museum
are marked with descriptive
labels and icons that the user
can tap to display details.
On the top right corner, we have
a level picker to switch between
levels.
The app also takes advantage of
indoor positioning to display
the user's location inside the
museum.
So, what does it take to build
this app?
Displaying a basic indoor map
can be done in three steps.
In step one, we'll add the IMDF
files to our project and create
model classes for each of the
feature types.
In step two, we will decode the
IMDF files and create instances
of these model classes.
We will then relate them to
create a graph of feature
objects.
Venue consists of buildings.
Buildings have footprint and
levels.
Levels have units and openings
and so on.
In the third step, we will
retrieve the geometry from the
decoded feature objects and
render them to create an indoor
map.
Now, let's take a quick look at
some of the code that we'll
write.
For step one, we'll create an
abstract class called feature.
Every IMDF feature must have a
unique identifier.
It must also have a set of
properties that describe the
feature.
And it may have geometry, which
is an array of MKShape objects.
Using this as the base class,
we'll write concrete
implementations of feature class
such as Unit.
For decoding an IMDF file, which
is also a GeoJSON file, we'll
use the new MKGeoJSONDecoder
and call decode on the data.
We'll look into the details of
decoding in a short while.
During step three, we will use
addOverlays and addAnnotations
APIs of the MapKit framework to
draw polygons, lines, and point
geometry on the map.
And for every overlay that is
added to the map, we get a
callback to MKMapViewDelegate
method mapView render for
overlay.
And for every annotation, we get
a callback to mapView view for
annotation.
In these delegate methods, we'll
have the opportunity to
customize the appearance of the
indoor map elements.
And with that, let's start
building our dinosaur museum
app.
We'll start with a very basic
This is a single view
application based on MKMapView.
The first thing I want to do is
to make sure I have added my
IMDF files to the project.
And here they are.
In your application, you could
choose to either bundle these
files with your app or download
them from your servers.
Let's take a look at one of
these files.
This is for the Unit feature
type.
Our goal is to decode and render
the contents of this file.
I'll now write the abstract
class called Feature.
This has the three properties we
saw earlier.
Identifier, properties, and
geometry.
Our class is missing an
initializer, so let's add one.
Initialization is
straightforward with the
exception of properties.
MKGeoJSON feature exposes
property as opaque data, and we
must decode it before we can use
this.
We use the JSON decoder class to
decode our data and convert it
into adjacent object.
And now, I can write concrete
implementations of Feature
class.
We'll do that for the unit type.
Let's set the base class to be
Feature.
To describe the unit feature
type, we need to define some
properties.
It consists of category, which
is used to differentiate between
different kinds of unit and
level ID, which is the
identifier of the level this
unit belongs to.
Units have occupants and
amenities.
So let's add them here.
And that's all we needed to do
for the unit feature class.
Similar to unit, we can create
model classes for venue and
level and all the other feature
types that we wish to decode.
I've already implemented them
and added them to the project.
You can check them out by
downloading the sample code
provided for this session.
Okay, now we can move onto step
two, which is to decode the IMDF
data.
We'll do that in a class called
IMDFDecoder.
Let's add a property of type
MKGeoJSONDecoder.
This is the new class available
in the MapKit framework that you
can use to decode any GeoJSON
data.
I'll now write a method called
decodeFeatures that decodes a
single IMDF file.
In this method, we first read
the contents of the IMDF file
from disk and by using the
instance of MKGeoJSONDecoder,
we all the code on the data.
We get back an array of
MKGeoJSONFeature objects, which
we can use to initialize our
model classes.
I'll now write a method called
decode that decodes an IMDF
archive or a collection of IMDF
files.
Let's create the instances of
the feature objects that we wish
to decode such as venues and
levels and units, and we use the
decodeFeatures method I wrote
earlier in passing in the type
of feature I wish to decode.
To make it easier to render the
correct subset of features, we
need to create associations
between these feature objects.
For example, venue contains
levels.
So let's relate them.
We do that after grouping the
levels by the ordinal.
Levels contain units and
openings, so let's make that
association.
Both units and openings have a
property called levelID.
We group the units and levels by
the levelID, and then iterate
through all the levels of this
venue and find the units that
are contained in this level and
relate them.
And the same thing for the
openings.
Units contain amenities and
occupants, so let's create that
association.
We iterate through all the
amenities, find the unit it
belongs to, and make the
association.
In just the same way, we can
relate occupants to units as
well.
But there's one exception for
occupants.
Remember that we use occupants
to display a business' name on
the map, but they do not have
geometry of their own.
Instead, they rely on the anchor
object to get the display
point.
Okay.
So, now we have a decode method
that decodes and IMDF archive
and gives us a fully decoded and
configured venue object with
references to all the feature
types that we wish to render.
So now we can move onto step
three, which is to render the
IMDF data on a map.
We'll do that in our main view
controller class called
IndoorMapViewController.
Let's call the decode method
that we defined in step two, and
we get back a venue object, and
now we can add features on the
map as overlays and annotations.
And to do that, I'll write a
method called showFeaturesForOrdinal
where ordinal is an
integer representing the level's
position within total range of
floors in the building.
In this method, we first remove
all the overlays and annotations
that belong to a previous level
and then aggregate the subset of
features that we want to display
for the current level and
retrieve the geometry from those
feature objects and add them to
the map as overlays and
annotations.
Let's call this method from
our viewDidLoad.
We set the initial level to be
the one with ordinal one.
We've already implemented the
MKMapViewDelegate method,
mapView, render for overlay,
where we create instances of
MKOverlayRenderer for every
GeoJSON geometry type including
the new MKMultipolygonRenderer
and the new MKMultipolylineRenderer
for much more efficient
rendering of polygons and lines.
Let's run this app and see if we
have an indoor map.
Okay.
We have a very basic map of a
museum.
Let me zoom in a bit.
In this map, the units are shown
as polygons.
Amenities such as this restroom
is displayed as an annotation,
and occupants such as our
Jurassic Table Restaurant is
also displayed as an annotation.
Our museum is a multilevel
building, so it needs a level
picker.
Let's add one.
I've already added a level
picker to the story board.
It's a UIStackView based
level picker.
I'll make it visible.
And to receive the level picker
related update messages, we have
implemented a level picker
delegate, which has a method
called selected level did
change.
This method is called every time
the user taps to make a
selection in the level picker.
Let's handle the level change
event here.
When the level changes, we use
showFeaturesForOrdinal to
update the map with features for
the selected level.
Let's run and make sure we have
a level picker.
Okay.
I can now tap the items in the
level picker and see every
single level of this museum.
[ Applause ]
Let's pause for a moment here
and recap what we have done.
First, we created model classes
for all the IMDF feature types.
Then we decoded the IMDF data
using MKGeoJSONDecoder and
created association between the
feature types.
And finally, we rendered IMDF
data on a map view using
addOverlays and addAnnotation APIs
of the MapKit framework.
You might have already noticed
that our current map lacks any
styling, and the annotations
don't look very interesting.
You can significantly improve
the indoor map experience and
functionality with two
additional steps.
First, by applying style to your
indoor map elements.
Styling your map is critical to
how it is perceived and used.
Use distinct colors and icons
that match your app's team or
your company's brand.
And in the final step, we can
make your app more useful by
showing the user's current
location.
Remember that you can take
advantage of accurate indoor
location on iOS by participating
in the indoor maps program and
having your venue surveyed using
the Indoor Survey app.
Luckily, we had a team survey
our dinosaur museum, so we can
go ahead and add location or the
blue dot to the map.
Let's take a look at some of the
code that we'll write to help
with styling.
We'll define a protocol called
StylableFeature, which has a
property and two methods.
Every stylable feature must have
geometry.
And to apply styles to overlays,
we will implement the configure
overlay renderer method.
Similarly, to apply styles to
the annotations, we'll implement
the configure annotation view
method.
I'll switch to Xcode and show
you how this can be done.
To apply the styles, we'll take
advantage of the asset catalogue
where I have added colors very
specific to the indoor map we
are using here.
So, to apply these colors, I'll
go to a file called Styles.swift
where I have defined the
StylableFeature protocol.
Now, let's say we want to apply
some styling to the amenity
features.
We can do that by extending the
Amenity class to adopt the
StylableFeature protocol.
And because amenities have point
geometry, we will implement the
configure annotation view
method, where we set the
annotation view's background
color to a default fill color
from the asset catalogue.
We also take this opportunity to
set the display priority of the
annotation to a default low.
In a similar way, we can extend
the unit class to adopt the
StylableFeature protocol to
apply styling to units.
But for units, we want to apply
unique colors for every category
of units.
So, to do that, I will define
and enumeration type called
StylableCategory, and the
values in this are the category
names that we wish to style.
And because units have polygon
geometry, we will implement the
configure overlay renderer
method.
And in this method, we handle
the different values of the unit
category and apply different
fill colors to each one of them.
I'll now switch to the main view
controller class, and in my
mapView renderer for overlay
method, instead of using the
same stroke and fill color for
every polygon, we will now call
configure overlay renderer
method to apply feature-specific
styling.
In a similar way, for
annotations, I will call
configure annotation view and
apply feature-specific styles to
annotations.
We want to render occupants as a
simple dot and a label and the
amenities with just gray dots.
To do that, I have implemented
custom annotation views and
included them in the project.
Here, we're calling the
configure annotation view and
set the feature-specific style
to that annotation view.
So, let's run this app and see
if our map looks any different.
Okay.
This definitely looks better
than what we had before.
Now, we can see the different
units in different colors, and
the gray dots are our amenity
points.
And the occupants such as the
Jurassic Table Restaurant is
displayed with a dot and a
label.
But something is not right here.
This area on the map, I believe,
is a unit of category walkway,
and its color is not so
different from the other units
around it.
Let's see if we can fix that.
To do that, I'll go to the
Style.swift file and here let's
add a value of type, for the
walkway category.
And we must handle this in a
configure overlay renderer
method.
Where we are setting the color,
the fill color of the walkway to
a color called walkway fill,
which should be there in our
asset catalogue.
Let's make sure.
Okay.
We have a white color set for
that.
I'll run the app and see if we
have fixed that problem.
Okay.
Cool.
This definitely looks better.
Simply by applying a distinct
color to the walkways, the
appearance of our map has improved
significantly.
Let's make one more enhancement
here.
The gray dots for the amenities
are good, but I think icons are
better.
And what's better than icons?
Dinosaur icons.
So, let's use them.
Our designer has given us some
icons that we have included in
our project.
Let's add these to the map.
I'll go to my Styles.swift file,
and the dots we saw were for
amenities, so let's make a small
change here.
For convenience, we have set the
icon's name to be the same as
the name of the category for the
amenity.
So we look at the asset
catalogue for that particular
name.
If we find an icon, we set it to
the annotation view's image
property, but if we don't, then
we continue displaying the gray
dots.
Let's run the app and see.
Cool.
Now we have some
beautiful-looking icons on the
map, and we can clearly see
where the restrooms are and the
escalator and the elevator and
more importantly the exhibit
called T-Rex.
[ Applause ]
One last thing.
We know that we have indoor
location available at this
museum.
So let's take advantage of that.
Let's add the user's location to
the map.
To do so, I'll go to the map
view and enable the user
location from here.
In my view controller, first
I'll add a property of type
CLLocationManager and then use
this property to request the
user's permission to use
location services while the app
is in the foreground.
And every time we get a location
update, we get a callback to
MKMapViewDelegate method, mapView
did update user location.
So let's handle the location
updates.
First, we check to see if the
user is inside the venue.
If the user is inside, there's
no need to update the map.
If the user is outside, there's
no need to update the map, but
if the user is inside, then we
use the CLLocation property on
MKUserLocation to get the
user's coordinates.
CLLocation not only provides
the user's longitude and
latitude but also the floor
information if your venue has
been surveyed and the user is
inside that location.
So, we'll use the floor
information from the CLLocation
object and update our map using
the showFeaturesForOrdinal to
display the user's location.
Let's run the app one more time.
I'll hit allow, and here we have
the user's indoor location.
[ Applause ]
I must mention that if the user
were to switch between levels,
the map will update the user's
current level.
And that's all I have for you in
this demo.
I'll now hand over to Stephane,
who will show you how to display
and indoor map in a web app.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
With MapKit JS we can achieve
similar indoor maps look and
feel on the web.
I will demonstrate how to render
our map with MapKit JS and bring
the same indoor maps experience
to all major browser
implementations.
The key MapKit JS method that we
will use for this demo is import
GeoJSON.
ImportGeoJSON takes two
parameters.
The first one is the GeoJSON
feature to convert and the
second one is GeoJSON delegate
object that allows us to
customize how items are created.
In this basic example, we have
two delegates.
GeoJSONDidError that allows us
to react on errors and GeoJSON
did complete that gives us an
array of the items that were
just created.
Then we show these items by
giving them to the showItems
method.
We can also use addItems;
the difference being that add
items does not center the map on
the added elements.
In order to style the overlays,
like polygons and lines, we can
use styleForOverlay.
It takes a newly created overlay
as a parameter and expects a
style object to be returned.
We can, of course, craft a brand
new one, but we can also use the
default one that is associated
with the overlay through the
style property and customize it.
We can also customize how points
are rendered with item for
point.
ItemForPoint takes a
coordinate of the point feature
as a parameter and should return
an item.
Here, we return a marker
annotation.
We can, of course, set options
like the title and the color.
We can also set the display
priority.
When the zoom level is too low
and that many annotations are
present on the map, they may
collide.
There are multiple strategies to
deal with this issue like
annotation clustering or
display priorities.
MapView JS may use display
priorities to decide what
annotations it should hide
first.
With importGeoJSON we had
everything that needed to create
our dinosaur map.
So let's get started.
Alright. So we start off our
project with a simple mapView.
I'm running an HTTP server that
serves our web
assets and is responsible for
generating the MapKit JS
authorization token.
To draw the dinosaur map on the
browser, we need to load the
IMDF files and create MapKit
items for each feature they
contain.
That sounds like a difficult
task, but it's really not thanks
to the importGeoJSON method
that we just saw and the fact
that IMDF uses GeoJSON.
In the iOS demo, you saw
that we created a graph of
features.
In this demo, we will take a
slightly different approach by
filtering the features on
demand.
We will create a class called
IMDF archive that will provide
the essential methods to load,
organize, and filter the
features.
The static load method downloads
all the files that we need from
the server, then aggregates the
features into an array and
passes that array to the
constructor, and then we create
two objects, featureById and
featuresByType.
They will help us afterwards.
Now we can call this method to
load our features, and we can
use import GeoJSON to create
MapKit items for each of
them.
Okay.
And now what we have to do is to
call showItems with these newly
created map items.
So let's do that.
Okay.
Let's try.
There is a lot of geometries
showing up on our map, and
that's expected because we asked
MapKit JS to render all the
features in our venue.
What we need to do is to retain
only the feature types that we
want and to filter them by
level.
So let's implement a few methods
in our IMDFArchive class
that returns only the features
of a certain type on a given
ordinal.
We'll start with levels.
Okay.
So we retain only the levels
that have the right ordinal, and
similarly we can do the same
thing for units.
Okay.
Same thing with the level ID.
And we can do also the same
thing for amenities in units,
openings on level, and amenities
and anchors on level.
Let's pause for a moment here.
The fact that IMDF files are
plain old GeoJSON makes
our job so easy.
There is not complicated parsing
or decoding logic.
We only have to know what
properties we expect depending
on the feature type.
Okay, so now let's rewrite our
rendering logic.
We will create a function called
createItemsForOrdinal that
will create the items for a
given ordinal.
Now, what we need to do is to
get the features for that
ordinal.
So let's start with levels,
okay, and for each of these
levels, we will get all the
units and similarly amenities
and openings.
Okay.
So that's all the features that
we are interested into right
now.
Okay.
And now what we need to do is to
show them.
So, we call create items for
ordinal with an ordinal, let's
say ordinal 1, which would be
second floor and add them to the
map.
Alright.
Let's write that.
Okay.
So, that's a lot better.
Now we have a clean view over
the structure of the second
floor.
Now, let's add a level picker.
I already implemented a simple
level picker that is just a basic
HTML list.
That's what I did with level
names of our venue.
You can check out the
implementation details in the
sample code that's linked to
this session.
The level picker will use our
createItemsForOrdinal
function to create items if
needed.
I already imported the script, so
the only thing that I need to do
here is to instantiate it and
select the ordinal 1, so that
the second floor shows up when
the page is loaded.
Let's try again.
Okay.
So, now I can switch between
floors.
Okay, so now what we need to do
is to add some styling.
All units look the same,
and we cannot even distinguish
the opening LineStrings from the
rest of the geometries, which
gives us the false impression
that all the units don't have
any doors.
That's a bit confusing.
We can customize the style of
polygons and lines by
implementing the style for
overlay function in the GeoJSON
delegate object.
So, let's start by drawing our
openings in white.
Okay.
So that's really simple.
We just select the opening
features and we set the stroke
color to white.
And as we did in the iOS app,
let's set a fill color to units
depending on their category.
In order to do that, let's
create an object called unit
style.
Okay.
So that object will contain the
styling properties for each unit
category that we want to show.
But we also need a default one
if we don't have a style for
some categories, so let's do
that first.
Okay, and now we can set the
styles for the unit categories
that we care about.
Okay.
So, now we can go ahead and use
that object to apply a style to
unit overlays.
Okay.
So what we do here is to get the
proper unit style with the
category and set fillOpacity,
strokeColor, and fillColor to
the style values or setting the
default if there isn't.
That's actually a good example
of how easy it can be to render
IMDF maps.
Most of the styling can be done
by using a combination of the
feature type and the category.
Of course, we can also rely on
all other properties as well.
Okay.
So, let's see the changes.
That's a lot better.
Now we can see where the
walkways are and what units our
visitors can access to.
Now, you may also have noticed
all these red pins on the map.
They are amenities.
Remember, amenities have point
geometries, and importGeoJSON
renders point geometries with
marker annotations by default.
So, what we would really like to
have here is using the same
icons as we did in the iOS app.
For that, we will use MapKit JS
ImageAnnotations.
As we saw earlier, we can
replace the default behavior of
importGeoJSON by providing our
own implementation of item for
point.
So let's do that.
Okay.
So what we do here is inserting
a name from the properties or
fall back to the category if
there isn't and use that name as
a title of our annotation.
When the annotation is clicked,
the title will appear in the
callout.
We also set a relatively low
priority to all amenities so
that we can set a higher one to
the more important amenities,
which are exhibits.
We'll do that in a short while.
And finally, if there is, if we
have a URL for our icon, we
create an image annotation.
But if there isn't, we create a
dot annotation.
I already implemented a simple
dot annotation in a separate
file, and I already imported it.
So, we can use it here.
Okay, so what we have to do here
is to provide the right URL for
the icons depending on the
category.
So, let's create an object for
that called iconUrls.
Okay.
So that's pretty
straightforward.
And now we can use that object
to get the URL for our icon.
Okay. You may also have noticed
that some of the entries here
are really specific.
They are not amenity categories.
They are icons for our T-rex,
sauropod, and bone hall
exhibits.
So, we need to handle them a bit
differently.
So what we do here is test the
name, and if this is the right
name, we set the right icon.
Of course, we can also use the
feature ID if we want here.
We also set a higher priority
for all exhibits, and the
highest of all for the T-rex
exhibit.
And last but not least, we also
append the matching unicode
character to the name of the
exhibits.
And yes, you heard that right,
there is actually a unicode
character for dinosaurs and
T-rexes.
Okay.
So let's reload and see how it
renders on a map.
Okay, so now that's a map that's
worthy of Dinoseum!
[ Applause ]
And look, between, if I zoom out
very, very, very, very far, here
is our last annotation standing,
the dinosaur exhibit.
Alright.
So, of course what we can also
do is to restrict the capacity
of the users to zoom out too
far.
We can do that with a new
setting from MapKit JS, which
is cameraZoomRange.
Okay.
So let's try that again and see
if we can zoom out now.
No, we can't.
That's great.
Okay.
So the last feature type that we
want to handle here is
occupants.
Remember, it's a bit more
challenging though because
occupants do not have a display
point.
But they are linked to anchors,
and anchors have display points.
So we can use the associated
anchor to get the coordinate to
place our MapKit annotation
on the map.
So, let's implement a method in
our ImdfArchive class that
gathers all occupants on a
certain ordinal along with their
anchors.
Okay.
So that method returns an array
of objects containing the
occupant and its associated
anchor.
So, now let's use it to render
the occupants.
As you can see here, it's fairly
similar to what we did for
amenities with one exception.
We don't provide the occupant by
itself to the importGeoJSON
method, but anchor because
anchor has the geometry.
We use the occupant name to set
the title of the annotation.
And I also set a specific class
based on the category, so
category-annotation,
so that I can give a specific
style to some categories of
occupants.
I already provided a style in
our CSS file.
Okay.
So let's reload one last time.
Now we can see the Jurassic
Table, which is our famous
in-house restaurant.
[ Applause ]
Okay, let's recap what we did.
First, we downloaded the GeoJSON
files from the server, extracted
the features from them and
organized them by type.
Then, we implemented a few
methods to get features of a
certain type on a given ordinal.
Then, we added a level picker so
that our users are able to
choose what level they want to
see.
And we provided a custom style
to units and openings.
And finally, we created icons
and custom annotations instead of
these default marker annotations
for amenities and occupants.
With MapKit JS we were able to
build a map that shares the same
look and feel as its iOS
counterpart.
Now we have a beautiful map that
we can embed in the Dinoseum
website and provide the same
user experience on all the major
browser implementations.
And on that note, I will hand
over to Mithilesh to conclude.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello again.
I hope you like what you saw
today.
Before we end this session, I'd
like to go through some of the
best practices that apply to
indoor maps.
Let's talk about styling.
You should design an indoor map
that feels like a natural
extension of your app.
Use colors and icons that match
your app's theme or your
company's brand.
Don't try to replicate the
appearance of Apple Maps or
another application.
Instead, make sure the overlays,
icons, and labels match the
visual style of your app.
Select distinct styles to
differentiate the features of
your map.
Using specific color for
categories such as elevator area
makes it easy for people to spot
them at a glance.
Use easily recognizable icons.
Icons should not only be visually
appealing but should also be
effective in communicating their
purpose.
You should adjust the map detail
based on zoom level.
Too much detail can cause the
map to appear cluttered.
Show large areas like rooms and
buildings at all zoom levels,
then progressively add more
detail features and labels as
the map is zoomed in.
You should include surrounding
areas to provide context.
Adjacent streets, playgrounds,
and other locations can help
people orient when they use your
map.
And finally and very
importantly, enable indoor user
location on iOS to enhance the
indoor map experience when your
users visit the venue.
For more information, you may
check out the related sessions,
What's New in MapKit and MapKit
JS and Introducing the Apple
Maps Program.
If you have any comments or
questions, visit us at the lab
right after this session.
Thank you very much for coming
out today, and I hope you have
had a great conference.
[ Applause ]