[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. My name is Alex Schaefer,
and I'm an engineer on the iOS
system UI team.
And this is Targeting Content
with Multiple Windows.
To get a sense of the problem
we're going to talk about today,
let's take a quick detour to iOS
12.
In iOS 12, we had a 1-to-1
mapping between your application
and your user interface.
Let's say a notification comes
in.
The user taps on it.
It gets routed to your app, and
your app will update your user
interface in response.
Great.
What could be different?
Well, in iOS 13, you could have
multiple user interfaces running
which raises the question -
Which scene should activate in
response to this notification?
Well, I know what you're all
saying.
Just ask my app.
Well, I guess.
But what if your app isn't
running?
Who cares?
Just launch my app.
Well, hold your horses.
iOS needs to know which scene in
your application should be
frontmost and activated in
response to that launch event,
like that incoming notification.
So, if we're going to background
launch your app and ask for the
appropriate scene, we'd have to
wait until your app is fully
loaded and then wait again until
you could've made that
determination.
This could lead to a
less-than-desirable user
experience.
The system would basically grind
to a halt waiting for that
feedback.
And when I tap a notification, I
expect it to go somewhere
immediately.
So, what could we do about that?
Well, let's take a step back and
let's think about what we have
to work with with the system.
We have your application.
Maybe it's running, maybe it
isn't.
Your app has your scenes and
also the knowledge of the
capabilities of each scene.
That's going to come in handy.
And finally, the system has this
incoming notification.
We've talked about why we can't
rely on activating your app, and
we know that the notification
has to somehow trigger an
appropriate scene to be
activated.
So, let's try and pull together
a solution, given these
constraints.
First, we need to find a way to
describe what that notification
pertains to.
So, let's add some of the
notification that lets the
system know what it is about.
Then we need to get your scenes
to describe somehow something
about their capabilities.
You know, what kind of content
they can show.
Well, if your scenes are
describing what kind of content
they can work with to the
system, and the notification has
this hint about what it's about,
then we don't really need your
app.
The system is informed enough to
make a selection of a desired
scene to activate in response to
this notification.
So, to think about that and
think about those capabilities,
we need to think about what's,
what those capabilities are.
And those capabilities are
housed within this UIKit class,
UI Scene Activation Conditions.
This is an object attached to
UIScene.
And your scene activation
conditions are really just a
couple of NS predicates that set
the course for what specific
scene can activate for it.
Let's dig into the API.
So, your activation condition
consists of two parts, your
canned predicate and your
preferred predicate.
You should think of the canned
predicate as the main predicate
of the two.
This is expressing to the system
what kind of content the scene
can display.
Your prefers predicate is a way
to express to the system that
this scene is especially
interested in a particular type
of content.
You should think of canned as
expressing capability and prefer
is a way to delineate amongst
the capable scenes the content
that should be chosen.
I've told you these predicates
help you define your
capabilities, but I haven't
really gone into detail about
what these predicates operate
on.
These predicates operate on
something called target content
identifiers.
You might be asking yourself
what that is.
Target content identifier is a
string.
It's just the string.
But, it's a little bit more
complicated than that.
A target content identifier is a
structured way to represent data
within your model.
The system's not going to access
your model - that's your job.
But what we're going to use that
for is a way to build off these
scene activation conditions.
iOS 13 is going to use that
target content identifier and
evaluate it against your scene
activation conditions for all
the scenes your application has
and use it that to make the call
on what scene the content should
be targeted to.
Clown Town is our exciting demo
application which answers the
age old question - What would it
be like to order a clown at any
time to my current location?
So, let's take a look at what a
target content identifier might
look like for Clown Town.
So, this looks exactly like a
URL.
In this case, Clown Town is
actually using a universal link.
Like we were saying, target
content identifiers should
ideally express in a structured
format, just like a universal
link or URL.
Many of you are already using a
universal link and that'll be
great here as your target
content identifier.
Let's take a look where in the
SDK target content identifiers
have been added.
First, UNNotification Content.
New in iOS 13, you can actually
augment your JSON payload prior
to sending it off to the Apple
Push notification server with a
new key, Target Content ID.
So, this raises also a very
important point.
You can actually structure this
target content identifier the
same on your back-end server and
actually pinpoint what scene
that notification should open up
in.
Next, UI application shortcut
item has been extended to allow
for using target content
identifiers.
New in iPad OS this year, you
can actually long press on an
icon in the homescreen and get
the same quick actions you've
been using on your iPhone.
And finally, NS user activity.
Use this date restoration as
well as features like handoff
could also be very useful there.
So, let's set up that scene in
Clown Town in response to that
target content identifier we
just talked about.
Up top we have our target
content identifier.
It's our URL format and it looks
like it's geared towards a clown
named Crusty.
Okay.
On your left, we have a general
overview of all clowns we can
order in the area.
This is our main scene and where
all content in our application
lives.
The user's really unlikely to
associate Crusty with this
scene.
I think it would be ideal to set
this scene's activation
conditions up in such a way that
it can display anything but
doesn't prefer anything
specifically.
And that makes sense.
It's my main scene and where I
enter into my application, it
has all my content.
Lucky for us, that's actually
the default when you create a
new scene.
Your UIScene Activation
conditions will be set up to
allow any content, or can allow
any content, but not prefer
anything specifically.
Alright.
On your right, we have a scene
set up just for Crusty.
This scene can display any
specific clown's details but
it's likely the user would
associate Crusty with this scene
specifically.
So, we should express that
association within our scene
activation conditions, as the
scene can be activated, and we
prefer it to be activated
specifically for Crusty.
So, let's take these
requirements and put together
some scene activation conditions
for our Detail scene.
Okay, let's break this down.
For this scene, we want to only
activate if this scene is about
Crusty.
And so we're just going to check
to see if the target content
identifier that's passed in is
equal to the one we would expect
for Crusty.
Cool.
Now, you'll note that this is a
place where we actually use the
same predicate for our can and
our prefers.
This is a pretty common pattern
you'll find yourself using when
you want to target a scene for a
specific piece of content.
Sure, we could accept any other
clown here.
It's just a detail scene.
But if I have a notification
come in, I want it to be
targeted to exactly where Crusty
is.
Cool.
So, let's talk about what
happens when we set these
predicates.
When I set the Crusty predicate
on our scene activation
condition, the system's going to
package these predicates up and
ship them off to somewhere else
in the operating system.
That has a couple repercussions
for how NSPredicate is used
within scene activation
conditions and I'd like to go
over them right now.
Scene activation conditions have
three restrictions with its use
of NSPredicate.
First, block-based predicates
aren't allowed.
Unfortunately, we can't package
up code within your running
application and ship it out to
other parts of the system.
Next, regular expression-based
predicates aren't allowed.
We can't use them because they
could introduce an indeterminate
amount of time during the
evaluation of your scene
predicates.
We encourage you to take a look
at the like operator.
It's the de facto glob operator
to NSPredicate and it should
help you do all the kinds of
wildcard matching you might want
to do.
With that being said, if you
have a unique thought on how you
might use a regular expression
predicate, please use the
feedback assistant and inform us
of what you're thinking.
We'd really like to hear about
it.
And finally, the only keypath
your NSPredicate can reference
is self.
Which is to say, you're not
going to set your scene
activation requirement
predicates on something along
the lines of the length of the
string or your target content
identifier.
We want you to put real content
that you could actually use in
your model there.
Next, let's take a look at
another example for what their
scene activation conditions
might look like for our commonly
used app architecture.
Let's talk about what a tabbed
application might do like
Safari.
You'll see that Safari here has
two tabs open, each analogous to
their own document.
And we should sort of think of
each tab, since they're their
own document, as having their
own target content identifier.
But note, if we have two of
these target content identifiers
up on screen and we want to set
it on our scene activation
conditions as something we
prefer, how would we do that?
First, let's examine the canned
predicate.
Simple enough.
Document-based apps can
typically open any kind of
documents in your application.
So to encode that, we actually
use an always true predicate
here to describe that any scene
can display any content passed
to it.
What kind of content does it
prefer?
Because this UI has multiple
tabs, it makes sense that we'd
use something like a compound
predicate in order to gather all
the subpredicates within it.
And then we'll use that with our
scene activation conditions.
Great.
Well, for more information,
please visit
developer.apple.com.
We have all of our slides and
notes and you can go there and
get some more information about
that.
And really, thank you for
coming.
It has been a tremendous WWDC
and we are so thrilled to see
what you guys make with these
new APIs.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]