[ Music ]
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone, and welcome
to our session on Swift
Playgrounds 3.
My name is Grace Kendall.
&gt;&gt; My name Joy Forbes.
&gt;&gt; And my name is Jonathan Penn.
We're all engineers working on
Swift Playgrounds and we are so
excited to talk about the new
features that you can use to
build ideas right on iPad with
Swift.
And we'll demonstrate some
techniques that you can use to
build even more engaging
Playground experiences.
&gt;&gt; Swift Playgrounds is an app
that you can write Swift code in
as well as learn from content
that other authors have made.
The code that you write is real
Swift and it's compiled and run
all on the iPad by the app.
&gt;&gt; Playgrounds you've created or
downloaded show up in your list
of documents as shown here.
And the more Playground section
at the bottom shows other
Playgrounds that are similar to
the content you already have.
If you tap the See All button,
you'll see all the content
available for download from
Apple and the other feeds that
you're subscribed to.
You can also browse featured
subscriptions in the From Other
Publishers section at the
bottom.
&gt;&gt; Apple has published six new
pieces of content in Swift
Playgrounds 3.
The Learn to Code family has
expanded with Lights, Camera,
Code, Assemble Your Camera, and
Flashy Photos.
These and the starting point
Camera Create introduce the
concept of building with
components to create things like
cameras and photo editors.
This Sonic Workshop challenge
and Sonic Create starting point
use touch events on iPad to
compose music and create visual
soundscapes.
&gt;&gt; Today, we'll be reviewing
some of the exciting new
features in Swift Playgrounds 3.
I'll be going through the
breadth of development that you
can do just on iPad, and then
Joy will talk about some of the
new features available to
authors on the Mac.
But first, Jonathan is going to
show us a demo that exemplifies
the power of Swift Playgrounds 3
for developers.
Jonathan?
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Grace.
[ Applause and Cheering ]
I would like to demonstrate how
powerful this tool can be as a
scratchpad for ideas with a
little bit of fun.
These devices are quite nifty.
I am personally very excited
about the sensors that it has
like the accelerometer.
I'm a big fun of games that use
the accelerometer to do cool
things and bring a sense of
physicality to what's going on,
on the screen.
So, I'm going to show some steps
that I took to build an infinite
scrolling marble obstacle course
from scratch on an iPad all in
Swift Playgrounds.
If you've ever played one of
those tiny puzzle games where
you've got a roll around a
marble and not fall into any
holes, it's just something like
that.
We need a few things to make
this work like a marble that
response to the tilting motion
of an iPad.
We'll need a procedurally
generated map of holes that the
player guides the marble pass.
And to keep things simple, the
goal is just to get as far as
possible, as fast as possible
without falling into a hole and
out of the course.
There's a bunch involved in
building something like this.
I'm going to focus on a few
steps in the process using, of
course, Swift Playgrounds to
read the raw accelerometer data,
experimenting with the in line
results to do that, using the
live view to learn about the
SpriteKit game in physics
engine, experiment with how to
do this procedural hole
generation placement throughout
the course, and then, we'll add
it all up and take a look at the
full prototype.
Let's get started.
All right.
Let's begin with a blank page.
Every page in a Swift
Playgrounds document is its own
execution entry point.
It's a main .SWF file.
I love to use separate pages.
It's like a journal of my
travels as I'm trying to either
solve a problem or learn a new
API, just figuring something
out.
I'll start with one subsystem or
working on a function or
something over here, and then
move to a new page.
It's a completely blank slate
where I can work on the next
idea leaving behind a trail that
I can return to further
experimentation.
Now, our chief mechanic is the
tilting motion of the iPad.
So, we should probably start by
importing CoreMotion.
We'll create a CMMotionManager.
Now, I'm using the Tab key of
the hardware keyboard to select
the different options in this
shortcuts bar at the bottom for
code completion.
And then I'm pressing the Return
key to select it.
We'll tell the manager to start
up by saying
startAccelerometerUpdates.
Now, I don't know about you but
I never remember which of the
xyz coordinates of the
accelerometer corresponds to how
the iPad is supposed to move in
this orientation.
It's always confusing to me.
But hey, let's figure it out
right here.
We need to wait a brief moment
before we can start.
The accelerometer has to take
time to spin up.
We'll worry about reading this
thing regularly later.
Right now, we just want to get
an experiment going to see if we
get a value out of this thing.
So, I will tell the manager that
I want the accelerometer data,
the acceleration property, and
the x-coordinate.
By putting it on its own line,
this line gets logged, the
expression gets logged and turns
into an inline result on the
right-hand side.
We can see this here when I tap
around my code.
All four lines get an inline
result.
I'm going to tap on the last
icon here for the last line.
Hey, we see a value, negative
0.78.
That means something.
Well, let me try this here.
I'll tilt the iPad and try
running it again and see what
value comes out now.
It says, hey, negative 0.061.
That's a different number.
So somewhere in here, we're
getting some sort of reaction
that I think is related to the
movement of the iPad.
This is a start.
But I'd really like to have some
sort of real time feedback to
give me an idea of what's going
on.
So let's fast forward to the
next page where I've prepared an
example to try out.
Usually, when you run a
Playground page, as the program
counter reaches the very end,
execution stops.
You can restart whenever you
want by just tapping around my
code.
And that's useful in many cases.
But in this case, I would like
the execution to continue so I
can gather values over time.
And because of that, I'm using
the Playground Support API to
tell the current page that I
need indefinite execution.
We create the CMMotionManager
just like before, we tell the
accelerometer to start.
And here, I wrote a simple
function, just to helper
function called repeatEvery that
takes a trailing closure, calls
the closure immediately, and
then schedules calling it again
after the given time interval
but using the asyncAfter method
on the name dispatch queue.
It's crude a way of repeating
things, I know.
But, you know what, we're just
experimenting and it works
great.
I can reuse this wherever I need
to on this page.
And I'm using it right here.
Every half a second, this
trailing closure gets called and
as soon as the accelerometer
data is not nil, we log the
x-coordinate using that
expression on this line.
Let's take a look and see what
happens when I tap around my own
code.
All right, we have things
happening on the screen.
Let me tap on the inline result
and look what happens here.
A graph representation is
automatically selected for us
because this is a sequence of
simple numeric values.
I'm going to pick this up and
move it around.
Whoa, we have things, stuff.
All right.
I'm going to try to get a
baseline here.
I'm going to hold it flat and
then I'm going to tilt it
upright.
I will tilt it down.
OK. I think we've kind of
figured this out.
The x-coordinate of the
accelerometer corresponds to
movement along this axis of the
iPad in this orientation.
All right, there we go.
I could do the same thing to
figure out how y and z work as
well.
This is quite useful.
Now, this repeatEvery function
[applause].
Thank you.
This repeatEvery function is
nice.
It's is crude of course but it's
terse.
It's clear.
And I'm going to use it other
places until I figure out how to
do it the right way.
That's fine.
Well, because I created this as
a blank playground in Swift
Playgrounds 3, I have access to
the new tabbed editing
experience.
Let me show you.
I'm going to tap on the File
icon up in the Navigation bar,
and then I'm going to tap on the
Utilities Module.
This brings up the user module
and source file picker.
And you can see I've already
done a lot of things in here as
I was working on this idea.
Well, in the Utilities Module,
I'm going to put that function
in here, make a Timing.swift
file.
I'll tap on the Tab for the main
file of the page to go back.
I will tap on the repeatEvery
function to select it.
If I tap and hold, I can pick it
up.
And with my other hand, I will
tap on the Timing Tab, and then
let go to drop this piece of
code as a copy in its place in
this file.
Because this is a new file,
Swift has no idea what time
interval or dispatch queue you
are, I'm going to have to tell
it by importing foundation so it
knows what to do with those
symbols.
And because I want to use this
function everywhere on every
page and possibly even in other
modules, I need to mark this
function as public so it's
visible.
Now, I can go back to the main
file, tap to select the
function, delete it, and if I
did it right, everything should
work.
All right, there we go.
Yay. Now, I can open as many
files as I need to, to
experiment on different ideas.
Like, let's try this one here,
Math.swift.
I threw a bunch of bits and
pieces in here as I was going
just to help me experiment.
These are math helper functions
and a few extensions on system
types that made writing the code
more fluent at the point that I
was using it, just part of the
process.
I can tap and drag to reorder
the tabs, tap the Close button
to close them.
And all of this code is
available for use anywhere in
this document.
Quite convenient.
Now, let's fast forward a bit
more in this story.
I've been poking around a bit
with SpriteKit, refreshing my
memory about how it works.
Let's see how far I've gotten on
the next page.
I needed to bring up the
documentation for SpriteKit.
So I did that by tapping on the
Tools Menu icon in the
Navigation Bar and choosing
Documentation.
I searched for it by tapping on
the magnifying glass and search
for SpriteKit.
By reading through this, I was
able to refresh my memory of how
this works, built up this body
of code on the left-hand side of
the screen.
I learned about SpriteKit's
scenes and nodes, that SpriteKit
uses to layout everything in the
game and render it on the
screen.
I learned about the physics
engine and how you can apply
forces to nodes so that the
physics mechanism starts working
over time.
And I learned about the game
loop when SpriteKit calls my
code back on every frame so that
I can affect changes in the
environment.
That last point is very
important.
Let me close the side panel and
open up the Execution Controls
Menu at the bottom.
Because SpriteKit calls me back
on every frame, I have to be
quick, and I'm going to turn off
the inline result.
As we've seen, they're quite
useful in many cases, but the
logging of those expressions
takes time.
I don't want to slow SpriteKit
down in this case, and I don't
even need them.
Because as you'll see, when I
tap run my code, SpriteKit I set
it up as the live view.
SpriteKit itself is giving me
the feedback that I needed while
working on this part.
And here you go, we have a
circle shape thingy moving
around in response to tilting
the iPad.
All right.
Now, this is an important part
of the story because--
[applause] thank you-- once you
get something like this going,
once you've got this kind of
physical stuff happening on the
screen, you've got to take this
out and do user testing, right?
So I took this to my kids.
And as I started to tell them,
hey, do you want to see
something cool, they interrupted
me, grab the iPad out of my
hands and started looking at it,
and tilting it around to watch
it bounce around the screen.
And they were amused.
They said, "This is nice,
father.
This is very nice."
[Laughter]
But it's missing something.
You see, there are not enough
marbles on the screen.
We need more marbles, lots and
lots of marbles.
They have a future in project
management, all right
[laughter].
This had nothing to do with my
ultimate goal but it did sound
kind of cool.
We should get more marbles.
So I added the tap, just to
recognize and I sat down with
them.
We did this together.
And so, every time you tap now
on the screen, we insert a new
SpriteKit node into the scene
and add it to the physics engine
so that it will participate in
all the fun forces going on
here.
Now, this is usually how it
went.
The younger the child, the more
furiously they would tap to try
to fill this thing up as fast as
they could and they wanted to
see if it would crash.
It didn't.
And then they would just make
this thing go and slosh it
around.
And I'm not going to lie, I find
this absolutely mesmerizing.
I can look at this all--
[Sound Effect]
I'll do that later.
[ Laughter and Applause ]
I would recommend you do it too.
It's very relaxing.
So anyway, we have SpriteKit now
doing something in response to
the accelerometer that's on the
iPad as you tilt it around.
This is close.
We're getting a feel for how
this game could work, and it's
getting more and more exciting.
But now, I need to figure out
how to do this procedural whole
generation.
Now remember, this is a trench
that has the holes laid out that
the marble is supposed to go
pass and avoid them.
And we probably want to remember
the holes that we put down.
So if the user happens to scroll
backwards for some reason, they
can revisit the holes they saw
before.
So let's jump ahead to see an
experiment that I was working
on.
Now, while building this page, I
decided to go into my game
module and create a MapStruct.
This goal of this type was just
to calculate and remember where
the holes go as you're
proceeding through the course.
It basically breaks up the map
into a grid of columns and then
places the holes inside there.
It's really simple.
This could easily be swapped out
for something more intricate or
complicated if I want.
Eh, it works for now.
And also in the Game Engine
Module, I created a MapNode that
receives a map and knows how to
layout the whole nodes at
different points along the
course.
All you have to do is pass it a
rectangle that represents where
the camera is and the viewport
of the-- that the user sees.
As soon as you do that, it will
render the holes in that spot
reusing nodes if it needs to.
It kind of acts like UI table
view, stuff like that.
So, let me run the code here and
we'll see how this works.
We get some inline results on
the right-hand side, and I'm
going to tap to view this
preview.
I wrote this preview method on
the MathNode myself because I
wanted to generate an SKView,
the UIView subclass that shows
SpriteKit scenes.
I wanted to generate it and put
it here so it can just show up
as a static inline result.
I didn't have to build any extra
plumbing to show this up.
It's just right there ready to
go.
And now, we see if the whole
diameter is 20 points wide and
we're at this point in the
course, this is the map density
you'll get.
I can experiment with this
density anyway I want and tweak
the values here, jump into the
other files and tweak those two.
And the inline results gave me
the feedback that I needed at
this point.
Now, we're ready.
Let's skip ahead even further to
the final point where we see the
game.
Now before I start, I have to
turn off the inline results
again.
As before, we're doing a lot of
work on every frame.
And we don't need the expression
logging and we don't want it to
slow us down.
I'll tap around my code, and
there it is.
We have a marble looking thing
on top of a wall looking thing
with parallax.
Look at this, lovely stuff.
Now, when I was working on this
idea, Joy reminded me that
there's a bunch of textures that
I can grab out of the templates
that you can download right in
the app just, you know, grab
those resources and have fun
with them.
So I pulled up the sensor create
template, used the asset picker,
pulled out some of these
textures and dropped them in my
app.
And here they are.
I even went over to a-- an image
editing app to find-- there we
go, make some fuzzy looking hole
shape things.
Oh, that's all right.
It's amazing what radial
gradients can do.
It's so cool.
Here, let me tap in the middle
and make this full screen by
dragging the midpoint all the
way over to the left.
And I'm going to try this again.
I added the tap recognizer to
start over if the game ends.
And let's see how far I get.
The faster you go, the faster it
increases the score to add a
little bit of recklessness to
the fun here.
Whoa, OK.
It's really hard to do this in
front of a crowd [laughs].
But, hey, you know what, all of
what you've seen here, each step
leading up to this point was
done entirely on this iPad.
This was a lot of fun.
My family had a great kick out
of it.
I learned more about SpriteKit.
I had a chance to use the new
user module and source file
support in the app to break up
what I was doing into different
pieces.
It was a fantastic experience.
Swift Playgrounds on iPad is a
great scratchpad to try out your
ideas, maybe even look and use
our APIs and see how they work,
or even increase the stress in
your life by building speed
running games to play with your
friends.
And now, I would like to invite
Grace back up to the stage so
that she can talk about how this
stuff works and do a deep dive
into how you can use these new
features to make the most of
Swift Playgrounds 3.
Thank you.
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jonathan.
So, if you're already familiar
with Swift Playgrounds, you
might have noticed a couple of
new things in Jonathan's demo.
Let's go through those now.
Most notably is the addition of
Modules, which allow you to
separate your code into multiple
Swift files.
Modules are represented as
directories of Swift code that
can be used by any page in a
book.
And you don't need to worry
about setting targets or making
new build settings.
Users can add modules to books
as well as Swift files to any
module.
Be aware though that if you
reset a document, all of the
user edits are reset as well.
And this does include any added
files or modules.
So with the opportunity for all
of these new files, let's go
through the structure of a
Playground.
I'll be using the shapes
template as an example.
Each book has a set of pages,
and each book can also have
multiple modules.
Each of these modules in turn
can have multiple source files.
So, let's quickly talk about the
access levels between all of
these different Swift files.
Code in pages is not shared to
other pages within a book.
That is to say, the code on the
Canvas page is not shared with
the code on the Create page.
However, every module is
automatically imported into each
page.
This means that the code in your
modules is accessible on every
page as long as that code is
marked as public.
Files within the same module
have access to each other
without needing to mark code as
public.
However, if code is marked as
private, it won't be visible to
other files in other modules or
pages.
It'll just be private to that
file.
Code between modules is not
shared by default.
But let's say I have some code
in my Graphics Module that I
want to reference in my
Calculus.swift file which is in
my Math Module.
All I have to do is make sure
the Graphics code is marked as
public, and then import the
Graphics Module into my
Calculus.swift file.
With modules, you'll still have
access to inline results and
step through execution.
So you can watch the path that
your code takes between all of
your files.
As the app steps through your
code, it automatically switches
between the files where your
code is executing.
You can also turn off inline
results which can speed up
execution as we saw in
Jonathan's demo.
You can find this control within
the Execution Control Menu along
with Step Through My Code and
Step Slowly.
The new Issues popover can show
you errors throughout all of
your files in a document and
allow you to easily navigate
between them.
If you tap on any of the errors,
it'll take you right to the
corresponding line, both for
builds and for runtime errors.
Swift Playgrounds support Swift
5 and the iOS 12.2 SDK.
This lets you play with
frameworks like Core ML 2 and
ARKit 2, developing for iOS
right on iOS.
So now, all from a blank
Playground, you can add pages
through the Table of Contents
popover, add modules, and add
Swift source files to those
modules all without ever leaving
the app.
So there are also lots of ways
to customize your content, like
setting module modes, adding
localizable code comments, and
changing what files the user
sees when they open your
document.
So I'd next like to invite my
colleague Joy to the stage to
tell you how.
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Grace.
Next, let's talk about all the
new features authors can
customize in Xcode whether
you're sharing your Playground
directly or through a
subscription.
When I'm teaching, it's
important for the tools I give
my students to be leveled
appropriately and as user
friendly as possible.
In order to create the right
tool for your audience at any
level, there's several features
you can take advantage of in
Swift Playgrounds 3 to highlight
the most important parts of your
Playground and remove
unnecessary complexity.
All these new features can help
you create more engaging content
and give your learners a
friendly experience in a real
developer tool.
First, let's dive into the
Module Modes.
Now, you've heard a lot about
Module Modes in the app from
both Jonathan and Grace.
As an author, you can decide
what Module Mode is right for
your book.
Because all modules are an
exciting new feature, not all
books will benefit from the use
of modules.
And for that purpose, we have
three module modes: None,
Limited, and Full.
The Module Mode you choose will
change the nature of your book
fundamentally, and should be
considered the foundation of
your user experience.
Let's start with the module
called None.
This mode gives your students
the original Playground
experience, not allowing any
access to user modules.
This mode relies completely on
pages and chapters to advance
the story and code.
And each page works completely
independently so no user code is
shared between pages in any way.
In the Module Mode None, all of
the code in your book will go
into the Modules folder.
This will create private modules
that can be referenced in your
Playground book but not editable
by your students.
You can use private modules in
any of the three modes.
However, the difference in the
Module Mode None is that all of
your code will go into private
modules.
As you build your book, keep in
mind that pages and chapters are
intended to be experienced
linearly.
As the author, you should think
about what the goal is for each
page, and have each page
culminate in something new, you
can do or see in the live view.
This will give your learners a
tight feedback loop ensuring
they know they've completed the
task and they're ready to move
on.
To see examples in our library
of Module Mode-- of this Module
Mode books, you can check out
Learn to Code 1, Learn to Code
2, Lights, Camera, Code, and a
variety of our challenges.
Now, Limited Mode is your first
foray into user modules and
shared files.
Limited Mode allows for a single
user module.
And unlike private modules.
user modules are completely
editable by your students.
The shared files in a user
module persist throughout the
book and they're placed to build
up code over time.
With access to a single module,
your students can learn how to
manage multiple files and bugs
coming from files they don't
necessarily have open.
Within your one module, you can
provide as many shared files as
you want and your learners can
edit, create, or delete any of
the shared files within their
user module.
As the author, you can also use
private modules to include API
you don't want to be editable by
your students in the modules
directory.
As you saw in Jonathan's demo,
he did several math functions to
a single Math.swift file.
Adding new shared files is a
great learning opportunity to
teach how to organize code in
logical ways.
You can teach your students to
move code into a shared file
they'll build up over several
pages, or move aside code
they'll change in frequently.
To see examples in our library
of Limited Mode books, you can
check out Blu's Adventure,
Assemble Your Camera, Flashy
Photos, and a variety of the
challenges, some of which you
see here.
And if you want all the bells
and whistles, you have Full
Module Mode.
This mode gives you all the
tools available, including
making multiple modules, and new
files within those modules.
This mode is perfect for
teaching code architecture and
organization.
In Full Module Mode, you cannot
only teach how to manage
multiple files, but multiple
modules, and importing those
modules into each other when
necessary.
In Full Module Mode, you can
still use private modules and as
many prebuilt user modules as
you want.
Full Module Mode also gives your
students the freedom to extend
those user modules and make user
modules of their own.
When you're authoring for
modules, you should consider
when you might want to use a
private module versus a user
module.
By putting all the code into a
user module, your students can
go beyond simply just playing in
your Playground to seeing how
it's built.
It also gives them complete
control to tinker and remix,
giving your students a chance to
go beyond just being a student
to getting that much closer to
becoming app developers
themselves.
To see examples in our library
of Full Module Mode books, check
out any of the starting points.
And to specify which module mode
you want your book to full
under, you must edit the key
UserModuleMode in the book level
Manifest.
Another customization you can do
when using modules in Limited
and Full Mode is auto-opening
and activating files on a page
by page basis.
Now, that you can expose
multiple files in a tabbed
editor experience, you can
specify which files will be
opened and which one will be
active when you arrive on a
page.
To add open files means that
main.swift will be the active
file, but there may be other
files open as tabs in the
editor.
Providing the user with open
shared files when they arrive on
a page will help them know which
files they'll be editing or need
to reference without having to
locate those files themselves in
the files' popover.
You can specify which files will
be opened on a per page basis in
the page of a Manifest.
In the Manifest, used the key
UserModuleSourceFilesToOpen
followed by an array of shared
files.
The value of each item should be
the relative path to a shared
file.
In any case that you opened
files, the default action is for
main.swift to be the front most
file or the active file.
However, if one of the shared
files is going to be the first
or most prominent place your
user will be working, you can
set this file to be active when
they arrive on a page.
To declare a shared file to be
active, use the key
UserModuleSourceFileToActivate
again in the page level
Manifest.
The value of this key is the
path to a single shared file.
Now, Code Completion is
something you've always been
able to do in main files.
Now, in Swift Playgrounds, let's
see how Code Completion has been
extended to shared files.
Code Completion Directives
determine what API is exposed in
the Shortcut bar.
The Shortcut bar can be a
helpful tool to keep your
learners on track, minimize the
time they have to type, and
ensure they always know what to
do next.
In the introductory content, you
want to lower the barrier to
entry by enabling your students
to tap through most of their
code.
In more advanced content, you
want to expose API at the right
times.
As the author, you can control
what appears in the Shortcut bar
on a page by page basis in both
main and shared files.
In order to manage these
completions, Swift Playgrounds
now offers two places you can
provide Code Completion
Directives.
Let's start in a place you might
be familiar with in the
main.swift file.
Now, this is just the start of
what you'll see if you don't
have any Code Completion
Directives in the new content,
Assemble Your Camera.
To ensure you have full control
over what appears in the
Shortcut bar, you want to start
with a directive, everything,
hide.
Just as it sounds, this will
hide everything from the
Shortcut bar giving you a blank
slate to work from.
To start building suggestions
back into the Shortcut bar, you
can use currentmodule, show.
This is a special keyword that
you can use to ensure everything
you or your students create on
the main file is shown.
The directive module show,
followed by comma separated list
of modules will show everything
marked as public in those user
module files, as well as any new
code a user may write while
playing in your Playground.
This is the same directive you
would have used to expose a
library like UIKit.
For more information about the
various directives, please check
out the documentation for Swift
Playgrounds.
And newly added in Swift
Playgrounds 3 is how to add Code
Completion Directives in a
shared file in the page of a
Manifest.
This means that just like how
you can scaffold what API is
exposed in the main files as
your students move through your
book, you can do this in shared
files as well, ensuring you
won't overload your learners at
the start of their journey.
To do this, you'll use the key
UserModule
CodeCompletionDirectives
followed by an array of Code
Completion Directives similar to
how you would make them in the
main file.
Again, if using everything hide,
you want to use currentmodule
show and module show, to show
everything created on the main
and shared file.
Additionally, you can add
keywords like public and private
as identifiers to show these to
your students as they start new
functions, classes, and structs
in a shared file.
Next, let's talk about making
Cutscenes in Swift.
Several of the books in the
Swift Playground's library use
Cutscenes to introduce a new
skill, engage the user, or
summarize a concept.
What was previously only done in
HTML, you can now also write in
Swift.
[ Applause and Cheering ]
This offers loads of benefits to
you as a developer.
You can leverage frameworks like
SpriteKit, UIKit, and
CoreAnimation.
By using Swift, you don't have
to switch tools to create
Cutscenes which means you can
use the Interface Builder for
storyboards and auto layout.
And you can localize your
Cutscenes using the same tooling
you use to localize your
content.
Using Swift, you'll now add
Cutscenes to your book similar
to how you would a new page.
In the Pages folder, you'll
still need a folder ending in
.cutscenepage, only now you'll
need both a .swift file and a
Manifest.
The .swift file you include
behaves like a liveview.swift
file and should run and present
a live view.
In order for your Cutscene to
appear in the Table of Contents,
you add it to the chapter level
Manifest, just like you would a
new page.
Now, finally, I'm excited to
introduce you to Localized Code
Comments.
If you're distributing your
Playground book to multiple
locales, you can now localize
code comments and strings in any
main or shared files.
This means that your book will
be fully localized to your
students.
[ Applause ]
For code comments, you can have
a single or multiline comment in
a localizable-zone.
Each localizable-zone should
have a unique identifier.
You can also use inline
localizable-zones to make string
literals localizable.
The output of your Localized
Code Comments will be stored in
the LocalizableCode.strings file
in the book level Private
Resources folder.
That's a taste for all the
powerful new features in Swift
Playgrounds 3 for authors.
Next, let's see all these new
author and app features come
together with the demo from
Grace.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So with all of these new
features, I really wanted to
show off that you can create
something super robust and fun
for Swift Playgrounds on the
iPad.
So as you all know, the general
workflow for creating an app
that incorporates the iOS camera
on iPad is to start with a blank
app in Xcode on the Mac, write
some code, run it on your iPad,
see if it worked, and then
iterate back and forth between
your two devices.
But, you can iterate much more
quickly if you're writing the
code right on the iPad itself
with Swift Playgrounds.
So I wanted to use the Vision
framework which does use the
camera along with Core ML to do
object detection and live
capture.
So, Swift Playgrounds was
actually a great place for me to
build this app.
So there is a concept in
American Sign Language of name
signs which are special signs to
uniquely identify a person.
When I was little, my mom gave
me the name sign of this which
is the letter G and a smile.
But that is me on the left not
smiling.
So maybe it should have been
more like this.
So working off of this idea, I
created a piece of content that
incorporates some doodling and
some sign language recognition
which I want to show you now.
All right.
So, here's my piece of content
packaged up into a book that I
call Sign Me Up.
So what I wanted to do was make
something to let Jonathan, Joy
and I create a unique face
painting for ourselves and then
trigger those drawings with sign
language.
So, I'm doing touch recognition
to draw on live video output and
then I'm using the Vision
framework to track those
drawings to detected faces.
And then I'm using Core ML to do
object recognition and live
capture to rotate between those
drawings based on what's being
signed.
So I created my book and I put
it in Limited Mode so I can hide
away some of the implementation
details.
I really just want my users to
focus on a few of the Swift
files I've created in my user
module.
On the Mac, I trained a Core ML
model to recognize three signs.
So G, Y and N, then I imported
the model to my iPad into this
Playground.
So G is for Grace, and my
co-presenters Jonathan and Joy,
both have the same first two
letters of their names so I
settled for the third.
So Y for joy, and N for
Jonathan.
So I'd like to invite them both
back up now to demonstrate.
[ Applause ]
Alright. So on the first page, I
added some pros instructing the
user what to do.
And when Joy taps in the Source
Editor, you'll see that I've
added a code completion
directive to suggest the
setColors function.
Just by tapping, she can fill
this function out by selecting
color literal placeholders in
the Code Completion bar.
The quick editor for this makes
it super easy to see different
UI colors this way.
The setColors function sets some
of the different drawing colors
that will be available once she
runs the code.
So let's go ahead and do that
now.
Awesome.
And let's expand the live view
to full screen to get a better
perspective.
So she'll cycle through in the
bottom, left-hand corner to set
Y for Joy, and then can tap
through in the right hand color
to pick the color to draw with.
And then she can do some face
painting.
So what she draws is tracking to
her face using the Vision
framework which can return a
bounding box of a face and some
facial landmarks.
So I'm using the left pupil to
map all of these points to their
correct locations.
Once she's satisfied, she'll tap
Done and give Jonathan a turn.
So these drawings are then
represented as a set of colors
and x, y distances to the left
pupil and are then mapped to a
letter.
This information is then saved
to the Playground key value
store of this Playground.
And all of this code for the
mapping is in the FaceView.swift
file and is available for the
user to peruse without messing
up any of the cleanliness of my
main page.
So it looks like Jonathan's
done.
I'll follow suit.
Cool.
[Applause]
Awesome. So let's go to the next
page now which instructs us to
run the code and see what
happens.
And let's bring the live view to
full screen again to get a
better perspective.
So, so far, nothing is happening
except for our face detection.
But try signing the letter Y.
Awesome. So Swift Playgrounds is
recognizing-- [applause] Yeah.
Swift Playgrounds recognizes
that Joy is signing Y and is
projecting her drawing onto her
face.
So let's see if we try a
different letter.
Let's try G.
&gt;&gt; Oh, I don't know.
&gt;&gt; Rotate a little bit.
Oh, we're getting there.
Maybe N for Jonathan.
There we go.
Cool, cool.
And it can even switch between
faces.
Perfect. You've never looked
better [laughs].
[ Applause ]
So, all of this code was written
entirely in Swift Playgrounds
and is running on this iPad.
And you can customize it for
your students, your friends or
fellow developers on the Mac
making for unique and really fun
piece of content that makes
Swift Playgrounds accessible.
So both Jonathan and my
Playgrounds are available for
download online in a
subscription at
wwdcswiftplaygrounds
2019.github.io.
&gt;&gt; And for more information,
please check out our
documentation
developer.apple.com.
And please come to the labs
tomorrow morning, bright and
early at 9:00 a.m. We're going
to be there and we'd love to
talk with you.
&gt;&gt; Thank you all for coming and
have a great rest of your
conference.
[ Applause and Cheering ]