[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, and welcome to
Getting Started with
Instruments.
My name is Tibet Rooney-Rabdau
and with me today are my
teammates, Ben Mitchell and
Anand Subramanian.
When I think about delivering a
great user experience, I
immediately think about
performance.
Responsiveness builds trust
between the user and your app.
No matter how much I love the UI
of an app, when I encounter a
spinning gear, or a poor battery
life, my overall experience with
the app is diminished.
It is important to remember
these areas when trying to
create a great user experience
in your app.
In today's session, we will
share with you our favorite tool
to measure performance -
Instruments.
This is a great session for
those who are new to Instruments
and are looking to better
integrate Instruments into their
engineering workflow.
It is important to measure
performance early and often,
because regressions can be
introduced anywhere in the
development cycle and can have a
compounded effect.
In fact, I like to think of
Xcoded Instruments as best
friends, so I keep instruments
in the dock beside Xcode as a
reminder to proof that early and
often throughout the engineering
process.
Today we'll start out with an
orientation of Instruments, its
features, and a tour of its user
interface.
Then we'll show you how to
profile your app to measure the
time taken by various
operations.
We'll figure out what kind of
work and how much work your app
is doing by using a tool called
Time Profiler.
In the last section, we'll talk
about adding Signposts to your
application to gain insight into
your app's behavior.
Let's get started with a
walkthrough of Instruments.
Instruments is a powerful
performance analysis and testing
tool that's part of Xcode
toolset.
Instruments can help you profile
your apps on all platforms -
iOS, macOS, watchOS, tvOS - in
order to better understand and
optimize their behavior and
performance.
You can use Instruments during
development, testing, and
debugging.
Also, I have good news.
If you have Xcode already, you
already have Instruments.
From Xcode's product menu,
choose Profile.
Although Instruments is embedded
within and is often used with
Xcode, Instruments is a separate
app which may be used
independently as needed.
You are free to choose how you
start your performance analysis
quest.
Now, I'll start using the word
Instruments in two different
ways.
We've already talked about the
Instruments app.
Why is it named that?
Because it provides tools called
Instruments that are used to
profile errors in your
application.
In areas where it might be hard
to understand what I'm referring
to, I'll refer to the
application as the Instruments
app.
An Instrument collects time
series trace data from
infrastructure that is inserted
into important parts of apps,
processes, and the operating
system.
We sometimes refer to the data
an Instrument collects as a
treat.
Here we have a couple of my
favorite Instruments.
The Time Profiler Instrument on
the left uses infrastructure
provided by the operating system
to collect call stacks of
relevant threads at a fixed
interval.
The Points of Interest
instrument on the right collects
data from important areas of
your app that you can highlight
using various APIs such as
Signpost API.
When you first open Instruments,
you're presented with a list of
templates similar to the
templates in a pages or numbers
document.
A template provides a
preconfigured collection of
Instruments to help you answer a
performance question, similar to
how the page's birthday card
template provides a document
structure to help you create a
birthday card.
There are too many templates to
cover in this short session, so
we will focus on the Time
Profiler template which contains
the two Instruments I just
mentioned - Time Profiler and
Points of Interest, as well as
others.
These Instruments are great
tools for understanding
responsiveness and your app's
utilization.
When you first open the Time
Profiler template, you're
presented with this blank
document ready for Profiling.
So, the top right, you can add
additional Instruments to this
document by clicking the Add
Instruments button.
Then, the Instrument's app shows
the Instrument's library
palette, which contains a
complete list of available
Instruments.
From here, you can find new
Instruments and drag them into
the document to gather more
data.
So, the top left, we have the
Profiling Controls.
This allows you to record,
pause, and stop data collection.
Beside the Profiling Controls is
the Target Area.
The Target Device List on the
left allows you to select the
device on which you wish to
profile.
This is similar to the Xcode
Target Area where you choose the
device and the process to
Profile on the device.
Typically you will choose your
app's process as your Target
Process, but for instance, if
you're Profiling a shared
extension, you would choose your
extension Process, which will be
separate from your app.
When I start recording in the
Time Profiler template, the
document will start being
populated with trace data.
As an aside, recording with
Instruments uses System
Resources, just like your app
does.
To minimize its impact on your
app, Instruments also offers a
feature called Last Few Seconds
Mode, sometimes called Windowed
Mode.
Windowed Mode keeps Instruments
from analyzing or displaying
results until recording ends and
ignores events prior to the last
few seconds of recording.
This is helpful when you just
want to start recording and
select stop when you see a
problem.
Some templates use this mode by
default because they gather a
lot of data over a short period
of time.
Now that I've just finished
recording in the Time Profiler
template, a lot of trace data
has been populated into various
parts of this window.
This may look like a lot, so
let's go on a side quest to
learn what each part does.
The top portion of the window
contains the Track Viewer.
A Track shows time series trace
data corresponding to one source
of events, such as the process,
thread, or CPU core.
A single Instrument may
contribute trace data to
multiple Tracks.
In this example, three Tracks
are visible.
The top Track is a summary of
our application's CPU
utilization provided by the Time
Profiler Instrument.
The next Track shows data
collected from the Points of
Interest Instrument, which Anand
will show you later.
Additional Tracks follow
breaking things down in finer
detail.
A given Instrument's trace may
have dozens of Tracks.
You can use the Track Filter to
just show the Instruments or
break it up by thread, or by CPU
core.
You can also get more specific
and search for Tracks by name.
Lower down in the window, the
detail view allows you to
explore the trace data for the
selected Track.
In this example, with the Time
Profiler Track selected, we can
explore the functions called on
each thread during the trace.
To the right side of the Detail
View, you'll find the Extended
Detail View within the
Inspector.
This is a view that may provide
richer information from the
Instruments in use, depending on
current context and selection.
In this example, because I'm
using Time Profiler, I have a
summary showing the heaviest
call stack.
Another way to see what is
happening at a moment in time is
through the Inspection Head.
The Inspection Head is a
selector which can be placed at
a specific time in the trace in
order to select all traced
events or intervals occurring at
that time.
Additional details about the
selected events are displayed in
Hovering Labels.
The Detail and Extended Detail
views are updated to focus on
information about the selected
events where applicable.
We've finished our side quest
and now better understand the
Instruments' User Interface.
Everything shown in the window
is part of a trace document.
The trace document contains any
Instruments configured for
Profiling along with collected
data and views you're using to
analyze the results.
The Instruments app can save and
reopen these trace documents,
allowing you to explore old
results or share them with a
teammate for investigation.
With that, I would like to
welcome my teammate, Ben
Mitchell, to the stage, so he
can show some of these things in
action.
Thank you!
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Tibet.
Hello, World.
My name is Ben Mitchell and as
Tibet mentioned, I'm going to
show you how to Profile your
application using Instruments.
Let's get started.
For those of you who saw some
sessions at last year's
conference, WWDC2018, you might
recognize the Solar System app.
We shipped it about a year ago,
and we've gotten some good
feedback from our customers.
But, also some less-than-awesome
feedback; in particular, in
areas of performance.
Our customers have reported some
responsiveness issues,
particularly on older devices.
I was able to reproduce one of
these before the session and I'd
like to demo it to you know with
Instruments attached so we can
see if we can fix it.
Let's dive right in.
With the application already
running, I'll just open
Instruments.
The Instruments Template
Selector already has Time
Profiler chosen, because I've
used it previously.
Time Profiler is a great tool
for looking at issues that occur
over a particular window of
time.
I'll select Time Profiler and
using the Choose button, will
open a new trace document.
Because I didn't launch this
from Xcode, the first thing I
need to do is select which
process I'm going to trace.
Using the target selection area,
I'll click All Processes and
select the Solar System Mac
application that's already
running.
To the right, you can see a
number.
That's the process identifier
and it appears in Activity
Monitoring.
We've selected the application,
and now we'll click Record in
the top left of the window.
There we go.
Instruments is recording.
I'll switch over to the app.
The Solar System app supports a
number of gestures on the Track
Pad.
It supports clicks and drags,
but also pans, pinch to zoom,
and so on.
And our customers have reported
that when they're performing
these operations and they press
command + R to reload data, the
user interface freezes and the
dreaded Spinning Wait Cursor
appears.
You may know it by some other
names.
That's not awesome.
We were able to reproduce it, so
let's switch back to Instruments
and see what we can find.
I'll quit the application and
Instruments automatically stops
recording.
So, we can see the populated
trace data here.
And the first thing I'm going to
do is make it a little larger so
we can see it in more detail.
With the mouse cursor over the
track area, a pinch to zoom
gesture makes it larger and
allows us to see things closer.
On the left-hand side in the
track area, we can see several
instruments have provided tracks
for us.
Time Profiler is showing us a
summary of the CPU utilization.
The Points of Interest
Instrument is currently empty.
Anand will show you that later.
And there are a number of
others, including thermal state,
and then breakdowns further on
down the scroll view.
If we move our mouse cursor over
the CPU Usage summary track, we
can see a hovering label that
shows what the utilization level
is.
And when I hit this large area
here, the utilization is above
100%.
So, this appears to be
suspicious and I suspect this is
around the time of that reload
operation.
I'd like to compare this to some
of the other tracks.
So, we're going to use a feature
called Track Pinning.
In the left-hand side of the
window, when I move my mouse
over one of the track entries, a
plus button appears.
Clicking it, pins that track to
the bottom of the track area.
And now we can scroll through
the other tracks and see the one
that was of interest side by
side.
You can pin multiple tracks.
As we scroll down, we can see
things broken out by each CPU
core on the system.
And now we have a track entry
for the process itself, Solar
System Mac.
In addition to a CPU usage
summary, this also shows us app
lifecycle events.
We can see here where the
application came into the
foreground when I clicked it on
the dock.
There's also a suspicious red
area over here during the CPU
usage spike.
Moving the mouse over it, I can
see that the label is spinning.
Spinning is how Instruments
refers to your main thread being
blocked.
And on the Mac, that's what
causes the Spinning Wait Cursor.
The main thread has just a few
very specific uses.
It should be used for handling
user input or for updating the
user interface.
Clearly, something else is going
on here.
I'd like to look at the main
thread.
So, I will expand the Solar
System Mac process.
And now there are a number of
other tracks corresponding to
each thread in the application.
Scrolling all the way down,
here's the main thread.
And the main thread is showing a
spike.
So, this looks like the event
that I want to take a look at.
The next feature of Instruments
that we're going to use allows
us to filter events by clicking
and dragging in the track area.
Now, the Detail view at the
bottom is only showing events
from the selected window of
time.
Let's look in the Detail view
and learn more.
The Detail view shows us a call
graph.
These are all the functions that
were invoked during the time of
our profile.
Or, in this case, during the
time we have selected in the
filter.
It's important to understand
what this is doing.
We're not actually tracking
every function entry and exit.
Instead, Time Profiler takes a
snapshot many times per second
and notes all of the functions
that are running in your
process.
So, on the left-hand side, we
have a wait column.
Solar System Mac appears 100% of
the time.
This means that in every sample,
Solar System Mac was present.
That's good, because that's the
application that we're
profiling.
As we move on down, the main
thread is present in 96.7% and
so on.
And we can begin disclosing
these threads to the deeper end
of the functions that were
called.
But there are a lot of them here
and I'd have to click a number
of times to find something
interesting.
So, Instruments provides another
useful trick.
If you hold down the Option key
and click the Disclosure
Triangle, Instruments
automatically expands the track
list until there is a control
flow branch, which might be an
interesting event.
As you can see, there's a lot
here, and it can be hard to dig
in and find exactly what your
problem is.
So, Instruments also provides
the heaviest stack trace in the
Extended Detail View for Time
Profiler.
The heaviest stack trace is the
set of functions that were
called most often during the
Profile.
So, up at the top, we can see
Solar System Mac appears, and
some of these frames are
highlighted in white.
These are the frames that are
from your own process.
Frames that come from System
Frameworks or Libraries are
shown in grey.
So, the main thread executes the
main function, and then there's
a block of System Framework
provided functions.
It's only further down that we
find another area of highlighted
functions.
The first one here is labeled as
a thunk.
What is a thunk?
This is a piece of helper code
generated by the compiler.
It doesn't correspond directly
to any source code in your
application.
So in this case we'll ignore the
thunk.
What we want to focus in on is
this one, the first closure in a
method in the network request
scheduler.
If I click on this line, it is
selected in the Detail view.
Double clicking it displays the
source code right in line.
So, I can see that we have a
method called Schedule Parsing
Task.
And it's doing some work on the
main dispatch queue including
doing some data parsing, and
that seems problematic.
As mentioned earlier, the main
thread should really only be
used for user input and for user
interface updates.
So, I'd like to fix this.
In the top right of the detail
view, there's an Open File in
Xcode button.
I'll click it now.
And Xcode has come to the front.
So, I want to move this on to
its own dispatch queue so that
it's not blocking the main
thread.
The first thing we'll do is
we'll create this dispatch
queue.
We'll call it Parsing Queue.
Now, let's move the work onto
Parsing Queue by using an
asynchronous closure.
We'll just move this work item
up there.
And we still want to notify the
user interface that parsing
completed after that is done.
So, we'll take this call onto
the dispatch main queue after
that.
We'll save, and now we're ready
to try to reproduce our bug
again.
This time, I'll use the Product
Menu and select Profile, as
Tibet showed you earlier.
Xcode builds the application and
brings Instruments to the front.
The Template Chooser has
appeared again because this time
we're not testing a downloaded
copy of this application - we're
testing the one that Xcode has
put in its Drive Data directory.
Time Profiler is selected and
we'll click Choose.
This time, we don't need to
select a target because Xcode
has already informed Instruments
of the application we want to
test.
And furthermore, clicking Record
at the top left launches it for
us automatically.
Switching to the app, let's try
the problematic series of user
inputs again.
A bunch of clicking and dragging
and command + R.
And we can see no more Spinning
Wait Cursor.
Let's do that one more time just
to be sure.
Click, drag, command + R.
No Spinning Wait Cursor.
So, we've addressed our
responsiveness issue.
I'll stop recording and we'll
pinch to zoom again to expand
the track view.
I want to make sure that this
work has been moved off of the
main thread, so I'm going to use
the track filter area, top left.
And we'll search for the main
thread.
The only track that appears is
the Solar System Mac's track
entry.
And when I expand it, I can see
the main thread is visible.
Over here, where we have a spike
of CPU usage, the main thread is
doing relatively little work,
and the second time period is
showing the same.
So, it appears we have addressed
the responsiveness issue and
moved this work off of the main
thread.
[ Applause ]
I'd like to discuss a few
Profiling tips.
First off, Time Profiler is a
great tool for understanding how
your app is spending time.
This may be a responsiveness
issue, like Spinning Wait
Cursor.
This could also be when your
application launches, you want
to speed up its launch so that
it displays to your users
quickly.
Use Time Profiler for these
cases.
Next, if you have a
responsiveness issue, check the
main thread.
It should really only be used
for updating user interface or
for handling user input events,
like a mouse click on the Mac or
a touch on an iOS device.
Third, something I didn't
discuss before.
You should Profile in Release
Mode.
The Compiler supports a number
of different optimization levels
and when you're doing the
Build-Run cycle in Xcode, we use
a low-level of optimization to
allow that to occur quickly.
But this isn't the optimization
level that's used when you ship
code to your customers using the
App Store or Xcode's Archive
feature.
If you're using Xcode's default
configuration, the Profile
action in your scheme is set to
use Release configuration.
However, if you're using custom
Compiler flags, be sure that the
app you profile is using your
Release set of Compiler flags.
Finally, it's important to
Profile with difficult workloads
or on older devices.
In this case, we had a bug that
we didn't see at our desk, but
customers in the field who had
devices with different
performance characteristics did
encounter it.
So, if you have access to those
devices, be sure to test on
them.
As Tibet mentioned earlier,
Instruments supports all
platforms.
We demoed this on the Mac, but
it works equally well on iOS,
watchOS and tvOS.
It also supports the Simulator.
But there's an important caveat
to understand with the
Simulator.
It's running on your Mac.
That means that it has your
Mac's resource contention.
It has your Mac's CPU and memory
performance characteristics.
It has your Mac's file system
behavior and disc behavior.
And it has your Mac's thermal
limitations, which are
significantly different than
that of a smaller embedded
device.
Instruments in this case is
great for looking at trends.
Did something get faster or did
it get slower?
But it's not going to give you
second-by-second accurate
simulation of how the
application would run.
Be sure to test on real hardware
before shipping to your
customers.
So, we took care of a
responsiveness issue, but that's
not the whole story.
We still have a large spike of
CPU usage and it seems like we
should be able to reduce that.
CPU usage can drain the battery.
It can increase the temperature
of a device or on many Macs
it'll spin up fans and annoy
your users.
So, now I'd like to introduce
Anand to use the Signpost
feature to help dig into the
work that our application is
doing.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ben.
Good morning, everyone.
I'd like to show you how to use
Signpost in your code today to
augment the Instruments' traces
you collect from it and get a
finer understanding of how your
code uses system resources.
So, let's begin understanding
Signposts by contrasting with
what we've been doing so far
with Time Profiler.
Time Profiler builds a
statistical profile of your code
and it does so by observing all
the threads in your application
at a fixed interval and building
the correlation between call
stacks and time.
But a correlation is no
substitute for aa precise
measurement which can tell you
how or why your code is
executing.
There may be a block of code
that executes in several short
bursts.
Or, it might execute in a few
longer stretches.
There could be a function which
when called on certain arguments
can keep the CPU continuously
busy.
In order to distinguish these
kinds of execution patterns, you
need to log precise measurements
from your code and that begs the
question.
What is the best way to log
performance measurements from
your operations?
I'm pleased to tell you that you
don't have to worry about
printing from your code and
teaching Instruments how to read
your print statements.
Just use Signposts.
Signposts have numerous features
that make them ideal for this
use case.
It is purpose built for logging
structured performance data.
So, it is simpler and more
efficient for this purpose than
even printing.
It has built-in support for
measuring time.
So, you don't have to worry
about what clock source you're
reading from or what time base
you're measuring in.
My favorite part is that
Instruments already knows how to
trace Signposts.
In fact, let me give you a sneak
preview of an Instruments trace
that I collected after adding a
Signpost interval to my code.
Highlighted is the points of
interest track which shows a
region of interest that
corresponds to a Signpost
interval that I added to my
code.
So, let me take you to a demo
now where I'll resume Ben's
investigation of the Solar
System application.
So, we have the last Instruments
trace we were looking at, and we
see the familiar region of high
CPU utilization.
And we'd like to find out why
we're using so much CPU time and
we'd like to add some Signposts
to the code that is using most
of the CPU time.
Let me take a look at the heavy
stack trace.
Last time, Ben started looking
from the top of this heavy stack
so that we could find out how
the code began executing on the
main thread.
But this time, I'd like to start
looking from the Leaf Level
functions to get an idea of what
are the most expensive or
commonly called functions in
this workload.
There's something called Setup
Scene over here which appears to
be manipulating lots of arrays
as a part of this reload
operation.
And I'd like to find out how
much time precisely it is
taking.
So, let's go to Xcode and take a
look at this code.
Here's the Setup Scene function,
and you can see some vestiges of
my previous attempts to log some
performance measurements from
here.
There's a print statement
emitting the mock absolute time
right at the beginning of the
function.
And if we scroll all the way to
the bottom of the function,
there is another Print Statement
showing the mock absolute time
of when I ended this.
But as I previously mentioned,
Instruments doesn't know how to
read Print Statements.
So, we first need to create a
log handle that lets us
communicate what Instruments.
Let's do that.
I created this log handle with a
category called Points of
Interest.
That corresponds to the name of
the Points of Interest
Instrument.
We'll replace our first Print
Statement with a call to an OS
Signpost API that begins an
interval.
Now, every time you begin an
interval you should also end
that interval.
Instead of scrolling all the way
to the bottom of the function,
I'm going to take advantage of
Swift Defer Blocks to end the
interval.
The contents of the Defer Block
will be executed at the end of
the current scope.
Let's build our application with
these changes and Profiler in
Instruments using the Profile
action in the menu.
Let's select the Time Profiler
template once again and the
target selection area has
already been populated by Xcode
with a currently built
conversion of the Solar System
app.
Let's start recording.
I'll interact with the app and
perform the troublesome sequence
of operations again, reload
operation.
And we've got some data.
So, I'll stop the recording.
Let's pinch to zoom into the
region of high CPU utilization.
Below the Time Profiler frack,
the Points of Interest track now
has been populated with the
regions of interest that we
added in our code.
There's a row called Setup Scene
corresponding to the name of our
Signpost interval, and there are
several adjacent regions of
interest recorded in the track.
I wasn't expecting many; I was
only expecting a few.
I could mouse over each of these
and count the number of regions
of interest.
Or, I could take advantage of
the detail view.
So, let me click and drag to
select this particular region
and then click in the Points of
Interest track to repopulate the
Detail view with a summary of
the Points of Interest track.
Taking a closer look, I see that
Setup Scene has occurred a total
of eight times in this region,
and it's averaging about 200
milliseconds for each time it
occurs.
There are more Detail views
available.
Let's click on the Jump Bar and
select a list of the regions of
interest to see a full-time
series list of every region of
interest that was recorded in
this trace.
The duration column shows the
duration of each of these and I
can see that all of these
intervals are taking a very
similar amount of time to
complete, about 210 to 220
milliseconds.
So that's a real headscratcher.
Why are we doing a similar
amount of work over and over
again?
Let's look at the caller of
Setup Scene to find out if it's
being called redundantly for
some reason.
And the best way to do that is
to look at the call graph
information recorded by Time
Profiler.
Let's take advantage of the
heavy stack view again at the
bottom right-hand corner of the
window, and this time I'll look
at the caller of Setup Scene, a
function called Prepare Scene.
We can double click it to bring
up the sources.
And it appears that Prepare
Scene called Setup Scene only
once.
So, this isn't the root cause of
our repetition.
To bring back the entire call
graph, I'll click on Root in the
Jump part and take us to the
root of the call graph.
Let's go further up on our quest
in the heavy stack.
I'll select the next caller and
here we see a four loop, which
is very plausible cause of the
repetition that we're seeing.
Let me bring up this code in
Xcode so that we can take a
closer look.
And I'll use the Jump to File in
Xcode button.
Xcode comes up with the four
loop displayed.
I remember this function.
The purpose of update with
planets is to receive the data
sent to us by the server, the
part of the Reload operation.
And then for each planet for
which we have new data, update
the internal model in the
application of each of the
planets wherever an update is
required.
However, we can receive a blob
of data containing updated
information for multiple
planets, and we appear to be
calling Prepare Scene and
redrawing the entire view for
every single planet that we need
to update.
The trace shows us that the cost
of redrawing the scene vastly
dwarfs the cost of just updating
our internal model of the
planet.
So, the right thing to do here
would be to batch up all of our
updates to our internal model
and just redraw the scene once
after we've made all of our
updates.
This may seem like a very simple
fix but in our experience, we've
seen that numerous performance
issues of this type can creep
into our code as we add new
features or fix unrelated bugs.
And a great way to prevent such
bugs from getting out to our
customers is to write tests that
routinely exercise their
functionality.
To save us some time, I've
already written an XC test which
exercises the Reload
functionality.
If we click on this button to
the left of the test, normally
it would just run the test.
But I will secondary click to
reveal the Profile action.
This instructs Xcode to build
and launch the test under
Instruments.
Let's select the Time Profiler
template and start recording a
trace.
In this test, I've placed the
Reload operation inside a call
to the Measure API.
The Measure API runs the
workload several times in order
to collect several repeated
measurements.
That can be really helpful for
you to learn whether your
measurements are repeatable and
consistent, or whether there's a
lot of run-to-run variation.
It looks like all the
repetitions have ended, so I can
stop this trace.
I'll pinch to zoom into the
contents of the points of
interest track.
And we can see there's an extra
row here.
At the very bottom is a Setup
Scene interval which I
previously added to our code.
And above it is another point of
interest that is now being
contributed to by the Measure
API.
That tells us the interval
corresponding to each iteration
that it ran your workload.
Scrolling over this and just
eyeballing it, I feel like the
workload is behaving pretty
consistently from run to run.
So, I'd just like to find out
what is happening within a
single iteration of the test.
Instead of clicking and
dragging, there is a nice
shortcut for you to select
exactly the region corresponding
to one event or interval in a
track.
I'll triple click.
This populates the Detail view
with information specific to
that selection.
And taking a closer look, there
appears to be only one call to
Setup Scene right now.
Let that sink in.
We used the information that we
gained from Signposts to reduce
the amount of CPU time we were
using by an order of magnitude.
[ Applause ]
So, let's review some of the
concepts we just encountered.
A statistical profile such as
that collected by Time Profiler
can be really useful to show
what code is most commonly
executed.
But that is not a substitute for
a measurement such as that which
can be recorded using the
Signpost APIs that can show you
how and why your code is
executed.
We've also seen how it can be
really useful to run tests to
reliably and repeatedly
reproduce our workloads and
profile them early and often in
our development cycle.
Today, we've largely
investigated the kinds of
performance issues that arise
from high or inappropriately
placed CPU utilization.
But Instruments has numerous
templates which can help answer
performance questions about
other kinds of resource
utilization.
We've got a template for file
and disc usage.
We've got another template for
network utilization.
And there's another template
that'll help you understand the
interaction between your
application and the operating
system or other processes
running on the OS.
But that's not all.
Instruments has some really
advanced features such as Custom
Instruments.
If you're a framework author,
for instance, and would like
your clients of your APIs to be
able to answer performance
questions about how they're
using your framework, then you
can provide them with a Custom
Instruments package.
You could also create Custom
Instruments templates, which
assemble together a different
collection of the Instruments in
the Instruments app to help
answer a particular performance
question.
Coming out of this presentation,
I'd really love for you all to
start Profiling your code early
and often in your development
cycle.
And please try to out
Instruments 11 today.
It's packed with some great new
features such as Track Pinning
and Hierarchical Views which I
think will make it really fun to
use.
We've got comprehensive
documentation of the advanced
features and certain events
workflows of Instruments in our
session notes, and there's some
great talks from the previous
year's conference.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]