&gt;&gt; Hello, and welcome to
debugging in Xcode 11.
I'm Chris Miles, one of the
engineering managers on the
Xcode team.
I'm really excited to be here
today.
We've got a lot of great stuff
to get through, so I'm going to
jump straight in and start by
telling you about device
conditions and environment
overrides.
So, you may have received
reports from users where your
app isn't behaving as expected
under certain real-world
conditions, and they may be the
types of conditions that are
really hard to replicate in your
development environment.
Such as real-world networking
conditions.
Network response out in the real
world isn't always as ideal as
it is in our home or office
where we typically build our
apps.
And if users report an issue
while using your app in
situations where network
connectivity is limited, you
need a way to reliably reproduce
these types of network
conditions to debug and improve
your app.
Or, when devices out in the real
world are under thermal pressure
and need to regulate resources
available to your app in order
to help cool down the device.
You need to understand how your
app behaves in these types of
thermal conditions and for apps
that make heavy use of
resources, you may be
proactively responding to
thermal state changes by
reducing resource usage when the
device is under thermal
pressure.
But how do you reliably put the
device into an elevated thermal
state in order to debug and
verify your logic?
And this is where device
conditions come in.
New in Xcode 11, you're able to
use the new thermal state
condition to safely and reliably
raise the thermal state of a
device to any of the elevated
levels, fair, serious, or
critical.
You can use this to understand
your app's behavior under these
elevated thermal states, and to
debug and verify your handling
of thermal state changes.
Just note the device does not
actually get physically warmer,
so don't use this functionality
to try and warm your hands on a
cold day.
Along with the thermal state
condition, we also have the
network link condition.
This allows you to simulate
real-world networking conditions
directly from Xcode on that
device, such as a high latency,
low bandwidth, high packet loss,
and slow DNS.
So you can use this to
understand and debug your app's
behavior under these various
networking conditions.
Now this functionality is
similar to the network link
conditioner in iOS developer
settings that some of you may be
already familiar with, but it
has been updated with a wider
range of modern network
profiles, and it's fully
controllable by Xcode, and I'll
show you how that works in a few
moments.
Now, some conditions that an app
must adapt to are controlled by
the user.
There are numerous settings that
a user can adjust in order to
customize their interface, such
as the light or dark interface
style that an app is running in.
In iOS 13, your app must provide
a great user experience when
running in either light or dark.
A setting that is highly
customizable is dynamic type.
Users can choose between very
small dynamic type sizes up to
very large sizes, and there are
even larger sizes available in
the accessibility settings.
So you need to be able to debug
your UI layout across a wide
range of dynamic type settings.
And then there are many
accessibility options available
as well.
Many system controls already
adapt to these settings, but you
need to ensure that your custom
views and controls also do the
right thing when these settings
are enabled.
As you can see here, there's a
large matrix of environment
settings available to users.
Do you debug and test your app
with many of these settings
adjusted or enabled?
Do you even remember where to
find many of these settings?
And this is where environment
overrides can really help,
allowing you to effortlessly
override any combination of
these settings while debugging
your app directly from Xcode.
That's a quick introduction into
device conditions and
environment overrides, but I'd
love to show you how they work,
and I'm going to do that by
jumping into Xcode.
So here we have Xcode open with
the Trouble Project.
This is an iOS app that we've
been building that allows users
to discover places to travel to,
create a travel plan, and record
a travel journey.
You may have seen it from some
of our other sessions this week.
I've been focusing on this
beautiful 3D rendering of the
Earth here with pins in it
indicating places to travel to.
Now, I want this app to be a
good thermal citizen, and so
I've started adding code to
observe thermal state changes on
the device, and I'd like to
reduce the use of GPU resources
when the device is under thermal
pressure.
So, let me show you how I've
done that.
I'm going to switch to this
Globe Scene Controller.
This is the controller
responsible for configuring the
3D scene.
In the initializer, you can see
that I've added an observer for
the thermal state did change
notification.
This is called whenever the
thermal state of the device
changes.
In the callback, we call through
to configure scene features.
So let's take a look at this
function.
It's responsible for two
parameters of our 3D scene, the
anti-aliasing mode and the
requested frame rate.
So when this is called, we can
fetch the thermal state of the
device, and then when the device
is in the critical thermal
state, the recommendation is to
reduce our use of energy
impactful resources as much as
possible to help the device cool
down.
So, in our case, what I'm going
to do is to turn off
anti-aliasing and also to reduce
our frame rate to 30.
In the serious thermal state, we
don't have to be as aggressive,
so let's just turn off
anti-aliasing but leave the
frame rate as it is, and in the
lower thermal states, we don't
have to take any action in this
particular case.
So with that change in place,
I'm going to stop and rerun, and
I have a device next to me, and
I'm mirroring that device back
to the desktop using QuickTime
player on the right.
Now what I'd like to do is to
put the device into the critical
thermal state, so we can test
this logic and debug it if there
are any problems, and so I can
use the new device conditions
for that.
But before I do that, I'd also
like to monitor the thermal
state of this device, and I can
do that now by switching to the
debug navigator and selecting
the energy impact gauge.
This gauge shows you a breakdown
of the average energy impact as
well as the component
utilization here on the top
right, and you can see as I
interact with the app the GPU is
the primary component in this
case, as expected.
But I'm going to draw your
attention to the middle here
where we have the new thermal
state track available in Xcode
11.
This shows you two pieces of
information.
The top of the track shows you
whether any device conditions
are active, and there are no
device conditions active yet.
The bottom part shows you the
current thermal state of the
device.
And blue indicates the nominal
thermal state, everything is
running cool and smoothly.
So let's leave that open while I
use the window menu to open the
devices window.
I'll move that up here.
Now, with the device selected,
we can scroll to the bottom and
find the new device conditions
UI.
And here we can see all the
device conditions available for
this device.
We have the network link
condition and all the new
profiles available.
In our case, let's select
thermal state.
And here we can choose an
elevated thermal state level,
and I'm going to choose critical
and press start.
Now, there's a few things to
take note of here.
One is that it takes a few
moments for the device to
transition to the critical
thermal state, and down here in
the thermal state track, we see
confirmation that that device
condition is now active, and
after a few moments, you can see
that the device transitioned to
the critical thermal state.
Over here on the right, on the
device itself, note in the top
there's a background filler on
the time, and that's you status
bar indicator that a device
condition is active on this
device.
Now, finally, if we interact
with our 3D scene, we can see
that the frame rate indicator
that we've added shows 30 frames
per second.
And so we can verify easily as
that, that our logic is doing
the right thing.
Also, the anti-aliasing is
switched off.
It's a little hard to see on
this small device, but on a
larger device, you'd be able to
see that.
So now that we've used device
conditions to verify our code,
we can switch it off.
I could press the stop button
here, but there are a couple of
other ways to disable the device
condition.
One, is to disconnect that
device from Xcode or quit Xcode.
If the device ever comes
disconnected from Xcode, it will
automatically tear down a device
condition, because we don't want
to leave your device running in
one of these states when you're
not developing.
Another is on the device itself,
we can tap that status bar
indicator at the top, which I'll
do now, and we'll see
information about the currently
active condition, and I can
press the stop button to turn
off that condition.
So, I'll press that now.
We can close the devices window,
and in the thermal state track
here, we see confirmation that
the device condition is no
longer active, and we can see
that the device starts
transitioning back down to the
fair thermal state and the
nominal thermal state.
[ Applause ]
So that's a quick example of
using the device conditions, in
this case the thermal state
condition on our connected
device.
Now, I'd like to move on and
show you environment overrides.
Now what I'm going to do is stop
running and switch to a
particular view.
I'm going to choose profile
view.
This is written in Swift UI, and
I really, really like writing
Swift UI and using the new Xcode
preview.
So I'm going to open the canvas
to start the preview engine.
Now, I don't need the device
anymore, so I'll close
QuickTime.
Previews will start up.
Now, to use environment
overrides, you need to be
debugging your app or debugging
your preview, and if you haven't
seen already, you can debug
previews by control clicking on
the live button down on the
bottom right.
You'll see a pop-up menu, and
you can just choose debug
preview.
This does two things.
It puts the preview into live
mode, and it also attaches a
debug session.
So, now the preview is live and
interactive, and here we go down
the bottom, which I'll lift up a
bit.
In the debug bar, we can see
that we have confirmation that
we have a debug session active
debugging the preview.
So we have all of our usual
debugging tools, such as view
debugging, memory graft
debugging, and the new
environment overrides.
So, if I click that, we see the
environment overrides UI, and we
can simply override the
interface style by clicking the
switch, and now we've put that
preview into dark mode.
We can just switch back and
forth between light and dark to
test our layout and test our UI.
So, you might have already
noticed an issue.
The description text here looks
great in light, but in dark, we
can't even see it.
So, while we're here, let's take
a quick look.
This text element under my
cursor is responsible for
drawing the description, and you
can see that I haven't finished
transitioning this view to take
advantage of dark mode.
I'm still using a fixed color.
I should use a semantic color
like secondary, so I'll make
that change.
What I love about previews,
refreshes for me.
Because we have asked for
debugging, we still have a debug
session, so I can bring up
environment overrides and look
at dark mode, and we've made our
fix as easy as that.
[ Applause ]
Let's try out the dynamic type
override.
I'll switch on text overrides.
I can simply use this slider to
choose any of the dynamic type
settings down to the very
smallest, up to the very
largest, and then we can keep
going into the accessibility
sizes, all the way up to the
very largest accessibility
dynamic type size.
Notice that our layout is pretty
good in this case except here.
These little rectangles get
clicked in the very largest type
sizes.
So, while we're here, let's fix
that too.
I'm going to scroll down to
image text pill is the view
responsible for drawing these
rectangles.
It lays out an image and a text
in a horizontal stack.
What I'd like us to do is when
the type size gets too large, to
switch that to a vertical stack
and lay them out one above the
other.
Now, I've had to solve this
elsewhere, and I build a custom
view called an adapting stack.
I'm going to option click that
now to open that, and we don't
need the canvas in this case, so
I'll close that.
So we've opened this
in an editor split, and let's take a
quick look.
An adapting stack is a custom
view that takes a view builder
closer as an import, the same as
an H stack or a V stack does.
It binds itself to the size
category environment.
And so when a size category
changes, which is what happens
when you change dynamic type,
our bodies fold, and then if we
switch on size category, if it's
accessibility large or larger,
then we wrap the content in a
vertical stack and adjust some
padding.
Otherwise, we wrap it in a
horizontal stack.
So, let's try this one out.
I'll change this H stack to an
adapting stack.
Our preview will refresh for us,
and now we can try out our
environment overrides.
And now, as we go into the large
sizes, we can see that our
layout adapts.
[ Applause ]
I'm happy with that change, and
let's take a quick look at
accessibility settings.
You can see there are a lot of
settings here.
We don't have time to play with
them today, but I highly
encourage you to try out all
these settings with your apps
and previews and make sure your
UI is doing the right thing with
these enabled.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So let me give you just a quick
summary of what I showed you.
First, we looked at device
conditions, which is available
from the devices window.
It allows you to enable a
network link condition or a
thermal state condition.
Device conditions are tied to
the Xcode device connection.
So if the device becomes
disconnected from Xcode, we
automatically tear down that
device condition.
And in iOS status bar indicator,
it is your indication that a
device condition is active on
that device.
You can tap that indicator to
see details about the condition
and use it to stop the
condition.
Environment override is
available while debugging.
You can use to instantly
override many of the settings
that you saw, and it only
affects your debug app.
It does not affect any other
processes that are running, and
it doesn't, importantly, it
doesn't change any system
settings.
So, it's really great and
convenient to use.
It's supported while debugging
in any cases, devices,
simulators, or previews as you
saw, and it's available for all
of our platforms.
Some of the settings may differ,
but it's available for any of
the platforms that you can
debug.
So, I hope you can take
advantage of these new features
to develop and test your apps in
a wider range of conditions and
environments so you can create a
great user experience for more
users in more situations.
Thank you, and I'm going to hand
over to Han Ming, who is going
to tell you more details about
debugging live previews.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Chris.
Good morning.
In the past few days we have
learned that live previews are
great for testing interactions
between, with a particular view
of your project, and Xcode is
optimized for the fast
turnaround time between editing
your source code and updating
the preview.
But because some of us, no all
of us are mere mortals, we are
bound to introduce code, a bug
in the code.
So Xcode allows the debugger to
be attached to the preview
instance in order to seek out
those bugs.
When the debugger is attached,
you access to all the great
tools, such as debug navigator
where you can examine the
backtrace.
Break points, where you can
pause the debugger.
Debug bar, where you can search
for your process control button,
such as stepping controls.
And variables view, where you
can inspect the state of the
process when paused.
New in Xcode 11 is going to
start showing you Swift UI
runtime issues.
Now this is part of a new
category of issues that are
generated by system frameworks,
and typically it's related to
how their APIs are not used
correctly.
Xcode will find them when the
process is running, and we
currently have a couple of
frameworks that are
participating, and because Swift
UI is brand new, it's designed
from the get-go to generate
these issues for you.
These issues do not crash a
process, but instead they point
to important bugs that we want
you to solve before deploying
your app to the app store.
To grab your attention, they
will show up prominently in
Xcode.
They will show up as purple
icons in the activity viewer and
with more details in the issues
navigator.
Besides previews, these issues
are available for all platforms
and run destinations.
To learn more, let's get
straight to demo.
All right.
This is the project that we have
been working on, and the canvas
starts off with showing you the
static preview.
And this preview will show
temperature on the right-hand
side when data has been fetched.
But before that, it you will
show the spinner.
The presence of the spinner is
controlled by a state value
called loading.
Loading becomes false when data
has been fetched, and that's
when with the spinner
disappears.
Pretty simple logic.
So to get the live preview, as
Chris mentioned, you click on
the play button.
To get the debugger attached,
you can control click to bring
up the contextual menu and select
debug preview.
Now, my QA engineer told me that
she has found a bug in which
spinner doesn't disappear.
So keep an eye, keep your eyes
on it while I get the debug
session going.
What happens now is that Xcode
will recompile this particular
Swift file with debug info and
launch the new preview.
You know that the debugger is
attached in two ways.
First, you can go to the debug
navigator and look for it, or
you can look for the process
control buttons in the debug
bar.
It looks like we have a debug
session going, and in the
canvas, we can see that the
spinner didn't disappear.
So she's right.
Let's solve this bug.
Under the debugger, we can see
that a new runtime issue is
showing up in the editor.
We can click on the annotation,
and it will show you a message.
Says here modifying state during
view update.
This will cause undefined
behavior.
Now that's quite a mouthful, so
let me explain that.
The body property retains a
view hierarchy that will be
shown later.
The framework will ask for the
body property whenever it thinks
that the views need to be
updated.
So you have no control over when
or how many times it's going to
be asked.
Thus there's no context, there's
absolutely no context for you to
make a decision on how to change
the state value.
Luckily for us, its loading can
be changed at a better place,
which is at the callback of the
weather fetcher.
On line 47.
So, I'm going to move this chunk
of code to line 47, but you will
see that Xcode notices source
code added changes and will
automatically try to launch a
new preview.
So, again, keep your eye on the
spinner in case I'm doing it too
slow.
So here's the spinner.
Data is fetched.
Oh wait, debugger session has to
come in.
Here's the spinner.
It's fetching the data.
The data comes in, spinner
disappears.
So bug is number one solved.
[ Applause ]
To stop the debug session, you
go back to the same place where
you started it and click on the
stop button.
So my ever diligent QA engineer
told me that she also has a
different bug for me, and this
time it's with a different view.
It's called a plain details
view.
So let me show it.
And I'll get the debug session
going while I describe the
situation.
So we have a header here at the
top, and the design here is for
it to get slightly bigger, when
I do a pull down on the screen.
This is to help folks like me
see better.
So, it looks like we have a
debug session, so let me try it
out.
So it does get bigger, that's
good.
And at some point it suddenly
disappears.
So this must be the bug she's
referring to.
And then over here I'd noticed
that a purple icon popped up in
the activity viewer.
So, I'm going to click on that,
and that should bring me to the
issues navigator where it says
cannot invert singular matrix.
Hmm. For those of us who
breathe CGAffine transform daily, you know
exactly what this means.
For the rest of us, here's a
two-hour lecture on high school
linear algebra.
And there's my math PhD friend
pumping his fist, but no, let's
not do that.
But here's a very brief
explanation.
Getting the inverse of a matrix
is akin to doing some math
division.
Now math division you guys all
know.
There are some values that are
simply not possible.
So, we'll see why in a little
bit, but for now let me draw
your attention to another piece
of data in the issues navigator,
which is the recorder backtrace
generated by the debugger.
You disclose that, you will see
backtrace and then there will be
a frame with your debug symbol,
which is frame number one.
You select that, it will
navigate you to the following
line where the issue is
generated.
But in this case, knowing where
is less important than how or
when.
And typically to do that, we
need to pause in the debugger,
and then you can inspect the
state of the process.
Now you guys probably know what
tool I'm going to use to hunt
down these bugs.
Yes, break points.
I can simply put a final break
point in line 44, but guess
what?
It's going to be hit many times
when I do the pull down, so it's
going to be less effective.
So, let's not do that.
Instead, let's head over to the
break points navigator and click
on the add button.
Where in Xcode 11 we have
introduced a new breakpoint
called runtime issue breakpoint,
let's add that.
We'll leave the target
system frameworks.
Now, during the demo I like to
introduce tips and tricks that
will make your workflow more
productive.
Here's another good one.
If you ever have a need to stop
and restart your preview, you
can use the appropriately named
refresh shortcut under the
editor menu.
Let's try that.
So we have a new preview with a
debugger attached.
The Xcode will always remember
your previous configuration.
So if you use the debugger, the
debugger will be attached to the
new preview session.
So, I'm going to do a pulldown.
If I'm lucky, I'll hit the
breakpoint.
There we go.
And Xcode conveniently brings up
the variables view.
Now we know there's something
wrong with our skill transform,
so I'm going to twist it open
and look at the matrix.
M11 is the value that we're
using for X scaling.
We're not doing anything with
it, so we're keeping it at a
constant one.
M22 is the value that we are
using for Y scaling, and when
this value gets to 0, the math
formula for getting the inverse
just doesn't work, right.
Yeah. So, now we know why the
issue is generated, and let's
get up in the code to see where
I assign the value to be 0, for
the Y scaling to be 0.
It looks like it's this line
right here.
Now fix it.
And while I'm here, I'll make
the code more succinct.
Oops.
All right.
I will close the debug area.
All right, let me try it now and
get-- okay, it gets bigger, and
it sticks.
Good. Bug number two solved, and
that actually marks the end of
my demo.
[ Applause ]
So, when you are debugging live
previews, there are three things
that can be different compared
to when you are doing regular
debugging.
First, you use the contextual
manual of the play button in the
canvas to start you debug
session.
To stop it, you click on the
same button.
And you guys saw that Xcode
automatically notices source
code added changes and then
tries to launch a preview, a new
preview for you.
This happens with or without the
debugger.
But with the debugger, there
will be a new debug session.
So, if you want to keep the same
debug session associated with
the same file in the editor, do
not change that file.
To view a different file, you
use a different pane, a
different tab, or a different
window.
So Sebastian will show the
workflow in a little bit.
All right.
For my demo, we learned that
when you are debugging live
previews, you have access to all
the great tools that you are so
used to, but to be more
productive, you want to leverage
on the workflows that we have
designed especially for
previews.
And pay attention to those Swift
UI runtime issues, because they
do point to real bugs and make
use of the runtime issue
breakpoint to help you with the
debugging.
And I've shown you several ways
to do debugging, but sometimes
you just need to do it visually,
and to do that, let's bring out
Sebastian.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Han Ming.
We will indeed take a look at
debugging Swift UI View
hierarchies in a demo, but
before we do so, let's take a
look at a couple characteristics
of Swift UI and key differences
between Swift UI and traditional
UI frameworks like AppKit and
UIKit and see how that may
impact your debugging workflows.
First of all, Swift UI makes use
of a declarative API.
That means, instead of
initializing the views that will
be presented at runtime yourself
and your own source code, you
provide a recipe of your view
hierarchy, and the framework
constructs your views and keeps
them up to date for you at
runtime.
Swift UI embraces composition
and lightweight modifiers over
complex view types, so views
that you may be inspecting at
runtime have a lot less
properties to inspect.
Views in Swift UI are value
types.
That means debugging workflows
that rely on references to views
may not be applicable anymore,
and at runtimes, Swift UI may
translate certain views that you
use in your code and to platform
specific UIKit and AppKit views,
and we will see an example of
that later in the demo.
Swift UI also mixes very well
with existing framework views
from your UIKit or AppKit, and
the travel app that you saw
earlier actually makes use of
exactly that concept to mix a
UIKit view with the Swift UI
views, which are the main views
used in that application.
With these aspects in mind,
let's switch to the demo machine
and take a look at inspecting
the view hierarchy of our
profile screen of the travel
app.
[applause] Thank you.
And we're debugging the profile
view of the travel app again,
and we're already in debug mode
here.
And let me resize the inspector
a little bit.
To inspect the view hierarchy,
we can use this button down here
in Xcode's debug bar to debug
view hierarchy.
And as Han Ming mentioned
earlier, we have to ensure that
the preview stays open while
we're debugging since the debug
session is tied to the lifetime
of the preview.
We can do so using the new
editor split feature in Xcode 11
by holding down option while we
click the debug view hierarchy
button in Xcode's debug bar.
That will open up the view debug
canvas in a separate editor
split, and we have access to the
source code on the top left, the
preview on the bottom left, and
the view debug canvas on the
right-hand side.
[Applause]
Thank you.
If you've used the view debugger
before, this is very familiar to
you.
You have a canvas areas where
you can inspect all your views.
You can export in 3D by simply
rotating, so you get a good
overview of your views, and you
can select elements and see
inspect the properties on the
right-hand side.
The navigator on the left-hand
side has an outline
representation of your view
hierarchy so you can orient
yourself relative to subviews
and superviews.
Okay. So, as I mentioned
earlier, this profile view
combines UIKit and Swift UI, and
looking at the implementation,
you can see that it returns a
vertical stack as part of its
body, which includes avatar view
controller view here, and that
view simply loads a UI view
control from a storyboard file,
and below that, it instantiates
a list.
What that means, the top part
here is built up using UIKit,
and the bottom part is built up
using a list with Swift UI.
The first part of this demo, I
want to focus on the UI Kit part
of the view hierarchy, and then
the second part will focus on
the Swift UI part.
New in Xcode 11 is support for
UI Window Scene, which is a
concept used for multiwindow
support and UIKit apps in iOS
13, and you can see how all UI
windows are now listed below
owning windows scene.
So once you add multiwindow
support in your iOS app, it's
very handy to look out for these
window scenes, and when you
select one in the navigator, you
can also inspect their
properties, for example, see the
title and the activation state
in the inspector.
Another new feature in iOS 13 is
dark mode, and there are several
ways where we enhance the view
debugger this year to help you
add support in your own
application.
First of all, when you select a
UI view or UI view controller,
we now show you trade collection
information in the inspector,
such as the interface style, so
you can ensure that the
interface style is as expected,
and when you override the
interface style for certain
subparts of your view hierarchy,
you can debug it right from the
view debugger.
Another key feature of dark mode
are dynamic colors that adapt to
appearance changes, and a good
way to do that is using
asset catalog and name
colors.
And when we select this badge
here, you can see that it's
achieving its orange tint with a
named color, the accent color,
which is coming from an accent
catalog, so it's now very easy
to tell whether a color is a
name color coming from an accent
catalog that can dynamically
adapt to appearance changes or
whether it's a hard-coded color
that cannot adapt to appearance
changes.
Another new feature are symbol
images, and this badge actually
makes use of a symbol image.
When I just go up a little bit
in this inspector, you can see
details about the symbol image
in the inspector.
We now show names for all images
that you select in the
inspector, and you can get
details like symbol
configuration and see that it's
in fact a system symbol image
compared to for example a custom
symbol that you created in your
assent catalog.
[ Applause ]
Symbol images are aware of their
baseline, so they lay out very
nicely next to text.
We visualize the baseline in
this view on the right-hand
side, and to make sure it
actually lays out nicely next to
text, we have to, in the UIKit
world where we use auto layout
constraints and ensure that we
use the baseline constraints
instead of, for example,
centering them.
Because if this name gets longer
and causes a line break, and we
have a multiline label, we want
to ensure the badge is aligned
to the first line of this label.
We can very easily verify this
with the badge selected.
We can switch to the size
inspector and take a look at the
constraint details.
We overhauled this section in
Xcode 11 to be a lot more like
interface builder and be more
powerful, so you can now
highlight constraints as you
mouse over them.
You can use this mini navigator
here to filter down to a
specific edge, and we can easily
confirm that this badge is in
fact using the first baseline
constraint to the label that's
next to it.
So, that's exactly what we want,
and we were easily able to
confirm this.
Okay. So, these are the
enhancements we made on the
UIKit side.
Let's switch our focus to
SwiftUI.
As we saw, we're currently
looking at the preview of the
profile view, and looking at the
navigator on the left-hand side,
you can see the profile view
shows up there, and we can get a
good understanding of its size
in the canvas area.
We saw that it's using a
vertical stack, and we can also
see that in the canvas area, and
selecting it, you can get
details about it and then
inspect on the right.
Switching back to the profile
view, which has a few more
properties, you can see that a
lot of properties about this
view show up in inspector, and
we actually use Swift reflection
to automatically discover these
properties.
So, even for your own custom
views, we automatically now show
these properties in inspector,
which is a lot more powerful
than before where we only
supported system views.
And we even went one step
further.
You can now customize the
properties that show up in
inspector on the right-hand side
by implementing the customer
reflectable protocol on your
view types, and profile view is
exactly doing that.
You can see that it's returning
three different properties here,
account status, last login, and
profile, as part of a custom
mirror, and looking at the
inspect on the right, you can
see that these are exactly the
properties that I'll return.
So that's a very powerful
feature to let you return
exactly the data that you need
while you're debugging.
[ Applause ]
Taking another look at the
inspector, you can see that at
the top we get properties of
view that is selected currently,
the profile view, and then
further down, we can see all the
modifiers that are currently in
effect on that selected view.
So we can see details about the
padding and the safe area
inset, for example.
Let's take another look at a
different part of the view
hierarchy, and as we saw
earlier, the bottom part is
using a list to lay out all the
views.
So let's select one of the views
that we see here, for example,
the 965 text here, and I will
use a gesture of navigate and
reveal in debug navigator so we
have a good understanding of
where it is inside the view
hierarchy.
And we can see that Swift UI
actually translated that list
into a UI table view under the
hood, and it's using table view
cells to host the Swift UI views
that we construct in our code.
This is an implementation
detail, and you should not rely
on it in your implementation,
but it can be very helpful when
you're trying to debug layout
issues, for example.
With this text selected, there's
actually an issue here that our
designer pointed out.
Instead of vertically centering
these two texts, they should
actually be baseline aligned.
Now, we already saw that there's
a horizontal stack that is
laying them out next to each
other, and when we take a look
at the implementation, here, you
can see that it's a plain
horizontal stack that has no
parameters passed to its
initializer.
But when we take a look at the
inspector, you can see that it
actually defaults to an
alignment of center.
Now, we don't want center
alignment, we want the baseline
alignment.
So, let's adjust the code and
fix this problem.
I will close the view debugger,
continue the debug session, and
activate the previews again.
And for the H stack, I will now
add a parameter of alignment to
dot first baseline, and we can
now see that the two labels are
in fact baseline aligned.
So we were--
[ Applause ]
We were able to see the default
value that the H stack assumed
for its alignment, figure out
the fix for it, and then
instantly verify it using the
new previews in Xcode 11.
With that, I will switch back to
slides.
We just saw, when you're
inspecting Swift UI view
hierarchies, the view hierarchy
shows up in the navigator on the
left-hand side and in the canvas
area, and properties and
modifiers are presented in
inspect on the right-hand side.
Inspect the properties are
automatically discovered using
Swift Reflection, and you can
even customize the inspector
properties that show up in
inspector on the right-hand side
using the custom reflectable
protocol.
And, of course, just as Swift
UI, we also have support for
mixed view hierarchies, and we
just saw how the UIKit view
showed up right next to the
Swift UI views.
We also have numerous
enhancements for UIKit views,
namely support for UI Window
Scene, which will be handy as
you start adopting multiple
windows in your UIKit
applications, and we have
inspector enhancement to provide
even more details such as trait
collection details.
We saw the named images and
symbol image information.
We also saw named colors, which
will be very helpful as you
start it up in dark mode.
And we have greatly improved
constraint details in the
inspector, which are more
powerful than ever before when
you're debugging your auto
layout constraints in your UIKit
application.
If you want to learn more about
device conditions, I recommend
this session here, and there's
also a great video that's
teaching about LLDB and
enhancements.
With that, that brings us to the
end of this talk.
I wish you a fantastic rest of
the conference, and I'll see you
at the bash.
[ Applause ]