[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everybody.
I'm Ben. And together with my
colleague Doug, we're going to
talk to you about API design in
Swift.
So, with the introduction of
both binary and module stability
we're really excited that for
the first time we can introduce
frameworks that make full use of
Swift to provide rich,
efficient, and easy to use APIs
as part of Apple's SDK.
Now, we've learned a few things
as part of designing these APIs
that we want to talk to you
about today.
So, we're going to cover a
couple of fundamental concepts
and understand how they affect
your API designs.
And then we're going to take a
deep dive into some of the new
features in Swift 5.1 and see
how they can help you make your
APIs more expressive.
Along the way we're going to
show you some examples from some
of our latest Swift frameworks,
including SwiftUI and
RealityKit.
Now, we talked about API design
before.
In particular, in 2016, when we
introduced the Swift API Design
Guidelines.
And these were available on the
Swift.org website.
And they contain some really
useful advice around how to name
and document your API.
But I'm not going to recap here
except to say that if there's
one message they're trying to
achieve, it's this: Clarity at
the point of use is your most
important goal as an API
designer.
You want to make it so that when
you read code using your API
it's obvious what it's doing.
And you want to make it easy for
your API to be used correctly.
And good naming and readability
is a critical part of this.
And there's one new thing around
naming that we want to talk
about, which is that going
forward, we're not going to be
using prefixes in the Swift
types in our Swift-only APIs.
Now, this really helps give
these APIs a much cleaner, more
readable feel.
Now, in C and Objective-C, we
had to use prefixes because
every symbol was in the global
name space with no good way to
disambiguate.
And for that reason, both Apple
and developers had to stick to a
really strict prefixing
convention.
And for consistency, we're going
to keep using prefixes on the
Swift versions of APIs that also
have an equivalent in
Objective-C.
But Swift's module system does
allow for disambiguation by
prepending the module name in
front of the type.
And for this reason, the
standard library has never had
prefixes.
And many of you have found that
you could drop them from your
Swift frameworks, too.
And bear in mind that you do
still have to be a little bit
careful even then.
A very general name will cause
your users to have to manually
disambiguate in the case of
conflicts.
And always remember clarity at
the point of use.
A general name from a specific
framework can look a little bit
confusing when you see it out of
context.
Now, we're going to talk about a
couple of topics: Values and
references and protocols and
generics.
And then we're going to cover
our two new features, key path
member lookup and property
wrappers.
So let's start by talking a bit
about values and references.
First a very quick recap.
Swift has three basic concepts
for creating a type: Classes,
Structs, and Enums.
Classes are reference types.
And that means when you have a
variable, it just refers to the
object that actually holds the
values.
And when you copy it, you're
just copying that reference.
And that means that when you
change a value through the
reference, you're changing the
same object to which both
variables refer.
And so they both see the change.
Structs and Enums, on the other
hand, are value types.
And when you copy them, they
copy their entire contents.
And that means that when you
make a change, you're just
changing that one copy.
Now, using value types in your
API can bring a lot of benefits
in terms of clarity at the point
of use.
If you know you're getting a
fresh, unique copy every time,
then you don't need to worry
about where the value came from
and whether somebody has a
reference to it still where they
might change it behind your
back.
You don't need, for example, to
make a defensive copy.
Now, given this, a common
question comes up, which is:
Should I be using a reference or
a value type in my particular
piece of code?
And every use case is different.
So there are no hard rules here.
But here's some general
guidance, which is that in
general, you should prefer using
Structs over classes unless you
have a good reason for using a
class.
If you default to using a class
whenever you create a type, try
flipping that default in your
code going forward and see how
you get on.
Now, classes still play a
critical role in Swift.
They're essential if you need to
manage resources through
reference counting.
Though often you'll want to wrap
that class inside a struct, as
we'll see shortly.
They're also a useful construct
if something is fundamentally
stored and shared.
And importantly, if your type
has identity.
And that notion of identity is
separate from its value.
That's often a sign that a class
might make sense.
Now, a good place where we had
to make this decision was in
RealityKit.
RealityKit's API revolves around
these things called entities.
And these represent objects that
appear in scenes.
And they are stored centrally
inside RealityKit's engine.
And they have identity.
And when you manipulate a scene
by changing an object's
appearance or moving them
around, then you're manipulating
objects directly in that engine.
You can think of the reference
types as like handles into the
actual object stored within
RealityKit.
So this is a perfect use for a
reference type.
But the attributes of those
entities, such as their location
or orientation in a scene, those
are modeled as value types.
Now, let's have a look at how
this looks in code.
So let's say we want to create
this scene here.
So, we would first create a
material type.
And then we'd create two boxes
out of it.
And then we need to anchor them
within the scene.
And then, once we've done this,
we can manipulate the scene
directly using code so we can
move the smaller box up along
the y-axis.
Or rotate the larger box by 45
degrees.
And as we're performing these
operations on these reference
types, we're directly
manipulating the scene.
And this feels fairly intuitive.
Now, supposing then want to do
what we've got here, which is to
make one of the boxes a
different color.
One way we might do that is by
changing the material color to
be red.
Now, what do I expect, as a user
of this API, to happen at this
point?
Should both boxes change because
I've changed the variable they
were both created out of?
Or should only the subsequent
box that I create make use of
this new change?
That is, should material act
like a reference type or a value
type?
And either model would be a
reasonable design for an API.
The benefit of using value types
for this, though, is that if
there's a long distance in your
code between when you first
created and used the material
type and when you change it,
then you might forget that you
had used it previously.
And you might end up changing a
part of the scene that you
didn't expect.
And so for that reason,
RealityKit does choose to make
material a value type.
But reference semantics also
make sense for other APIs like
we've seen with entities.
What's important is that your
API has an easy to explain model
for how things behave and why.
And most importantly, how that
behavior works should not be
driven by incidental
implementation details of the
types.
But instead should be a
conscious choice based on the
use cases.
So, what do I mean by an
accidental implementation
detail?
Well, let's have a look at an
example type.
Let's say a material type.
And I want it to act like a
value, so I make it a struct.
And I give it a couple of simple
properties such as roughness.
And then I give it a texture
property.
And let's say that that texture
property needs to manage
resources with reference
counting.
So I decide to make it a class.
Now, we said a moment ago that
when you make a copy of a value
type, you copy all of its stored
properties.
But that when you copy a
reference type, you're just
copying that reference.
And so when you make a copy of
this material type, what will
end up happening is that they
make a copy of the reference.
And so the two types end up
sharing the same texture object.
Now, whether that's okay or not
really depends on the
implementation of texture.
If textures are immutable, then
it's perfectly fine.
In fact, it's pretty desirable
from a sharing perspective.
But if texture were
fundamentally a mutable type,
then what I've created here is
actually slightly strange.
It behaves neither like a
reference, nor a value.
I can make changes to properties
on the struct.
And it just affects one of the
variables.
But if I make changes through
the texture reference to the
object, then it affects both
variables.
And this can be really
surprising for users of your
API.
And probably more confusing than
if you had just stuck with
reference semantics all the way
through.
And so here we need to make a
really key distinction between
value and reference types,
Structs versus classes, and
value and reference semantics,
how the type behaves.
Just because something is a
value type, like a struct,
doesn't necessarily meant that
you automatically get value
behavior from it.
One way that you might not, not
the only way, but a common way,
is if you include a mutable
reference type as part of its
public API.
So the first question if you
wanted something to behave like
a value is: Are any of the
reference it exposes mutable?
And bear in mind, this isn't
always obvious.
If we were dealing with a
non-final class, then what you
might actually have is a mutable
subclass.
Luckily there are lots of
techniques we have to avoid
problems like this.
So the easiest one is to do what
we've always done with reference
types, which is to make a
defensive copy.
So we could switch our texture
stored property to be private.
And then instead have a computed
property.
And inside the setter, we just
make a copy of the texture
object.
And this avoids the mutable
subclass problem.
But, it doesn't solve the
problem if texture is
fundamentally a mutable type
because you could still mutate
it just through the getter
property.
That's how references work.
And so let's consider another
option, which is to not expose
the reference type at all.
And instead, to just expose the
properties we want on the object
as computed properties on our
material value type.
So, we can create a computed
property.
And in the getter, we just
forward on to the relevant
property of the object.
But in the setter, we can first
check if the object is known to
be uniquely referenced.
And if it's not, at that point
we can make a full copy of the
texture object before going on
and making our mutation.
By adding this one line to check
for uniqueness, we've
implemented full copy-on-write
value semantics while still
exposing the properties we want
on our reference type.
So next, let's talk a bit about
protocols and generics.
So, we've seen how value types
can add clarity at the point of
use to your API.
But, value types aren't new.
We've had types like CGPoint or
CGrect in Objective-C all along.
So what's different?
Well, what's different in Swift
is the ability to apply
protocols to Structs and Enums
as well as just classes.
And that means you can share
code across a variety of types
using generics.
And so if you feel you need to
share some code between
different types, don't feel like
you have to create a class
hierarchy with a base class that
has that shared functionality.
Instead, as the saying goes, in
Swift, start with a protocol.
But, that doesn't mean that when
you open up XCode and you've got
an empty source file you type
the keyword "protocol" as your
first thing.
In Swift API design, like any
Swift design, first explore the
use case with concrete types.
And understand what code it is
that you want to share when you
find yourself repeating multiple
functions on different types.
And then factor that shared code
out using generics.
Now, that might mean creating
new protocols.
But first, consider composing
what you need out of existing
protocols.
And when you're designing
protocols, make sure that they
are composable.
And as an alternative to
creating a protocol, consider
creating a generic type instead.
So let's have a look at some
examples that show some of these
different things.
So, let's say I wanted to create
a geometry API.
And as part of that, I wanted to
create operations on geometric
vectors.
I might start off by creating a
protocol for a geometric vector.
And I could give it the
operations that I want to
define, like dot product or the
distance between two vectors.
Now, I need to store the
dimensions of the vector.
So I might make my geometric
vector refine the SIMD protocol.
If you're not already familiar
with SIMD types, they're
basically like kind of
homogenous tuples that can
very efficiently perform
calculations on every element at
once.
And they've got a lot great new
features in Swift 5.1.
And they're perfect for doing
geometry calculations.
So, we're going to store our
dimensions in that base SIMD
type.
And we'll also want to constrain
it to only work on scalar SIMDs
so that we can do the
calculations we want.
Now, once we've defined this
protocol, we could then go and
implement default
implementations for all of the
operations we want to do on
vectors.
And then we want to give a
conformance to this protocol to
each of the types that we want
to get these new capabilities.
And this three-step process of
defining the protocol, giving it
a default implementation, and
then adding a conformance to
multiple types, it's actually
kind of tedious.
And it's worth taking a step
back for a second and saying:
Was the protocol really
necessary?
The fact that none of these
conformances actually have their
own custom implementation is
actually kind of a warning sign
that maybe the protocol isn't
useful.
There's no per type
customization going on.
And in fact, this operation
works on every different kind of
SIMD type.
So, is the protocol really
giving us anything?
If we take a step back, and
instead of writing our default
implementation on our new
protocol, we just write it as an
extension directly on the SIMD
protocol with the same
constraints, then we're done.
In this single page of code
we've automatically given all of
the capabilities we need to all
of the SIMD types that contain
floats.
It might feel tempting sometimes
to create this elaborate
hierarchy of protocols and to
classify the different types
into this hierarchy.
But this sort of type zoology,
which it feels satisfying, isn't
always necessary.
And there's also a practical
consideration here.
This simpler extension-based
approach without the protocol is
a lot easier for the compiler to
process.
And your binary sites will be
smaller without a bunch of
unnecessary protocol witness
tables in it.
In fact, we've found that on
very large projects, with a
large number of complex protocol
types, we could significantly
improve the compile time of
those applications by taking
this simplification approach and
reducing the number of
protocols.
Now, this extension approach is
good for a small number of
helpers.
But it does hit a scalability
problem when you're designing a
fuller API.
Earlier when we're thinking
about creating a protocol, we
said that we'd define geometric
vector and make it refine SIMD,
which we'd use for our storage.
But is that really right?
Is this an Is-a relationship?
Can we really say a geometric
vector "is a" SIMD type?
I mean, some operations make
sense.
You can add and subtract
vectors.
But others don't.
You can't multiply two vectors
by each other.
Or add the number 1 to a vector.
But these operations are
available on all SIMD types.
And have other definitions that
do make sense in other contexts.
Just not in the context of
geometry.
And so if we were designing an
API that would be easy to use,
then we might consider another
option, which is instead of an
Is-a relationship to implement
as a has-a relationship.
That is, to wrap a SIMD value
inside a generic struct.
So we could create instead a
struct of geometric vector.
And we make it generic over our
SIMD storage type so that it can
handle any floating point type
and any different number of
dimensions.
And then once we've done this,
we have much more fine-grained
control over exactly what API we
expose on our new type.
So we can define addition of two
vectors to each other.
But not addition of a single
number to a vector.
Or we can define multiplication
of a vector by a scaling factor,
but not multiplication of two
vectors by each other.
And we can still use generic
extensions.
So our implementations of dot
product and distance remain
pretty much the same as they did
before.
Now, we've actually used this
technique within the standard
library.
For example, we just have one
SIMD protocol.
And then we have Structs that
are generic that represent each
of the different sizes of SIMD
type.
Notice that there's no SIMD2 or
SIMD3 protocol here.
They wouldn't necessarily add
much value.
Users can still write generic
code for a specific size of SIMD
by extending, say, the SIMD3
type with the cross product
operation you would only want to
define on three-dimensional SIMD
types.
So hopefully this gives you a
feel for how generic types can
be just as powerful and
extensible as protocols can be.
Now, we're still using the power
of protocols here.
We have our floating point
protocol constraining the scalar
type on the generic SIMD that
gives us the building blocks
that we need to write this code.
Now, we could write this same
cross product operation on our
geometric vector type.
But when we do, the
implementation looks a little
bit ugly.
Because we keep having to
indirect through the value
storage in order to get at the
x, y, and z coordinates.
And so it would be nice if we
could clean this up.
Now, obviously we could just
write computed properties on our
vector type for x, y, and z.
But there's actually a new
feature in Swift 5.1 called Key
Path Member Lookup that allows
you to write a single subscript
operation that exposes multiple
different computed properties on
a type all in one go.
And so we could use this if we
chose to, if it made sense, to
expose all of the properties on
SIMD on our geometric vector all
in one swoop.
Let's have a look at how we'd do
that.
So first we tag our geometric
vector type with the dynamic
member lookup attribute.
And then next, the compiler will
prompt us to write a special
dynamic member subscript.
And this subscript takes a key
path.
And the effect of implementing
this subscript is that any
property that is accessible via
that key path automatically is
exposed as a computed property
on our geometric vector type.
So in our case, we want to take
a key path into the SIMD storage
type and have it return a
scalar.
And then we just use that key
path to forward on and retrieve
the value from our value storage
and return it.
And once we've done this,
automatically our geometric
vector gets all of the
properties that SIMD has.
So for example, it gets the x,
y, and z coordinates.
And they even appear in
autocompletion in Xcode.
And if you tried this feature in
Swift 5 when it was
string-based, the difference
here is that this version is
completely type safe.
And a lot more of it is done at
compile time.
Now that we have access to the
x, y, and z properties, we can
clean up the implementation of
our cross product operation
quite a bit.
There, that's much nicer.
Now, this dynamic member
capability is not just useful
for forwarding onto properties.
You can also put complex logic
into the subscript.
So, let's look at one more
example.
Let's go back to our example
from earlier where we exposed a
specific property from texture
with copy on write value
semantics.
Now, this works for one
property.
But it would be unfortunate if
we had to write this same code
every single time.
What if it wanted to expose all
of the properties on texture as
properties on our material type
with copy-on-write semantics?
Well, we can do it with dynamic
member lookup.
So first we add to the dynamic
member attribute to our type.
And then we implement the
subscript operation.
And we're going to make it take
a writable key path because we
want to be able to both get and
set the properties.
And we're going to make it
generic on the return type
because we want to get any
different type out of the
texture.
And then we implement the getter
and setter.
In the getter, we just forward
on like we did before.
But in the setter, before we do
our mutation, we add the unique
referencing check and full copy
of texture.
And by doing this, in one
subscript method that's not too
long, we expose every single
property on texture with full
copy-on-write semantics on our
material type.
And this is a really useful way
to get value semantics out of
your types.
This new feature has lots of
different applications.
And it actually composes really
well with a new feature in 5.1
called Property Wrappers that
Doug is going to you about next.
Doug.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ben.
So, Swift is designed for clear
concise code and to build
expressive APIs, right?
It's also there for code reuse.
We've been talking about
generics and protocols.
And they're there so you can
create generic code, so for your
functions, for your types, that
can be reused.
So property wrappers is a new
feature in Swift 5.1.
And the idea behind property
wrappers is to effectively get
code reuse out of the computed
properties you write.
Things like this large pile of
code here.
And what is going on here?
So, all we tried to do was
expose a public property, right?
And here we have it.
We just want an image property
that's public.
But we don't want all of our
users, our clients, to be able
to go and write whatever value
in there.
We want to describe some policy.
So it's a computed property.
And our actual storage is back
here in this internal image
storage property.
All the access to that storage
is gated through the getters and
setters.
This is a lot of code.
You've had a few seconds with
it.
Some of you have probably
recognized what this is.
It's a really long-winded way to
say this is just a lazy variable
image.
Now, this is so much better.
It's one line of code instead of
two properties with a mess of
sort of policy logic for
accessing.
And we have this nice modifier
"lazy" there to tell you here's
what the actual semantics are.
This is important.
It's better documenting.
It's easier to read.
That's why "lazy" has been in
the language since Swift 1.
Now, the problem is, this is one
instance of a more general
problem.
So, let's take a look at another
example here, the code
structure.
Basically identical.
But the policy, what's actually
implemented here in the getter
and setter, is different.
So if you're looking through the
logic here, you see this is sort
of a late initialization
pattern.
You have to set this thing once,
or initialize it once before you
can read it.
Otherwise you get a failure.
This is a fairly common thing.
This kind of code shows up in a
lot of places.
We couldn't go and extend Swift
with another language feature
that attacks this one problem.
But really, we want to solve
this more generally, because we
want people to be able to build
libraries of these things, where
they have the notion of
separating the policy for
accessing a value out.
And so this is the idea behind
property wrappers, to eliminate
this boilerplate and get more
expressive APIs.
So, they look a little like
this.
And the idea here is we want to
capture the notion of you're
declaring a property.
So here it is this public text
variable, and applying the late
initialized property wrapper to
give it a particular set of
semantics, to give it a
particular policy.
Now, this at-LateInitialized,
this is a custom attribute.
It's a new notion that we're
using a bit in Swift.
And essentially, it's saying:
Apply this late initialized
pattern, whatever it is.
We'll get back to that in a
moment.
But just from the code
perspective, this is a whole lot
like lazy.
And it's giving us all the same
benefits as lazy.
We've gotten rid of all that
boilerplate.
But also we've documented at the
point where we declare this
thing, what are the actual
semantics.
This is far easier to read and
reason about than that mess of
code.
All right.
Enough talking about this one
little line of code.
Let's see what LateInitialized
actually looks like.
And what you'll see here it's a
bit of code.
But it's the same code we just
saw.
It's the same policy pattern
behind late initialization.
You've got the getter and setter
here.
The set is just updating the
storage.
The getter is checking to make
sure we've set it at least once,
and then returning the value
when we have.
Fairly direct.
Now, what makes this simple
generic type interesting is that
it is a property wrapper.
It's indicated as such by the
property wrapper attribute here
at the top.
Now, what that's doing is it's
enabling the custom attribute
syntax to say we can apply this
thing to some other property.
Now, with the property wrapper
attribute come a couple of
requirements.
The main one is to have this
value property.
This is where all the policy is
implemented.
So all accesses to a late
initialized property go through
here.
And we can see that the actual
notation is finding some
extracted notion of what late
initialized is.
The other interesting thing in
this particular example is that
we've declared an initializer
that takes no parameters.
Now, this is optional with the
property wrapper.
But when you have it there, what
it's saying is that properties
that are applying this wrapper
get implicit initialization for
free going through this
particular initializer.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Let's actually use this thing.
So, when you use a property
wrapper by applying it to a
particular property, the
compiler is going to translate
that code into two separate
properties.
We're essentially expanding out
into that pattern we saw in the
beginning here.
So you have the backing storage
property with this $ prefix.
So $text. And the type of this
is an instance of the property
wrapper type.
So now we have a late
initialized string.
That's providing the storage.
It's going to be initialized
implicitly by the compiler by
calling that no parameter
initializer that we just talked
about.
Because it's there, now we get
implicit initialization.
And late initialize is free to
do whatever it wants.
As you might recall, it set the
storage to nil.
The other thing that the
compiler is doing here is it's
translating text into a computed
property.
And so the getter it's going to
create is accessing $text.
And then retrieving the value
out of $text by calling the
getter for value.
And we do the same thing for the
setter, writing the new value
into $text.value.
And so this is what allows your
property wrapper type to have
its own storage, however it
wants to store it, either
locally or somewhere else.
And then enforce whatever policy
you should have about accessing
that data through the getter and
setter value.
So overall, this is really nice.
We've teased apart the policy,
put it in one place in the late
initialized wrapper from the
application of that policy,
which we can do on any number of
different properties of whatever
types we want, making it far
simpler and having less
boilerplate.
So, let's take a look at another
example.
Ben was talking a bit about
value and reference semantics.
Now, when you're dealing with
reference semantics and mutable
state, you're going to find
yourself doing defensive copying
at some point.
Of course, we could manually do
that wherever we need it.
But why not go and build a
property wrapper for it?
So, here the property wrapper,
the shape of it, is basically
the same as we've seen before.
It had some kind of storage.
And it has a value property.
All of the policy for this
property wrapper is here in the
setter.
When we get a new value, go
ahead and copy the value.
And since we're using NSCopying
to do our copies, it just goes
ahead and calls that copy method
and does the cast.
The other interesting thing with
defensive copying is it provides
an initial value initializer.
This is like that no-parameter
initializer.
You don't have to have it in
your property wrapper.
But when it's there, it lets you
provide a default value on any
property that's wrapped with
this property wrapper.
That default gets fed into this
initializer.
And we can enforce whatever
policy we want on
initialization.
In our case, it's the same as
the set policy.
We want to go ahead and create a
copy defensively and assign that
a result then.
Let's take a look.
So, if we go define some
defensive copying UIBezierPath.
What's going to happen?
Well, the compiler is going to
translate this into the two
different definitions.
We're going to have an
initializer here first.
So here, whenever we create this
path, it has a default of the
UIBezierPath.
Just an empty instance that's
created.
And then when we go ahead and
explode this out into multiple
properties, there's the backing
stored property, $path.
And notice how we're
initializing it.
We're feeding the initial value
that the user gave into the
initial value initializer so it
can be defensively copied.
The getter and setter look
exactly the same.
We're just going through
$path.value for both get and
set.
Now, this is of course the right
semantics by default.
Defensive copying should go
ahead and copy.
In this case, well we know
something about our default
value.
It's creating a new object.
Why would we go and copy that
thing?
So, let's optimize this a little
bit just because we can.
So we can extend defensive
copying.
It's just a type.
There's nothing magical about
this type other than the fact
that it's behaving like a
property wrapper when used that
way.
And so we can give it this
withoutCopying initializer.
When we want to use that, we can
go ahead and write an
initializer for our type.
And what we're doing here is
we're assigning to $path to call
the defensive withoutCopying
initializer so we can avoid that
extra copy.
So there's really nothing more
magic that's going on here.
$path is just a stored property.
It's only magical in the sense
that the compiler generated it
for you as part of applying this
property wrapper pattern.
But you can go and treat it like
a normal variable whenever you
want, including setting up your
own initialization.
Now, this is a little bit
boilerplatey, still.
It's unfortunate that we had to
write that initializer.
So there's one other
initialization form that you
might see.
And that is that when you are
declaring the customer
attribute, so
at-DefensiveCopying, you can
actually initialize right there
in the properties declaration
with whatever you want.
So here we can go and call the
withoutCopying initializer to
initialize the backing storage
property with exactly what we
want.
It's one nice little
declaration.
And you get the benefits of
getting the default in the
memorize initializers for free,
still.
All right.
So, property wrappers are
actually fairly powerful.
They abstract away this notion
of policy to access your data.
So you can decide how your data
is stored.
And you can decide how your data
is accessed.
And all your users need to do
with your property wrapper is
use that custom attribute syntax
to tie into your system.
So as we've been developing
property wrappers, we've found a
lot of different uses for them
all around this sort of general
notion of data access.
So for example, you may have
seen the user defaults example.
And here's where we're setting
up a relationship between a
well-typed property here in
Swift that you just referred to
as a Bool and some
stringly-typed entity.
So we describe in the
construction arguments exactly
how to go ahead and access that
thing.
And all of the logic for dealing
with user defaults, that's over
in this user default property
wrapper.
So we built thread-specific.
If you want thread local
storage.
You can apply the
thread-specific property
wrapper.
All the details of dealing with
the system's thread-specific
storage are there in the
property wrapper once.
You can just think of this thing
like a local memory pool.
And also, from the Swift
community, as we've been
building this feature, we found
that this actually works really
well for describing command line
arguments.
If you're building a command
line tool with a library out
there that uses this kind of
shorthand syntax, just say,
well, I want a minimum value.
Here's how I describe the
option.
Here's the strings that the user
passes, where they're short,
what the documentation is.
All the extra stuff that you
need to very, very succinctly
declare your command line
options.
There's a ton of really cool
stuff that we can do with
property wrappers because we
have this nice, clean syntax for
factoring stuff out.
Now, as you probably noticed
from another session, we use
property wrappers extensively
throughout SwiftUI to describe
the data dependencies of your
view.
And there's several of these
different property wrappers that
exist within Swift UI.
So here we have State for
introducing view local state.
We have Binding for a sort of
first class reference out to
state that's somewhere else.
You've probably seen
Environment, an environment
object.
All of these things are property
wrappers.
And the really nice thing about
describing them that way in
Swift is that you're stating
your policy for where this data
is and how it's accessed in one
place in the declaration.
But when you go and build your
view, you don't care about that.
You don't care where the data
is.
It's managed by the system for
you.
You just can refer to the
particular slide I'm on in my
keynote deck.
Pull out its number.
If you want to go and edit
something, you can use $ and get
back at the actual binding.
So, all of the logic for dealing
with the data and watching for
change updates and maybe even
storing the data on the side,
that's all handled off in the
policy in the property wrapper
types.
You don't have to think about
it.
You just worry about working
with your actual data.
Now, there's one thing that's a
little bit interesting on this
slide.
So, there's $slide.title.
We're passing down so we can
edit the slide title in a text
field.
$slide -- well, we've seen that
before.
That's the backing storage
property.
That's what the compiler is
synthesizing on our behalf
because we applied the binding
property wrapper here.
But that's a binding.
It doesn't have a title.
Title is something that's part
of my data model.
I have a slide data model.
What gives?
So, this is actually a
combination of both property
wrappers and the key path member
lookup feature that Ben talked
about earlier.
And so, let's actually focus in
on binding, the thing that's in
Swift UI and provides this first
class reference.
First and foremost, binding is a
property wrapper.
So, it has the standard value.
It's parameterized over any type
because you can have a binding
to anything.
It has whatever the access
pattern is.
It doesn't matter.
We don't know what it is because
it's handled by the framework
for us.
But, binding also supports key
path member lookup with this
generic subscript.
These generic subscripts are
kind of a mouthful.
And we don't have to know what
the implementation is, but we
should look at the type
signature a little more closely
because it is interesting.
So, what we're taking in is a
key path.
It's rooted at our particular
value type.
So the thing that we're binding,
like a slide, and accessing any
property within that particular
entity.
Now, returning is not a value
that's referring to like
something in there.
We're returning a new binding
that is focused in on just one
particular property of the outer
binding, still maintaining that
data dependency there.
So, how does this work in
practice.
Well, we had our slide, which is
a binding into one of our slide
types.
And primarily we think about
this as the value.
So we can refer to slide, we get
an instance of slide.
We can refer to slide.title and
get an instance of that string.
All the while tracking
modifications behind the scenes.
If we enter $Slide, well, we get
that binding instance to the
slide.
When we enter $slide.title, well
now we're looking for a property
that's not there on binding, so
the compiler's rewriting this
into a use of the dynamic number
subscript, passing in a key path
to slide.title.
The way this is resolved is one
of these focused bindings
pointing into the string
property within the previous
binding following all the data
dependencies throughout.
And so, if we step away from the
language mechanism that we've
been focusing on and sort of
look at the high level code that
we did here, it's really nice.
We established our data
dependency using this custom
attribute in the property
wrapper.
We have primary access to our
data very easily to go read it
or modify it.
And if we want a pass down a
first class reference through
our binding, we put this prefix
of $ at the front of it.
And the effect we get is we
always get to pass down a
binding to some other view.
So, we've talked about a couple
of different topics.
We talked about value semantics
and reference semantics, when to
use each of them and how to make
them work together.
We've talked about the use of
generics and protocols.
And remember, protocols are
extremely powerful.
But use them for code reuse.
That's what they're there for.
Not for classification and
building big hierarchies because
those are going to get in your
way.
You're not going to need it.
And finally, we went into a
little deep dive into the
property wrappers language
feature and how we can use it to
abstract access to data.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Come see us in the labs if you'd
like to chat about any of these.
[ Applause ]