[ Music ]
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
My name is Harlan.
And I am super excited to talk
to you about how Xcode 11 allows
you to create and distribute
Binary Frameworks in Swift.
Now, before I talk about binary
frameworks, I actually want to
take a moment to talk about
Swift Packages.
With the new support for Swift
Packages in Xcode 11, it's easy
to create and use them in your
projects and distribute them to
others.
And Swift Packages are a great
way to distribute your code,
because Xcode knows how to
manage their dependencies, and
it will figure out which version
of your Packages to use
automatically.
And because they are distributed
in Source form, there is no
requirement to maintain binary
compatibility with your clients.
If you have the ability to ship
the source code of your project,
then Swift Packages are really,
really great.
But not everyone has the ability
to ship the source of their
libraries, and if you don't,
then Xcode 11 supports
distributing binary libraries
using the new XCFrameworks
format.
[ Applause ]
So, in this talk, I'm going to
introduce you to XCFrameworks,
the new supported way to
distribute binary frameworks.
And I will also talk about some
things that clients should
consider when they're choosing
to use third-party code.
Next, I'll talk about what's
inside an XCFramework, and how
you can go about creating one
for your project.
And then finally, my colleague,
Jordan, will come up and talk to
you about some things that
framework authors should
consider to make using their
framework as smooth as possible.
So XCFrameworks are a new way to
bundle up multiple variants of
your framework in a way that
will work across Xcode versions
going forward.
A single XCFramework can contain
a variant for the simulator, and
for the device.
[ Applause ]
Not done yet.
Because a single XCFramework can
also contain a variant for any
of the platforms that Xcode
supports.
[ Applause ]
You can also have a variant for
Mac apps that use AppKit, and a
variant for Mac apps that use
UIKit.
So, no matter which API your
clients want to use, they will
be able to use your framework
effectively.
And not only can you bundle up
frameworks, but you can also use
XCFrameworks to bundle up static
libraries, and their
corresponding headers.
And Xcode will set up your
client's search pads
automatically.
And of course--
[ Applause ]
XCFrameworks support binary
distribution of Swift and
C-based code.
So, now I'd actually like to
just show you how easy it is to
get started using an
XCFramework.
So here, I've got a pretty
simple iOS app.
And I will go ahead and click
Run to run it on the iPad
Simulator.
You can see, it has got a big,
blue Launch button, and when you
click it, it does nothing.
Well, that is because it's
hooked up to this launch method
right here, and its body is
totally empty.
Well, I've actually got this
awesome XCFramework I'd like to
use, called FlightKit.
And FlightKit gives me some UI
that I'd to present in my
application.
So, to actually be able to use
the FlightKit XCFramework, all I
need to do is click on the
Project in the Project
Navigator, select my target, and
make sure the General tab is
selected.
Then, I'll scroll down to
Frameworks, Libraries, and
Embedded Content.
Then, I'll just drag in my
XCFramework, and that has been
wired up automatically as a
dependency of my target.
So let's go back to the code and
start using it.
Well, just like any framework
you're used to using already,
the first thing you'll do is
Import it.
And now, I'd like to go ahead
and get started using some of
the APIs from FlightKit.
So, either I could go look at
the documentation, or I can
Command click the name
FlightKit, and click Jump to
Definition.
What this will do is it will
take me to the generated
interface for FlightKit.
And this shows all the public
APIs.
Every public type, public
method, everything that I can
use when I import FlightKit.
So I can see that there is this
LaunchViewController, which is a
subclass of UIViewController.
That seems to be some little
piece of UI that I might want to
show.
Great. So, now I need to know
actually how to create one of
these, and I can see in the
interface that there is an
Initializer that takes a
Spaceship.
And that Spaceship is also part
of FlightKit.
So, if I jump to its definition,
it will take me further down in
this generated interface and
show me everything that is in
Spaceship that I can make use
of.
I can see that there is a public
stored property called Name, and
there is also a public
initializer that takes a name.
Okay, so I can create a
Spaceship, and I can create a
LaunchViewController, and then I
can present it.
So, let's go back to the code
and do exactly that.
So, first I'll create a ship,
and I can see that auto
completion is already suggesting
to me all the things that were
in FlightKit, again, just like
any framework that you are
already used to using.
I can accept this auto
completion, then I'll pick a
name for my ship.
Well, I've got this array of
ship names already, and any one
of them would be a great name
for this ship.
So I will actually go ahead and
pick a random element out of the
ship names array.
Now, I will create a
LaunchViewController, and I'll
pass it the ship that I just
created.
And finally, I'll show the
controller passing myself as the
sender.
So, created a ship, created some
UI, and now I'll go to show it.
I'll build and run my program in
the Simulator.
And when I click the Launch
button, it picks a random name,
and launches the UI.
If I click it again, it will
pick another name, and another.
You get it.
So, that's how to use an
XCFramework for just one
platform, but one of the great
things about XCFrameworks is
that you can put multiple
variants in the same bundle.
So just by dragging the one
XCFramework in, not only am I
able to build and run for the
simulator, but if I select
Generic iOS Device, then I can
go to Product Archive, and build
an archive for the App Store as
well.
So that is how easy it is to use
an XCFramework from your code.
[ Applause ]
So when you are making the
choice to use a framework, it's
really important to be aware of
what you're making available to
third party code.
Importantly, you want to make
sure that you trust the source
of the framework.
You trust that they're not going
to introduce bugs or instability
to your app, and you trust that
they'll respect your user's
privacy.
For example, if you've been
granted Entitlements for your
application, and you use a
framework, that framework is
also granted those entitlements.
And those permissions, if your
users have granted them
permissions.
Additionally, if you're adopting
a framework that expects a
certain entitlement to be
available, it's your
responsibility to add that
entitlement to your app.
Another thing to consider about
using frameworks is that
sometimes you will use a
framework that brings its own
dependencies along, and those
dependencies might have their
own dependencies, and it's your
responsibility not only to add
all of these to your project,
but also to extend the same
trust to each of them as well.
Now, it is worth noting that
this trust extends to using
Swift Packages as well.
One advantage of packages over
binary frameworks is that you
can inspect the code, and you
can step into it while you're
debugging.
If you want more information
about using Swift Packages in
Xcode, I'd recommend these talks
from earlier this week.
But whether you're using a
package or a binary framework,
Xcode 11 makes it easy to use
third party code that you trust.
So now, I'd like to talk about
how to create an XCFramework.
Well, the first thing you'll
want to do is have some source
code that you'd like to
distribute.
So let's actually take a look at
some of the source code from
FlightKit, from earlier.
This is just a subset of the
objects in FlightKit, just for
an example.
But you can see that Spaceship
type that we looked at earlier.
You can also see an enum called
Speed, that describes how fast
something can move in space.
You also see a struct called
Location, that describes the
location of an object in space.
Great. So we have this code.
Now, how do we make sure that we
build this library for
distribution?
Well, in Xcode 11, there's a new
Build setting called Build
Libraries for Distribution.
And it does exactly that.
It turns on all the features
that are necessary to build your
library in such a way that it
can be distributed.
Now, let's talk about one of
those features right now.
If you've tried sending somebody
a built Swift Framework before,
you may have seen a variant of
this error.
Compiled module was created by a
newer version of the compiler.
What does this error actually
mean?
Well, when the Swift compiler
goes to import a module, it
looks for a file called the
Compiled Module for that
library.
If it finds one of these files,
it reads off the manifest of
public APIs that you can call
into, and lets you use them.
Now, this Compiled Module Format
is a binary format that
basically contains internal
compiler data structures.
And since they're just internal
data structures, they're subject
to change with every version of
the Swift Compiler.
So what this means is that if
one person tries to import a
module using one version of
Swift, and that module was
created by another version of
Swift, their compiler can't
understand it, and they won't be
able to use it.
Well, in order to solve this
version lock, Xcode 11
introduces a new format for
Swift Modules, called Swift
Module Interfaces.
And just like the Compiled
Module Format, they list out all
the public APIs of a module, but
in a textual form that behaves
more like source code.
And since they behave like
source code, then future
versions of the Swift Compiler
will be able to import module
interfaces created with older
versions.
And when you enable Build
Libraries for Distribution,
you're telling the compiler to
generate one of these stable
interfaces whenever it builds
your framework.
So, what does one of these
interfaces actually look like?
Let's take a look again at the
source of FlightKit.
So that is the source from
FlightKit.
And on the right, you'll see the
Module Interface for FlightKit.
Now, this is a lot, and it goes
off the screen, so we are going
to look at it piece by piece.
So first you'll see this section
of meta data.
So this includes the version of
the compiler that produced this
interface, but it also contains
the subset of command line flags
that the Swift Compiler needs to
import this as a module.
Next, you'll see all the modules
that this framework imports, and
then we'll start seeing the
types that are part of the
interface.
So, here's the public API of the
Spaceship class.
Now, I want you to notice three
things here.
Number one is that the public
name property is included in the
interface, but the private
current location property is
not.
It's not part of the public API.
Next, notice that the public
initializer and the fly method
are included in the interface.
But their bodies are not
included, again, because they're
not part of the public API.
And finally, notice that the
class has a de-initializer in
the interface, but there wasn't
one written in the original
source code.
Now, when you write a class in
Swift, and you don't provide an
explicit de-initializer, the
compiler generates one for you.
And this sort of highlights one
of the underlying principles of
Module Interfaces.
If this format is supposed to be
stable across versions of the
compiler, then the compiler
should not make any assumptions
about the underlying source
code.
So we include it in the Module
Interface.
Next, let's look at that Speed
enum.
Well, the first thing to see is
that both cases of the enum are
included.
Those are part of the public
API.
However, in the interface,
there's an explicit conformance
to Hashable.
And we list off the methods that
are required to conform to both
Hashable and Equitable.
Well, this is because in Swift,
if you make an enum without any
associated values, then the
compiler implicitly makes that
conform to an Equitable and
Hashable, and automatically
derives the methods that are
required.
So, in the spirit of being
explicit, and not making
assumptions, it's included in
the Module Interface.
And finally, the Location struct
is included as is, because it
only has public stored
properties, and does not declare
any conformances.
So that's a quick look at the
Module Interface for FlightKit.
Now that you've taken a look at
what's inside a framework, let's
talk about how to build a
distributable binary XCFramework
yourself.
Well, the first step to building
your framework is by building an
archive.
Archiving Your Framework will
build it in Release Mode, and it
will package it up for
distribution and you can see
that in the Organizer window.
And as an added benefit, this
archive will also contain the
debug information that
corresponds to that build of
your framework, which means if
your clients have any crashes or
any instability that originate
in your framework, they'll be
able to send it to you, and you
will be able to look at the
symbols and debug it.
To Archive your framework, you
can use the xcodebuild archive
command.
You'll pass in the scheme of
your framework in your project,
and list out the destinations
that you'd like to compile it
for.
So if you're building for iOS,
this can be one for the
simulator, one for the device,
and one for the Mac that's
running UIKit.
You will also need to pass the
Skip Install build setting, and
set it to No.
This tells xcodebuild archive to
install your framework in the
resulting archive.
So, by doing this, you will be
building archives of each
variant of your framework, and
those will be available in the
Archives directory in the Xcode
Locations tab, in the
Preferences window.
Once you've built these
archives, you can extract the
frameworks, and bundle them up
together in one XCFramework.
And to do this, you'll run the
xcodebuild -create-xcframework
command.
You'll pass in the path to each
framework on disk, and then
provide a path that you'd like
the output XCFramework to be
output to.
So, that's how to build an
XCFramework.
And in summary, remember, you'll
want to enable Build Libraries
for Distribution, to make sure
that your library is built to be
distributed.
You'll run xcodebuild archive,
to build archives of your
framework, and finally you'll
run xcodebuild
-create-xcframework, to package
it up for distribution.
And then you can start sending
it to your clients, and they can
start adopting it.
So that was XCFrameworks.
Now, my teammate, Jordan, will
come up to talk to you about
what you should consider as a
framework author to make using
your framework as smooth as
possible.
[ Applause and Cheering ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Harlan.
All right.
So we saw how easy it was to
bring one of these XCFrameworks
into an app that is a client of
the framework, and we saw the
steps required to produce an
XCFramework.
But that's just the first step,
because you're framework
authors, and you're developing
new capabilities every year, and
making things better and better
for your clients.
So, in this section, I'm going
to talk about three major
things.
Evolving your framework from
release to release.
Trading some flexibility that
Swift gives you for
optimizability of your clients,
and helping your clients have
the smoothest experience
possible.
So, start with evolving your
framework.
And what do I mean when I say
evolving your framework?
Well, like I said, every time
you release a new version of
your framework, it will have new
capabilities, new APIs, maybe
some bug fixes, and we want to
be able to do that without
breaking source or binary
compatibility.
Now, why is binary compatibility
important here?
It's because you don't
necessarily know who your
clients are going to be.
A lot of times it will just be
an app target.
They'll take your framework,
bundle it up, and send it off to
the store.
But other times, you'll have
clients that are themselves
binary frameworks, either from
your company or another company
entirely.
And in that case, the two of you
probably have separate release
schedules.
They might get all the way up to
version 2.1, while you're still
working on your newest version.
And when you finally do release
that version 1.1, well, they
shouldn't have to do any extra
effort to adopt it.
You don't want to get in a
situation where two binary
frameworks are version locked
with one another, because then
the application who is using
them might decide not to update.
So, I'm saying here that the
version of your framework is
important, and not only do you
want to put that on your
website, and your documentation,
but you should also put it in
the framework itself, and the
place to do that is the Bundle
version string setting in the
framework's Info.plist.
This is the place for a human
readable version number to
communicate to your clients what
changes you've made since the
last release.
And the way that we recommend to
do that is with Semantic
Versioning.
Now, if you weren't in the
Packages talk, I'll do a quick
review of what Semantic
Versioning is.
The smallest component is the
Patch Version, and represents
when you make bug fixes, or
implementation changes to your
framework that shouldn't affect
your clients.
The middle component is for
backwards compatible editions,
new APIs, or new capabilities.
And the Major component is for
any breaking changes that you
have to make, whether that's
source breaking, binary
breaking, or semantics breaking
in a way where clients will have
to rebuild, and possibly redo
some of their client code, in
order to adopt the new version
of the framework.
Let's see what this looks like
in practice, with the FlightKit
model objects.
So here is the same thing on the
left that we had from before.
And now, on the right, I've made
a bunch of changes to this
framework.
Let's go through them piece by
piece and see how each change
can affect the framework's
version number.
We'll start at the top.
I've added a new private
property to the Spaceship class.
And I'm using it in the
Spaceship's initializer.
Now, neither of these things are
going to appear in the module
interface.
They're not part of your
framework's public API.
So this sort of change only
requires updating the minor, or
the Patch Version component.
Keep in mind though that I did
change the behavior of the
initializer, and so if this was
documented behavior before, then
this would be a semantics
breaking change, and clients
would have to consider whether
to update, and therefore, I
should change the major version
number instead.
Now, the next change I've made
here is to add a new method to
the Spaceship class.
It's a new public method, which
means clients will start using
it and depending on it.
So, the right thing to do is to
increment the Minor Version
number.
And you'll notice, I also reset
the Patch Version to zero.
Finally, I've also added a new
parameter to the fly method.
I've given it a default, so that
most of the use sites won't have
to change.
But in Swift, a function is
uniquely identified by its name,
and its parameters.
Both the argument labels, and
the types.
So, here I've broken both source
and binary compatibility, so
this requires updating the Major
Version number, and asking any
clients to re-compile.
Maybe I should have made a new
overload instead?
Now, these are all changes to
the Spaceship class, but I've
also changed some of the value
types in FlightKit as well.
I've added a new case to the
Speed edum.
I've made locations Hashable, so
that clients can have sets of
them, and this is my favorite
change, I've added a new stored
property to the Location struct,
without breaking source or
binary compatibility.
[ Applause ]
Now, in Swift, all of these
changes are backwards
compatible, so I only need to
bump the Minor Version number.
Now, this flexibility here has
some implications for how you
design the API of your
frameworks.
The most important one is to
start small.
It's easy to add new
capabilities if you find out
that you need them, or if your
clients file feedback saying
that more capabilities are
needed.
But it's really hard to remove
something, because it will most
likely break source or binary
compatibility for at least one
of your clients.
For the things that you won't be
able to change after the fact,
like the names of your types,
make sure you consider them
carefully up front, that those
names are not just going to make
sense in this release, but also
in all future releases.
And finally, don't add
extensibility too early.
You don't need to make your
classes open, or to provide
arbitrary callbacks in the first
version of your framework.
Why is this important?
Because it makes reasoning about
your framework's behavior much
harder when you have to consider
what your clients might be doing
at the same time.
So, you can always make your
classes open in the future.
You can always add properties
that represent additional
callbacks, but you can't remove
the flexibility that you put in
by default.
So, how does this all work?
Indirection.
That's just a word, so let's
step through an example.
On the left, here again, I have
the Spaceship class, stripped
down to its module interface
this time, and on the right, I
have a use of the fly method.
This is from a client code
that's outside of the FlightKit
framework.
And what's going to happen here
at runtime is that the client is
going to have to ask which
method is the fly method?
And the framework will respond,
it's the second one.
This is how Swift ensures binary
compatibility even when you add
new methods to a class.
And it's basically the same way
that Objective-C does message
dispatch, doing it in a call
from one Library to another, but
Swift only does it when you're
crossing this client framework
boundary.
There's another form of
indirection as well.
And that's when clients are
using the structs or enums
defined in the framework.
So in this case, one of the
arguments to the fly method is
that fast case from the Speed
edum.
And I said before that enums
could have new cases added
without breaking binary
compatibility.
That means that the client can't
assume that it knows how big the
enum is going to be in memory.
So this use of the enum requires
the client to ask the framework
how big is it?
And the framework responds, it's
just one byte.
The other possibility here is
that one of the new cases added
in the future might have
associated values.
And those associated values
might require some kind of
cleanup.
And so the client will also ask
the framework to cleanup the
enum value when it's done with
it, and the framework will do
so.
Now, a couple of you in the
audience at this point are
probably getting a little antsy
because we're talking about all
this extra communication between
the client and the framework,
and that's because you have
performance sensitive
frameworks, and that's why the
next section is about trading
the flexibility that Swift is
giving you for the
optimizability of your clients.
Now, this really is a tradeoff.
As framework authors, we want
the flexibility to change
things, to add things, to
improve things, without breaking
source or binary compatibility.
But in order for the compiler to
make the client code as fast as
possible, it needs to make
assumptions about what's in the
framework.
And so Swift needs to be able to
handle both sides of the
spectrum.
And the way that this works is
through the Build Libraries for
Distribution build setting.
Harlan said before that this has
multiple effects in addition to
generating the Module Interface
file, and one of those effects
is to set the default to the
Flexibility side.
But again, Swift needs to be
able to handle all of these use
cases, and so in this section,
I'm going to talk about what you
can do once you've profiled the
behavior of your framework from
the outside, and seen that you
need additional performance.
And there's three ways to do
that: inlinable functions,
frozen enums, and frozen
structs.
So, we'll start with inlinable
functions, a feature introduced
last year in Swift 4.2.
In this case, I have a CargoShip
subclass of the Spaceship class
we saw earlier, and it has a
method canCarry that just
determines whether the CargoShip
is able to carry some piece of
cargo.
And I've made this inlinable,
because I think that this is
important for the performance of
my clients.
What this will do is make this
method part of my public
interface, not just its
declaration, but also its body.
And the effect of that is to
copy that body into the Module
Interface file.
If you're reading very quickly,
you'll also see that this method
references an internal property
of the CargoShip class.
And that's possible, because
I've marked that property as
usable from inline.
This lets you get the best of
both worlds.
The property is available as
part of your framework's public
interface, but it's only
available to the inlinable code.
It's still protected from being
arbitrarily read or written by
outside clients.
So it's still internal, but
usable from inline.
And it's important to note that
this is a per declaration
decision.
The current cargo property here
that's also internal is not
included in the Module
Interface.
So, okay, we have the body of
the canCarry method in the
Module Interface.
And when a client is compiling
against that interface, they'll
be able to copy that body
directly into their own code,
and possibly optimize it even
further if they know something
about the cargo that's being
checked.
But what happens if the
framework owner changes the body
of the method, and the clients
aren't recompiled?
For example, what if there's a
new rule that says that
CargoShips are not allowed to
carry Radioactive cargo?
Well, in this case, we're going
to run into trouble.
Because now two different parts
of the program have different
ideas about what this method is
supposed to do.
And on some inputs, they're
still going to agree, for some
regular cargo, both the client
and the framework will say that
it's okay.
But if we try to test
Radioactive cargo, then the
client code will say that it's
okay, because that's what it saw
in the Module Interface when it
was compiled.
While the framework has the new
version of the method, and will
disallow it.
This could indicate a serious
logic error in the program.
So, as a rule of thumb, if
you're a framework author who
has made a function inlinable,
make sure not to change the
output or observable behavior.
It's okay to add a better
algorithm, or some additional
fast pads, but if you change the
observable behavior of the
function, then you could end up
with these really subtle
problems that are only visible
at runtime, and possibly only
under certain inputs.
If you need to do this, all your
clients need to recompile.
So next I want to talk about
enums.
Swift enums are great.
I love them.
And one thing that we talked
about here is that you can add
new cases to an enum without
breaking source or binary
compatibility.
What this means for clients is
that they always have to have a
default case when they switch
over the enum.
And in this client, they've
decided to use the unknown
default syntax that was also
introduced in Swift 4.2.
What this means is that they've
handled all the known cases in
the enum but will still handle
any future cases that are added,
and this is necessary when
switching over C enums, and also
enums built in binary
frameworks.
The other effect that this has
is what I talked about earlier,
this sort of handshake between
the client and the framework,
about how big the enum is, and
whether it needs any cleanup.
But the example I've picked here
is a Flight Plan.
You can really only have one-way
flights, or round-trip flights.
So by marking this enum with the
frozen attribute, then I as the
framework author can promise
that there are no new cases
added in future releases of the
framework.
The first effect of this is that
clients no longer have to write
that default case.
It can just go away.
And next, the compiler is able
to compile it more efficiently.
The clients are able to assume
that this enum won't have any
additional cases and won't
require any cleanup.
So that's great.
Except I forgot something.
There is another kind of Flight
Plan.
A multiHop flight.
And now we're in trouble,
because that client code no
longer has a default case, so
adding a new case to a frozen
enum is both source and binary
breaking and requires
incrementing the Major Version
and asking all clients to
recompile.
Now, after frozen enums, frozen
structs are much the same.
By default, a Struct in a binary
framework can have new stored
properties added, or the
existing ones reordered without
any trouble, but that does
result in that same sort of
handshake and extra
communication between the client
and the framework.
So, in order to avoid this, for
structs that are known to have a
frozen layout, the frozen
attribute can be used to promise
that the stored properties will
not change.
They will not be added, or
reordered, or removed.
And the other thing that this
does is require that the stored
properties all have types that
are public, or usable from
inline.
Because remember what the goal
is here.
We want the compiler when it's
working with client code, to be
able to manipulate the stored
properties of this struct
directly, so that it can
generate more efficient code on
the client side.
This also has a semantic effect,
which is that the framework
author can now write inlinable
initializers.
An initializer is already
required to set up all of the
stored properties in the struct,
but now the compiler can be sure
that it will also do so in
future versions of the
framework.
Now, I want to close up this
section by reminding you that
flexibility is the default for
reasons.
And the main one of these is
that breaking changes are really
inconvenient for their clients.
A client is going to have-- make
a second guess over whether or
not to take the new version of
your framework, because it might
break them in some way.
And you could also get into
trouble when you have one binary
framework depending on another.
It's also worth the reminder
that these attributes only
affect client code.
Within your framework, you still
get the full power of the
compiler optimizations.
So, before reaching for frozen
or inlinable, make sure that you
have profiled the behavior of
your framework form the outside,
and demonstrated that you have a
need for additional performance.
Otherwise, keep that flexibility
because you may need it.
Now, the last section I want to
talk about is making sure that
your client's experience is the
best it can be.
And this is going to mirror
Harlan's section a lot from the
first half of the talk.
And so we'll start off with
Entitlements.
If your framework has certain
Entitlements that it needs to
get its job done, well, let's
start with the basics.
Make sure that you document
them, so that any potential
client knows what it needs to do
to successfully adopt your
framework.
And furthermore, try to minimize
the entitlement requests of your
particular framework, because
that means that it will be
applicable in more contexts.
And you can get more clients
using your framework.
And finally, keep in mind that
while both the framework and the
application can request
permissions from the user, it's
ultimately the user's choice
whether or not to grant them.
So if you get denied a
particular permission, make sure
your framework handles that
denial gracefully.
It should not crash the app, it
should not stop working.
Make sure it still does
something useful so that your
clients can use the framework
without having to give up.
Now, Dependencies have a lot of
the same concerns as
Entitlements.
Because like Entitlements, your
framework's Dependencies become
the application's Dependencies.
And so again, you should start
off by documenting them, so that
a potential client knows what
they are signing up for.
And you should minimize your
Dependencies, so that you're
asking less of your clients.
Less in extending trust, and
even practical matters like the
code size taken up by your
Dependencies.
And finally, all of your
Dependencies do have to be built
with the Build Libraries for
Distribution build setting in
order to get that binary
compatibility guarantee that we
talked about.
This does have a particular
implication that binary
frameworks cannot depend on
Packages.
Let's look at a Dependency
graph.
I said just a few minutes ago
that the Dependencies of the
framework become the
Dependencies of the app.
But when an app builds a
package, it has to pick a
particular tag to do so.
And that may not match the
version that your framework was
built against.
It may not be compatible at all.
And beyond that, not all
frameworks can necessarily be
built in a mode that is
compatible with Build Libraries
for Distribution.
So this configuration is not
supported.
Now, the last thing I want to
talk about is your Objective-C
Interface.
Yes, you, Swift framework
authors, you have an Objective-C
Interface, most likely, because
Xcode's default template is set
up for a mixed source framework
that has both an Objective-C
Umbrella Header, and a generated
header containing the
Objective-C parts of the Swift
in your framework.
But if your Swift code doesn't
have any Objective-C API that
it's trying to publish, well,
you don't need to install that
second header at all.
There's an Install Objective-C
Compatibility Header build
setting that you can just turn
off.
And if your framework doesn't
vend any Objective-C API, well
then there's no reason to
support this Objective-C Import
Syntax, and you can turn that
off as well, with the Defines
Module Build setting.
Set it to No, and that will no
longer be valid Objective-C
code.
Once you've done that, you can
delete the Umbrella Header that
Xcode generated for you.
So, let's wrap things up.
We talked about a lot of things
today, but the most important is
XCFrameworks.
They're the new Bundle format
for distributing multiple
framework variants in a way that
is super easy for your users to
use.
In order to build an
XCFramework, you'll need to turn
on the Build Libraries for
Distribution build setting,
which activates everything that
you need to get a proper binary
compatible framework.
And as framework owners, make
sure that you know the
responsibilities that you have
to your clients, so that you can
serve them the best.
Harlan and I will be down in the
Lab immediately after this
session, but for everyone who
came here, thank you very much,
and let's see some great
frameworks.
[ Applause and Cheering ]