[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, I'm Kai Kaahaaina and
today along with Alejandro
Lucena we'll be discussing how
to optimize storage for your
app.
Just like CPU memory, storage is
a finite resource.
When an app makes optimal use of
storage, we can help better
ensure long battery life,
better performance,
reduced app footprint,
and good device health.
Our main optimization topics
today will be efficient image
assets, syncing to disk,
serialized data files, Core
Data, and SQLite.
First up, efficient image
assets.
As screen sizes have gotten
larger there's been a
corresponding increase in the
size of image assets.
For our session we've created a
very simple demo app for
cataloging and favoriting
photos.
However, even when preloaded
with just a few photos, our app
has already grown to 24.6
megabytes in size.
We'll now talk about two ways we
can reduce the size of our app.
The first is HEIC.
HEIC, also referred to as HEIF
sometimes, is a more efficient
and capable alternative to JPEG.
HEIC offers 50 percent smaller
files at comparable quality to
JPEG which of course means a
smaller on disk footprint, and
smaller files could be more
easily moved up and down the
network.
They can also be more quickly
loaded and saved to disk.
HEIC also offers many features
not available in JPEG such as
the ability to store auxiliary
images that contain depth and
disparity information.
HEIC also supports alpha and
lossless compression.
HEIC even allows you to store
multiple images in a single
container.
iOS has supported HEIC since iOS
11 and macOS has supported HEIC
since macOS High Sierra.
It's also available in other
operating systems.
So going back to our demo app we
start off using JPEG assets and
had an on disk footprint of 24.6
megabytes.
By simply adopting HEIC instead
of JPEG, we were able to reduce
the size of this app to 17.9
megabytes.
That's a 27 percent reduction
simply by adopting HEIC.
The other way we can reduce the
footprint of our app is by using
Asset Catalogs.
Asset Catalogs are a great way
of organizing the assets for
your app.
Assets such as the app icon and
device and scale variants to
your images.
Asset Catalogs provide a very
easy way of storing multiple
resolutions of the same image
which makes it very easy to
support a wide variety of
devices.
We also can use Asset Catalogs
to tag on demand resources so
the user doesn't need to see
them downloaded until they're
ready to use them.
We get both storage and
performance benefits through the
use of Asset Catalogs.
We first get to reduce our on
disk footprint because Asset
Catalogs store all of our image
assets in a single optimized
format instead of individual
files.
And the App Store also uses
metadata from your Asset Catalog
to help support app slicing for
your iOS apps.
This way when a customer
downloads your app from the
store, they get only the assets
they need for their particular
device.
This makes the download smaller
and the user has to wait less
time for the app to download and
they can start enjoying your app
much sooner.
We also get performance wins.
Again, owing to the optimized
format that Asset Catalogs saves
our image assets in, images can
be loaded more quickly.
This is especially beneficial
for app launch time.
Particularly on Macs with hard
drives where we've seen up to a
10 percent improvement on app
launch performance.
Asset Catalogs also make it
really easy to adopt GPU-based
compression.
This compression is lossless by
default, but lossy image options
are available.
All enjoy hardware accelerated
decompression, and one option
even provides a way of lowering
the in-memory footprint of your
image assets.
So going back to our demo app,
earlier we saw we were able to
reduce the size of the app to
17.9 megabytes by adopting HEIC.
Now, by having also adopted
Asset Catalogs, primarily though
the app slicing feature, we're
able to further reduce the
footprint of this app to 14.9
megabytes.
That's a 40 percent reduction in
footprint since we started
simply by adopting HEIC and
Asset Catalogs.
So if you aren't already using
HEIC for your image assets and
Asset Catalogs to help organize
your assets, we highly recommend
looking into using them.
They're a great and easy way of
getting a more efficient and
smaller app footprint.
Next up I'd like to talk a
little about file system
metadata.
Our demo app maintains a small
plist that just keeps track of
the last time the app was
launched.
Each time the app is launched,
we read in this plist, update
the last app launch time
property, and write the updated
plist back out to disk.
If we observe what this behavior
looks like using the File
Activity instrument Alejandro
will be discussing a little bit
later in the talk, we can see
that this behavior causes one
read which makes a lot of sense,
we read the plist in, but it
causes three write operations
which might be a bit surprising
since we're only writing out one
file.
We also see an fsync operation
and these can be expensive and
we'll talk a little bit more
about why that can be expensive
a bit later.
So why three writes instead of
one?
Well the answer is file system
metadata.
File system metadata is data
that the file system needs to
update every time we create a
file or delete a file.
So in this case, our writing a
plist, creating a file, causes
extra overhead.
So what is file system metadata?
File system metadata is the
information the file system
needs to track about our files.
Things such as the file name,
size, location, and dates like
date created or last modified.
And a lot more.
To get a better understanding of
what the file system has to do
every time we create a file,
let's walk through what APFS has
to do when we go to write our
NSDictionary file to disk.
Well the first thing that APFS
is going to do is update the
file system tree and it's going
to do this by updating one of
its nodes.
However, owing to the copy on
write nature of APFS we don't
actually update an existing
node, we create a copy of an
existing node.
Let's look at this in detail.
So here's our existing file
system tree.
And we see a copy made of an
existing node.
How this new node differs from
the original isn't in the node
name, it's actually the same as
the original node, but the new
node has an incremented or at
least different transaction ID.
And it's this different
transaction ID that allows APFS
to support advanced features
such as snapshots.
So going back up a level, now
that we have our updated file
system tree, APFS needs to
update the object map so it's
aware of the new node.
So in total, to support writing
this new file, APFS had to do
two separate operations that
totaled 8K of write I/O, 4K to
update the file system tree,
another 4K to update the object
map.
And we still need to write the
file itself which, in this case
even though it's only 240 bytes
of NSDictionary data, the
smallest file we can write to
disk on an iOS device is 4K so
it gets rounded up.
So in total we had to write 12K
of data to disk to store a 240
byte NSDictionary.
That's about 2 percent
efficiency.
So not only does the example
show us the work that APFS needs
to do to track file creation, it
also highlights how expensive it
can be to store small amounts of
data in individual files on the
file system.
So in the example we just walked
through we saw that we had to do
8K of I/O to support creating a
file on APFS.
Well what about deleting a file?
That's 8K.
Other common operations such as
renaming a file is 16K.
Modifying an existing file is
8K.
The big take away from this is
that file system updates aren't
free.
In fact, they can involve more
I/O usage than the data being
stored.
So as a result, we need to be
selective about how we create
and modify and delete files.
We want to try to avoid
expensive behaviors such as
rapidly creating and deleting
files.
If we have a use case where we
do need to keep temporary data
on the file system, here's a
great way of trying to reduce
the cost to the system for that
temporary data.
First, create your file but keep
it open and unlinked, and do not
call fsync on it.
Doing this will give the file
system the hints it needs to
keep the temporary file in the
OS cache as long as possible and
not write out to disk as
frequently as it might have to.
If you'd like to learn more
about file system metadata in
APFS we have a great reference
document on our developer
website and I highly recommend
checking it out.
Next up, syncing to disk.
When it comes to managing where
our data lives, we want to keep
our data in the cache closest to
the CPU for best performance,
but we also want to ensure that
our data gets to disk when we
need it to.
First let's talk about the
various caches that we have.
First there's the OS cache.
This is where we want to keep
our data for best performance.
Reads and writes to the OS cache
are referred to as logical I/O.
As this cache is backed by
memory, logical I/O operations
complete very quickly.
Keeping data in the OS cache is
often advantageous for
frequently used and modified
data.
Next, we have the disk cache and
the disk cache is actually
physically located on the
storage device.
And lastly, we have permanent
storage.
This is the actual physical
medium which will be persisting
the data long term.
In the case of iOS devices and
most Macs, this is NAND.
Physical I/Os are reads and
writes to and from the physical
storage.
These I/Os may be to the or from
the disk cache or the permanent
storage.
So now that we have talked a
little about the caches and
permanent storage, let's talk
about the most common APIs we
use to move data from the OS
cache to the storage device.
First up is fsync.
fsync causes data to be moved
from the OS cache to the disk
cache.
It doesn't however guarantee
that the data will be written to
permanent storage immediately.
Without further input from
software, it's up to the
device's firmware to determine
when data gets moved from the
disk cache to permanent storage.
It also doesn't guarantee write
ordering.
That's to say, the order in
which data's written from the OS
cache to the disk cache may not
necessarily be the same order in
which data is written from the
disk cache to permanent storage.
fsync can also be expensive if
it's overused.
When we had our data in the OS
cache, the OS cache was able to
easily absorb overwrites or
modifications to the same data.
Once we used fsync it got moved
to the disk cache.
And depending on the cadence in
which we need to ensure our data
gets moved to the disk cache,
calling fsync manually may not
even be necessary as it's done
periodically for us by the OS.
The primary way data gets moved
all the way from the OS cache to
permanent storage is through the
use of F controls, FFULLFSYNC.
This causes the data in the
drive's disk cache to get
flushed.
However this causes all of the
data in the disk cache to get
flushed so not only is the data
that we were interested in
moving all the way to permanent
storage get moved to permanent
storage, all the data in the
disk cache does.
As a result, it's expensive
because this could be a lot of
data and it could take a lot of
time.
And again, it might actually not
even be necessary to do this
manually as this is done
periodically for us by the OS.
If the primary reason we were
using FFULLFSYNC was to ensure
I/O ordering, a great and much
more efficient alternative is
using F BARRIERFSYNC.
F BARRIERFSYNC enforces I/O
ordering.
F BARRIERFSYNC is probably best
thought of as being basically an
fsync with a barrier and the
barrier is a hint to the Apple
SSD to execute all the iOS that
were received before the barrier
before executing any of the iOS
which were received after the
barrier.
As a result, it's a lot less
expensive than F FULLFSYNC as we
get the same result we wanted
without having to push all the
data in the disk cache to
permanent storage.
So if you're concerned about I/O
ordering, please use F
BARRIERFSYNC and not F
FULLFSYNC.
It's a much faster and efficient
way of getting your data to
disk.
Serialized data files.
Files such as plist, XML and
JSON, they're great.
They're convenient to use.
They're a great way of storing
infrequently modified data and
they're extremely easy to parse.
However, all this ease of use
comes with a few tradeoffs.
Any time we make a single change
to the file, the entire file has
to be re-serialized and
rewritten to disk.
As a result, they scale poorly.
And since they're so easy to
use, they can be easy to misuse.
And because we're having to
replace the file with every
single change, they're very
system file metadata intensive.
And they're very much not meant
to be a database replacement.
Looking at a screenshot from the
file activity Instruments we can
see that the act of creating,
reading, and modifying the plist
causes 12 separate I/O
operations which is quite a bit
for what is probably four lines
of code.
And if we look at this in a
slightly different view, then we
see every time we call
NSDictionary to write to file
atomically, the operation ends
with an fsync operation.
This means that all the data
we're storing in this
NSDictionary we're pushing to
disk is never enjoying the
benefit of the OS cache.
As a result, really large data
sets or data sets which are
modified frequently aren't
really efficient in a serialized
plist format.
If the amount of data you have
is either too large or too
frequently modified, Core Data
is a really good alternative.
Core Data management is built on
SQLite and provides a great
abstraction layer between an
SQLite data source and the model
layer for your app.
Core Data automatically manages
object graphs and relationships,
support for change tracking and
notifications, automatic version
tracking and multi-writer
conflict resolution.
Core Data will even
automatically pool connections
for multiple concurrent
operations.
And new with iOS13, Core Data
supports CloudKit integration
which is a huge win for Core
Data adopters.
And Core Data also supports live
queries which allows you to
generate queries on the fly so
you don't have to hand code in
advance all the SQLite queries
you think you might need.
Core Data also offers automatic
memory management, statement
aggregation and transactions,
schema migrations, and new in
iOS 13, data denormalization,
and so much more.
We've also observed that
adopters of Core Data have to
write 50 to 70 percent less code
to support their model layer.
That's code that never needs to
be written, modified, or
debugged.
If, however you have a use case
which requires the direct use of
SQLite, we do have some best
practices we'd like to share.
This is a bigger topic so we
have some subtopics including
connections, journaling,
transactions, file size and
privacy, and partial indexes or
subconnections.
The robustness guarantees of
SQLite aren't free.
Opening and closing a database
can cause expensive operations
such as consistency checking,
journal recovery, and journal
checkpointing.
As a result, we actually
recommend not using a more
traditional model of opening and
closing a database each time
it's needed.
Instead we recommend the
inverse.
Keep the database open as long
as possible and close
connections only when necessary.
For multi-threaded processes,
pool connections so that so long
as one thread still needs the
database the database can remain
open.
This really helps amortize the
cost of opening and closing a
database over time.
Next up, journaling.
Delete mode journaling is the
default journaling mode for
SQLite but it isn't necessarily
the most efficient.
To see why let's take a look at
how delete mode journaling
works.
Let's say we have a database and
we want to modify four pages in
it.
The first thing that happens, we
end up copying those four pages
to a journal file.
We then can modify the four
pages within the database.
And once that's completed, the
journal file gets deleted.
So if we think about that, we
had to write twice the number of
pages we meant to modify and we
had all the file system overhead
of this short-lived journal file
that we kept around just for a
single transaction.
Fortunately, SQLite provides a
much more efficient alternative
in Write Ahead Log or WAL Mode
Journaling.
WAL Mode Journaling provides a
great way of reducing writes.
It allows us to combine writes
to the -- multiple writes to the
same page.
It uses fewer barriers.
It can support multiple readers
at the same time as a writer,
and supports snapshots.
Let's take a look at how WAL
Mode works.
So let's say again we have a
database and we want to modify
four pages.
Instead of modifying pages
directly in the database, they
just get written to the Write
Ahead Log file and, as we have
additional transactions, those
pages get added to the Write
Ahead Log file too until the
Write Ahead Log file gets
sufficiently large and it makes
sense to checkpoint it.
And, when we checkpoint it we
get one of the huge wins of WAL
Mode, pages which would've been
modified multiple times in a
Delete Mode database, all those
changes to the same page get
merged during the WAL checkpoint
and that same page only needs to
be written out once.
And when we're done, a simple
overwrite of the header of the
WAL file is all that's needed to
make it available for future use
thus reducing the file system
cost of maintaining this Write
Ahead Log file.
So we can see WAL Mode is more
efficient for most use cases of
SQLite.
If you weren't already using WAL
Mode for your SQLite databases,
we highly recommend switching
over to WAL Mode.
It can be a great way of getting
some huge performance wins for
your app.
Using multiple INSERT and UPDATE
and DELETE statements in a
single transaction is a great
way of giving SQLite more
information so that it can make
more efficient operations on
your behalf.
Pages that are changed multiple
times by, in the same
transaction by multiple
statements, only get written out
to disk once.
Let's say in this example we
have three separate
transactions, each with one
statement that modify the same
page in the database.
We'll see the same page in the
database get modified three
times.
If, however, we had a single
transaction with those three
statements, all those changes
would get combined and the page
in the database would only get
written out once.
As a result, using multiple
statements in a single SQLite
transaction is a great way for
aggregating changes over time.
File size and privacy.
So what happens when we delete
data from the database?
Space containing the deleted
data is marked as free and while
it's no longer part of the
database, it's still technically
on disk.
So how do we securely delete
sensitive information in an
efficient manner?
We recommend using secure
delete=fast.
secure delete=fast is great.
It automatically zeroes deleted
data and there is no cost for
data that was in the same page
as the header file that we had
to modify to mark the data as
being free.
And it's also now the default
behavior for SQLite in the iOS
13.
If you need it for older builds
of iOS, please specify the
secure delete=fast pragma.
When it comes to managing the
size of our database files, we
highly recommend not using
VACUUM.
VACUUM is a very slow memory and
I/O intensive operation.
To better understand why let's
take a look at how VACUUM for
SQLite databases work.
So let's say we have a database
and we wanted to VACUUM out all
the free pages.
What happens is we end up
opening up a cache door to our
database, a journal file gets
created, then we end up
performing an SQLite dump from
the database to the journal file
copying all of the valid data
from our database to the journal
file.
Then later when it's time to
checkpoint the journal file, the
database gets truncated to the
size of the journal file and all
the data from the journal gets
reinserted back to the database.
And then when that's complete,
the journal file gets discarded.
As we can see, this is pretty
expensive as all of the valid
data we had in our database had
to be written at least twice,
once to the journal file and
then once again back into the
database.
And if the working side of the
database is too big to fit into
memory, SQLite actually has to
utilize spill files to help
manage the extra data until the
operation is complete.
Again, fortunately there's a
much more efficient alternative
in SQLite and in this case
that's auto vacuum=INCREMENTAL.
auto VACUUM incremental is great
because not only does it allow
us a more efficient way of
managing the size of the
database file, it lets us
specify the number of pages we
want to vacuum out of the
database providing an option for
leaving some free pages in the
database for future use.
Let's take a look at how auto
vacuum=INCREMENTAL works.
So in this example we're going
to vacuum out the two free
pages.
Whereas before we would have had
to move all of our data from the
database in the WAL file, for
incremental auto vacuum, all we
do is migrate two pages from the
end of the database into the
Write Ahead Log and any parent
nodes that get modified during
the rebalance of the database
tree also get written to the
Write Ahead Log.
Then, when the Write Ahead Log
gets checkpointed, the database
file itself gets truncated, the
pages we migrated from the end
of the database go to where the
free pages used to be, and any
updated parent nodes get written
to the database.
So as you can see, whereas
before we had to move all of our
data in and out of the database,
now we're simply modifying a
subset of the pages within the
database.
This is much more efficient.
There's all -- we highly
recommend using incremental auto
vacuum and fast secure delete to
manage both file size and
privacy for your SQLite
databases.
Partial indexes.
Indexes are great.
Indexes allow for faster ORDER
BY, GROUP BY, and WHERE clauses.
Unfortunately, they aren't free.
There's a certain amount of
overhead the database needs to
do to support these indexes.
And after we add more indexes,
each new write of data to the
database can become more
expensive.
Fortunately, there's a more
efficient alternative in the
form of partial indexes.
Partial indexes allow you to
describe where you'd want to pay
the price of your index using a
WHERE clause which is great
because now you can get the
benefits of an index when you
want it, but not -- but not
necessarily having to pay the
price of the index when it won't
do you any benefit.
So in summary for SQLite, please
keep database connections open
as long as possible.
Use WAL journaling mode instead
of delete journaling mode.
Whenever possible, use multiple
statements per transaction so
SQLite can do some optimizations
for us.
Use fast secure delete and auto
vacuum incremental to manage
both file size and privacy for
your databases.
And, when it's practical, use
partial indexes instead of
regular indexes.
And if you'd really rather not
worry about these details in
SQLite, we highly recommend just
using Core Data.
Core Data handles all this heavy
lifting for you and as Core Data
gets improved over time,
adopters of Core Data will also
get those benefits for free.
Next up Alejandro will show us
how we can use the updated File
Activity instrument and show us
real-world examples of how we
can profile and optimize I/O for
apps.
Alejandro.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right thank you Kai.
And good morning everyone.
Thank you for attending this
session on optimizing storage.
What I'd like to do is talk
about some of the improvements
we've made to the File Activity
instrument to see how we can use
that to optimize storage in our
app.
So let's get started.
What changed with the File
Activity instrument?
Well, one of the first things we
did was we added support for all
Apple devices.
So this means you can have the
same uniform profiling
experience across your iOS
device, Mac, Watch, TV,
etcetera.
The File Activity instrument
also lets you support tracing
for not just your own
application but also for the
entire system so you can see how
your application behaves with
regards to the I/O subsystem
alone and how it interacts with
the rest of the system so you
can see different interactions
going on.
Next as Kai mentioned, there is
the distinction between logical
and physical I/O.
And understanding how they
interact with each other is
actually really important for --
to understand your I/O usage.
So the File Activity instrument
lets us see both of these
together.
And lastly, we also added
support for automated reasoning.
And the automated reasoning
comes in a variety of different
mechanisms, so I'd like to talk
about this very briefly.
First and foremost, one of the
automated reasoning anti-pattern
detections that we added was
actually that for excessive
physical writes.
So the File Activity instrument
will actually notify you while
you're tracing that it detected
some sort of excessive activity
in your application and you can
go in directly from instruments
and see what may have caused it.
We also added support for seeing
when certain I/O related system
calls that either you call
directly or maybe are called on
your behalf because of a
framework have failed.
And these are important to
understand, not just for I/O but
also for correctness in your
application.
And lastly, to Kai's points
about fsync and F control with F
FULLFSYNC, we also have a
mechanism for detecting
suboptimal caching so you can
see when your application might
be performing certain behaviors
that aren't making the best
utilization of the OS cache.
So let's get started with File
Activity instrument and see what
it looks like.
With Instruments 11, when we
open up the instruments, we see
the file activity still has
roughly the same icon but we get
a new string at the bottom which
kind of sums up what it's
capable of doing.
And if we go ahead and select
it, we're presented with some
new tracks.
First and foremost is the file
system suggestions track.
And this track is where all of
these anti-patterns and
automated reasoning suggestions
will live.
Directly beneath it we have file
system activity and the file
system activity will be broken
down for logical reads and
logical writes and it'll show
you a count of how many of these
operations happened.
And you're also able to see in
more depth how many calls were
made, who called them, and
certain other statistics.
Similarly, right beneath it is
disk usage where you can get the
same sort of read and write
distinction but for the physical
layer.
And lastly, the disk I/O latency
so we can see just how long
certain physical I/Os took.
So let's get started and I'll
refer back to this demo app.
And the first thing I'd like to
implement is actually favoriting
of photos.
So in the bottom right-hand
corner of each of these images
there's a star and what I'd like
to implement is being able to
select that star to consider an
image a favorite.
As an example, I can select a
banana slug as a favorite as
well as these skyscrapers.
And the very first approach that
I'll take is implementing this
by opening and closing the
database every time that we have
a favoriting.
Now Kai told us that this isn't
the best pattern but I still
think it's useful to get this
into a File Activity instrument
trace so we have a baseline and
we can see what sorts of things
are happening.
So here behind me I have exactly
that.
I ran the File Activity
instrument against this same
workload by opening and closing
the database per operation.
And the first track I'd like to
focus on is disk usage because
this is where all the physical
I/O information will live.
Here we see in the physical
writes column or the physical
writes row, we see the different
amount of physical I/Os that
happen.
In this case in the tool tip
text we have 54 for this
particular column.
But right beneath it is the
detail view and the detail view
is where all of the extra
statistics will live so I'm
going to go into here so we can
see what sort of things we're
getting.
By zooming in I'd like to point
out that for this workload of
favoriting these photos with the
opening and closing database per
operation, we had 1,002
different physical I/O
operations totaling just under 6
megabytes of total footprint.
And this may not seem like that
much but when we compare it to
some of the other ones, we'll
get a better understanding of
why this is perhaps as bad as it
is.
So here we get some statistics
about, you know, latency and
average latencies as well.
But I would like to switch back
to the overall view because I
also noticed that in the file
system suggestions track, we do
have some notifications that the
instrument told us and I'd like
to go into these as well so we
can see just what happened.
Again, at the bottom we have the
detail view, and here the detail
view in that count column is
telling us that we had 12 total
notifications.
And if we go into that dropdown,
we see that these notifications
were precisely for excessive
physical writes.
And we know that opening and
closing the database isn't
necessarily a good thing and
we're going to try different
techniques so we can get this.
But I like to start off with
this baseline of 12
notifications from the file
system -- File Activity
instrument.
And lastly, I also want to talk
about the actual file system
activity track where we can see
statistics about which
operations were called such as
writes and reads and so forth,
but also in this table here we
get different views of the
logical I/Os that our
application did.
Here are the default is file
system statistics but we can
also go down to file descriptor
information as well.
All right so with that in mind,
now I want to go and switch to a
different model which is opening
and closing the database as
needed.
Specifically I'll go back into
the disk usage detail view and
the first thing that I'd like to
point out is we're down from
1,002 physical I/O operations
down to 54 and we're down from
just under 6 megabytes of disk
footprint to 288 kilobytes which
is quite a significant win and
this was simply just by changing
the usage model of when we open
and close our database.
Furthermore, focusing again on
file system suggestions, we
started off with 12 in the
previous version of doing this
but now we're down to 3.
And while this still isn't the
ideal case, we are making
progress.
And as we implement different
behavior such as journaling,
we'll see this number change.
Speaking of which, let's start
with Delete Mode Journaling.
Now as Kai mentioned, Delete
Mode Journaling is the default
for SQLite and so this
statistics page that I have here
is actually the same exact one
that I showed where we were
opening and closing the database
as needed.
So I won't show the entire trace
again but I do want to recall
the numbers.
54 physical I/O operations
totaling 288 kilobytes.
But when we switch to a model
that uses WAL Mode Journaling
there are some interesting
observations that I'd like to
point out.
First and foremost is that now
we have zero suggestions on the
file systems suggestions track.
We started at 12, ended up at 3,
and now we're at zero so this is
very significant gains that
we're making by simply adopting
the WAL Mode Journaling.
And secondly, this is the
interaction between the logical
and physical I/O that I'd also
like to point out.
Specifically, here in the file
system activity track we see a
lot of logical I/Os happening,
but we don't get a physical I/O
until we stop the trace of the
application.
And why is this significant?
Well when we compare it to what
we had previously with the
Delete Mode Journaling, notice
how in Delete Mode Journaling
every time that we had file
system activity, so logical I/O,
we also had a corresponding
physical I/O to go with it.
Whereas with WAL Mode Journaling
it's making really great use of
the OS cache and getting us a
lot of great performance
benefits.
To see this in a little more
detail we can go into that file
system activity track again and
focus on the detail view.
With WAL Mode journaling we only
had a single fsync call whereas
with Delete Mode Journaling we
were all the way up to 16.
So WAL Mode is definitely making
a lot of great use of the OS
cache.
Now the next thing I'd like to
talk about is how we're going to
implement deleting of photos.
We talked about favoriting, but
we also want a way to remove
photos from the application.
And the first approach that
we'll talk about is actually
using what's called single
statement transactions and Kai
mentioned this as well.
Specifically, when we want to
select a photo for deletion,
we'll select the checkmark at
the bottom left corner, and
we'll issue a delete query to
the database.
Now we could think of this as a
single statement transaction
because we're executing this
delete query per photo and we're
not doing any sort of coalescing
on our own.
With this model here's the
single statement transaction
approach and we do have some
file system activity to point
out as well as some disk usage.
But one thing to focus on is
with this approach we had 111
different file system operations
and going over to the disk usage
track we had 12 writes for a
total of 72 kilobytes of total
footprint.
Next, I'd like to talk about
multiple statement transactions
and this is by taking the idea
that each of these photos, even
from a logical perspective, we
don't want to delete these
photos one at a time.
Logically we want to get them
all deleted at the same time and
we have an analog for this
within SQLite by merging all
these delete statements into one
transaction.
So we have multiple statements
in a single transaction.
And if we do this, we're down to
37 file system operations.
So we're doing significantly
less work but in addition to
that if we look at the disk
usage we're down to 4 total
writes and 24 kilobytes of
footprint.
Looking at these side by side,
we started with 111 for single
statement transactions of total
file system activity, we're down
to 37 with multiple statement
transactions.
And looking to how this
translates to actual physical
disk usage, we started at 12
writes totaling 72 kilobytes and
now we're down to 4 writes
totaling 24 kilobytes with
multiple statement transactions.
And while we're on the topic of
deleting, we should also mention
vacuuming because we want to
keep our database compressed or,
you know, compact as possible.
And we'll start off with a full
vacuum.
In this case we'll be issuing a
vacuum statement every time that
we issue a delete.
And Kai told us that full
vacuuming isn't the most optimal
way of doing it, but we can see
how this exactly works within
the File Activity instrument.
Specifically, by doing this we
have a total of 27 different I/O
operations totaling 168
kilobytes by issuing a full
vacuum, but if we switch this
over to using incremental
vacuum, we have some different
numbers.
We have 12 total I/O operations
for 72 kilobytes of total
footprint.
Again, looking at these side by
side, we're down from 27 I/O
operations with a full vacuum
down to 12 by using incremental
vacuum and from 168K of total
disk footprint for the full
vacuum down to 72.
So it's pretty significant gains
that we're making by adopting
these sorts of patterns within
SQLite.
So what I'd like to do now is
sort of summarize and one of the
first points is we want you to
apply these lessons, whether
you're using Core Data or SQLite
or plist and so forth, we want
you to apply these lessons but
don't just apply them.
We also want you to verify them
with the File Activity
instrument.
Now the File Activity instrument
may be able to help you by
proving these points but also
you may have some other
suggestions that you don't even
know about and perhaps the File
Activity instrument can help
bring those into vision for you
and help you notice them.
And with that in mind, we also
want you to continue optimizing
storage.
There's a lot more than just
meets the eye and we hope that
with these lessons and with the
tools that we're providing it
could be a great experience for
everyone.
For more information we have a
lab later on today for
performance and we also had a
session this year at WWDC '19
for making apps with Core Data
if you'd like to learn a little
bit more about how exactly to
adopt this.
Thank you everyone for
attending.
Enjoy the rest of the session.
[ Applause ]