[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Welcome to our session on
Drawing Classification and
One-Shot Object Detection in
Turi Create.
My name is Sam and I'll be
joined by my colleagues,
Shantanu and Abhishek to talk to
you about what we've been
building to enable even richer
experiences in your apps.
Let's dive right in.
First, a quick refresher on Turi
Create itself.
Turi Create is a Python library
used for creating Core ML
models.
It has a simple, easy to use
task-oriented API.
Now, tasks are our term for a
collection of complex, machine
learning algorithms abstracted
away into a simple, easy to use
solution for you to build your
models.
It's cross-platform, working on
both Mac OS and Linux and we're
extremely proud to be open
source, working closely with our
community on features and fixes.
We built Turi Create to enable
you to create Core ML models for
your intelligent applications.
Now to build these models, we
integrate with a various of
system frameworks, accepting
data from frameworks like
PencilKit and Core Motion.
Once we've built our model, we
integrate with other system
frameworks like Vision and Sound
Analysis to create extremely
compelling app experiences.
So say you'd want to build an
application used to classify
musical instruments.
[ Guitar Sound ]
Using microphone data, you can
understand what instrument is
being played and attempt to tune
the instrument.
Or say you'd want to use raw
sensor data from the Apple Watch
to detect what activities a user
may be performing in the gym.
Or say you'd want to use image
data to be able to detect what
ingredients a user may be
holding and to suggest recipes
using these ingredients.
All of these are possible
because we have built an
intelligent Core ML model.
And to build these models, we've
identified a five-step pipeline
to do so.
First up in our pipeline, we
need to identify the task or
what problem it is that we're
trying to solve.
Next, we need to collect data
and sometimes, lots of it.
After that, we train our model.
Next, we evaluate our model,
attempting to understand the
real-world performance
characteristics and to
potentially offer corrections.
After that, we deploy our model
for use within Core ML and your
application.
Now let's take a look at these
five steps in code.
After we import turicreate we
load our data from an SFrame on
disk.
An SFrame is something that
Shantanu will cover in a little
bit.
After this, we split our data
into two sets, one used for
testing and one used for
training our model.
Next, we create our model with
just a single line of code for
running complicated machine
learning algorithms.
Next, we gather metrics as to
the performance of this model.
And finally, we save it to disk
for use within XCode and your
app.
Now we think one of the great
things about Turi Create is its
simple and consistent API.
So no matter whether you're
using an object detector, a
sound classifier, an activity
classifier, or any of our other
tasks, the API remains
consistent and easy to use.
Now I've mentioned these tasks
multiple times and I'd like to
cover the full collection that
Turi Create offers.
We offer tasks that work with
images and sound as well as user
activities and text.
We offer tasks that work with
user preferences and numeric
data.
And today we're extremely
excited to share with you two
brand new tasks.
First, we have our One-Shot
Object Detection task.
Now you may already be familiar
with object detection.
Object detection is the ability
to detect the presence and
location of specific objects
within a frame.
One-Shot Object Detection is a
twist on this existing
framework, which depending on
the type of data that you're
attempting to detect, can
dramatically reduce the amount
of data needed to train a model.
Next, we have our Drawing
Classification task.
Using user input in the form of
a finger on screen or the Apple
Pencil, you can now attempt to
classify and understand what
your users have drawn into your
app.
Now I'd like to take a deep dive
into the One-Shot Object
Detection task.
Say you'd want to build an
application to take an image of
a player's hand in a game of
poker and to offer probabilities
that this hand would occur.
Or say you'd want to build an
application to take a picture of
your car's dashboard and to
attempt to understand what those
obscure icons may mean.
Or say you'd want to build an
app to detect company logos to
provide your users with more
information about this company.
What do all three of these
applications have in common?
They're all trying to detect 2D
regular images.
One-Shot Object Detection is
able to take advantage of these
characteristics of regularity
and consistency to dramatically
reduce the amount of data needed
to build an accurate model.
So let's use this card counting
app, which Shantanu will build
for us in just a minute, as a
case study into how this works.
Originally in order to build an
object detection model, you
would need to collect vast
amounts of data of your object
in the real world.
In addition to this, you would
also need to annotate each of
these images with the location
in the frame of your image.
As you can see, this is an
incredibly data intensive and
time-consuming task.
So we built a better way.
With One-Shot Object Detection,
you now need as little as one
image per class that you're
attempting to detect.
So instead of dozens of images
of the Ace of Clubs, you now
need a single image in order to
build a reliable and accurate
model.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
So let's talk about how this
works behind the scenes.
This works with a process called
Synthetic Data Augmentation.
Turi Create ships with a
collection of images of the real
world.
We then take your source image
that you have supplied and
overlay onto these real-world
images along with various color
perturbations and distortions to
simulate real world effects.
In addition to this, there's
absolutely no need to annotate
these images as our algorithms
do that for you automatically.
Now One-Shot Object Detection
works with 2D objects only.
It requires very little data and
absolutely no annotation.
However, if you're wanting to
detect an object that is
potentially 3D or more
irregular, you may be interested
in our more traditional object
detection framework.
Now let's take a look at this in
code.
As you'd expect, our API is
incredibly consistent with our
other tasks using just a single
line of code with our dot create
method to train an incredibly
accurate model.
And now with code up on the
screen, I'd like to invite my
colleague, Shantanu to talk to
you about our Three Card Poker
App and to give you a
demonstration of this in the
real world.
Shantanu.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Sam.
Good morning everyone.
Welcome to the last day of WWDC.
Now I'm super excited to give
you a first look into the
One-Shot Object Detector.
The thing is, Sam and I play a
lot of three card poker at work.
And to be honest, I'm getting a
little too tired of winning all
the time.
So I thought, you know today on
stage, why don't we build an app
for Sam that helps him, that
tells him what his hand is, and
you know, helps him make a
better decision.
Now to build an app like that,
we'd need a Core ML model that
can detect all the cards in your
playing deck.
So why don't we just go ahead
and write some code to build
that?
Okay, so here I have a blank
Jupyter Notebook which is an
interactive Python environment
to write some code and
immediately see the output of
your code after that.
And we're going to use that to
write some code today.
Now the first line of code that
we write, and this is our
favorite line of code, it's
import turicreate as tc.
And I need to select the cell
before I write that.
And this will be your favorite
line too after this session.
Next, I'm going to switch to
Finder to take a look at all our
starter images and it looks like
we have a bunch of cards here
where the playing card spans the
entire frame of the image.
We have an Ace of Clubs, an Ace
of Diamonds, Ace of Hearts, Five
of Hearts, and we have a lot of
images here.
So why don't we go ahead and
load this up into an SFrame?
An SFrame is Turi Create's
scalable data structure.
It's tabular and it's to
represent all the data that you
have.
So we're going to create a
variable called starter images
and Turi Create has this
functionality to load images,
where you just pass in the --
directly that contains all your
images and it builds an SFrame
out of that on its own.
Now let's take a look at what
the starter image SFrame looks
like.
Alright, so there are two
columns in this SFrame.
There's a path column and an
image column.
The path column contains the
relative path to the image that
is in the image column.
Looks good but the path column
has this redundant .
/ and .png.
So let's write a quick code
snippet to get rid of that.
So we're going to create another
column in the starter image's
SFrame and call that label and
we're going to write some code
to extract the label out of the
path.
And we're going to use something
like a Python slice applied to
all the elements in the SFrame
-- in the column of the SFrame.
So we do an element slice from
the second index to the negative
four index similar to a Python
slice.
And next, let's explore this
SFrame.
Turi Create has an explore
functionality on the SFrame,
which we're going to take a look
at.
This pops up, a new
visualization window, which
gives us a way to interactively
explore all the data that is in
our SFrame.
And as we can see, there's three
column here.
There's a path, image, and
label.
And it looks like we did
successfully extract the label
out of the path.
We did get rid of the .
/ and .png.
We can also take a look at all
the thumbnails of our images in
this SFrame which we one day
will do when we just printed it
out.
Great. How many rows are in this
SFrame?
Let's take a look at that.
So it looks like there are 52
rows and that's the number of
cards in our playing card deck.
So that looks good.
But the important thing to note
here is that it's one image per
class of the object that we're
trying to detect.
Now we looked at the data.
We've looked at the task.
We know the task is One-Shot
Object Detection.
The next step in our five-step
biplane is to take a look at the
model creation process.
And consistent with all our
other toolkits, the model
creation process looks something
like
tc.oneshotobjectdetector.create
and we pass in the starter
images SFrame as well as the
target column, which is in this
case, is label.
But I won't run this line of
code because this take a while
and what it does behind the
scenes is it not only generate
all the synthetic data by
applying different projections
on your starter images,
superimposing them on random
backgrounds and applying color
perturbations, but it also
trains a model after that.
So instead, we're going to
switch to a Cooking Show Mode,
where we're going to load a
model that we've already baked
in the oven sometime.
So let's use the load model
functionality and it's called
carddetector.model.
Let's see what this model looks
like.
So it looks like it's a One-Shot
Object Detector trained on 52
classes.
But hold on.
The number of synthetically
generated examples is 104,000.
That's strange.
We just provided 52 images.
The toolkit automatically
synthetically generated 2,000
images per class and created a
training set of 104,000.
And that's not it.
It also synthetically generated
bounding boxes for all the data
that it generated because the
toolkit generated the data
itself.
That's pretty insane.
[ Applause ]
So we've looked at our model.
The next step is let's small
test this model on an image that
the model hasn't seen before.
So I'm going to load up a test
image.
And I have a test directory
which contains a test image.
And it's definitely not Sam's
hand and you'll see why that it
is when I show you what this
test image is.
Yeah, Sam never gets this lucky.
This is probably my hand.
It's a Flush.
So anyway, we can see that
there's an Eight of Clubs, a
Nine of Clubs, and a Ten of
Clubs in this image.
Let's see if the model agrees
with us.
So we're going to call the
predict method on the model and
pass in our test image.
And let's save this result in
variable called prediction.
And next, let's print this
prediction out.
Okay. Let's take that in.
So it looks like there are three
dictionaries in this list and
each dictionary represents a
bounding box that is part of the
prediction.
Let's go through the fields in
each prediction.
It looks like there's a
confidence, there's a
coordinates, a label, and a
type.
Confidence represents how
confident the model is in this
bounding box.
Coordinates represents the
coordinates of the bounding box.
Label is what class label
belongs to this bounding box.
And type is what type of
bounding box it is, which it's
rectangle.
That looks great.
And we can see that the model
did detect the Ten of Clubs and
Eight of Clubs and the Nine of
Clubs.
But it doesn't really tell us
what location the model detected
it in.
So let's use a utility that the
One-Shot Object Detector has to
draw bounding boxes and we'll
pass in the test image along
with annotations, which in this
case, is the prediction.
And let's call this annotated
image.
And next, let's print this
annotated image out.
[ Applause ]
Yeah that looks pretty good.
On an image that the model has
never seen before, an Eight of
Clubs with 70 percent
confidence, a Ten of Clubs with
91 percent, and Nine of Clubs at
69 percent.
And notice how all the bounding
boxes perfectly capture all the
clubs.
So we've small tested this model
on a test image that the model
never saw before.
The last step is deployment on
device.
And like all our other toolkits,
the model has a method to export
Core ML.
And let's call this Core ML
model CardDetector.mlmodel.
And next, let's open this
CardDetector.mlmodel in XCode.
Alright. So we can see that we
have a CardDetector model which
is trained by Turi Create 5.6.
The inputs are image, which is a
416 x 416 color image and
confidence is representative of
how many classes the model was
trained on and coordinates
represents the coordinates of
the bounding box of the classes.
This looks good.
It looks like a very good Core
ML model.
But why don't we have some fun
and put this into action in an
app that Sam can use next time
he plays three card poker
against me.
Alright. And here's my Three
Card Poker app.
So it says add an image to
evaluate cards.
Here I have a deck of cards and
I'm just going to randomly draw
from this.
And this will be Sam's hand.
So let's take a photo right
here.
So it looks like there's -- this
looks like one of the best hands
Sam has gotten in a while.
Alright. So it looks like the
model thinks there's a Five of
Clubs, a Three of Hearts, and a
King of Hearts.
And it also detected it was a
hard card.
The probability of which is
74.39 percent.
[ Applause ]
Yeah. Now given that it's a high
card, Sam should probably fold
because it's pretty likely to
get a high card.
But just for fun, let's see what
I got.
Yeah, that's -- well let's take
a picture and then talk about my
hand.
I have a Flush.
Nine of Hearts, Six of Hearts,
and Four of Hearts.
So even though we built this app
for Sam, we do sort of -- I'm
still reaping the benefits of
it.
Alright. So that was it for the
Card Detector Demo.
And to sort of recap, we started
with one image per class.
We just called one line of code
that automatically,
synthetically generated a
training data set for us.
Trained a model.
We then small tested it on a
random image the model had never
seen before.
And we then saw it in an app.
And this is just one example of
the kind of user experience that
you can build.
We were thrilled with the sort
of stuff you built last year
with the Object Detector and
that sort of led us to build
this toolkit because we wanted
to reduce your overhead on data
collection and annotation.
That time has gone down from
like, I don't know, a few days
to like five minutes and only
for 2D objects though.
And we can't wait to see what
you build with the One-Shot
Object Detector.
So feel free to come to our labs
and try this demo out live.
We will be really excited to
have you.
And with that, I'm going to move
onto to our next toolkit for
today.
I'm really excited to talk to
you about the Drawing
Classifier.
So far Turi Create has enabled
you to build apps with sound
input, raw sensor data input,
and images.
Today, we're adding a new form
of input, the Apple Pencil.
[ Applause ]
Imagine building an app that
let's your users create handsome
greeting cards by recognizing
their strokes and automatically
replacing them with professional
drawings.
Power to the user.
Or imagine building an app that
breaks ground in education by
helping professors grade their
student's exams much faster by
recognizing their strokes.
We're actually going to build
this app.
But before that, let's talk
about the data.
The Drawing Classification task
can accept bitmap-based
drawings, represented as Turi
Create images, but that's not
all.
The task can also accept
stroke-based drawings, where
every stroke is a time series
data of x and y coordinates.
We wanted to give you as much
flexibility in your data as
possible.
Model creation follows an API
consistent with all our other
toolkits, turicreate
drawingclassifier.create with
the training SFrame and the
target column.
The model that you get out of
here is state of the art.
The Core ML model that you get
is less than 500 kilobytes on
device.
And this is GPU accelerated.
[ Applause ]
But we didn't stop there.
We trained a model on millions
of drawings and published it to
automatically one start your
models.
And not only does this help you
create more accurate models, it
also helps you train on as few
as 30 drawings per class.
Thirty. Let that sink in.
So what does the code look like?
Five lines of code, five steps.
We start with importing
turicreate.
Looking at our data, calling
model creation, evaluating our
data, and then exploring to Core
ML.
And with that, remember that
grading app that we saw which
was like recognizing checks and
crosses and doing some more
fancy stuff?
Why don't we go ahead and build
that?
So we're going to take a look at
this app on the iPad, which
helps us grade exams.
So let's say I'm a professor and
I have my Apple Pencil and I
want to grade my students'
exams, but I want to grade them
really quickly.
So let's add an image to begin
grading.
This is an exam of my student,
Jane Appleseed and it's Math
101, which is pretty hard.
So let's take a look at the
image and now let's start
grading.
So one plus one is two, right?
Last I checked that was still
true.
So let's mark that as correct.
And as you can see, the model
detected the check and recorded
ten points on the right-hand
side, giving the student ten out
of ten on this question.
One plus two is four.
That's correct too.
Oh I guess it's not.
So erase that.
I think I should go back to Math
101 maybe.
So let's mark that incorrect
because the model made a
mistake.
So let's erase that again.
And to give you a preview into
how you can improve your models,
Abhishek is going to be up on
stage in a few minutes.
And this app is also designed to
take care of models failing.
So if you want, you can check
out the 11:00 AM session on
Designing Apps for Machine
Learning.
So let's keep grading.
So one plus two is four.
That's incorrect.
And the model detected the cross
as incorrect.
And it's a pretty serious
mistake for Math 101 in college.
So let's give that a negative
seven.
And as you can see, the model
registered the negative seven
and gave the student three out
of ten points on the right-hand
side.
Three plus two is five.
That's correct.
To give you an insight into what
the model is that powers this
app, this model is trained on
check, cross, and ten negative
scored deductions from negative
one through negative ten.
So let's keep grading.
One plus 99 is.
It's a hundred, okay.
So that's incorrect.
And that's another mistake the
model made.
So let's correct that and mark
that incorrect.
So let's give that maybe a
negative five and the model
registered the negative five and
stored it on the right-hand
side.
And this last question is, it's
hard but I don't know how the
student this right, but they got
one plus two wrong.
Anyway, let's give them a
correct for this.
Okay. So this is the kind of
experience that you can build
with the Drawing Classifier.
And why don't we go ahead and
write some code to actually
build a Core ML model that
powered this app.
So here I have another blank
Jupyter Notebook and we're going
to go through that five-step
pipeline again.
The first step being, the task.
The task here is Drawing
Classification.
We've established that.
So the next step is the data.
But before that, let's write our
favorite line of code which is
import turicreate as tc.
Now to look at the data, we're
going to load up an SFrame of
some data that we've already
accumulated.
Let's call it train.
And it's called train.sframe.
Next, let's use the explore
functionality on the train
SFrame and see what it looks
like.
Great. So it looks like we have
a lot of data here.
We have a negative three.
That's labeled as a negative
three.
A check labeled as a check.
Again, this SFrame has two
columns, bitmap and label.
And for this demo, we're going
to be using bitmap-based
drawings, but you can also have
stroke-based drawings instead of
the bitmap column.
So we have a bunch of drawings
here.
If we scroll through it, we have
a cross, another check, some
negative score deductions.
Looks pretty good.
How many examples are there,
4,436?
Okay, that's quite a few
examples.
You might be wondering, "Well
how did you collect all that
data.
How did you get all that data?"
So three of us got into a
conference room with iPads and
Pencils and we just drew these
strokes on our iPads for about
an hour and then just converted
it to an SFrame.
So data collection overhead for
this toolkit is also pretty low.
So now that we've looked at our
data, let's go ahead and look at
what the model creation process
looks like.
So we have
drawingclassifier.create.
We pass in the training SFrame
and we pass in the target
column, which in this case, is
label.
And I'm also going to pass into
a max iterations perimeter of
one to just give you a feel of
what the training process looks
like.
Behind the scenes what this is
doing is it's resizing all our
images down to 28 x 28 and then
parsing them through the neural
network for one iteration.
And looks like that's done.
But this model is not going to
be good enough for our use case.
So again, let's switch to
Cooking Show Mode and open the
door of the oven and take out a
model from it.
So we have the load model
functionality and we load up the
grading model.
Alright. So if we take a look at
this model, we have a Drawing
Classifier model that's trained
on 12 classes with the feature
column being bitmap, the target
column being label, and it's
trained for 200 iterations and
only for 30 minutes.
So after training for only 30
minutes we got a model with a
pretty high training accuracy.
That's pretty good.
So now that we have the model,
the next step is to evaluate
this model.
But I'm going to skip that
because my colleague, Abhishek
will be up here in a few minutes
and not only will he show us how
to visualize the model's
mistakes, but he'll also show us
how to establish a feedback loop
of the model and improve it.
So let's skip ahead to exporting
to Core ML.
And consistent with all our
other toolkits, we have an
export coreml method on the
model and it's not CardDetector,
it's Grading.
So let's call it Grading.mlmodel
and then let's take a look in
XCode.
Great. So this model has bitmap
as its input which is a
grayscale image of size 28 x 28
and the outputs are label
probabilities and class label.
Label probabilities being the
probabilities of all the classes
that the model was trained on
and class label being the class
label of the top prediction.
So this looks good.
We worked really hard to bring
the size of the Core ML down as
much as we could because we
wanted this model to be as
portable as possible for your
use case.
And we brought it down to 396
kilobytes.
That's kilobytes.
[ Applause ]
So now that we've taken a look
at the Core ML model and we've
taken a look at what the final
app that we had was, let's also
take a look at what the Swift
code you need to write to
integrate this model into your
apps.
PencilKit released their API
this past week and they have a
Peek at Canvas view, which has a
Peek at Drawing, which is the
drawing data model.
You can extract the drawing out
of the Canvas view as a UI image
using that line of code.
And next, you can crop it using
again, API from PencilKit to
crop it down to the bounds of
the drawing where the user drew
their strokes.
And now that you have this
cropped, your image that is
ready to be consumed by the Core
ML model, you can use the Vision
API and that's all you need.
To recap, we started with some
drawings and their labels.
We interactively explored our
data.
We saw what the data looked
like.
Then we trained a model or
loaded it from the oven,
exported it to Core ML, and then
deployed using PencilKit and
Vision.
But I did miss one thing.
I did skip it on purpose.
I did skip evaluation and that's
a pretty important part of your
workflow.
And if you actually evaluate
your models and make them
better, you won't see errors
like you saw in the app today.
So with that, I'm going to
invite my colleague, Abhishek to
take us through an exciting
model evaluation journey.
Abhishek.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
So today I'd like to talk to you
about Model Evaluation and why
it's really important in
building the best possible user
experiences.
But first, let's understand how
evaluation works.
Let's take the Drawing
Classifier model we trained in
the previous demo.
And if we pass a drawing through
it, we get a prediction.
Using ground truth data, we can
identify whether this prediction
is correct or sometimes
incorrect.
But using a single data point to
evaluate a model doesn't give us
a full picture of what the model
is doing.
So what do we do?
Well, we use more data.
This is our test data set.
We can run the model across the
data and get correct and
incorrect predictions for each
of the drawings.
By grouping the drawings
together in correct and
incorrect groups we get a sense
for how well the model is
performing.
This is analogous to the metric
of accuracy, a measure of the
correct predicted drawings over
the total number of drawings in
our data set.
And there are other metrics we
can use to help us quantify our
model's performance.
To access these in Turi Create,
simply call the evaluate method
available to use on the model
object and pass in that test
data set.
A dictionary of these metrics
will then be returned to now
evaluate our model.
But this actually doesn't tell
us the whole story.
For instance, take a model with
an accuracy of 85 percent.
Initially that seems pretty good
to us, doesn't it?
Well, if we dig down into the
per class accuracy, we see that
the class of four has a much
lower accuracy than the rest of
the other classes.
And this is a case that you
usually might run into.
Well, what's causing this low
accuracy?
One thing might be that there
might be a low number of
examples present for that
particular class.
To correct for this we may want
to add more examples.
But there are other things that
can be going on.
For instance, we've noticed that
in some data sets the
annotations are incorrect.
In the drawing to your left, you
see that the model has predicted
this drawing to be one, but the
annotation is seven.
And when visually inspecting
this drawing, we can see that
the annotation probably should
be one.
So we can go and correct the
annotation.
But in other instances such as
the one to your right, the model
has predicted it to be four and
the annotation is one but it's
unclear whether the annotation
or the model is incorrect.
There also may be systematic
biases present in your model.
For instance, in this example,
the model has predicted sevens
with bars to be incorrect as
three but correctly predicts the
sevens without bars.
And to help you identify these
issues, we've created an
interactive visualization tool.
Let me show you how it works.
Alright. So let's go back to the
Jupyter Notebook that Shantanu
was showing us and load in a
test data set that we can use to
evaluate our model.
Now that we've loaded in our
test data set, let's call that
evaluate method passing in that
test data set.
So now that we have our metrics
object, we can simply call the
explorer method on that metric's
object to now look at our
interactive visualization.
And as you can see, a window
popped up and it has three
distinct sections, an Overview
section, which gives us the
overall accuracy of the model as
well as the number of iterations
in the model that we've trained,
the Drawing Classifier model.
The second section is a Per
Class breakdown of the metrics
as well as a couple of example
images that have been correctly
been predicted by the model.
And lastly, there's an Error
section that shows us all of the
errors that the model has made.
So let's take a look at the
first class, negative four.
We see that class has an
accuracy of 20 percent.
If we click on it, we see that
there are actually four errors
that have been made by the
model.
But something else that we see
is that the number of elements
that we've tested is five.
And that's a pretty low number.
So to kind of determine whether
the model is performing
improperly on this class or
simply we have a low number of
examples that we're testing, we
might want to go back and add
more examples to this class to
get a better determination of
whether the model is performing
incorrectly or simply we don't
have enough examples.
Let's go to class of negative
two.
We see something that stands out
when we filter by this class.
There are 11 incorrect
predictions of the same type,
meaning that the actual
annotation is negative two, but
the model has predicted all of
these examples to be negative
seven.
But when we look through these
examples that have been
misclassified, we see that some
of these examples are, in fact,
negative seven.
And this is a case where the
data set has some misannotated
data points.
So we might want to go back and
correct those annotations to get
a better indication of our
model's performance.
We've also included a number of
other metrics such as F1 Score
Precision and Recall which may
be more relevant to your use
cases when evaluating your
models.
So, a recap.
We now allow you to
interactively visualize model
predictions.
This can help us easily spot
annotation errors as well as
identify those systematic biases
we talked about.
But now that we've identified
these issues, what steps can we
take to improve the model?
Well, let's take a look at our
pipeline.
First, we have our test data
set.
We've passed it through the
Drawing Classifier model and
used our interactive
visualization tool to identify
some issues.
And we may want to add more
examples to correct for some of
these issues.
We also may want to remove
incorrectly trained data as well
as maybe update incorrect
annotations.
In Turi Create, we enable you to
load data as well as sort and
filter data if you want to
remove incorrect training data.
If you want to add more data,
simply use the append command.
And new in Turi Create 6.0 we've
introduced an annotation tool.
To use it, pass in the data set
that you want to annotate, and a
GUI pops up with two distinct
sections.
To your left, you can see the
image that you want to annotate
and to your right you see a
labels column.
You can add labels and annotate
your data points.
But we also recognize that if
you're going through a large
data set it may be annoying to
kind of spend that time to go
through the entire data set.
So we've included image
similarity and we're going to
help you quickly go through your
data set.
We've also included a Table view
that allows you to scroll
through your data set, look at
annotations, maybe identify
those systematic biases we
talked about, and add multiple
annotations to multiple images.
[ Applause ]
So a summary of this session.
Sam and Shantanu showed us the
new One-Shot Object Detector
Toolkit.
Shantanu upped Sam's game with a
Three Card Poker app and was
able to build a robust model
with only one example per class.
Next, we looked at the new
Drawing Classifier ToolKit.
In it, we saw the new
integration with the Apple
Pencil.
The interactive visualization
tool showed us how to evaluate
models interactively and
hopefully showed us a process
for building better experiences
for our users.
And finally, we introduced a new
annotation tool that not only
allows you to label data, but
quickly go through your data
sets with the use of image
similarity.
Please install Turicreate.
We hope you've enjoyed this
session and join us in the labs
at 2:00 if you want to see any
of the demos or have any
questions.
We encourage you to check out
these related sessions.
Thank you for coming to WWDC
2019.
[ Applause ]