[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
Alright, good afternoon.
My name is Chad Woolf.
I'm a performance tools engineer
for Apple and this is session
421, we'll talk about modeling
in Custom Instruments.
Now, within the Custom
Instruments Architecture,
modeling is done by this piece
in the middle here called a
modeler, and the modeler's job
is really to reason about the
raw events that are being
recorded by the operating
system, perform some
transformations, and create the
displayable events or the input
to another modeler for
instruments in the Air
Instruments UI.
Now, this architecture was
covered in its entirety in our
2018 session, Creating Custom
Instruments.
So in this session, what we're
going to do really is just take
sort of a spotlight focus on
this piece in the middle, called
a modeler.
Now modelers are important to
all of our instruments including
the Time Profiler up here.
Now in the Time Profiler, the
data that you're seeing
presented in the UI is not
exactly the same as being
recorded by the kernel.
We use a modeler to do some
transforms.
So now when the kernel takes a
sample of what your thread is
doing, it creates or captures
what's called a primitive
backtrace, and it puts that into
the time sample table, which is
then picked up by the Time
Profiler modeler, which is then
transformed into a more
displayable form of the
backtrace, which goes into the
Time Profiler table, which is
ultimately viewed by the Time
Profiler instrument.
Now, the reason we do this is
because it's a lot simpler and
thus more efficient to capture
these primitive backtraces, and
then we can fix them up in user
space later inside of our
modeler and therefore we keep
that recording side in the
kernel very efficient.
Now, another kind of
optimization that's made by the
kernel is if the kernel samples
a thread that it knows hasn't
moved since the last time it
samples it, instead of taking a
full back trace, it just puts a
placeholder backtrace into the
time sample table and then our
time profiler modeler picks that
up, takes the last known
backtrace for that, and
replicates that into the Time
Profile table that's viewed by
the Instrument.
Now, this does two things.
It saves a ton of space in the
kernel's recording buffer,
especially if your threads are
mostly idle.
And it also keeps the UI
efficient, because the UI
doesn't need to know about this
placeholder convention because
that's all been normalized by
our modeler.
So, you're going to see these
themes repeat in today's
session.
And that is basically to take
the complexity of your custom
instrument and absorb that in
the modeling layer.
And that will promote simplicity
in other areas, specifically
when it comes to the tracing
code that you embed inside your
logic and also the UI that you
use in Instruments.
So, today's session looks like
this.
We're going to review some
modeling basics and then we're
going to walk you through the
process of building a custom
modeler.
When you get to build a custom
modeler, sometimes it's tough
when you do it from scratch.
So, this year we have sample
code attached to this year's
session, so you can follow along
with that, or use that as the
basis for your own modelers.
Now, in the process, we're also
going to talk about execution
and the rules engine, Cliff's
rules engine.
And also an important topic
called speculation.
So, let's start with reviewing
some modeling basics.
Now, when you create a modeler,
you also have to define the
other pieces of that
architecture as well.
So, you also have to define the
schemas that will glue all this
together in the Instrument,
which will ultimately view the
output of your Instrument.
And that all gets built into an
Instrument's distribution
package, which can then be
installed inside of Instruments
and tested.
Now, at this point we're going
to assume that you already have
one of these projects set up in
Xcode.
And really, what you're looking
to do is add a custom modeler or
you're going to be working from
our sample code that's attached
to the session this year, and
you're going to have that
project already set up.
Now, when do you need to create
a custom modeler?
It's true that Xcode will
generate modelers for you, in
some cases specifically when
you're using OS Signpost as your
input.
But these modelers are really
meant to get you an Instrument
up and running quickly.
They're not really there to
expose the entire feature set to
you that you can do with custom
modelers.
Such as being able to fuse data
from multiple input tables.
That's something that you can do
with a custom modeler.
You can't do it in the generated
case.
And more importantly, maintain a
working memory.
This allows your modeler to keep
some running totals.
To track open intervals.
And perform some more extensive
calculations using the modeler's
working memory.
Now, another thing that you can
do is create custom graphs.
If there's a graph that you'd
like to create but Instruments
doesn't do it natively, you can
synthesize the data inside your
modeler.
For example, maybe you can
compute a running average or
something as sophisticated as a
Calvin filter.
It's really, it's up to you and
you can do all of that in a
custom modeler.
Now, ultimately the goal here is
really to build smarter and
smarter instruments so that the
instruments know what's going on
in your code.
And it's to even reach a point
where the people who are working
with your code will turn to your
Instruments first before they
turn to you for trouble
shooting, and that'll kind of
free you up to work on the next
great thing.
Now, a modeler is basically a
rules engine that is bound to a
set of input tables and a set of
output tables.
The Instrument's analysis core
takes on the task of time
ordering the input tables and
injecting them into the
modeler's working memory.
Now, objects in the working
memory are called facts.
And the way that you reason
about the changes to the working
memory and these facts is by
defining a rules system in the
CLIPS language.
Now, CLIPS is an open source
language.
It's been around since the '80s,
so there's lots of great
examples and documentation to
help you get started and there's
a lot of great examples in our
sample code and also in our
slides today.
Now, ultimately when your
modeler discovers something that
it wants to output, there are
functions in the modeler as well
to write to the bound output
tables.
Now, to get started writing a
modeler from scratch, we have a
three-step process that starts
with basically deciding what you
want to model.
Now, this means understanding
the technology you're creating a
Custom Instrument for.
And it also means knowing how
the Custom Instrument's
infrastructure works and how to
really get the most out of it.
In our 2019 session, Developing
a Great Profile Experience, our
team will walk you through the
process of trying to tell a
story of what's going on with
your code using Custom
Instruments, so that's a great
place to start with
understanding what your'e trying
to model.
All right, so now that you have
the output defined for your
modeler, it's going to need some
input.
And the best way to get input
into instruments from your code
is through the OS Signpost API.
This is an API that you can
sprinkle throughout your code to
basically trace what's happening
in your code and pass argument
data, gives your modeler
something to reason about in
your input stream.
Now, once you have your inputs
and your outputs, then it's time
to start defining your rule
system and start writing your
rules.
Now, we know that steps two and
three are going to be iterative.
So, as you write your rules, you
may discover that you need to go
back and add more Signposts or
that you need to change your
Signposts, which is totally
fine.
You can do that.
But keep in mind that your
Signposts re going to really
form the boundary between what's
going on in your code and your
Instrument.
So, at some point you're going
to want to, like, make sure that
you comment those Signpost
invocation calls and let people
know that that's really a
contract and it'll break your
instrument if you modify it.
All right, now we think that
this process is probably best
understood with a practical
example.
So, I would like to now turn it
over to our modeling expert,
Alejandro Lucena, to walk us
through.
[Applause]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Good afternoon, everybody, and
thank you, Chad.
So, what I'd like to do is I'd
like to go through this thought
process that Chad just
highlighted and apply it to an
example so we can see how all
these pieces fit together.
And to do that, I want to start
off with this demo app.
And full disclosure, this is
probably the coolest thing I
have ever worked on and it's a
list of goats, right?
Now, these different goats don't
just have themselves displayed
on this app.
The app also lets me sort the
list.
Now, the sorting is implemented
using something we call the
mobile agent pattern.
And this pattern has a lot of
parallels to different patterns
that you may be using such as
futures and promises or
operation queues.
So, whenever you hear the term
mobile agent, when we're talking
about it, you can mentally
substitute that in for whichever
pattern you're using.
But we'll stick with the mobile
agent pattern for the purposes
of this session.
So, as the name implies, the
mobile agent pattern has a very
important concept which is that
of a mobile agent.
And we'll visualize the mobile
agent as this circle in the
upper lefthand corner.
Now, the goal of an agent is to
take a task such as sorting a
list and really breaking it down
into a few subtasks such as
obtaining the initial list and
then sorting it, and then
committing the results, with
each of those subtasks being
executed at what we call stops.
And stops can provide the agent
with some sort of dependencies
or execution context for it to
achieve its subgoal.
So I want to take a look at how
we can implement something like
sorting using this mobile agent
pattern.
Now, what we'll do is when we
click the sort in the upper
lefthand corner, the agent is
going to move over to its very
first stop.
In this case, the stop is hosted
by a UI and it will execute its
first subtask of obtaining the
list.
Now, once the list is obtained,
it can move over to a different
stop, such as one hosted by a
dispatch queues.
And at that dispatch queues stop,
it can then perform the actual
sorting.
And once the sorting is
complete, it can move back to
the UI to end up populating the
list with those sorted results.
And finally, it can park itself
back at the sort button for
future use.
So, what we just saw is that the
mobile agent pattern, or really
the agents can be in one of two
primary phases.
They can either be executing at
a stop, or they can be moving
over to a stop.
And this is what we're
interested in modeling.
And more specifically, we're
interested in seeing the
duration of these things, how
long they take and the
interactions between them.
And to better visualize this, I
want to go through the sorting
example again but put these
intervals into perspective.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to move this device over
to the lefthand side because
we'll need some space.
So again, when we click the sort
button, the agent is moving over
to that UI stop.
And as soon as that movement
happens, we want to see an
interval with maybe some
descriptive string or something
telling us what happened.
Next, we know that at the stop,
the agent is going to perform
its first subtask, which is
getting the list.
And we see that in a different
interval here.
Next, the agent is going to move
over to a dispatch queues, and
that'll be represented by its
own interval.
At the dispatch queues, the agent
will perform some sorting, and
we see it; it's executing in the
sorting mode.
Before it finally moves back
over to the UI stop and we have
a final movement interval,
moving back to the UI.
And at that stop, it will
execute the next, or the last,
subtask of filling in the list
with the sorted results.
So, with these intervals, we can
really think of the beginning of
the interval as being the time
at which the activity started,
either execution or movement.
And the end of the interval
being the time at which that
activity ended.
And with these intervals in
mind, we can have or we can
design some instrument that we'd
like to see, and that's
precisely what I have behind me
now.
Here in the topmost track, I
have al these intervals together
and we can see the different
movements and executions.
And beneath that very topmost
track, we have the different
stops that were active during
the trace.
Now, on top of the visual aspect
of the instrument, we also want
to see a detail view.
And the detail view will give us
some more information about what
happened at each stop, such as
the time that it started, how
long it took, which agent was
there, and so forth.
Now, at this point, we should
notice these columns at the top.
Because these columns are how we
define what we're interested in
modeling.
Here, the columns tell us that
this is a start time and a
duration and an agent kind, but
more generally we specify these
columns in our Instrument's
package files written in XML.
And these columns collectively
form our output tables.
Which brings us to our very
first checkpoint.
And that is that with these
columns, we define what it is
that we're trying to store.
And that fulfills the first goal
of deciding what it is that we
want to model.
And now that we have that, the
next thing we need to do is get
data from our application into
Instruments, and we'll
accomplish this by using OS
Signpost.
So, let's take a look at our
intervals again.
We have these.
And we do have an API that
utilizes OS Signpost, that is
natively built for intervals.
But we want to take it one step
further and specifically I want
to use event Signposts.
And each of these event
Signposts will be emitted at the
borders between the activity
intervals.
And the reason for doing this is
not only because we get to save
roughly 50% of the amount of
Signposts we would otherwise
emit.
But this is actually a more
accurate representation of the
mobile agent pattern.
Specifically, when an agent is
done with the current activity,
it will immediately begin
another one, and so we can just
emit a single Signpost that
tells us that it's moving on to
the next thing.
And in order to accomplish this,
here we have an execute stop
function that is part of the
mobile agent class.
And before we perform the actual
internal logic of executing
whatever it is that we're doing
at that stop, we have a Signpost
that has a name, a specific
Signpost ID and a message that
we'd like to embed.
In addition to that, we have the
same sort of OS Signpost setup
within this visit next stop
function, which implements the
logic of moving an agent from
one stop over to the next.
And again, before we perform the
movement, we title it
appropriately such as mobile
agent moves, then we give it
another Signpost ID and a
message.
But now we've really got to
focus on this middle piece which
is the modeler, and the modeler
is what's going to transform
those Signposts that we just put
into our app into the usable
intervals that we want to see in
the output table.
So, I'd like to give you an
example.
Here we have a modeler, and this
modeler starts off with a blank
view of working memory, because
it doesn't really know anything
about the state of the
application yet.
But what we do know, however, is
that the modeler interacts very
closely with the OS Signpost
table.
And the OS Signpost table is
populated from our application.
So, let's consider the case of
the modeler trying to detect a
mobile agent from the Signpost.
While when we click the Sort on
our demo app, the modeler is
going to receive an OS Signpost.
And the modeler will represent
that Signpost by a fact.
And that fact has its slots
filled out according to however
we made the OS Signpost call.
Now, at this point the modeler
sees that the OS Signpost fact
is actually advertising a lot of
information about a mobile
agent.
And so the modeler can use that
OS Signpost fact to deduce the
agent and introduce it into
working memory by asserting a
fact.
In this case, it's asserting
that it knows that there's a
sorting agent that's moved to
the background.
Next, the modeler should
determine the activity that the
agent was doing, such as what it
was actually, you know, trying
to do as well as the time.
So, the modeler can look at the
facts already and say, or it
knows that it has a mobile agent
that was moving.
And it sees the Signpost fact
and that it started at time 42.
And the modeler can again make
note of that by introducing
another fact into working memory
that tells us that it started at
time 42.
Now, at this point the Signpost
facts go away but that's okay,
because we kept all the relevant
information in the facts that we
asserted into working memory
ourselves.
So, I'll move these facts up a
little bit, because we need some
space.
And the last thing that the
modeler has to do here is
determine the full interval of
the activity.
Right now we only have the start
time.
We don't really know the entire
interval.
But we know that at some point
our demo app is going to emit
another Signpost.
And again, when the modeler
receives it, it will represent
it as a fact accordingly.
And because we structured our
Signposts such that they were
emitted at the borders between
these intervals, the modeler now
knows that when it receives
another Signpost, it can look at
any open interval facts that it
previously had open and close
them.
In this case, the modeler is
going to look at these values
from the facts that it has, and
it has enough to determine the
full interval.
And to do that, it'll summon the
output table and then remove
that open interval fact that it
had to replace it with a full
interval.
In this case, moving it to the
background.
And use that interval to
populate the output table.
All right.
Now, before delving into some
CLIPS code that actually goes
through all this, I think it's
important to understand how an
API call from our application
code translates to a fact within
CLIPS.
Specifically, when we call OS
Signposts with a particular
name, that name becomes the same
name slot in the OS Signpost
fact.
Furthermore, the type of
Signposts that we have, in this
case event, becomes the
event-type slot within the OS
Signpost fact.
And lastly, the Signpost ID
becomes the identifier value
within the OS Signpost fact as
well as a message.
The message that we embed also
takes on the message value
within the OS Signpost fact.
So, now that we know that, we
can try to look at some rules to
detect a mobile agent.
Here we have a rule written in
CLIPS, and the first thing that
it's trying to do is to detect
the presence of an OS Signpost
that has a particular name such
as mobile agent moved.
And what we'll do is we're going
to capture the value that's held
within the identifier slot in
this instance variable.
Additionally, we can perform
some parsing on the message to
extract any useful information
that we see from there.
And now in the second part, we
have one more condition that
we'd like to express, which is
that we're trying to match
against the absence of a mobile
agent that has already been
identified by the Signpost.
Signpost is what we're going to
use to identify mobile agents,
but we don't want to introduce
any duplicates.
So, here with the knot keyword,
we're telling the modeler only
do this if you don't already
have a mobile agent that has
been identified with this
instance variable.
And if that's the case, the
modeler can go ahead and assert
that mobile agent into working
memory.
Likewise, when we're trying to
detect what the mobile agent was
doing, we match against the OS
Signpost fact again, because
we'll need that to determine
some properties.
But in this case, we omit the
use of the knot keyword, because
we really do want the presence
of this agent fact to live in
our working memory.
So, we know that we have already
parsed the agent and we can do
something more with it.
Specifically, once we do have
these two facts present, we can
assert or introduce that
movement fact so that the
modeler can keep track of what
the agent was actually doing.
All right, so we've seen some
examples of how we can write
CLIPS code to detect agents and
activities that they were doing,
but we need to learn a little
bit more about the underlying
execution to help us structure
our modeler a little bit better.
And in order to do that, I want
to invite Chad back onto the
stage to talk to us about rule
execution.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, so let's talk
about rules execution in the
CLIPS language in Rules Engine.
All right, when we define Rules
in CLIPS, they're defined with a
lefthand side and a righthand
side separated by a production
operator.
Now, lefthand side is really the
declarative part of the
language.
So, this is where you define a
pattern that you want the rules
engine to find in the working
memory of facts.
And when the Rules Engine
identifies a set of facts that
satisfies that pattern on the
lefthand side, it creates what's
called an activation.
Now, for each activation, it
will fire the righthand side of
the rule.
Now, the righthand side of the
rule is really the imperative
part of the language.
This is where you have access to
functions like retract, which
allows you to remove a fact from
working memory.
Or assert, which allows you to
add a fact into the working
memory.
And also some specialized
functions that allow you to
write to the output tables of
your modeler so you can write
the output.
Now, let's talk about facts for
a minute.
When we assert a fact into the
working memory, we use our
assert function.
And each new fact is assigned
what's called a fact address,
and they're identified with a
lowercase f, dash, and then some
unique number.
Now when we want to modify a
fact in the working memory, we
also have a modify function
which takes the fact address and
the slots that we'd like to
change on that piece of the
working memory.
Now, this is actually
implemented as a combination of
a retraction and an assertion.
So what happens here is we first
retract the fact from the
working memory, make the change,
and then reassert it back into
the working memory with the
updated fields or updated slots.
Now, this is important because
when you reassert something into
the working memory, it will
refire and potentially
reactivate some of those rules,
which exactly what you want in
most cases because that's how
your rules system is going to
react to the changes you're
making to the working memory.
However, this can lead in some
cases to a complication I like
to refer to as a logical loop.
So, let's see how we might have
accidently created a logical
loop in our code.
So, we have this pretty small
rule here.
And what it's designed to do is
to count the number of mobile
agents-- mobile agent instances
that have appeared in the
working memory.
So, it starts off with a counter
fact, with a slot that's
initially zero.
And for each mobile agent that
gets placed into the working
memory, it will fire the
righthand side of the rule which
simply modifies the counter by
bumping the count slot up by
one.
Now, this sounds pretty
straightforward.
However, let's look at it when
it actually executes.
So first thing, we start off
with our counter in working
memory with an initial count of
zero.
And let's say at some point in
the future a mobile agent is
asserted into the working
memory.
Now we have enough on the
lefthand side to fire the
righthand side.
So, that will call our modify
function which will first do a
retraction of that fact.
It'll modify by increasing the
count value, and then it will
reassert it back into the
working memory.
Now when we do this, notice that
it refired that same rule.
So now for that same mobile
agent instance, it's going to
count two, three, four, five,
six, seven, right.
It's going to keep going on and
on and on until eventually the
trace stops and instruments
tells you this was a fatal error
and that the rules engine
appears to be stuck.
Now, in the Instruments
Inspector in the console of your
modeler, you'll see trace, which
indicates all the events and
activations that were happening
during that loop.
So, that'll give you a head
start on how to debug that and
get out of it.
Now, the easiest way, in my
experience, to get out of a
logical loop is to do what I
call a little bit of
goal-oriented programming.
So instead of modifying the
counter fact directly, what we
do is we create a goal fact to
bump the counter for us.
And now this time when we detect
a mobile agent instance, we
assert a goal fact to count that
instance.
And then in our counting rule,
we capture the counter and the
goal and we retract the goal
because now it's being satisfied
when we bump the counter.
And that's going to keep that
rule from coming back through
and that's how we've broken out
of that logical loop.
All right, now let's talk about
the firing order of our rules
and how that might change the
outcome of our modeler.
So, let's return back to our
execute stop function.
This is what's called right
before a mobile agent goes into
its executing stage.
And now you'll notice here in
our OS Signpost, that first
argument in our first version of
the code, we're actually using
the agent's type string.
Which in this case would be
sorting agent or it's about 14
bytes of data that has to be
logged into the trace buffers.
Now, we think we can improve on
that by changing it from a
string over to a type code.
Now, this is only going to be a
four byte integer which is going
to save us about 10 bytes per
event.
And if these things are coming
in by the thousands, which they
are, it's going to save 10s of
thousands of bytes in the
tracing buffer.
Now in order to do that, we're
going to have to create some
mapping inside of our modeler
that coverts that code over to
that string, and so we're going
to use facts to do that.
And this time, in our detection
rule, we're going to capture the
agent's type code and when we
assert our mobile agent, we're
going to assert it with a kind
slot that's the symbol sentinel.
It's going to indicate we
haven't set the full string yet.
Because on a second rule, what
we're going to do is look for
any mobile agent that has a kind
of sentinel and we're going to
find for that corresponding type
code, the type string map that
you saw on the previous slide.
And once we have those two
pieces, we'll modify the kind
slot, changing it from the
symbol sentinel to a real
string.
Now, this whole design really
relies on this second lookup
rule, firing immediately after
we perform the assertion.
But what happens if another rule
in our system, for example our
agent parked rule, which also
references the mobile agent and
captures and uses the kind slot.
What if it happens to slip in
there between the assertion and
the lookup rule?
Well, it's going to see a kind
of sentinel.
And since this is a change we're
making to our rule system, it
might not be ready for that.
We have a whole new set of bugs
now.
So, one way to work around this
is to add a restriction to that
rule that says as long as the
kind is not equal to sentinel
and that effectively delays the
rule firing until that lookup
rule does change the agent's
kind from something, from
sentinel to something real.
Now, you can certainly do this
but you're going to have to do
this to all of the rules.
And so that could be a little
bit of a maintenance problem if
you already have an existing
rule set that assumes that will
never be sentinel.
So, let's look at another
alternative way to do that.
Now, really what we're trying to
do is get that lookup rule to
fire immediately after we
perform that assertion.
And one of the ways that we can
do that is by telling CLIPS that
that specific rule is more
important than or more salient
than the default salience of
zero.
Now, as long as that rule is the
most salient rule in the system,
as soon as our first rule
finishes, that second rule is
going to be the one that fires.
Now, if you're using salience in
other locations, you're going to
have to go through your code and
make sure that 100 is still the
highest salience value, but
that's another way to ensure
that.
Now, there is a little bit more
direct way to control the rule
ordering and the rule firing,
but that requires that we learn
a little bit more about
activations.
So, a reminder, an activation is
basically a combination of facts
in the working memory that
satisfies the lefthand side of
our pattern.
And for each activation, we fire
the righthand side of the rule.
Now, we don't fire the righthand
side of the rule immediately.
Instead, what we do is the
activation is logged to a data
structure called the agenda, or
an agenda.
Now, an agenda is basically a
list of activations that have
resulted from a working memory
update, and so all the rules
engine needs to do is start from
the top of that list and work
its way down, firing the rules
in that particular pattern.
So, here we've fired the first
rule, now we come down to the
second rule.
Now, this data structure is
dynamic, so if rule 99 here were
to retract fact 17, and fact 17
is being referenced by these
other two activations, CLIPS
will first retract those
activations before moving
forward, and then thus the
agenda will look like this when
execution resumes.
Now the agendas are ordered by
salience, so that's where
salience comes into play.
The higher salience, the higher
it appears on the agenda.
But the more important part here
is that there isn't a single
agenda on your modeler.
There's actually one per module
that's defined.
And we take advantage of that in
the analysis core by defining a
couple of standard modules for
you.
The first one being the modeler
module, and this is where you're
going to want to put your pure
reasoning logic and your
reasoning rules in this module,
by prefacing the rule name with
modeler colon colon.
And we defined a second module
called a recorder module that,
this is where you're going to
want to put your output writing
rules, by prefacing those with
recorder colon colon.
And the reason you're going to
want to do that is because when
we execute these rules, we
execute everything that's on the
modeler's agenda first until
it's completely empty before
moving over to the recorder's
module.
And so what that allows you to
do is have confidence that when
you're having an output writing
rule, you're not looking at
working memory that's in the
process of being reasoned in the
modeler module.
Now, you can take advantage of
this yourself by defining your
own custom modules in CLIPS.
And so let's take a look at how
we could do that to better
adjust our lookup rule
execution.
So the first thing we want not
do is define the module for our
lookup module.
Now we want to place our lookup
rule inside that module by
prefacing it with lookup colon
colon.
Now, when we assert a mobile
agent fact, immediately the next
thing that we do is tell CLIPS
to focus on the lookup agenda.
Basically run all of the
activations that are in the
lookup agenda before returning
back to the modeler's agenda and
thusly executing the next set of
modeling rules.
So, that's a great way to slip
rules in between execution in
the execution order.
All right, so that gives us
enough information now and we
can start taking a look at how
to start debugging and
profiling.
And in order to do that, I'd
like to ask Alejandro to come
back up to the stage and walk us
through that.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, thank you Chad.
What I'd like to do is talk
about some of the debugging and
profiling primitives we have
available to us when we're
building these models.
Starting off with logging.
Now, the logging primitives that
we have available to us are very
similar to print f, in that we
can specify a format string,
format flags as well, and the
variables that we'd like to
represent those types.
Now, unlike print f or just
normal use of print f, through
the Instruments Inspector, we
actually have the ability to
dynamically enable or disable
these log statements, and we'll
see an example of this very
shortly.
Now, how do I actually get these
logging statements into my
rules?
Well, there's a function in
CLIPS which is log narrative.
And log narrative works, as I
mentioned, very similarly to
print f in that we can specify a
string, such as resolve agent
kind code, and then we specify
the format type using percent
and then the actual engineering
type, in this case UN 64 and
then a percent sign to string,
followed by the variables that
we'd like to take on those data
types.
Now, likewise, we can also
enable different type of
primitive here which is
profiling through the
Instruments Inspector, and the
profiling primitive gives us
things such as rule activation
counts so we can see how many
times certain rules fired as
well as a time distribution so
we can see how much time in
seconds and percentage wise we
spent activating certain rules.
Now, to put all this in context,
I'd like to switch over to a
demo and I'll show you how all
these things work together.
So here with me I have the
sample code that is again
available to download.
And within the sample code we
have many different targets that
you can use.
But the one that I like to start
with first is this plot
templates modeling target that
we can see over here.
So, this will actually open up
instruments when I build and run
it.
Looks like the build succeeded.
And we can open up instruments
accordingly.
Now what I'll do here is I
actually have the goats app
already pulled up, so I won't
maximize the screen, because
we're going to need to keep this
in mind here.
Initially what I'll do is I'll
go to the blank template and in
the upper righthand corner, I
can select an instrument that
I'd like to add.
And so to do that, I'll go ahead
and go here and start searching
for the mobile agents target
that we just built.
Now within here, again I
mentioned the log narratives can
be enabled or disabled
dynamically via the Instruments
Inspector.
So using command i, I can open
up the Instruments Inspector and
here in the login tab, by
default it's set to none.
Butt I can switch that over to
narrative, and that will enable
these log narrative statements.
So, I'll go ahead and close
this.
And instead of all processes,
I'm going to switch it over to
this goat list app.
So, I'll start recording.
And here in the goat list I can
perform some actions such as
sorting the different list of
goats.
And I see some activity popping
up here in instruments.
I can click it again and we'll
see some more activity popping
up, but I think that's enough to
demonstrate the purpose here.
First I'd like to zoom in and
show the different intervals
that we were talking about
previously such as activating
and the movements and
everything.
But to see the actual log
narrative statements, again,
I'll open up the Instruments
Inspector using command i.
And we got something new.
We got this modeler log table.
And in this modeler log table,
that's where all of our log
narrative statements will live,
such as this resolving agent
kind code that we saw in this
example of how we use log
narrative.
In addition to many other ones
that we have in our rules.
Now, how do we switch over from
using log narrative over to
profile.
Well again, in this login tab, I
can switch over to something
like profile 1, and I'll close
out of the Instruments Inspector
and try running Instruments
again.
I'll re-record the trace.
Now I realize that this is
already sorted but we can still
get some activity happening from
the mobile agents.
And that should be enough again
to demonstrate the purposes.
So, I'll stop and I'll open up
the Instruments Inspector again.
There is no more modeler log
table because we don't have any
log narratives to show.
But if, however, I go to this
modeler's tab up here, I can
actually see a very nice
descriptive view of these
different profiling values, such
as this rule, this lookup
unknown stop for execution got 7
entries in the amount of time
that it took and percentage wise
as well, in addition to many of
the other rules that I've
specified in my modeling.
Now, before closing this out, I
did notice something
particularly interesting.
I'm going to rerun the trace
once more because I want to
capture it one more time.
I'll start the sort and I see
these different activities
coming up.
But then if I sort again, I
notice that I get these long
orange intervals coming in after
the fact.
They don't really follow the
same live description or the
live rendering that I expect
with this Instrument.
Now, there is a reason why this
happens and in order to talk us
through it and how we can find a
solution for this, I want to
bring Chad back on to talk about
speculation.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. Thank you, Alejandro.
All right, so to describe the
phenomenon that Alejandro was
seeing, or work around it, we
have to introduce a concept
called speculation.
And now what happened with those
intervals?
What makes them unique is first
they're long intervals.
They appear over or they extend
over a period of several
seconds, so it's more obvious,
more visible.
But secondly, the real problem
is that the only record of these
intervals that exists is sitting
in the working memory of your
modeler.
Now, your UI is actually looking
at the output tables in your
modeler, so it's not able to see
those.
And we can't really write those
intervals into the output table
until we know, you know, when
they're going to close.
And that's what you're seeing in
that particular case.
Now, what we really want to do
is be able to write like
temporary or placeholder rows
into the output tables of our
modeler.
And to do that, we've introduced
a concept called Speculation
mode.
Now, Speculation mode in your
modeler really says if this were
your last chance to write to the
output tables, what would you
write right now?
So, let's look at an example
here.
Let's say our modeler has
processed all the data up until
this white line here, which we
call the event horizon.
The event horizon is a point in
time after which the modeler has
no visibility.
Now, that could be due to the
fact that the trace just ended,
or it could be that the analysis
core hasn't filled in that
portion of the trace yet.
And so it's unaware of what's on
the other side of that line.
Now, do you see that we've
created an interval that says
moving to the background.
And we can do that because it is
nicely bookended between a
moving and executing Signpost
pair.
But we don't know where that
followup executing interval's
really going to end because it's
ending event is on the other
side of the event horizon.
So what we want to do is when we
get into speculation mode, just
write a temporary placeholder
event into the tables so that
the UI can see something and
we're going to run that interval
basically from the executing
Signpost up to the current value
of the event horizon.
Now, you know that your
modeler's in Speculation mode
because you get a Speculate fact
that's going to be injected into
working memory.
And in your recorder rules, you
can combine that Speculate fact
with any interval facts to write
those open intervals into the
table with the captured event
horizon timestamp.
And that's your opportunity to
write the open intervals.
So, let's take a look at example
rule that we might define here.
So first off, we're going to put
our speculative output writing
rule in the recorder module.
So, prefix it with a recorder
colon colon.
Now, we're going to match on the
Speculate event, capture the
value of the event horizon.
So, we have the end time for our
interval, our theoretical end
time.
Now, for each open interval fact
sitting in the working memory,
we're going to fire the
righthand side of the rule.
And what we're going to do here
is compute the duration based on
the end time which is the event
horizon and start time which is
whenever the interval started.
And then you create a new row
and fill out the columns just
like you would in normal output
writing rule.
Now the only difference really
between a normal output writing
rule and a speculative output
writing rule is that you're
testing or predicating this rule
on the Speculate fact, and
you're looking at the open
intervals instead of the closed
intervals, which you'd normally
be writing into your output
table.
Now, when you're in immediate
mode, what happens is that as
that recording head moves
forward, the older speculative
data is purged and your modeler
enters into speculation mode
again with a new value of the
event horizon and you're able to
put those speculation events
back.
And the UI just continues to
update like normal.
Now when the trace stops, your
modeler will enter Speculation
mode one more time.
But whatever you write now will
actually be recorded and saved
in the real trace data and
become available to downstream
modelers, not just the UI.
Now, if we make that change to
our existing instrument, it'll
start working like this now
where you have our mobile agent
trace and now you see this
parking interval continuing to
grow here at the end.
And it updates in real time.
If you look in the detail table
on the bottom, you'll see the
duration continuing to grow.
Now, when we press stop and end
the recording, you'll notice
that the interval sticks around.
It's actually been recorded and
will be saved as part of the
trace.
Now in summary, we know that
writing custom modelers
represents a significant
investment, both in your time
and learning a new technology.
But it's really the best way to
get the most out of custom
instruments and to add
intelligence to your custom
instruments.
And as we've seen, an
intelligent instrument can lead
to a more efficient recording
mechanism and a much better user
experience.
So for more information, we have
our attached sample code, also
some related sessions on our
sessions webpage.
And that about does it for
today.
Thank you very much.
Enjoy the rest of the show.
[ Applause ]