[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good evening, hello.
Welcome to Designing for Adverse
Network and Temperature
Conditions.
Whether you're just starting out
with your first app or if you're
a seasoned app developer, we
want you to design for a world
class experience.
Your apps have the potential to
be used by millions of people in
so many different situations.
Many of those people will not be
on a superfast 4G network, and
others may be in warmer
environments.
Now, we all do some level of
testing, but are you doing
enough to know what it's like to
interact with your app the way
those users would, and if you
are, are you providing the best
experience that you can?
Great apps continue to work well
even under challenging
real-world situations, which
might be difficult to design
for.
That's why we're here to share
some tips with you and brand-new
tools in Xcode to help with
that.
I'm Alex Kara.
&gt;&gt; And I'm Ilya Veygman.
We work in iOS system
performance so that the system
works well and reliably and
consistently in the real world.
IOS reacts to changing network
and temperature conditions, and
we want you to be able to do the
same thing with your app so that
you just can experience your app
the way that you designed it.
&gt;&gt; We have some exciting things
to talk about today.
First, we're going to dive into
real-world device conditions and
where they fit in to your design
process.
Next, we'll show you how to
improve your app's behavior
under different network links
with new and existing developer
tools.
And finally, we'll reveal a
brand-new way to optimize your
app with varying temperature
conditions.
&gt;&gt; I want you to picture how and
where you use iOS.
You don't simply use your
devices at home or at the
office.
You take them with you
everywhere.
To the beach, to the park, on
the subway, in your car on a
long road trip.
These might be places with a lot
of sunlight or heat or with weak
network connectivity.
Now, picture your users.
Chances are, they'll be using
your app in environments just
like these.
It's important for you to
consider how that compares with
your development and test
environment.
Now, you're probably doing most
or all of your development and
testing in your office or in a
lab.
These are all certainly going to
have fast, reliable internet
connectivity and climate
control, and that's a good
thing.
We all want a good controlled
place to work.
But these won't be the same
conditions your users around the
world face when interacting with
your app.
This difference can be a big
reason why you might be seeing
complaints about your app but
dismissing them as one-offs or
corner cases.
In addition to this, these
devices can multitask.
Your users might be in the
passenger seat of a car, getting
turn-by-turn directions while
streaming music even wirelessly
to CarPlay.
They might be at a coffee shop
charging their iPhone and using
it as a hotspot for their Mac.
Or, they might be using ARKit to
recognize objects in your app
through the camera while the app
runs 3D rendering or some other
kind of complicated background
processing.
The point of all this is all of
these scenarios can cause your
device to work harder and get
warm.
While your app's features may
work well in your test weaves
under isolation, are you taking
into account how the performance
of your app might be different
during these very real and
common use cases?
A potential pain point for your
users is when they try to
interact with an app designed
only for the conditions you've
been working in.
How might that look like to
them?
&gt;&gt; Well, we noticed some reviews
on the App Store which mentioned
worsened behavior in certain
situations.
Great apps, which would
sometimes feel short.
Whether it's on the train,
places with a bit of heat, or on
a road trip, this might end up
being the biggest way your users
remember your app, and they
might not want to come back to
it after an egregious
experience.
Now, we know that people use
their phones in direct sunlight
and that people go into tunnels
and expect your app to continue
to work, and we know that people
aren't always in the best
network situations.
It's easy to overlook this when
your development conditions are
less representative or clean
room.
So we want to take these
conditions into account, and we
want you to provide a consistent
experience, not one that's worse
than it needs to be.
You'll find users connected to
3G networks in your feedback, or
you might find a problem in your
app and notice that your device
was warmer to the touch.
Now you might be tempted to
think of these as expected bad
behavior, but these are not edge
cases.
These are real situations that
you and your users will face.
To be able to handle them
better, you're going to need the
right developer tools and the
process that lets you apply them
well.
So, let's get started with
network link.
If you're using the network
either for primary functions in
your app or for background work,
you might have made decisions in
your code to act on the type of
network that you're on.
You might be choosing to time
out if network calls take long.
Now, for your users, some of
them might be on 3G networks.
If that's their reality, they
might be happy to wait for a
download to finish even if it
takes longer.
But your decision to timeout
will not respect their wishes,
and they'll be surprised when
the app makes no progress even
when they're happy to wait.
It's these decisions that add up
to become part of your user's
experience.
When users launch your app, they
don't want to see a network
spinner that looks like it's
perpetually downloading or one
that totally stops.
This might be the experience you
provide if you're doing network
calls during your app launch,
but it might look fine to you if
you ran this on LTE or fast
Wi-Fi even if you were doing
performance testing.
After some time, your users
might give up on this screen and
maybe even on your app entirely,
especially if there are other
apps performing under the same
conditions.
Your app should continue to be
launchable even without a
network connection.
And if I'm trying to catch on
important news with an app that
times out early, I might notice
that content fails to load on a
slower network connection.
Now, if I use other apps and
notice that they don't fail in
the same way, I would think that
this app is frozen or that it's
buggy.
This situation could escape your
development or testing if you're
mocking out network calls or
explicitly skipping them in your
tests.
So, you should go and take a
look at Xcode's Scheme Editor
and see if you're setting an
environment variable for unit
testing purposes.
When you're running your app as
a unit test host, you might be
using this to prevent unneeded
work happening during your app's
launch.
For unit tests, it's okay to
skip work such as kicking off
background network requests in
order to optimize for execution
speed, but you need to make sure
you're still covering those
cases elsewhere.
XC tests will wait
until your app delegates did
finish launching method returns
before it begins running tests.
If you're using an environment
variable here, do check that the
code you skip is truly
nonessential for your unit tests
to run properly.
If you're mocking out or
skipping network calls entirely,
you need to make sure you're
covering those cases along with
realistic network types
somewhere else in the
development process, and to do
that, we need to consider what a
good testing model looks like.
Earlier this week in the testing
and Xcode session, we heard
about the Pyramid model as a
guide for how to structure a
maintainable automation test
suite.
A good testing model balances
thoroughness, quality, and
execution speed and consists of
a large number of focused unit
tests.
These are where it's okay to
optimize for fast execution
times, and because we want to
isolate features here, it's okay
to run these in clean room
conditions.
You might be using these to look
for functional regressions.
These are complemented by a
smaller number of integration
tests targeting a discrete set
of classes in your app.
Integration tests check that
your app's subsystems work
together from the perspective of
a user.
Since these test results will
more closely reflect real-world
use, they may come with an
increase variance.
So you should be prepared to
triage the failure reasons in
more depth and not just consider
these tests flaky.
And finally, the suite is topped
off with user interface tests or
UI tests, which exercise the app
in a way very similar to how
users would interact with it.
This is your place to validate
that all the pieces of your app
are hooked up and interact
correctly with external
resources like the network.
So this is where your most
representative tests might be.
At the same time, this is where
you might see the highest
variance in your results, and
because of that, it might feel
tempting to place more focus on
unit tests, and that might lead
you into a false sense of
security about your app's
behavior.
When applied well, this testing
model can provide a
comprehensive picture of how
your app's code base is
functioning.
This is great for the testing
coverage enables you to do, but
you need to be mindful of the
testing you might be leaving out
in your integration and UI
suites.
Putting your focus entirely on
unit testing comes with clean
room conditions, and while that
helps you find regressions, you
might be leaving out real-world
behavior that you can make
progressions under for your
users.
Now, it's easy to fall into the
habit of clean room testing
because it gives us many of the
qualities we like to see,
repeatable results, low
variance.
These translate into reduced
test flakiness.
Now we want your functionality
and performance wins to
translate into the real world,
so you're going to need the
right developer tools that also
have these qualities.
Variance can be a consequence of
realism, and it deserves the
same attention you would give to
testing and triaging those tough
edge case in your source.
As you apply the Pyramid model
to different parts of your
development workflow, you'll
find the right places to create
quality checkpoints that work
for you and your team, like
making sure that all unit tests
pass before you merge, so you
can find regressions early.
Now, while integration and UI
tests might not fit in well as
an early checkpoint because of
the variance that's incurred
when you bring in real-world
conditions, they must still have
a place in your process.
If you make sure you're running
them at appropriate times,
you'll be able to characterize
your app's behavior and find
areas of improvement and
behavioral progressions that you
can make.
So, now that we've made room for
real-world conditions, you can
bring back and focus on the
testing you might have skipped
earlier, like those network
ones.
So, we've seen some approaches
to do this like using custom
routers that condition the
network infrastructure, and this
can be really successful when
done right.
But this can also be really
difficult to do, especially if
you're a developer just starting
out.
Even with a good testing model
and a strong focus on triage, to
conduct real-world testing,
you'll need good and reliable
developer tools.
So, if you're targeting macOS
with your app, you should
download and use the Network
Link Conditioner Preference
pane.
You can use it to vary the
network type and see how your
app behaves under networks like
3G or EDGE.
The Network Link Conditioner is
available on iOS from the
developer settings menu on
devices that you're using for
development.
From here, you can vary the
network type between contended
or more representative presets
and design your app for them
without the need to set up or
change the network
infrastructure.
This is a reliable and
repeatable device supported way
to run your app under different
networks.
And if you have custom needs,
you can also create customized
presets for specific types of
bandwidth, packet loss, and
latency that you would like to
design for.
This is great to check how your
app behaves in specific
environments.
In Xcode 11, we've brought the
ability to activate and vary
different network types to the
devices and simulators window so
that you can start easily and
reliably including realism in
your design process.
You'll see a new device
condition section on the lower
part of the window.
From here, you can put your
device into a more
representative state.
If you want a network link,
you'll see all of the network
types from earlier as well as
new profiles to vary the network
quality itself.
This means you can have your
device and your app behave as if
it's running on networks like 2G
or EDGE, 3G or LTE, or different
types of Wi-Fi.
You can even choose the quality
of the network type like a good
EDGE network or an average 3G
one.
Now, people do use connections
like these, so I hope you find
it helpful to see how your apps
work with them too and look for
where you can find behavioral
progressions.
Once you've picked a condition
you want to activate, click
start from the devices window.
Now, these conditions are system
wide, so you can expect
everything to start reacting
differently, including your app.
On devices which have conditions
active, you'll see a new gray
status indicator.
Although activating a network
type affects the whole system,
the UI indicators for your
network will remain unchanged.
You should also know that an
activated network condition is a
ceiling or a cap on your network
type, and it cannot upgrade your
network performance from where
it actually is in the real
world.
From the device, if you tap the
gray status icon, you'll see a
prompt telling you about the
active condition as well as an
option to stop it, and if your
device is disconnected from
Xcode, the condition is
automatically stopped.
To show you how you can use
network link device conditions
to find areas of progression in
your app, I'm going to bring
Ilya back on stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; We often expect our apps to
behave slightly worse on a
slightly worse network link.
But it's important for you to be
asking yourselves whether the
behavior is as bad as it really
needs to be.
Could it be better?
Are there progression we could
make under an adverse or
different network.
Here's a mind-blowing example
app.
We can launch this to look at
baseline behavior for a network
connection with an ideal lab
condition.
This app probes an endpoint we
set up just for this demo to see
how long it takes to make the
connection.
We see that on average this
connection takes around 150
milliseconds.
We can think of this as
analogous to something like
requiring secure login or
streaming content from a
website.
And this looks great.
If we're doing UI testing in our
lab, we would assume that
everything is working smoothly,
and we have no problems.
Now let's see what happens if we
turn on the Network Link
Conditioner from the Xcode
devices window.
This is an average 3G network
connection in this example.
Let's see what happens now.
When we run the probe again, we
see it takes longer, in this
case, on average around a little
over 750 milliseconds.
This might not be all that
surprising because after all a
3G network is slower when
compared to something like LTE
or Wi-Fi.
But the important thing to note
is as we said before this is the
actual network many of your
users will see.
What can we do to improve this
experience for them?
So you probably noticed just
above the run probe button we
have these two switches which
are disabled for Optimistic DNS and
TLS 1.3.
Let's turn them on and see what
happens.
And now as we turn them on and
run the probe again, we see an
immediate improvement, around 33
percent faster.
Simply by testing this app with
the Network Link Conditioner
active, we explicitly noted that
there is a significant
performance loss when we have a
slower network like 3G or when
compared to a faster one like
Wi-Fi or LTE.
This told us that we should take
into account these new features
and use them to proactively
improve performance even under
realistic network conditions.
By running Network Link
Conditioner, you'll notice some
behaviors are worse than they
need to be whereas previously
you might not have.
Here are just a few things you
can do to proactively improve
the overall experience.
First, do set reasonable
timeouts.
That is, timeout when you stop
making progress, not just when
progress takes too long.
As we said before, if your users
are at 3G network, you might be
happy to wait longer for content
to load.
An arbitrary timeout will be a
worse user experience for them.
Additionally, do use HTTP/2 and
do avoid reachability checks
whenever possible.
Instead, just try to use a
network and do what you can to
make sure your app works well
under as many network conditions
as possible.
To learn more about what else
you can do, please see these two
sessions from last year's WWDC
as well as Advances in
Networking parts one and two
from earlier this week.
&gt;&gt; So, get conditioning.
You want to start considering
real-world network usage in your
app.
You want to use network link
device conditions to
characterize your app's behavior
under that usage and ask
yourselves, is this acceptable
performance or can it be better.
We recommend that you test with
at least 3G networks and look
for the progressions that you
can make.
You want to vary both the
network type and its quality to
see if you're still providing a
good experience and then you can
lock in those performance wins
by making this a part of your
integration and UI test runs.
Now, I want to talk about
varying temperatures.
People like to go outdoors and
use their devices on a sunny
day.
They might head to coffee shops
and use personal hotspot while
iPhone is wirelessly charging.
In these situations, devices
will start to feel warmer, and
that's normal behavior.
Some thermal conditions can
cause iOS devices to change
their behavior or performance in
order to regulate their
temperature.
And temperature can vary for any
number of reasons, whether it's
an increase in work done by the
device or environmental effects
like exposure to direct sunlight
and many more.
All of these are normal
scenarios, and iOS subsystems
react to changing temperatures
to regulate the impact of those
effects.
But what's missing is for your
app to work well under changing
temperatures and how you react
to them too.
Now, when certain thresholds are
exceeded, for example, if the
device is left in a hot car for
a prolonged time, users might
see this temperature warning
screen.
At this point, they can no
longer interact with your apps.
Part of the reason this happens
is to provide users with the
crucial ability to make
emergency calls should they need
to do so.
Now, the system is doing what it
can to limit its energy impact,
which effects heat and battery
life, and your app is a resident
of the system as well, and it's
important that you take into
account its energy impact too.
To do this, you can start
changing your app's behavior
dynamically when you're in a
different thermal state.
By designing defensively, you
can reduce your app's energy
impact by turning off background
work, which contributes to
higher thermal states.
You can register for thermal
state change notifications and
look up which state the device
reports to your app and consider
scenarios that are normal like
device warming, because the
system knows how it should react
to an increase in temperature.
But your app knows more details
about the work it's doing and
how that work should react to a
higher thermal state while
maintaining a good experience.
So, let's take a look at these
thermal states that you might
see reported.
At the nominal state, the device
is at normal operating
temperatures, and there's no
need for any corrective action
from your app.
At the first state, we recommend
that you proactively start some
energy saving measures so that
you're not contributing
significantly to an overall
increase.
When iOS sees thermal state
fair, we start to pause
discretionary background work
like photos analysis.
When the device reports a
serious thermal state, system
performance will be impacted,
and your app should start
stronger energy saving measures
and reduce heavy CPU usage,
graphics, and I/O.
At this point, you should use
lower quality visual effects.
Some measures we take on the
system include lowering the
frame rate of ARKit apps and
Facetime so that they're less
intensive.
And if a user is restoring from
an iCloud backup, they'll find
that it will be paused at this
state until the device cools
down.
And at thermal state critical,
your app should stop using
peripherals such as the camera.
If you're ending up on the top
of the list on the battery
impact screen, users might even
consider deleting your app.
Together with the system, your
app should dynamically react to
these changes so that you can
continue to maintain a good
experience while keeping your
energy impact low.
To learn more about the state
cases and our recommendations,
you can take a look at our
documentation.
And Ilya is now going to show
you how you can dynamically
react to these states in an
example.
&gt;&gt; I'm going to show you a
sample ARKit app based on a
modified version of our existing
sample code handling 3D
interaction and UI controls in
augmented reality.
I took it for a stroll in Apple Park
and it's performing some heavy
background work too.
Here you'll see the app running
under nominal conditions.
You can see the red focus square
turn solid, finding a
surface, and letting me drop a
nice chair and a lamp for myself
to sit in and do some reading.
Now you can see the camera
movement is quite smooth.
Everything stays in place.
Everything is behaving just like
it should be.
Now, let's look at this same app
again, but now I've been outside
for a long time.
I've been sitting in the sun.
It's warm out, and the device
has warmed up.
You'll notice two things.
First, the frame rate is not
quite as good as before, and
second is that despite the fact
that I'm aiming almost straight
at the ground, the focus square
does not have time to find a
surface.
This would not be a great
experience for your users, and
it might be a little frustrating
for them.
So, what can we do about this?
First, you should register for
the ProcessInfo.theremalStateDid
ChangeNotification.
When you receive a thermal state
change notification, read the
actual thermal state and then
react accordingly.
Depending on your state, you
should enable or disable certain
features to ensure smooth
functionality or whatever metric
you find is important.
Here's an example of how you can
register for the thermal state
and then read the thermal state.
And here is how you might choose
to react to the thermal state.
In this scenario, under nominal
and fair, I have all my features
enabled.
In this example, I have face
tracking, person segmentation,
and motion blur all turned on.
As the thermal state increases
to serious, I disable face
tracking and frame semantics,
but I leave motion blur on.
And at critical, I turn off
everything.
Now that we actually react to
thermal states, let's see how
this app behaves again in the
same scenario where we've been
outside for a long time, and we
see it's much better now.
The focus square finds a
surface.
I can drop my chair and my lamp
just like before, and I can get
some reading done.
Now, it's good to code
defensively and to react to
thermal state changes, but you
want to know ahead of time if
this works as you expect.
In general, we can do better by
testing how we expect our app to
behave under varying
temperatures ahead of time.
In other words, you should test
your defenses.
But for something like this, how
do we even go about that?
&gt;&gt; Thanks Ilya.
But the thing is, not all of us
are going to have access to
thermal imaging.
So, just like with network
conditions, we recognize the
challenge in trying to verify
your app's behavior and that
there's high variance in
existing approaches.
We've noticed some methods that
people are taking which we would
not recommend like running a
dummy CPU load to warm the
device, throwing away the first
hour of results, and then
profiling app behavior when the
device is hot.
So, we've been hard at work to
provide a developer tool for
this, and we came up with a way
to reliably change the reported
thermal state on the device
without physically warming it
and still keeping it safe to
use.
And we built that way into
device conditions in Xcode 11.
From the same devices and
simulators window, you can
activate elevated temperature
conditions and have your device
reach different thermal states
without it needing to be
physically warm.
So now, you can quickly and
easily have your device report
the fair state, to test your
proactive energy-saving
measures.
Thermal state serious, to check
that you're reliably lowering
your resource usage and energy
impact, and thermal state
critical, to see that your use
of peripherals do actually stop.
Running one of these causes the
device to behave exactly as if
it were really in that thermal
state, but before you start
using these, there's more you
need to know about how they work
on your device.
Ilya.
&gt;&gt; Thanks Alex.
I'm going to show you more about
how this condition works under
the hood.
You can see a graph here
representing the actual thermal
state of the device, the active
condition if there is any, and
how warm the device actually
feels to the touch, also
represented by a thermometer at
the top right.
Imagine a baseline device on
your desk.
It's at room temperature.
You have no condition active,
and you haven't been using it
for a while.
Here, the thermal state is at
nominal.
If you now activate the serious
thermal profile, the device will
ramp up over time to serious
starting from nominal, reaching
fair, and eventually reaching
serious.
This process will take a few
seconds.
Just like in real life, if you
are subscribed to thermal state
notifications, you'll receive a
notification at fair and at
serious.
Now, there are two important
things to note about this.
The first is that your devices
has not actually warmed up or
changed in temperature as a
result.
The second is that this does not
fix your thermal state, but it
rather acts like a floor.
Let me explain what that means.
Imagine you have your device in
this condition, and you ran some
heavy computational load, or you
just left it out in the sun for
a while.
And now the underlying
temperature is actually
increased.
The device feels warm to the
touch.
Regardless of why, the thermal
state will actually also
increase from serious to
critical.
This is a precaution to ensure
your system still behaves safely
even if you do very heavy
testing under the thermal
condition.
If you then stop using your
device or let it cool down, the
thermal state will return back
down to serious and remain there
until you tear down the
condition, at which point, the
device will ramp from serious to
fair and down to nominal.
In all these situations, you
will receive thermal state user
notifications.
In Xcode 11, this thermal state
information is visible in an
energy gauge in the debugging
navigator.
There are two thermal state
tracks here, both located toward
the bottom of the energy impact
section.
The bottommost track shows the
actual thermal state of the
device, color coded for easy
interpretation.
Here, you can see the thermal
state ramping up and then down
in reaction to the active
condition.
You can see in this scenario it
took around 10 seconds in each
direction.
The top track shows the active
thermal device condition, if
there is one.
To show you more about debugging
and optimizing with Xcode and
what tools you have at your
disposal, I'm going to call Jay
on stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
I'm Jay. I'm part of the Energy
TechnologyTteam in Core OS, and
I'm here to show you how an app
behaves when the device is
thermally constrained and what
can you do about it.
For the purpose of the demo,
we're going to use a modified
version of the Fox 2 app that's
a publicly released sample for
SceneKit from a few years back.
Let's get started.
I have a device that's running
the app without any thermal
condition active.
Let's see how it loads.
This is how the app looks.
First, let's look at the bottom
left corner of the screen.
That's the FPS.
We can look the FPS is
consistently hitting more than
30.
Let's look at the details on the
app.
There's a nice vignetting around the app for
a cinematic effect.
Let's look at all the details
inside the app.
There's just tons of details.
If you look at the green
gem on the right side,
there's a light source on top of
it, and it's doing a great
shadow.
If you look at the moving
objects, they have light sources
coming out of them, and they're
doing great shadows on the fox
as well.
Let's look at the lava.
There's smoke coming out of it,
and the GPU is doing a
great job of blending in with
the background.
There's a lot of tiny fire
particles coming out as well.
This is a great user experience.
Users really like to use apps
like these.
If you're running performance
tests, they're going to be all
green.
Let's switch gears and see what
happens when you run a thermal
condition.
I have another device running
the same app but with a serious
thermal condition active, and
let's see what happens.
I'm going to switch over to the
device.
Now, if you look at the bottom
left corner of the screen, the
FPS is down to 17.
We lost almost half of our
performance.
If you look at the moving
objects, there aren't as
buttery smooth as they were
before.
If you look at the moving
platforms or the moving rocks,
they aren't as smooth as they
were before.
What can we do to fix this?
We went ahead and we modified
the app to listen for changes in
thermal state.
Whenever the thermal state
changes, the app is going to
respond dynamically and reduce
the features it supports.
Let's see how that works.
I have a small debug UI on the
top that can switch it from
being static or dynamic, and I'm
going to switch it to be dynamic
now.
If you look at the bottom screen
now, we're close to 20 FPS
again.
The scene looks similar, but we
got rid of some of the details.
We got rid of the smoke coming
out of the lava.
We reduced the fire particles a
bit, but you can see, the
response of the app is still
great.
That's what we're looking for.
Now, let's look at the code
changes we had to do to make
this happen.
When you're at nominal or fair,
we don't have to do anything.
You can enable all of the
features on the app.
We have HDR.
We have depth of field.
We have soft shadows, and we
also have the post processing
set to high.
As soon as you hit serious, we
start doing something.
We react by disabling HDR.
We also turn the shadows from
soft to blob.
We also set the post-processing
to medium.
When we are at critical, we go
even further.
Critical is a very high thermal
state, and we disable as many
features as we can.
We disabled HDR.
We disabled depth of field.
We disabled shadows, and we also
turned on post processing.
All of this is going to help to
keep the app responsive at all
times.
Now, let's look at some tools
that we can use for tuning for
thermals.
This is an instrument stack
taken on the same app with and
without any optimizations.
Both have been captured with a
serious thermal condition
active.
Let's look at the FPS track.
This is the time display was
shown in the same frame.
Let's decode it a bit.
When the display is showing one
frame, the GP is working on
rendering the next one, and the
CP is working on creating the
instructions for the one coming
even after that.
What happens is when, and
without any optimizations what
happens is that the GP is not
able to deliver frames in time,
and the display keeps showing
the same frame.
This is what a stutter looks
like.
This is when your app is
lagging.
If you notice, after the
optimizations, the frames are
spaced consistently.
Apart from using instruments,
you should also be using the
Xcode energy gauge.
You should focus your attention
to the average energy impact
your app has.
The higher the energy impact,
the higher the battery drain and
the higher the chances of your
app causing a rise in the
thermal state.
If you look at without
optimizations, we had a very
high energy impact, but with the
optimizations enabled, we were
able to lower the energy impact.
What that means is the app is
not going to contribute to a
rise in the thermal state when
the device is running the app.
Back to Alex and Ilya for a
recap.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jay.
If you want to learn more about
debugging in Xcode as well as
other things you can do to bring
real-world scenarios to your
development process, such as
environment overrides, please
take a look at this session from
earlier this week.
&gt;&gt; So, we heard about real-world
conditions that people will be
using your apps under, like 3G
networks or elevated temperature
states.
And we heard about the
importance of providing the best
experience truly possible in
those states.
We heard about how a typical
development and testing workflow
might natural steer you towards
clean room in an attempt to
avoid flaky tests and variance.
And we heard about the new
device conditions in Xcode 11,
which lets to you quickly and
easily put your test devices in
adverse network or temperature
states.
That means no more waiting an
hour for devices to actually
warm up and no more throwing
away test results.
This is a great way to ensure
the code that you're designing
and all the great performance
and features that come with it
translate into progression for
your users in the real world.
So, to recap, do use the Test
Pyramid model for organizing
your automation test suites and
be prepared to triage your
results as you introduce
real-world conditions to your
testing.
Only skip truly unnecessary code
in your unit testing.
And there's a call to action
here.
Don't forget to take your
conditioners with you.
Do activate a device condition,
see how your app behaves, and
add test runs to find that
egregious behavior that you
might have missed.
We recommend, again, that you do
test with at least the 3G
network type of varying quality,
see how your app behaves in the
serious thermal state too.
We are really excited to see
what progressions you can make
with the device conditions we've
made available.
And we'd love to hear from you.
Contact developer support or
come to the Xcode labs right
after this session.
And for more information, see
our session link.
Thank you so much and we hope
you have a great WWDC.
[ Applause ]