[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone, my name is
Spencer Lewson, and I'm an
engineer on the Performance Team
here at Apple.
Today I'm very excited to tell
you about how you can optimize
your app's launch.
We'll be covering these four
main topics today.
First, what is launch?
What are the different types of
launches and how do we break
them down into their different
subphases?
Next, we'll be talking about how
to properly measure your app's
launch.
Out in the field, iOS devices
can be in a variety of different
states and conditions, and these
states and conditions can
produce inconsistent launch
results.
So, it's important to understand
these states and how to reduce
their impact when you're taking
measurements.
Once you've done that, you can
take a look at how to use
Instruments to profile and
understand your app to find
opportunities to improve it.
And finally, we'll leave you
with some tips and some tricks on how
to monitor your app's launch,
both over time and in the field,
to ensure that you consistently
deliver a delightful experience
to all of your users.
So, what is that app launch I
was talking about?
Well, app launch is a user
experience interruption.
What do I mean by this?
Let's take a look.
Okay, ready, set, go.
Wow, on the iPhone 6S Plus,
launch took nearly 2.5 seconds,
and this wasn't as delightful as
our users expect it to be.
You know, it's really important
for launch to be delightful,
because it happens a lot.
In fact, across all iOS devices,
it happens billions of times a
day.
So, we did some number
crunching, and we figured out
that with we save only one
millisecond on each of those
launches, we would save an
astounding 162 days of launch
time, yes, in other words,
[applause] thank you, in other
words, that's the amount of time
it takes to send a rocket to
Mars.
But it's also important for a
number of other reasons.
First of all, your app's launch
is your user, first experience
with your app, and as such, it
should be delightful.
Now it's important to remember
that as developers, we tend to
gravitate towards newer devices.
So, it's important to ensure
that the experience that you see
in your hand is the same
experience that the customers,
that your users, have in their
hands on different iOS devices
and under different conditions.
Furthermore, launch covers a
huge part of your code base,
from primer coating, to
initialization, to view
creation, and more.
And as such, if you're seen that
your launch isn't as delightful
as your users expected to be,
this might be indicative that
there's other parts of your code
base that are delightful, as
well.
Finally, launch is a very
intense time for the phone.
Involves a lot of CPU work and a
lot of memory work.
So, you should try to reduce
this as it impacts the system
performance, and of course, your
user's battery life.
So, let's take a look at those
launches I talked about before,
there's a cold launch, a warm
launch, and something is often
referred to as launch, but isn't
quite a launch, a resume.
Cold launches occur after
reboot, or when your app has not
been launched for very long
time.
In order to launcher app, we
need to bring it from disk into
memory, startup system-side
services that support your app,
and then spawn your process.
As you'd expect, this can take a
little time, but fortunately,
once it's happened once, you'll
experience a warm launch.
In this case, your app still
needs to be spawned, but we've
already brought your app into
memory and started up some of
those system-side services.
So, this will be a little bit
faster and a little bit more
consistent.
Finally, there's that resume.
This occurs when a user reenters
your app from either the home
screen or the app switcher.
As you know, the app is already
launched at this point, so it's
going to be very fast.
What you need to remember from
this is not to confuse resumes
with launches when you're taking
measurements.
So, given this information,
wouldn't it be great if launches
were as quick and as delightful
as resumes?
How can we achieve that?
Well, we need to hit the goal of
rendering our first frame within
400 milliseconds.
That's so that we have pixels
displayed to the user during the
launch animation, and by the
time that launch animation is
complete, your app is
interactive and responsive.
The first step to doing that is
understanding what is happening
during launch.
So, let's launch Maps.
As you know, launch generally
starts when the user taps your
icon on your home screen.
Then over the next 100 or so
milliseconds, iOS will do the
necessary system-side work in
order to initialize your app.
That leaves you as developers
about 300 milliseconds to create
your views, load your content,
and generate your first frame.
Now this frame doesn't
necessarily need to be fully
complete.
It can have some placeholders
for asynchronously loading data,
but at this point, your app
should be interactive and
responsive.
So, in the case of Maps, all the
tiles have not yet loaded.
You can still initiate your
search and browse your
favorites.
Then over the next couple
hundred milliseconds, you can
display that asynchronously
loaded data and generate your
final frame for your user.
Let's take a closer look at
these phases.
These six phases cover
everything from system
initialization to the app
initialization to view creation
and layout, and then depending
on your app, potentially a
asynchronous loading phase for
your data, the extended phase.
The first half of system
interface is dyld.
For those of you unfamiliar, a
dynamic linker loads your shared
libraries and frameworks.
Now in 2017, we introduced dyld
3, which added exciting
optimizations to the system.
Well, we're happy to announce
that in iOS 13, we're bringing
these optimizations to your
apps.
That means we are now caching
your runtime dependencies, or
warm launches, which should give
them a significant speed
improvement [applause].
Thank you.
Now with a new linker, comes
some new recommendations.
To take full advantage of these
new improvements, we recommend
that you avoid linking unused
frameworks, as this can have
hidden costs, which we'll show
you later.
We also recommend that you avoid
dynamic library loading, such as
DLOpen or NSbundleLoad, because
this forfeits those wins you
would have gotten by having
those in your cache.
Finally, that means that you
should be hard linking all of
your dependencies, as it's now
even faster than it was before.
The second half of system
interface is libSystemInit.
This is when we initialize the
low-level system components
within your application.
Now this is mostly system-side
work with a fixed cost.
So, use developers don't need to
focus on the section.
Now we have static runtime
initialization.
This is when the system
initializes your Objective-C and
Swift run times.
Now in general, your app
shouldn't be doing any work here
unless you have static
initializer methods, which are
possibly present in your code,
or more likely, a surprise from
the frameworks that you link.
In general, we don't recommend
static initialization.
So, let's take a moment to talk
about how to reduce its impact.
If you own a framework which
uses static initialization,
consider exposing API to
initialize your stack early.
But if you must use static
initialization, consider moving
code out of class load which is
invoked every time during launch
to class initialize, which is
lazily invoked the first time
you use a method within your
class.
Next up is UIKit Initialization.
This is when the system
instantiates your UIApplication
and your UIApplicationDelegate.
For the most part, this is
system-side work, setting up
event processing and integration
with the system.
But you can still effect this
phase if you subclass
UIApplication or you do any work
in UIApplicationDelegate
initializers.
Now we have application
initialization.
This is where the good stuff is.
This is where you as developers
can likely have the biggest
impact on your app's
launch.
For those of you who have not
yet adopted the new UIC in APIs
or are targeting iOS 12 or
earlier, Application Init works,
again, with these delegate
call-back methods.
application:
willFinishLaunchingwithOptions,
and application:
didFinishLaunchingwithOptions.
As your app is displayed to the
user, the further methods,
applicationDidBecomeActive: will
be invoked.
Now it's important to know that
if you have not UIScenes, you
should be creating your view
controllers and
didFinishLaunchingwithOptions.
That's because with UIScene,
ApplicationInit works a little
bit differently.
Now you will still get
willFinishLaunching and
didFinishLaunchingwithOptions,
but as your app is displayed to
the user, you will get the
UISceneDelegate lifecycle
callbacks.
Those are, of course scene:
willConnectwithSession with
options.
ScenewillEnterForeground, and
sceneDidBecomeActive.
You should be creating your view
controllers, and scene:
willConnecttoSessionwithOptions.
It's important to note that you
should be only creating your
view controllers, and scene:
willConnectToSessionwithOptions,
and that also, and
didFinishLaunchingwithOptions.
That the common pitfall, which,
of course, results in
performance losses and, likely,
unpredictable bugs in your code
base.
Regardless of whether or not
you've adopted the new UIScene
APIs, our advice for this phase
is generally the same.
You should be deferring any
unrelated work but it's not
necessary to commit your first
frame, by either pushing it to
the background queues or just
doing it later entirely.
If you did adopt UIScenes, you
can do one more thing, and
that's make sure that you're
sharing your resources between
your Scenes.
This is, of course, to reduce
the overhead of doing any work
unnecessarily multiple times.
To learn more about UIScenes,
please take a look at these two
talks from earlier this week.
Next is the first frame render
phase.
Now, this is relatively
straightforward.
This is when we create your
views, perform layout, and then
draw them.
We then take that information,
and we commit and render your
first frame into nice, shiny
pixels.
You can affect this phase by
reducing the number of views in
your hierarchy.
And you can do that by
flattening your views to use
less or by lazily loading views
that are not shown during
launch.
You should also take a look at
your auto layout and see if you
can reduce the number of
constraints you're using.
Finally, we have the extended
phase.
This is the app-specific period
from your first commit until
when you show your final frame
to your user.
This is when you load that
asynchronous data we talked
about.
Now not every app has this
phase.
But if you do have this phase,
your app should be interactive
and responsive.
If you do have this phase, we
only have general advice on how
you should approach it, and that
is to understand what is
happening, and you can do that
by leveraging OS signpost APIs
to mark out and measure the work
that occurs in between these two
time periods.
Now that we talked about what
launch is, let's talk about how
to get usable measurements.
At any given time, an iOS device
is under a variety of different
states and conditions, and this
can introduce substantial
variance into launch.
So, when we're analyzing and
comparing our launch results,
it's critical to ensure that
we're making apples-to-apples
comparisons, because how do you
know if you're making any
progress if before you make any
changes, your launch results are
completely unpredictable?
The first step to making them
predictable is removing those
sources of variance, such as
networking interference and
interference in background
processes.
Now we realize that this sounds
counterintuitive, as this may
result in a launch that's not
entirely representative of
regular usage, but we wanted to
let you know that that's okay.
It's more important to have
consistent results with which
you can evaluate progress.
At Apple, we've been using this
technique to successfully detect
regressions during development
and drive down launch times.
We then validate these
performance improvements by
using telemetry collected from
the field.
Fortunately, we have some tips
on setting up that clean and
consistent environment.
First, reboot your device.
This will clear out any
unnecessary state, and then let
it settle down over the next few
minutes to clear up any boot
time work.
You could also reduce your
dependence on the network by
either turning on airplane mode
or marking out your network
dependencies in code.
Networking can introduce a fair
amount of variance.
Next is iCloud.
ICloud is a great feature which
works in the background to
deliver a seamless experience to
our users, but that work in the
background can interfere with
app launch.
So, during your measurements,
using unchanging iCloud account
with unchanging data, or log out
of iCloud entirely.
Next be sure to use the release
build of your application when
you're making measurements.
This is, of course, to reduce
the overhead of unnecessary
debugging code during your
measurements and to take
advantage of the compile time
optimizations.
Finally, you should be measuring
with warm launches, which as
mentioned before, are more
consistent, because some of your
app may already be in memory,
and some of those system-side
services may already be running.
Now we can set up some data to
test with.
It's important to create a mock
data set which is consistent,
and you might need a couple data
sets for different types of
users, such as users with small
amounts of data and users with
large amounts of data, though,
in the ideal situation, your app
should be able to scale to any
amount of data.
That's why loading only the data
that is necessary to show your
first frame.
Now we're ready to pick out some
devices.
You should pick out a variety of
devices that are important to
your users and then stick to
them force consistency.
Be sure to include your oldest
devices for your
oldest-supported releases.
This is because performance
characteristics look different
between older devices and newer
devices, which have different
amounts of RAM and CPU cores.
This will ensure that your
launch is delightful for all of
your users on all of their
devices.
Now we're ready to take some
measurements.
We can leverage the new XCTest
for app launce performance in
Xcode 11.
With just a few lines of code,
Xcode will launch your app
repeatedly and then provide
statistical results about how it
performs.
We'll talk about this more
later.
So, now we've talked about what
launch is and how to measure it,
let's talk a little bit about
how to improve it.
When you're reviewing your app's
launch both in code and in
instruments, you should keep
these three tips and tricks in
mind.
That is to first minimize your
work, then prioritize your work,
and finally, optimize your work.
When minimizing work, you should
be deferring anything unrelated
to generating the first frame.
That means deferring things like
undisplayed views or pre-warming
features that are not yet used.
You should also avoid blocking
the main thread, either with
network I/O, file I/O, or more,
as this will affect launch.
Move it to a background thread.
Finally, you should take care to
reduce your memory usage.
Allocating and manipulating
memory can take time.
Next, prioritize your work.
This is when you should make
sure that work is scheduled at
the right quality of service.
Now in iOS 13, we've made some
exciting optimizations to the
Scheduler to make your apps
launch even faster.
But that means it's more
critical than ever to preserve
priority issue propagate work
across threads.
You should take a look at
Modernizing Grand Central
Dispatch Usage from WW 2017,
which goes into depth about how
to handle concurrency correctly.
Finally, we have optimizing
work.
Anything that's remaining after
you've minimized it and
prioritized it should be
optimized.
That is to say it should be
simplified and limited.
For example, limit the amount of
data that you fetch only what
you need during launch, or
lazily compute any variables and
results that you need.
When you're doing this, take a
look at your methods and
algorithms and see if you can
optimize them, as you could get
significant improvements by
calculating a result differently
or using a different data
structure.
And finally, you should be
caching your resources and your
complications.
This is, of course, to reduce
the CPU and memory overhead by
doing work multiple times
unnecessarily.
So, I'd love to hand the stage
over to Dan, who is going to
give you a great demo on how to
use the new App Launch Template
in Xcode Instruments to
understand and improve our app's
launch.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Spencer.
Hi, everyone, my name is Dan
Sawada, and I'm also one of the
performance engineers here at
Apple.
Today I will be going over a
typical workflow of
understanding your app's launch
and looking for opportunities to
minimize, prioritize, and
optimize the work, so that you
can actually deliver a
delightful first user
experience.
So, let's get started.
The app that I'm going to be
demonstrating today is called
Star Searcher.
It's an example app that we
specifically written for this
session.
As you can see, it's a very
typical UI table view that lists
all of my imaginary stars.
If you click on the cell, or a
star, it shows you a little
description blurb, in addition
to a picture.
However, we have one problem,
let's go ahead and launch it.
Ready, go.
So, that took an astounding 2.5
seconds to launch, not sure if I
could call that delightful.
So, let's use Xcode and
Instruments to see if there's
anything we can do about this.
So, here we have our Xcode
project for Star Searcher.
Now one important thing that we
should do before we do any
performance-related analysis is
selecting the profile scheme in
Xcode.
This will ensure Xcode to
recompile your app in release
mode, so that you can take the
advantages of compiler time
optimizations.
Once Xcode recompiles your app,
it will install it on your
device and launch Instruments.
Now we are happy to announce
that as of iOS 13, or Xcode 11,
we now have the
AppLaunchTemplate, which we can
use specifically for triage
purposes like this, figuring out
what's wrong with AppLaunch.
So, let's go ahead and
double-click on AppLaunch.
Now the first thing we want to
do here is hit the record
button.
At this point, Instruments will
automatically launch Star
Searcher, our app, gather all of
the metrics, telemetry data,
analyze them, and create
visualizations for all of the
app launch phases.
So, with take a look.
The first few phases marked in
purple are the phases that occur
before your main function is
invoked within your app.
Onto the green phases, these
phases of the early phases that
occur at the very first of your
main function, as your app
finishes its launch and draws
its first frame in UI.
Let's go ahead and expand the
lanes.
As we expand the lanes, you can
see the detailed states of all
of the threads that respond
within your app's process.
Obviously, the most important
one would be the main thread, or
also known as the UI thread,
which is responsible for handing
user input and drawing your UI.
Let's go ahead and pin down the
lanes that are relevant for our
purpose, starting with the app
launch phases, our main thread,
and there's one more worker
thread that's doing a
substantial amount of work
during launch.
So, let's go ahead and pin this
down, too.
Speaking of thread states --
oops.
Like that.
Speaking of thread states, gray
means it's blocked, meaning that
the thread isn't doing any work.
Red means it's runnable, meaning
that there's work scheduled to
be done, but lacking CPU
resources.
Orange means it's preempted,
meaning that it was doing work
but got interrupted in favor of
other competing work that has a
higher priority.
And last but not least, blue
means it's running, meaning that
it's actually doing work on the
CPU core.
So, with that information, let's
take a look phase by phase
starting with the system
interface initialization.
As we triple-click on a phase,
we can highlight the phase and
get detailed information towards
the bottom half of the screen.
To your left, you can see the
detailed stack trace of all the
work that's being done during
this time period.
To your right, you can see a
aggregated stack trace, which
lists all of the symbols ordered
by the number of CPU sample
size.
Now notice that this initial
phase only took 6 milliseconds
as it sets up its system
interfaces.
This is primarily due to the
benefits of dyld3 introduction
and third-party apps, in
addition to other system layer
enhancements.
So, as developers, we can take
advantage of all of those
enhancements without writing a
single line of code.
Let's move on, but before we do
so, there's one other thing I
should point out here.
Notice that while this phase
only spent 6 milliseconds on the
CPU clock for Star Searcher, it
spent 149 milliseconds on the
wall clock.
This discrepancy comes from the
overhead of the profiling
mechanism itself, which does
give us a lot of information and
insight, but has a cost of its
own.
So, this is why it's very
important to distinguish
profiling with measurements,
which I will explain more later
on.
On to the next phase, which is
static runtime initialization.
Now notice this phase took an
astonishing 375 milliseconds.
Now that's a little bit too
long.
So, let's take a look.
Looking at the detailed stack
trace, we see a highlighted
symbol with a blue icon marking
370 milliseconds' worth of work
on the CPU.
Now all of these highlighted
symbols indicate code that's
declared within our sources.
Let's click on it.
Now by expanding the stack
trace, it points us to the
SLSuperfastLogger.
Now, if a library is calling
itself superfast, that implies
some fishiness, but let's take a
look.
So, SLSuperfastLogger is a
external framework that we've
imported specifically into Star
Searcher to take the benefits of
powerful and convenient logging.
However, the only place we
invoke this framework is within
the table view controller.
Specifically, within the
didSelectRowAt callback.
Now this callback is completely
out of the launch path, because
it's only invoked when the user
taps on a cell.
So, why is it doing over 300
milliseconds' worth of work
during early launch and even
before our main function is
invoked?
Well, let's investigate.
By searching the symbol, it
points us to a plus-load method
declared within the SL
SuperfastLogger class.
Now, this is a static
initializer, meaning that all of
this work would be done at very
early in launch before a main
function is invoked, given the
fact that we link against it.
Now, the take away here is that
it's very important to
understand the impact of your
dependencies in the frameworks
that you use.
External libraries and
frameworks may be convenient and
may be powerful, but it may come
with a heavy cost.
So, if those costs justifies the
benefits, great.
But for our case, 300
milliseconds during launch is a
little bit too much for what
it's worth.
So, let's go ahead and pursue
alternatives.
In our case let's use os.log,
which is a very lightweight and
efficient logging mechanism that
comes right with iOS as well as
other Apple platforms.
Now once we remove the
dependency, there's one
additional thing that we
absolutely need to remember to
do, which is to remove the
actual linkage.
Now because the cost here is
with a static initializer, we
need to make sure to remove the
linkage in order for it not to
impact us.
So, with that, let's go back to
our trace.
The next phase is UIKit
initialization, which took 28
milliseconds on the wall clock.
Now this is pretty much a fixed
cost for all applications.
So, unless you subclass UI
application or do a custom
initialization work in
UIApplicationDelegate, it's
pretty much something that we
can disregard for now.
So, let's move on.
The next chunk of work is your
applications initialization,
which is pretty much what you
control.
Now notice there is a big amount
of work being done with
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
callback, which took 791
milliseconds on the wall clock.
Now that's very long.
Let's take a look.
So, this phase immediately
points us to heavy amounts of
work in the StarDataProvider
class.
It says, "loading stars."
Okay, now, notice that there's a
huge blockage in the main
thread, which essentially is a
delay in our launch.
Our main thread was blocked for
754 milliseconds.
Now that's not nice.
Let's take a look.
So, in order to inspect the
detailed states, we should look
at the event list.
By looking at the event list, we
notice that it was blocked for
754 milliseconds, and
afterwards, it was unblocked, or
made runnable, by thread
0x12253.
Now this corresponds to this
worker thread that was doing a
lot of work.
So, there's some relationship
here.
Now going back to the main
thread, notice that it's
scheduled to do work at priority
47.
Forty-seven is equivalent to the
user interactive QoS.
Now look at all this red meeting
there's a lot of work to do, but
it's lacking CPU resources.
Well, let's figure out why.
As we click on the worker
thread, we notice that there's a
lot of work scheduled to do work
at priority 4.
This is equivalent to the
background QoS.
What we're actually seeing here
is a symptom known as priority
inversion, where a given thread
is being blocked by a separate
thread that has a lower QoS, or
priority, than itself.
Obviously, this isn't ideal,
because it's still aimed to
launch more than it should.
So, let's go ahead and try to
fix that.
Looking back at the
StarDataProvider, which is at
the core of this issue, is a
very simple class that's
responsible for fetching data
for our stars from SQLite
database, has a dedicated
dispatch queue with a background
QoS, and note that this is to
ensure that data fetching
doesn't compete with the UI.
And there's two API being
exposed.
One for loading data
asynchronously using this
GrandCentralDispatch's async
primitive and another
synchronous API that loads the
data in a synchronous fashion.
Now looking at the actual call
sites within the
didFinishLaunchingwithOptions,
we are leveraging the
asynchronous API, but also
leveraging the dispatch
semaphore to ensure that we wait
for all of the data to be
fetched before we proceed on to
drawing the actual first frame
of our table view.
Now if we're going to be doing
this, we should use the correct
concurrency primitive, which is
the sync primitive in GCD.
Now using the correct
concurrency primitives,
GrandCentralDispatch will
temporarily propagate the
priority of the main thread to
the worker thread and boost it
up to user inactive so that it
matches.
So, at this point, I think we
have the potential to resolve
the priority inversion, but
there's one more issue that I
notice here.
LoadStarDataSync API accepts a
range of rows to load the data
for.
In our case, we're loading from
row 0 to the very last row,
which is essentially everything.
Now when you think about it, the
first frame can only fit just a
limited number of cells that may
be on the screen size.
In the case of Star Searcher,
perhaps around 10 to 15,
depending on the device.
So, let's go ahead and optimize
that, and instead of loading
everything, let's just load the
first 20 rows, just enough to
draw the first frame of the
table view in a synchronous
fashion.
Afterwards, we should load all
of the rest lazily in the
background and only update the
table view when finished after
launch.
Let's move on.
Back to the trace, last but not
least.
The last phase is our first
frame rendering.
Notice that this phase took 951
milliseconds, which is very
long, considering that this is
only responsible for doing the
layout work and the rendering of
our first frame.
Now let's taking a deeper dive,
it points us to the
StarTableviewController, and
looking at the detailed stack
trace, we see a lot of work and
a CellForRowAt callback, which
is responsible for doing the
layout work of the cells.
let's go ahead and expand that.
As we expand the stack trace, it
points us to a lot of
initialization work for the
StarDetailView controller which
took 882 milliseconds on the
CPU.
So, at this point, we've
identified this is pretty much
the bottleneck here.
Let's take a look at our code.
Now looking at the table view
controller within the
CellforRowAt callback, we create
the cells using our custom cell,
and at the same time, we put in
a speculative optimization which
is to pre-warm and cache the
DetailViewControllers of the
DetailVew, as we do the layout
work.
This is with the hopes to
streamline the transition from a
table view to a detail view.
But as we saw in the trace, this
doesn't create a high cost.
Now stepping back a little bit,
when you think about it, the
detailed view doesn't really
make sense for our first frame.
It only makes sense when the
user taps on a cell.
So, let's go ahead and defer
that work.
Where should we defer it to?
Perhaps the didSelectRowAt
callback, which is invoked when
the user taps on a cell.
So, at this point, we've made
several enhancements, or
optimizations, to Star Searcher.
So, let's go ahead and
re-profile it.
Now one thing to note here is
that as you make incremental
changes, you should consistently
remeasure and re-profile as you
make progress.
That way, you can actually
understand the exact impact of
your incremental change set.
But for the sake of his demo,
we've actually aggregated all
the changes into one for the
sake of time and boom.
There's a little UI glitch, but
we can immediately see that our
launch is under 500
milliseconds.
Now, as I said earlier, the
profiling mechanism does come
with a cost of its own.
So, to get a better
understanding of what our users
would experience, let's go ahead
and leverage the new XCTest APIs
to measure our launch
performance within our test.
With just a few lines of code,
we can actually integrate launch
performance tests, or any
performance tests, with an
XCTest.
Let's go ahead and kick this
off.
Now at this point, XCTest will
do one throwaway launch attempt,
which cancels out the variance
that would come about by cold
launches.
Afterwards, it will do the
specified number of iterations
or by default five iterations of
launches and measure the time it
took.
Afterwards, it will produce a
nice statistics of that data.
It's going to take a few minutes
for the test to complete, and
now we've taken the launch of
Star Searcher from 2.5 seconds
to just over 300 milliseconds.
[ Applause ]
And to wrap up the demo, I'd
like to show you what this
actually looks like on the UI.
So, let's make sure we kill Star
Searcher.
That was quick.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Back to you, Spencer.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Dan, for that awesome
demo on how to use Xcode,
Instruments, AppLaunchTemplate
to improve our app launch
experience.
So, we realize that in your code
bases, you're not going to find
just a few couple places in your
code that you can fix with just
a few lines and get such
substantial improvements.
It's more likely that you're
going to have to find a bunch of
5 to 10 milliseconds wins and
then stack all those together.
We want to let you know that
we've got your back.
We've been making a ton of iOS
optimizations to improve your
app's launch and help you reach
your goal with very little to no
adoption from your side.
I want to call on a few in
particular.
As mentioned before, dyld3
brings caching of your runtime
dependencies to your apps, which
you saw in the demo, that
provided a huge improvement.
The Scheduler has also been
optimized to help prioritize the
work that happens during launch.
We also put Auto Layout and
Objective-C under the microscope
and made a bunch of
optimizations there.
And then finally, we have
exciting changes to app
packaging coming later this
year.
We think that altogether these
changes should result in a huge
improvement your apps with very
little to no adoption.
So, let's wrap things up with
some tips and tricks on how to
make sure your app stays
delightful once you've done all
this work.
First of all, don't let
performance be an afterthought.
You should start working on it
and thinking about it at the
beginning of every bug fix, at
the beginning of every
re-factor, and the beginning of
every feature.
This is because it's incredibly
easy to introduce regression,
especially a little one like 2
milliseconds.
The problem is these little ones
add up to a big problem, and if
you don't address them
immediately, it becomes very
hard to find them all.
In order to do that, to detect
those regressions, you should be
plotting your app's launch over
time and running tests
regularly.
This will ensure that you're
meeting your target and that you
immediately know if you've
regressed from that target.
You should also take a look at
the new Xcode organizer, which
lets you know how your app
performs in the field.
In iOS 13, for users that have
opted in, power and performance
metrics will be gathered about
your app.
They will then be aggregated
over 24-hour periods and sent
back to your organizer where you
can view them in the form of
histograms by software version
and device version.
However, if you desire a little
bit more control over that data,
you can adopt MetricKit.
MetricKit allows you to specify
custom power and performance
metrics.
Now like the organizer, this
data will be gathered up and
aggregated over 24-hour periods
of time and then delivered back
to you through a delegate method
in your app.
From there, you're free to
handle the data as you see fit.
To learn more about this, we
recommend you check out
Improving Battery Life and
Performance from WW 2019.
So, in summary, we'd love for
you today to start understanding
your app's launch with the new
AppLauchTemplate in Xcode
Instruments.
See if you can find
opportunities to minimize,
prioritize, and optimize your
work.
Next, although well intended,
not all optimizations work out,
such as the pre-warming
DetailView controllers that Dan
addressed in his demo.
So, be sure to measure, not
estimate, performance whenever
you're making changes.
Again, it's very easy to
introduce regressions
unintentionally.
Finally, you should be tracking
your performance in all phases
of development.
This means utilizing the new
XCTest app launch measurements
on a variety of devices and
possibly integrating this with
continuous integration.
This will ensure that you're
consistently delivering a
delightful app launch to all of
your users on all of their
devices.
For more information, please
view the talks that we
referenced today, and have a
great rest of your Friday
afternoon.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]