[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
I'm Alex Brown, an Engineer in
Core ML.
And today, we are going to
present Create ML for Object
Detection.
In the What's New in Machine
Learning session, you were
introduced to the new Create ML
app.
It provides a really
approachable way to build custom
machine learning models to add
to your applications.
In this session, we're going to
dig a little deeper into two
specific templates.
Object detection, which works
with images, and sound
classification.
Let's get started with object
detection.
Object detection enables your
application to identify
real-world objects captured by
your device's camera, and
respond based on their presence,
position, and relationship.
You can download object
detectors from the web which
know the difference between
broad categories of objects.
But by training a custom machine
learning model on your own data,
you can teach your application
about the subtle differences
between individual animals, hand
gestures, street signs, or game
tokens.
If you've used machine learning
with Apple before, you may
already be familiar with image
classification.
With image classification, you
build a model which can provide
a single simple description of
an image.
This image we might describe as
outdoors or park, or for a
particular application, dog.
But what if we're interested in
more than one object in the
scene?
In this case, object detection
can come to the rescue.
It can identify multiple objects
within your photograph, and
provide the location, size, and
label for each one.
This can enable your application
to do more sophisticated things
using your camera, but in order
to do that, we need to go into
more detail when teaching the
model about your images.
To train an object detector, you
need to annotate each image with
labeled regions that you would
like the model to recognize.
The bounding box for your
annotated objects starting at
the center of each object of
interest and having a size,
height, and width, this is
measured in pixels from the top
left-hand corner of your image
to the center of each object of
interest.
You bundle together all of these
annotations, label, position,
and size, in a JSON file in the
following format.
You can download tools from the
web to help you build these, but
make sure they use the same
coordinate system the Create ML
app expects.
Once you've assembled your
annotations, simply drop them
into the same folder as the
images they describe, and that's
it.
Your training data is ready.
So now we know how to create
training data for object
detection.
Let's consider a real case.
My colleague, Scott, has got a
great idea for building a math
game that is really engaging for
kids, and uses real-world dice
to provide the questions.
You can hear more about this
application in session 228,
Creating Great Apps Using Core
ML and AR Kit.
So, Scott asked me to help build
a model for his game, and I
suggested using Apple's Create
ML application to train an
object detector.
Scott has already sent me the
training data.
He took a bunch of images of
dice from different angles and
with different values on the
top, and he's annotated them,
drawing bounding boxes around
the top face and adding a label,
counting the number of pips on
each dice.
So, now we've got our data
ready.
Let's take a look at how we can
use the Create ML application to
build our model.
So first of all, let's just
check the data.
You can see we've put all of our
images in a folder, and each one
contains multiple dice, and
we've gathered together the
annotations in a single JSON
file.
So now, I'll open the Create ML
application.
I can do this from inside X
code's menu, or I can just use
Spotlight.
When the Create ML application
opens, it gives us the option to
access documents we already
created.
Here, we want a new project.
First, you'll see the template
picker, which give you a
collection of machine learning
model types to select from.
In this case, we want an image
object detector.
I give it a name, so we can
identify it later on, and fill
in a few details.
Here, you can see the main
window with the training view on
the right-hand side.
It has already selected the
input tab, ready for our
training data.
I can drag that straight into
the training data well.
Even before training the model,
the application takes a look at
the data, and checks it's in the
right format, contains images
rather than sound, for instance,
and has a JSON file, which
correctly describes them.
It also provides some initial
statistics.
Here, we can see we have around
1,000 images, and there are six
classes, six, for the six sides
of a six-sided dice.
That's perfect.
We can do some other things on
this screen.
For instance, we can supply
testing data, to allow us to
compare the performance of two
different models.
Also, we can set some advanced
parameters, tuning the way the
model trains.
But we don't need to worry about
any of that right now, we're
actually ready to train.
Let's hit the play button, and
see what happens.
Training has begun.
It takes us instantly to the
Training tab, where we can see
the progress of the model
training.
This is a graph of loss.
Loss decreases as the model gets
better and better.
So we should see this converge
down to the bottom of the graph.
Object detection takes a lot
longer to train than image
classification.
I estimate this is probably
going to take an hour or more.
We don't want to wait for that,
so I've already trained a model
using this data.
Here we are, and I can jump to
the same training tab that we
just looked at.
You can see that the loss has
neatly declined, showing the
performance of the model has
really increased over the time
it took to train.
There's a couple of other things
that you should really have a
look at on this screen.
First of all, the overall
performance.
Ninety-two percent, which is a
really great number for an
object detector.
We also want to have a look and
check that we have consistent
performance across all of the
classes.
The classes, 1 to 6, each here
has 90% or more, and they're
about the same value.
This is important because it
shows that it is performing
equally well on the six sides of
the dice.
For a game of dice, where
fairness is important, that's
pretty important.
So, the model has told us
mathematically that it's pretty
good, but how do we get
confidence that it's going to
work for our cases?
Well, we can use the output tab.
Scott sent me a test image to
try out before I send the model
back to him, so let's drag that
in now.
That's looking pretty great.
You can see that it is
identified, the five dice in the
scene.
It has correctly drawn the box
around their top faces, and by
clicking through, 6, 1, 5, we
can see each label, and the
confidence is assigned.
That's performing really well.
So, if I was building my own
app, I could go ahead and drag
the model that has been produced
and use it within Xcode.
I think Scott is probably
waiting for this model to build
his application.
But before we go there, there's
something I want to try.
While I was preparing for this
demo, playing with dice, and a
camera, and my computer, my son,
who is 9, came over and asked
what I was doing.
Once I'd explained it, he got
pretty excited, and already
started coming up with an idea
for a game which had animals,
bears, and bats, and they
cooperate to collect bolts to
build a space ship.
And they use dice, colored dice,
to level up for each different
kind of monster.
So we got his dice, and I
decided to try them with Scott's
model.
So the dice he's using are a
little bit different.
They're role-playing dice,
so let's see how the model
performs.
Using the Max Continuity Camera
feature, I can import an image
directly from my phone.
This is really great because it
means it's using the same glass,
the same camera that your
application will use.
I take the photo and click Use
Photo.
And it's instantly analyzed it.
So let's take a moment to have a
look at what is going on here.
It has correctly spotted the two
six-sided dice with pips, and it
has given them the right labels.
It has ignored most of the other
dice in the picture, except for
a couple over here.
It has given those the wrong
numbers.
So why is this?
The problem here is a difference
in expectation.
Scott knows the dice that are
going to be used are six-sided
white dice with pips.
My son's idea of dice is quite
different.
They're colored.
They don't just have six sides.
So how might we address this in
our application?
Well, either we can insist on
using the dice that maybe are
supplied with the game in the
classroom, or we can train the
model with these dice.
There are two ways we can
approach this.
Either we can decide that only
the six-sided dice with pips are
valid, but we want to exclude
the other dice, in which case,
we just need to take photographs
containing both kinds of dice,
and just label the six-sided
ones.
Or if we were building a bear
and bat game, we might like to
add the other kinds of dice into
our model, and label those too,
either just using their numbers
or adding extra labels to
distinguish the colors.
Red 6, black 4, etc.
So let's send this model on to
Scott, so he can build his demo.
I can use the Share button to
simply mail the model.
And there we have it.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So, we've seen how you can
use the Create ML application to
train your object detector on
training data that you've
collected.
There are some things I'd like
you to consider when building
that training data.
Firstly, you should have a
balanced number of images with
annotations for each class.
This tells the algorithm that
you consider each of these to be
equally important, and we can
build a model which performs
equally well on all of the
classes.
Secondly, you are going to need
a bunch of images.
I recommend you start with 30
images with annotations for each
class you want the model to
recognize, and increase that
number if you find performance
isn't good enough, or if your
subjects are particularly
complicated.
For instance, they look
different on different sides.
What about the issue we
encountered with the different
colored dice?
Well, that's not the only way
pictures might differ.
We recommend you consider how
the application will be used in
the real world.
Your users may not have studio
lighting, standard dice, and a
beautiful wooden desk to work
with.
Perhaps ask your friends to
collect additional data in
different scenarios, such as
indoor lighting, outdoors in the
sun, different backgrounds, and
add in different objects that
you aren't using for your model.
This helps the model generalize
really well.
Something that may be surprising
to you, if you've used an image
classifier before, is that one
label is enough.
This is because by explaining a
part of your image that is a
dog, you're also saying that the
rest of it isn't, and the model
trains accordingly.
So, for example, if you were
building an application to count
the number of pickle jars in
your fridge, you don't need to
label all of the other
condiments.
It automatically infers that
they're not pickle jars.
Once you've built your model,
and you want to add the
functionality into your
application, we recommend you
use the vision framework.
The vision framework can
seamlessly integrate live camera
as well as video into your model
flow.
And that's all there is to
training object detectors.
[ Applause ]