[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; I am Yuxin from Core ML.
Today I'm very excited to
introduce a brand-new model in
Create ML this year, Activity
Classification.
We do lots of activities with
our devices every day such as
playing games, doing sports.
And our mobile devices have been
equipped with a very
rich set of sensors.
Such as for motion,
Accelerometer and Gyroscope are
very commonly used.
And they can help us to detect
your device's three-dimensional
acceleration, rotation rate or
device orientation.
And we could just use such sensor data
to represent our activities.
For example, if you are jogging,
your activity data may look very
different when you are standing
still.
Similarly, if you have different
gestures, gaming controls, or
different sports movement.
Your activity data could also be
distinctive enough to be
recognized.
So what is Activity
Classification?
It is a task that allows you to
recognize your pre-defined set
of physical actions that you do
with your devices.
Then what if you have a
different set of activities to
recognize or your app may have a
different need.
We think it will be really great
if you could customize your own
model for your own purpose and
that's exactly what we are
introducing this year, Activity
Classification in Create ML.
Perhaps, let's start with an
example.
I really love to go out and play
ultimate frisbee with my family
and friends.
So after a whole game, I'm also
very interested to see how well
I might have performed such as
what they types of throwing
techniques and how many of them.
So I trained a Frisbee Motion
Classifier to recognize my moves
and I use it on my watch.
I think it's going to be fine.
Let's see a live demo first.
So this is the screen of my
phone which is paired with my
watch.
So my model is going to run on
my watch.
You can see a Start button here.
So once I hit a Start button, my
watch is going to start
streaming the sensor data.
And then my model is going to
make continuous predictions.
So let's get started.
Now it asks me to try a frisbee
move which means it predicts a
no activity class which is true
for now.
Let me try something simple
first.
Forehand.
[ Applause ]
And next, Backhand.
And this is my favorite one.
Chicken Wing.
[ Applause ]
I also have a fancier and secret
one to show.
Bowling.
[ Applause ]
It's called Bowler but as if I'm
playing bowling.
Let me try that again.
Bowler.
Yeah, it's machine learning models.
Now, let me hit the Stop button
and see my results.
Looks like pretty okay to me.
For certain classes like Bowler,
I know I can always go back and
collect more data.
So I'm pretty fine with this.
Very good exercise for today.
Now, let's come back and I know
you as developers may have lots
of other more creative ideas to
explore.
So now let's see how could we
truly set your model in Create
ML.
Just the three steps.
First, collect some data for
your own activities.
Train the model using Create ML.
And finally, deploy the model to
your app.
Let's get some data first.
The easiest way to access sensor
data is to use Core Motion.
For more information, please
refer to our previous sessions
as well as Apple Developers
Documentation.
But from a high-level point of
view your app could simply
access a list of the sensors.
So Core Motion Framework.
You can also manipulate the
Start, Stop, or Set Update
Intervals from your app for your
recordings.
And you can also use exactly the
same mechanism for both your
training data collection as well
as your later on device
inference.
And here is how my data look
like.
This is one of my Forehand
recordings, which is in a CSV
format.
There's one column of Time
Stamps and several other columns
of the sensor features.
I actually used both User
Acceleration and Rotation Grade
for my frisbee motion example.
But here for simplicity only
three are listed.
And if they would like to take
one step further to look into
the data, this is how the
activity patterns may look like.
My Forehand recording has three
back to back moves in the same
class.
And later during training, the
deep learning model is going to
use a sliding window to move
through this time series data.
And in this way, it could
extract both your spatial and
temporal patterns of the
activities.
Now we have the files ready.
You could simply organize your
data in such a hierarchy of data
source, where each folder's name
is a Label name.
And all the files under this
folder belongs to the same
activity.
We support CSV,JSON , and
text formats.
You could choose either one of
them or if you like, you can mix
and match.
There's a data ready.
Now let's start printing.
Simply select Activity Class
from our template from the
Create ML app.
And now this is a standard info
screen where you could drag and
drop your training data into the
window.
For Activity, you can see a
preview of how many files and
how many samples in your
recordings.
The one special step above the
Activity is that you have to
tell Create ML what are the
sensor features you'd like to
try out.
Simply select one or a few from
this list.
And all these sensor features
actually come from your own
files, the headers of your CSV
files.
Optionally, you could choose to
adjust the parameters as well
such as this Prediction Window
Size based on how fast and slow
of your activities.
For my frisbee motion example, I
actually used the two second
window, which is 100 samples.
So I put 100 here and that's
because my data was initially
sampled at a 50 hertz frequency.
Now, let's hit the Train button
and we can start training from
here.
I'm sure you have seen this
whole process several times
during the week.
I'm going to skip this because
the whole workflow from here is
exactly the same as other models
in Create ML.
If you are satisfied with your
accuracies, you could move on
and try some new data to
evaluate the performance of this
model.
This is a standard testing tab.
Just supply your testing data
the same way you just did.
And after the evaluation, you
would see a table of your per
class matrix in terms of
precision and recall.
For my frisbee motion example,
you can see here, Bowler and
Hammer, these certain classes
are not that perfect.
So this perhaps means I need to
go back and collect more data
for these classes.
And iterate again, so we
can improve the performance.
And finally, we get a train
model and from this point, you
could choose either save the
model and deploy it to our app
or you can do batch predictions
in Create ML app on your Mac
directly here.
Simply add some new unseen
and unlabeled the data into the
window and you will see
immediate prediction results in
terms of Label Name, Confidence,
and also a preview of your
Activity Data so you could have
a better understanding of your
activities.
And finally, this is my Core ML model.
My Frisbee Motion Example is
a Neural Network classifier.
With only 1.1 megabyte which is
pretty small and very simple for
mobile devices.
In addition, you could also see
a complete list of all the
sensor features you have used in
training, as well as a
Prediction Window size.
So later for your own device
inference, you could simply use
the same data, same size to keep
consistent.
And this is Create ML app.
We also have the framework in macOS.
So you could automate this whole
process by using Xcode
Playground, Swift Script, or
Command Line Tools.
Like this.
The one special step above
Activity is that you have to
specify the selectedSensors.
And other than this, the rest of
the workflow is standard and is
the same with other models we
have,
where each training evaluation
and model saving is just a one
line of code for each.
And this is how we view an
activity classifier in Create
ML.
But additionally, I'd also love
to share a few better practices
for this model.
Understand your activities.
Use the relevant sensors, such
as Accelerometer and Gyroscope,
are very common for motion-based
tasks.
It will be also helpful to
collect some data for additional
no activity or other class.
This is especially helpful for
your runtime performance.
Providing balanced classes is
also good practice.
For activity, this is in terms
of both number of recording files and the
recording length for each class.
And finally, Core Motion
provides both raw sensor data
and processed device motion
data.
Device motion is a sensor fusion
under Core Motion Framework, and
it provides some additional
normalization, time alignment,
or bias removal.
So sometimes it could be really
helpful for you to process the
data.
And that's Activity.
[ Applause ]