[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; This year, our Create ML
release has new models and a
whole new workflow.
Every workflow starts with
input.
The devices that we develop for,
use, and love, are rich with
information from different
sensors such as a camera, the
microphone, the keyboard,
Accelerometer, even Gyroscope.
And all of these types of input
can be used so you can train
machine learning models and make
your apps more personalized and
more intelligent.
Last year, we supported three of
these types of input; images,
text, and tabular data.
This year, we're increasing the
set of available domains from
three to five.
And now, introducing Activity
and Sound.
We're also expanding the breadth
of available models within all
of them.
And all of this is being brought
into a new medium.
We call it Create ML app.
It all starts with identifying
your domain.
And once you filter by your
input, you can see all of the
available model types you can
create.
Create ML then breaks down the
task of creating machine
learning model into three simple
phases; input, training, and
output.
This new environment changes the
way you interact with machine
learning on the system.
The app then displays an
overview of your data and a rich
set of analytics as it trains.
You can visualize your model's
progress in an easy to
understand graphical view that
displays the accuracy of your
model across iterations.
You can also see a breakdown of
the precision and recall values
for each class your model was
trained on.
And the table is interactive so
you can filter by class or by
percentage to better understand
your model's performance.
The process of testing is as
simple as dragging and dropping
in new data.
You can have the ability to
train and retest just by
clicking the Test button.
And what's really unique about
Create ML is you can easily
preview trained models in the
Output tab.
This new feature allows you to
see exactly how your model will
predict without having to
incorporate your models into
your apps.
This means no more waiting to
deploy them.
You can do this directly in
Create ML, saving you time to
perfect your models instead.
The Preview section is also
custom built for every template,
ensuring a complete end-to-end
experience for every task.
But what better way to see this
than to show it to you live?
Let's take a look.
[ Applause ]
Now, over in Xcode, I've been
working on a flower classifier
app to help me identify
different types of flowers.
And I've been using a model that
I downloaded from the Model
Gallery called Resnet50.
And this is a well-known image
classifier model that's been
trained to recognize 1,000
different classes.
But this model is taking up
about 100 megabytes of my app.
And we can see when I actually
try it on different images it
knows that this Hibiscus is a
flower, but it doesn't know the
exact type.
So, it doesn't quite suit my
needs.
Now, what I can do is from Xcode
I can open Developer Tools and
launch Create ML.
This then prompts me to create a
new document.
And we can see I'm launched into
the Template View where I can
see all the available models we
can create.
Since I'm working with images,
I'll filter by image and select
the Image Classifier.
We can then name this.
And then, pick the place to save
it so we can come back to it
later.
And then, launch into the New
App view.
And you can see that I'm, I'm
first prompted to drag in input
as training data.
And if I progress through some
of the other tabs, they're not
unlocked yet because I haven't
gone through the flow.
So, let's try this sequentially.
On my desktop, I set aside some
images of different types of
flowers.
And you can see, I have some
hibiscus, some passionflower,
and then even some roses,
dahlias, and daisies.
I could take this folder and
drag it in and immediately see
that I have 65 different images
contained within it and they're
across five different classes.
Now, since we have our input
data, I can hit the Run button
and automatically this model
begins training.
It first starts by extracting
features from the images.
And then, we can see the
progress as training begins.
I can see a breakdown of how the
model's performing on this data.
But what I'd really like to do
is see how the model performs on
new data that it hasn't seen.
So, I'll navigate to the Testing
tab and I'll drag in these new
flowers that I've set aside and
hit Test.
Now, what I'd really like to do
is take a look at the trained
model in the Output tab.
And we can see here I have a
flower classifier that's 66
kilobytes.
Now, to actually preview this,
I've taken some other photos and
perhaps this hibiscus that
wasn't working before with
Resnet.
And I can see now, this model
can correctly predict exactly
what it is.
And I can see other predictions
the model has made and
confidence values for each one.
I can even take a full folder
and drag them in and debug any
image that this model has
predicted on.
Now, once I'm satisfied, I can
take this model and drag it out.
And then, reintegrate that into
my app.
But what's more, is you can also
leverage the power of Continuity
Camera in Create ML.
And from this, what I can do is
I can import from my phone which
is attached.
And I can try to take a photo of
this flower that I have here on
stage, and we can see how it
does.
And it actually turns out okay.
[ Applause ]
Now, if you're not happy with
your performance or if you'd
just like to run some more
experiments, there's a Plus
button here, as well.
And what you can do is you can
select more training data.
You can toggle how our
validation data is specified and
even your testing data, as well.
This time, I might want to tweak
some augmentations.
And then, I can hit Run to
train.
And that's a look at the new
workflow in Create ML.
Let's go back to the slides.
[ Applause ]
So, you've seen Create ML gives
you a whole new way to train
your custom machine learning
models on the Mac, with a
beautiful look and feel.
And with additions like metrics
visualization, live progress,
and interactive preview, Create
ML app sets the bar for a great
model training experience.
In the demo, we walked through
just one model that you can
create with Create ML.
But this release, we're
introducing nine.
So, let's take a high-level tour
of all of the models you can
create and some examples of
sample apps.
Starting with the image domain,
we have the Image Classifier and
Object Detector.
An Image Classifier can be used
for categorizing images based on
their contents.
For example, the Art Style
identifier uses a custom Image
Classifier to determine the most
likely movement of a piece.
It then separately provides an
overview of notable artists to
complete the app experience.
In Create ML, the Image
Classifier leverages core Apple
technology by performing
transfer learning on top of the
vision feature print model
already in the OS.
This allows you to benefit from
faster training times and a
reduced model size in your app.
Also, you have the option to
train with augmentation to make
your models more robust to
unseen input.
If you instead want to identify
multiple objects within an image
instead of one single one, you
might want to create an Object
Detector.
Object Detectors can be used for
localizing and recognizing
contents within an image.
For example, these can be
trained to detect one or more
classes such as specific playing
cards or the exact suits
contained on them.
The Object Detector is a deep
learning-based model and
performs data augmentation to
make it more robust.
And it does this entirely on
your Mac's GPU.
Our next domain is Sound.
Within Sound, we have a new
model called the Sound
Classifier.
This model allows you to
determine the most dominant
sound within an audio stream.
Since audio data is time series
based, you could differentiate
between the start and end points
of different sounds such as when
the guitar solo ends and the
crowd goes wild.
This model leverages transfer
learning so you can also
experience faster training
times.
And we also understand that
optimizing performance across
complex applications is
challenging.
Which is why we want to
emphasize that these models are
lightweight and run on the
Neural Engine, making them ideal
for real-time applications on
any device.
Our third domain is Activity.
And within Activity, we have the
Activity Classifier for the
first time.
This model also operates on time
series-based data.
And Activity Classifiers can be
trained to categorize contents
of motion data from a variety of
sensors such as the
Accelerometer and Gyroscope.
These models are deep
learning-based and train on the
GPU.
And they result in small model
sizes that are also ideal for
deployment on any device.
Our second to last input is
Text.
Within Text, there are two model
types available; the Text
Classifier and the Word Tagger.
Text classification can be used
to label sentences, paragraphs,
or even entire articles based on
their contents.
You can train these for custom
topic identification or
categorization tasks.
In Create ML, there are a
variety of different algorithms
for you to try and even a new
transfer learning option this
year.
The Word Tagger is slightly more
nuanced.
It's ideal for labeling tokens
or words of interest in text.
General purpose examples of this
are things like tagging
different parts of speech or
recognizing named entities,
though you could customize your
own to do things like tag
cheeses.
With a Cheese Tagger, you could
be sure to identify different
flavor notes from any cheese
description.
Our last domain is the most
general of all five; Tabular
Data.
And within this, we have three
model types; the Tabular
Classifier, Tabular Regressor,
and Recommender.
Classifiers are for categorizing
samples based on their features
of interest.
And features can be a variety of
different types such as
integers, doubles, strings, so
long as your target is a
discrete value.
These allow you to do things
like determine if a seat is
comfortable or not based on a
particular person's height and
weight and specific properties
of the seat such as the amount
of leg room.
What's unique about the Tabular
Classifier is it extracts away
the underlying algorithm for
you.
And identifies the best multiple
classifiers for your data.
If you instead want a model that
will predict a numeric value,
such as a rating or a score, you
may instead want to use the
Tabular Regressor.
This model quantifies samples
based on their defining
features.
So, you could train one to
estimate the price of a house
based on its location and number
of bedrooms, bathrooms, and
parking spaces.
Like the Classifier, the
Regressor also automatically
detects the best of multiple
regressors for your data.
Though, you still have the
flexibility to choose a specific
boosted or decision tree, random
forest, or linear regressor, if
you like.
And our last model is the
Recommender which allows you to
recommend content based on user
behavior.
The Recommender can be trained
on user-item interactions with
or without ratings.
And it's able to be deployed on
device, saving you the hassle of
setting up the server.
As we saw, Create ML comes with
great features to help you set
up your machine learning
experiments, use native support
for data visualization, metrics,
and performance.
And the machine learning models
you train can easily be saved
and shared with members of your
team.
Of course, all of this leverages
the power and efficiency of
training on your Mac.
This new medium augments other
ways you have available to you
to create machine learning
models such as in Swift
Playgrounds, Swift Scripts, or
Swift Frepple [phonetic], Xcode
Playground.
But allows you to do so without
writing a single line of code.
We believe this brings machine
learning to everyone.
To summarize, in Create ML this
year, you have new models, nine
templates, and a whole new
workflow.
[ Applause ]