[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to Delivering
Intuitive Media Playback with
AVKit.
[ Applause ]
My name is Jed Lewison, and I'll
be joined a little bit later by
my colleague Dan Wright.
And we're going to talk with you
about media playback with AVKit.
And what's new in best practices
with AVPlayerViewController on
iOS and tvOS.
AVKit is a cross platform media
playback UI framework built on
top of AVFoundation in
CoreMedia.
And our mission is to make it
easy for you to show and play
AVPlayer-based media content
using the same user interface
used by Apple's own apps.
For UIKit apps, we provide
AVPlayerViewController.
For APKit apps, we provide
AVPlayerView.
And for both UIKit and APKit
apps, we provide
AVRoutePickerView, which lets
you add a wireless route picker
to your custom playback UI's.
So let's take a look at some
code.
Getting started with
AVPlayerViewController on iOS is
incredibly easy, and tvOS.
The first thing you do is you
create an AVPlayer.
Then, you create and
AVPlayerViewController and
assign to it the player that you
just created.
And finally, you present it.
And that's all there is to it.
That's all it takes to get a
rich and fully functional media
playback UI that will be
familiar to your users because
it's the same UI used by Apple
in its own apps.
But there's a lot of power below
the surface.
And that's because when you use
AVKit, you own the media
playback objects.
You are in control of creating
and managing them.
And video rendering is built on
top of the same core technology
that powers AVPlayerLayer.
That means you get the full
power of AVFoundation in
CoreMedia playback UI's,
including all the power
delivered by AVPlayer,
AVPlayerItem, and AVAsset.
But because AVKit also sit on
top of UIKit and AppKit, you get
a user experience tailored to
each of Apple's unique
platforms.
So AVKit gives you the best of
both worlds.
You get full control over your
media playback objects.
And a familiar API for showing
and displaying them using UIKit
and APKit-based APIs.
So, that's a high-level look at
AVKIt.
Let's dive right into what's new
in AVPlayerViewController and
iOS for iOS 13.
I'm going to start talking about
new full screen callbacks that
we added that inform you about
transitions from embedded inline
presentations to full screen and
entering full screen and exiting
full screens.
So, to motivate this, in this
video, what we'll see is the
user's going to enter full
screen here and then start an
interactive dismissal.
But, they'll cancel that
dismissal.
So now we're back to full
screen.
And now the user has dismissed,
and we're back to where we
started with an
AVPlayerViewController embedded
inline.
So, the new API we're delivering
in iOS 13 informs you about all
of these states by extending
AVPlayerViewController Delegate.
You get notifications when a
full screen presentation begins
or ends.
And it looks like this.
Two new delegate methods.
If you link against the iOS 13
SDK, they will be available
starting with iOS 12, one for
beginning a full screen
presentation, and one that is
called when a full screen
presentation ends.
So, let's take a look at an
implementation here.
And the key object is the
UIViewControllerTransition
Coordinator.
At that works exactly the same
as it does with any other view
controller transition in UIKit.
And you can learn about all
those details and the power
there from UIKit documentation.
But the key thing I want to
focus on here is the completion
handler for the animate
alongsideTransition callback.
And this is where you find out
whether a transition succeeded
or whether the user cancelled
it.
And this is the source of truth
for learning about entering full
screen from an inline
presentation.
And obviously it's interesting
to know whether the player view
controller is full screen or
whether it is embedded inline.
But why is it crucial?
It's important because, let's
take the case of where your
player view controller may have
been in a scroll view.
And the user has entered full
screen.
When the device rotates, as you
know, sometimes your scroll
view's offset might change.
And it's possible that the
player view controller will
scroll offscreen.
And that's okay for it to scroll
offscreen during the full screen
presentation because the user
can't see it.
But you need to make sure that
the player view controller does
stay alive.
If it is deallocated, the full
screen presentation will end.
So you can use the new API to
know when to take a strong
reference to the player view
controller if your table view
controller or collection view
happens to remove the player
view controller if it's scrolled
offscreen.
But you're still left with the
question of how do you get it
back in place when the user
exits full screen.
And for that, you use the
willEnd variant of the new API.
And this is called the before
the animation begins.
So you can reset the location of
the player view controller in
your UI.
And the user will be none the
wiser.
Everything will be back the way
they expect.
So those are full screen
callbacks.
Now let's take a look at
AVPlayerViewController in iPad
apps on the Mac.
And as you know, iPad apps can
now be built on the Mac.
And AVPlayerViewController is a
full participant in that.
And here's what it looks like.
You get the same user interface
that you expect from Apple's
playback UIs with all the
functionality that
AVPlayerViewController delivers
for iPad apps.
But you also get some platform
specific features for Mac.
Things like touch bar support,
which you get for free.
And keyboard support.
And we've also added
picture-in-picture support to
iPad apps on the Mac.
In fact, we've extended
picture-in-picture support to
all UIKit and APPKit-based apps
on the Mac for this release.
And how many new lines of code
to you need to use
AVPlayerViewController in an
iPad app on the Mac?
You guessed it.
None.
[ Applause ]
So that's AVPlayerViewController
and iPad apps on the Mac.
Now let's talk about external
metadata.
And to motivate this, imagine
that your AirPlaying content.
And imagine when you did that,
your locked screen looked like
this, instead of like this.
And there's two things that make
it possible to show this UI.
The first thing is you need to
handle remote control commands.
And AVKit handles that for you
automatically for free.
You don't have to do anything.
But you also sometimes have
media that doesn't have all the
metadata that you would want to
publish baked in.
And for that, we're adding this
new API to iOS.
It's actually existed on tvOS.
And you take your AVPlayerItem.
And you can supplement metadata
with things like title,
metadata, or artwork metadata.
It's super easy.
And when you do that, we'll take
care of the rest.
We've also, in iOS 13, improved
support for interactive -- for
custom controls from
AVPlayerViewController.
That's always been possible to
do, use custom controls with
AVPlayerViewController on iOS.
But when you did that, you lost
all the other things that
weren't onscreen.
Things like interactive
dismissals.
Or landscape support.
Things like keyboard.
And now in
AVPlayerViewController on iPad
apps for the Mac, touch bar
support.
So, what you can do now in iOS
13 is if you set
showsPlaybackControls to False.
And then you present
AVPlayerViewController modally.
And finally use the
contentOverlayView as a place
where you place your custom
controls.
You can have a completely custom
playback UI but still take
advantage of things like
nowPlayingInfo support
and interactive dismissals.
But there's some things, if you
do this, some things you should
keep in mind.
You still are going to need to
take care of status bar and home
indicator appearance.
And you should always pass
unhandled touches through your
view hierarchy so that AVKit can
handle things like interactive
dismissals or double-tap for
zoom, which we'll talk about in
a little bit.
So, that's a look at what's new
in AVPlayerViewController on
iOS.
There's a bunch more things that
we've added.
And one of them is we've made
great strides in improving
performance in iOS 12.
And it's even better on iOS 13.
So if you're interested in using
AVPlayerViewController in scroll
view, it should be buttery
smooth now.
So, let's talk about some best
practices with
AVPlayerViewController.
I want to talk about three
different ways that we show
video on our devices.
And of course, there's a fourth
way that we show video from an
iOS device AirPlay.
And there was a terrific talk on
Tuesday morning at 9:00 a.m. If
you haven't seen it, I would
strongly recommend watching that
talk.
But I'm going to focus on
on-device playback today.
And let's start with full screen
video playback.
And of course, what I mean by
that is full screen in the UIKit
sense of the word.
So, we're talking about covering
your UIWindowScene coordinate
space.
And if we think about it,
there's two different reasons
why we might play a video full
screen.
It could be for sort of a
background video in a splash
screen scenario.
Or because the video is the star
of the show.
And we want full playback
controls.
And let's take a quick look at
the splash screen scenario.
And you're going to have set of
these things that you're going
to want to implement in your
application.
And to do that, you're going to
take the playerViewController.
You're going to embed it as a
child.
So it can be at the bottom of
your view hierarchy.
You're going to do things like
disabling playback controls and
setting the video gravity so
that the video scales to fill
the full screen.
If you're using the new video
with alpha APIs that are new in
this release, you're going to
want to set your view's
background color to clear or
some other color to leverage
that.
And there's some things to take
into account with AVFoundation.
You always want to make sure to
prevent external playback with
something that is playing as a
splash screen.
Because you don't want to
interrupt, say, music playing on
someone's Apple TV.
And you want to configure the
audio session.
And especially this last
property on AVAudioSession, that
this secondary audio should be
silenced.
It lets you know if the user is
playing audio from some other
application.
And they want that application
to be -- that audio to be
primary.
In that case, if you have audio
in your splash screen video,
make sure to mute it.
But then, let's look at full
screen playback where the video
is the star of the show.
And when we do this, of course
we want playback UI that adapts
beautifully whether it's a
portrait presentation like this
where we have a stacked playback
transport controls.
Or we're in landscape and we
need a slightly different layout
but the same -- but we need to
deliver the same functionality.
So AVPlayerViewController
delivers this to you for free.
And it also does things like,
you'll notice in those two
screen shots the video was
unzoomed in portrait.
And now it's zoomed in
landscape.
And it's zoomed to fill the
entire screen because the user
has generally, in this case, has
played video that is of similar
aspect ratio to the device
aspect ratio in a zoomed format.
But some users prefer to have
video unzoomed, like here.
And when that happens we want to
make sure that the video isn't
occluded by any physical
characteristic of the device.
AVKit is aware of all these
things and takes care of that
for you when you're using
PlayerViewController.
But rather than running through
every feature that we provide, I
just want to zoom in on two very
small things that we added in
iOS 13.
The first -- in this video,
you're going to hear audio
playing.
And the user's going to tap the
Mute button.
Notice when it mutes, there's a
subtle ramp to the audio.
And there's an animation in the
volume slider.
[ Music ]
And then in this example,
there's an interactive
dismissal.
And notice that the audio
gracefully fades with the user's
dismissal.
And then when the user cancels
the dismissal, the audio comes
back up.
[ Music ]
So those are two small things,
but they illustrate the level of
attention to detail that we're
able to give to
AVPlayerViewController and that
your users will get for free if
you're able to adopt it in your
app.
You get a whole bunch of other
things.
And the question that you might
ask is how do you get all of
this?
And let's take another look at
code.
So, this is basically the same
thing that I showed earlier in
the talk.
The only addition is this
external metadata.
This line allows you to
supplement your metadata.
And it really is that easy to
get started.
But it's worth talking about why
it's possible for you to do so
little on the UI side and to get
such a good experience.
And so, for that I want to talk
about a couple of best practices
here.
So, when you use
AVPlayerViewController for a
full screen presentation you
should always present it
modally, not as a child view
controller of some other view
controller.
And sometimes you may have done
that because you wanted to learn
about presentation state, which
you can now do with the
callbacks that I discussed
earlier.
Presenting modally lets us
handle things like status bar
visibility.
Let's us optimize the screen's
display mode.
It lets us handle video gravity,
video zoom mode, interactive
dismissals.
And when you are presenting
modally full screen, you should
use the default modal
presentation style.
As you may know, in iOS 13, the
new default modal presentation
style is automatic.
And what that resolves to for
AVPlayerViewController is a full
screen presentation.
And there's two types of full
screen presentations: Full
screen and over full screen.
The reason why you want to use
the default is because when your
view controller is presented,
the presenting view can be
removed by UIKit.
This allows, because your view
is covering the newly presented
view hierarchy, removing the
presenting view is an
optimization during rotation.
You don't want to do layout when
your view's not even visible.
But it also allows things like
landscape playback if your app
is otherwise portrait only or
this view controller hierarchy
is otherwise portrait only.
It's also best just to leave the
video gravity property alone for
full screen playback.
That allows us to do automatic
behaviors like I was
illustrating before.
If you set the video gravity,
we'll give you exactly what you
want.
We'll zoom the video or unzoom
the video.
But once you do that, the
automatic behavior, we can't do
the automatic behavior anymore.
So your users generally would
prefer to have the automatic
behavior.
And of course, use the new
delegate methods to track the
full screen presentation state.
A couple of tips related to
AVFoundation best practices
here.
What this one is about, the way
I think about it, is if you're
starting a video, say halfway
into the video, seek the player
item to the resume time before
setting it on the player.
And make sure you're going to
have a playing player that it's
already playing.
And then provide that to
AVPlayerViewController.
And this allows the UI to look
correct.
And more importantly, it avoids
loading content that isn't going
to end up being played.
You should also always observe
AVPlayer's and AVPlayerItem
status property.
Though you can use KVO to
observe them.
When they fail, when the
property status becomes failed,
there's an easy path to recovery
in many cases.
Check the error property.
See if media services were
reset.
And if so, just rebuild your
player, player item, your
AVFoundation object ref and set
it back on the
PlayerViewController and
everything should be fine.
And this property gives you an
optimized video rendering when
you're mirroring.
And of course, always configure
your audio session for playback.
So, when we talk about embedding
AVPlayerViewController inline,
there's a little bit more to
consider.
And we've already talked about
the full screen, new full screen
presentation state callbacks in
iOS 13.
So I won't go over those again.
But, one thing I want to touch
on is if you've used
AVPlayerViewController in the
past, when we enter full screen
from an embedded inline
presentation, the modal
transition style has been in
over full screen style, which
means that your view, your
presenting view, isn't removed.
If your app links against iOS
13, the default presentation
style now will be full screen.
Which means that the presenting
view might be removed.
And that has all the benefits
that I talked about earlier.
So, ideally you'll be able to
leave this modal presentation
style as full screen.
But if you don't, it's okay.
You can still set it to over
full screen.
But the recommendation is to
just stick with the default.
Another thing to consider is
when you have an embedded
presentation, your video, you
may want to zoom the video so
that you don't have black bars
on top or on bottom.
You also might want to have
things like a corner curve to
the video's view port.
And also, you may want to set
the background color of the
view.
You can do all that to
AVPlayerViewController's view or
to the video gravity when it's
embedded inline.
And we'll use that for the
inline part of the presentation.
If the user decides to go full
screen, then we'll do the right
thing there.
So, in contrast to, if you're
just presenting
AVPlayerViewController full
screen, it's okay to -- you can
change these properties for the
inline portion of the
presentation.
No problem at all.
We also have a couple of
properties that provide
automatic behavior when you have
an inline presentation.
And these allow you to do things
like, if the user taps a big
play button, the
PlayerViewController will -- the
content of the
PlayerViewController will
automatically enter full screen.
And similarly, at the end of the
video, will exit full screen.
And it's really best for us to
handle those things on your
behalf.
Because for example, let's say
that a user is scrubbing to the
end of a video.
Well, the time's going to be the
end of the video, but you don't
want to dismiss the video at
that point.
Because they're probably just
seeking around.
We keep track of what the user
is doing.
And we'll only exit if it's
appropriate.
Of course, you're always going
to want to adopt
UIViewController containment
API.
And it looks like this.
One other thing to keep in mind
is if you have a lot of videos
that you're scrolling through,
you may find that having a
poster image is a good idea as a
way to show a frame of the video
without having to have the video
fully loaded.
And that can take a little bit
of time.
And so you use
AVPlayerViewController's
contentOverlayView for this.
But then you want to know when
is the video -- when is the
first frame of video ready so
that you can remove the content
that you just put in the overlay
view.
You do that by observing
isReadyForDisplay on
AVPlayerViewController.
It's a property that you can
observe using KVO.
And this is what it looks like
to observe it.
You always want to take the
initial value because it could
be the video frame is already
rendered.
I want to finish by talking a
little bit about
picture-in-picture, which is
super easy to add to your app.
AVPlayerViewController takes
care of most things for you.
You do have to configure your
application to support
picture-in-picture.
And it looks like this.
Just click a check box in XCode.
One thing, this applies whether
you're using
AVPictureInPictureController or
AVPlayerViewController.
When a user swipes up to go home
in iPad, picture-in-picture may
automatically start.
And that means when your app is
entering background, you should
not pause any playing video.
Because picture-in-picture may
be starting.
You don't want to pause the very
video that your user is trying
to keep on watching.
So, don't pause.
And AVFoundation will take care
of this for you.
But if you absolutely must
pause, you should wait for the
application's background state,
application state, or the window
scene state to reach background.
And this is how you do that.
You can track state about
whether you're in
picture-picture or leaving
picture-picture using the
AVPlayerViewControllerDelegate.
And always toggle
PictureInPicture Playback.
Be prepared for your view
controller to dismiss when
picture-in-picture is starting.
And unlike in the full screen
case, we will prevent
deallocation of
AVPlayerViewController while
picture-in-picture is active.
But if the view controller's
been dismissed, you're going to
want to restore the UI when the
user wants to go back to your
app.
And so, it's really easy to do
that.
This is the callback you're
going to get
AVPlayerViewControllerDelegate.
And all you have to do here is
get your UI back into a state
that works, that is what you
want.
In this case we're just
presenting the view controller
again.
And then when you're ready, call
the completion handler that is
passed into the callback.
Let us know that you're ready to
go.
And we will animate back in
place.
You need to do it fairly
quickly, otherwise the
picture-in-picture window might
just go oop!
And no more picture-in-picture
for your user.
And they're not able to get back
to your app.
So, that's a look at what's new
in best practices for
AVPlayerViewController in iOS.
There's sample code illustrating
all these concepts at our
session website.
And now, I'd like to hand things
over to my colleague, Dan
Wright.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
Let's talk about video playback
on TV.
On tvOS AVPlayerViewController
supports full screen interactive
playback with standard controls
for navigation, information, and
settings.
Built in support for advanced
Siri features such as "what did
she say?"
Publication of Now Playing info.
Interstitials such as for ads.
Content proposals, and more.
So, what's new for tvOS 13?
Since last year we've updated
the appearance of the controls.
And starting with tvOS 12.3,
introduced fine precision
scrubbing.
Today, we're introducing custom
interactive overlays, channel
flipping for live streams, and
automatic enforcement of
parental content restrictions.
Fine precision scrubbing makes
it easier to use your Siri
remote to find the precise
moment in the video that you're
looking for.
PlayerViewController has always
supported -- the scrubbing in
made it easy to navigate quickly
across a wide range of your
video.
But now fine scrubbing makes it
easier to find a very precise
moment, like within about a
second, as you're navigating.
And of course, the info views
have a new appearance to match
the TV app.
Custom interactive overlays
support application controls.
A custom overlay is normally
hidden.
A hint onscreen guides the user
to swipe up, which presents your
overlay.
The overlay is fully
interactive, and it can contain
buttons, collections, or any
other interactive elements that
you like as defined by your view
controller.
And then you should, for
persistent non-interactive
elements like a channel logo,
for example, you should continue
to use the contentOverlayView
too.
Let's see what custom overlays
look like.
When the video begins, you have
a hint at the bottom to guide
them to swipe up for more.
And when they swipe up, they get
your overlay.
Just like that.
They can dismiss by swiping down
or by clicking the Menu button.
So, your view controller is
presented.
You get all the usual
UIViewController notifications.
We handle dismissal and
animations.
And your users get a consistent
experience across applications.
So all you need to do to use it
is to define your view
controller with the content that
you want to display.
And set the
customOverlayViewController
property on your player view
controller.
Live broadcast channel flipping.
Channel flipping is for live
streams.
It provides support for flipping
between multiple live streams.
For example, different channels.
The user swipes horizontally to
go to the next or the previous
channels.
And a channel interstitial
screen describes each channel
while it loads.
So let's see what channel
flipping looks like.
As the user swipes between
channels, your channel
interstitial view is shown.
Here it has a simple green
background, some text, and a
loading indicator.
But, that's entirely within your
control.
You can make it look whatever
you like in there, including
pictures, a gradient background,
your custom spinner, whatever
you like.
The main thing is to orient your
user to where they are and where
they're going.
And the one other thing I would
add is that this a
non-interactive screen.
It's meant to guide the user to
the next channel.
So you shouldn't expect to have
controls here.
To support channel flipping,
extend your
AVPlayerViewControllerDelegate
to implement
playerViewController
skipToNextChannel and
skipToPreviousChannel.
All these methods do is replace
the content in your player view
controller with that of the new
channel.
You can wait until the content
is ready to play if you like.
When you're done, call the
completion block.
Pass True if it was successful.
And pass False if something
failed.
But whatever you do, make sure
that you call that completion
block eventually, because that's
what's going to dismiss the
channel interstitial.
Now, there are two additional
methods:
nextChannelInterstitialView
Controller and
previousChannelInterstitialView
Controller.
And these are responsible for
providing that view controller
that displays between channels.
So, you need to instantiate your
view controller, if you have
one, if you need to.
And populate it with information
about the new channel.
And then just return it.
In this example we're
instantiating a new view
controller every time.
But in many cases, you could
probably just instantiate it
once and then reuse it.
tvOS has built in support for
restricting access to content
using a passcode, or with a
device profile.
Device profiles are commonly
used in a classroom setting or
perhaps a business setting.
In tvOS 13, AVKit provides
automatic support to help your
users regain control of
restricted content.
So, to test content
restrictions, go to Settings,
Restrictions.
Turn them on.
Provide and confirm a passcode.
Then change the allowed content
rating under Movies, and/or TV
Shows.
In this case we'll change it to
PG-13.
So, what do you need to do to
actually support it in your app?
Well, the most important thing
is you need to specify the media
content rating in all of your
content.
If your asset does not have this
information, then you'll need to
add it using the external
metadata property of
AVPlayerItem.
And you're going to want to use
the iTunes metadata content
rating identifier.
You'll want to provide this
rating at the start of playback
so that AVKit can test whether
this is restricted content
according to the user settings.
And present the passcode to
screen if necessary.
Now, if the content is
restricted by passcode, the user
will be prompted to enter it.
If it is restricted by a device
profile, however, it could
simply fail to play entirely.
There may be no option for the
user to override.
Now, AVPlayerViewController will
request access automatically to
your content when playback
begins.
But you can request access
earlier using a new API request
playback restrictions
authorization.
And of course, any kind of
failure here, if the user
doesn't know the passcode or
doesn't want to enter the
passcode, or if it's a device
profile that prohibits it, the
player view controller will be
automatically dismissed.
And finally, if you have a
custom playback user interface,
you can also request access
using the aforementioned API to
restricted content.
Now let's take a look at what
the user sees when attempting to
play restricted content.
Now, the video's going to load.
And as soon as it's ready to
play and the metadata's
available, the passcode screen
is going to immediately appear.
And as soon as the user enters
the passcode, the passcode
screen is dismissed and the
video begins playing.
So let's take a look at how to
provide the media content
rating.
This metadata is sometimes part
of your assets.
But usually it is not.
So you will need to provide it
via the external metadata
property of the AVPlayerItem.
We've seen this code before in
previous presentations.
But we just have a helper
function here that takes our
rating in the form of a string
and returns and AVMetadataItem.
The value is that string.
The extended language tag is set
to und for Undefined because
it's not any particular
language.
Your identifier is the
iTunesMetadataContent Rating.
And then finally, once we've
created it, in this case with a
rating of PG-13,
we add it to the external
metadata property of the player
item.
Now, AVPlayerViewController will
prompt automatically, if
necessary.
But let's say you want to prompt
earlier before you present the
player view controller, or
perhaps before earlier content.
You can do this using the
requestPlayback Restrictions
Authorization API on
AVPlayerItem.
The closure will be called when
the request is complete to
indicate whether there the
request succeeded or failed.
And if it fails, the error
provides information about why
it failed.
If it succeeded, you should
proceed with playback.
Otherwise, you should cancel,
dismiss, go back to your menu
screen or whatever.
And don't try to play the
content again unless the use
explicitly requests it.
All right.
Let's do a brief demo and get a
closer look at some of this.
All right.
So we have our little sample
app.
These videos may be familiar to
some of you who have done
testing with HLS.
Here's our swipe up.
Swipe for more hints at the
bottom.
And if we swipe up, we get our
custom overlay.
And see that it actually works
and everything.
And I can just swipe down to get
rid of it.
And what else do we have here?
Well, if I press and keep my
finger down, we see the Hints on
the left and the right sides of
the screens.
Those are the arrows to guide
the user to channel flipping.
And if I just swipe -- see
what's going on next door.
&gt;&gt; Using some great design
patterns, including --
&gt;&gt; Oh yeah, it's the bottom part
is using a list to lay out --
&gt;&gt; In the last month --
&gt;&gt; Let's see.
What else do we have?
Is that it?
Oh, what's going on over here?
[ Laughter ]
All right.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right.
So we have our little sample
app.
&gt;&gt; I passed me.
Let's go back to -- let's see --
back to the --
&gt;&gt; Here's our Swipe up bar for
more hints at the bottom.
And if we swipe up, we get our
custom overlay and see if it
actually works --
&gt;&gt; Let's pause.
[ Laughter ]
All right.
So let's take a moment to talk
about some best practices on
tvOS now.
Some of you already have
controls in your apps that are
revealed by swipe up.
Often, it's Up Next list.
And typically, you're doing this
by installing your own custom
swipe up gesture recognizer on
the player view or a super view.
And then presenting your view
controller.
Well, if you're doing that, we
want to encourage you to migrate
to using a custom overlay
instead.
What that gets you is much
better compatibility in the
future -- hint.
And a better and more consistent
experience for your users across
applications.
If you're using a UI tap gesture
recognizer on the Menu button to
detect dismissal of your player
view controller, or in some
cases to provide the dismissal
animation, you should use the
delegate to dismissal
notifications instead.
We introduced those in tvOS 11.
And they should give you all the
information that you need.
This is important because it's
no longer the case that the only
way that your play view
controller can be dismissed is
by the user hitting the Menu
button.
It could now be automatically
dismissed.
I've said this one before, but
showsPlaybackControls should not
be abused to try to force
immediate change in the
visibility of the controls.
The purpose of
showsPlaybackControls is to
configure the player view
controller to indicate whether
you want the user to have access
to the playback controls at all.
Provide media content ratings
for all of your content.
And of course, test with
parental content restrictions
enabled.
Most of you will have no issues,
but you might find that there's
something that you're doing that
doesn't work very well when a
passcode stream comes up.
For example, if you display a
hint for a few seconds at the
start of playback, you would
want to not do that while the
passcode is covering it or the
user won't see it.
So in summary, adopt
AVPlayerViewController across
platform.
You get great functionality on
iOS and on tvOS for a very low
cost.
And a wide range of
compatibility for remotes and
other features.
Use
AVPlayerViewControllerDelegate
notifications to track
presentation state, as seen
today on iOS, and to handle
dismissal, as on tvOS.
Observe the player item status
and handle errors.
Use external metadata, now on
both iOS and tvOS in addition to
some of these uses we've seen
today for parental content
restrictions and in the info
panel.
External metadata is also used
to publish Now Playing info,
which means that if you use
external metadata on both
platforms, you can now remove
all of your Now Playing info
support.
If you have a custom overlay on
a swipe up action, migrate it --
I'm sorry -- if you swipe up
action presenting an overlay,
migrate to custom overlays.
And finally, support parental
content restrictions.
So, for more information,
including sample code for this
session, visit our session page
at the URL on the screen.
And come with your questions and
your code to the AVKit Lab at
2:00 p.m. today or to the
AVFoundation lab at 4:00.
Thank you, and enjoy the rest of
conferences.
[ Applause ]