[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, and welcome to our
session about audio API updates.
My name is Peter Vasil, and I am
a software engineer in the Core
Audio team.
Let's start with what's new in
AVAudioEngine.
We have added a couple of
enhancements and new APIs to
AVAudioEngine.
We now have a voice processing
support.
We have added two new nodes,
AVAudioSourceNode and
AVAudioSinkNode, and we have
made some improvements to
spatial audio rendering.
Now, let's dive into the
details.
AVAudioEngine now has a voice
processing mode.
The main use case for the mode
is echo cancellation and
voice-over IP applications.
What does this mean?
When enabled, extra signal
processing is applied on the
incoming audio, and any audio
that is coming from the device
is taken out.
This requires that both input
and output nodes are in the
voice processing mode.
Therefore, when enabling the
mode on either of the I/O nodes,
the engine takes care that both
I/O nodes exist and that they
are switched to the voice
processing mode.
Voice processing is only
available when rendering to an
audio device, not a manual
rendering mode.
To enable or disable voice
processing, we can use set voice
processing enabled on either the
input or output node.
Voice processing cannot be
enabled dynamically, which means
the engine needs to be in a stop
state when enabling the mode.
The AV Echo Touch Sample Code
project demonstrates how to use
voice processing with
AVAudioEngine in detail.
Let's look at the new nodes in
AVAudioEngine, AVAudioSourceNode
and AVAudioSinkNode.
Both nodes wrap a user-defined
blog that allows apps to send or
receive audio from
AVAudioEngine.
When rendering to an audio
device, the block operates under
real-time constraints, which
means that within the block
there shouldn't be any blocking
calls like memory allocations,
call to lib dispatch, or
blocking on a mutex.
With AVAudioSourceNode, we pass
or render block to the node,
which sends audio data to its
output.
This makes it very easy to
create generated nodes without
having to implement a full audio
unit and wrap it with AVAudio
unit.
The node can be used in both
real time and manual rendering
mode.
AVAudioSourceNode support linear
PCM conversions such as sample
rate or bit depth conversions
and has one output but no input.
This short code snippet shows
how to use AVAudioSourceNode.
As we can see, the block is
passed as an initializer
argument, and after creating the
node, it can be connected just
like any other node.
A more detailed example can be
found in our Signal Generator
Sample Code project.
Let's look at AVAudioSinkNode.
AVAudioSinkNode is a symmetrical
counterpart of
AVAudioSourceNode.
It wraps a user-defined block
that receives the input audio
from the node chain that is
connected to its input.
AVAudioSinkNode is restricted to
the input chain.
In other words, it must be
connected downstream of the
input node.
It does not support format
conversions, and the format
within the block has to be the
same as the hardware input
format.
The node can be useful for
voice-over IP application when
the input needs to be processed
in real time, in which case
installing a regular tap would
not be sufficient because the
tap doesn't operate in a
real-time context.
Here is a code snippet
demonstrating how to create an
AVAudioSinkNode.
It is quite similar to
AVAudioSourceNode.
The main steps to note here are
to initialize the node with a
blog, attach it to the engine,
and connect it to a node
downstream of the input node.
Now let's see the spatial
rendering improvements.
We have introduced an automatic
spatial rendering algorithm, and
AVAudioPlayerNode now supports
spatialization of multichannel
audio content.
With the automatic spatial
rendering algorithm, the most
appropriate spatialization
algorithm is selected for the
current route.
This means developers don't need
to figure out what algorithms
are suitable for headphones or
different speaker
configurations.
This adds near-field and in-head
rendering for headphones and
virtual surround for built-in
speakers is available starting
with iOS devices and laptops
from 2018 and newer.
Here we see the new API in the
AVAudio3DMixing protocol.
The AVAudio3DMixing rendering
algorithm enum has a new entry,
auto.
Additionally, we can specify the
output type with the output type
property.
With the property set to auto,
the output type can be
automatically detected in
real-time mode but not in manual
rendering mode.
With the ability to spatialize
multichannel streams, we support
point-source and ambience bed
rendering.
We also support channel-based
formats and higher-order
Ambisonics up to the third
order.
We have added two new
spatialization properties to the
AVAudio3DMixing protocol, source
mode and pointSource and head
mode.
SpatializeIfMono is legacy
behavior.
This is the same as bypass for
any multichannel stream, which
means a pass through or downmix
to the output format.
With pointSource, the audio is
sum to mono and render at the
location of the player node.
And with ambienceBed, the audio
is anchored to the 3D world and
is rotatable with the player
node's position relative to the
listener orientation.
Here we see an example of
ambienceBed source mode with
automatic rendering algorithm.
After setting the properties, it
is important to make sure the
format that is used for the
connection between player node
and the environment node
contains the multichannel
layout.
Now let's talk about what's new
in AVAudioSession.
AVAudioSessionPromptStyle is a
hint to apps that play voice
prompts in order to modify the
style of the played prompt.
For example, if Siri is speaking
or a phone call is ongoing,
verbal navigation prompts is a
confusing user experience.
We also don't want Siri to
record a navigation prompt.
Navigation apps, for example,
are encouraged to pay attention
to prompt style changes and
modify the prompts for better
user experience.
We have three prompt styles,
none, short, and normal.
We can now indicate to disable
prompts completely, play
shortened prompts, or play the
regular prompts.
Let's look at other
AVAudioSession enhancements.
The default policy is to mute
haptics and system sounds when
audio recording is active.
A new property, allow haptics
and system sounds during
recording, allows system sounds
and haptics to play while the
session is actively using an
audio input.
It can be set using the
setter set allow haptics
and system sounds during
recording.
For more information, please
visit the developer website.
Thank you for your attention.