[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everybody.
My name is Cody and I'd like to
welcome you to the introduction
to RealityKit and Reality
Composer.
So today, the App Store is full
of many different AR experiences
that utilize the power of ARKit.
And developers of these apps
have a lot of common needs, for
example, rendering, physics and
animation.
And ARKit makes building AR
experiences pretty simple but
now we're going to make it even
easier.
The developing applications for
AR, provides very unique
challenges that really don't
exist anywhere else, and it
mostly centers around the fact
that your virtual content will
now interact with the real world
and vice versa.
So if you put like a virtual
lamp into a real living room, it
should probably light up the
surrounding objects whether
they're real or virtual.
And additionally, any content
that gets placed in the real
world should look like it
belongs there.
And this can be very important
in a case like online shopping,
where you want to see how the
product will look in your home.
So this gives us a very strong
requirement for a very realistic
render, otherwise, you'll lose
the illusion of augmented
reality.
So enter RealityKit, which is a
brand new Swift framework
designed to help you build your
AR applications and easily
exploit the power of ARKit.
RealityKit is an AR first
framework, which means that it's
been completely designed from
the ground up with an emphasis
on AR application development.
So the framework heavily
emphasizes highly realistic
physically-based rendering and
accurate object simulation with
the real life environment.
We also take full advantage of
the power of Swift to deliver a
high-quality framework that has
a very simple API.
In addition to RealityKit, we're
also introducing Reality
Composer, which is a Mac and iOS
tool that enables simple
AR-based content creation.
And its intuitive design is
really targeted at anybody who
wants to make their own content
exist in the world around them,
even allowing you to lay out
your scenes directly in AR.
But before we get into that,
let's focus on RealityKit and
see it in action.
So here we have a real living
room with a couch and a table
and some small objects that are
on the table.
It's purposely a bit blurry
because the focus of the camera
is very shallow here.
So with RealityKit, we can add
virtual objects to this world
and believe that they're really
in our environment.
So notice here how very accurate
lighting and shadows and camera
effects, really helped to make
the object feel like it belongs,
even something fantastical like
this.
RealityKit helps with the heavy
lifting and making your content
fit in the world automatically.
All you have to do is tell the
framework where you want to show
up and then supply any custom
logic that's specific to your
app.
And it's really easy to get up
and running with your very first
app.
And in fact for that app you
just saw, I only needed to write
four lines of code.
So here, I'm placing a
horizontal anchor in the world.
I'm loading a model that's
called flyer from my asset
bundle.
And I'm attaching that model to
the anchor.
So over the course of this talk,
I'll dive deeper into what each
of these concepts mean.
But now that we've seen this
framework in action, let's go
into some of the systems that
make up RealityKit and the
basics to help you get started
right away.
So to help build your apps,
RealityKit takes care of a lot
for you to all of its built-in
systems.
All of which are integrated with
other Apple frameworks such as
ARKit and Metal.
So first off, the rendering
system has a job of making your
content look amazing and
realistic in a real environment.
And it does this with a
physically-based shading system
that accurately simulates
lighting and material
interactions.
It's all built on top of Metal,
it means that it's highly
optimized for Apple devices.
The system takes advantage of
all the Metal has to offer, such
as multithreaded rendering and
other low level functionality.
And since RealityKit is designed
for AR applications, the feature
set of the render is entirely
focused around making your
content look great and in a real
environment.
On top of rendering, animations
really helped to breathe life to
your content and really enrich
your scene.
And RealityKit's animation
system achieves this through
supporting both skeletal and
transform animations, both of
which can be imported directly
from USDZ.
And you can even animate your
objects procedurally through
ARKit's motion capture
technology.
The physics system is
responsible for simulating
complex interactions between
content, including real world
objects.
And it provides a collision
detection system that supports
several different proxy shapes,
such as box, sphere, or even
compound shapes.
And it also simulates rigid body
dynamics, such as mass, inertia,
friction, and restitution.
RealityKit has built-in support
for networking and it
synchronizes the entire scene
across devices, including shared
representations of real world
data.
And it's all built on top of
Apple's multipeer networking
library.
This system it works out of the
box, and it really makes
building connected apps simple
and automatic.
RealityKit uses an entity
component system to represent
object data which gives users a
really powerful tool to easily
make content through composition
of properties as opposed to
large object inheritance
hierarchies.
And you can even create your own
custom components to add your
own data and functionality to
any entity.
And additionally, all components
automatically synchronize their
data with other devices in a
network setting, even custom
components.
So sharing data is a very easy
operation.
So far, all the systems that we
focused on are really
emphasizing a lot of the visual
side of AR, but that really
doesn't capture the whole
picture.
Audio is also an important
aspect in helping to create very
immersive content that you can
believe is in the real world.
RealityKit's audio system
understands 3D space and can
place audio sources on dynamic
content.
So this has the effect of making
virtual objects further from you
actually sound like they're
farther away, and vice versa.
I'd also like to mention that
RealityKit has defined a new
file type, known as the Reality
File, which stores optimized
content that's ready for loading
into your app.
And this file can include
everything that your app would
need.
For example, meshes and
materials and physics properties
or even audio sources.
RealityKit does also support
importing directly from USDZ
files, similar to how AR Quick
Look works.
But using Reality Files will
give you much faster uploading
time and much greater control
over your content.
And you can export these files
directly from Reality Composer,
which will be covered later in
this talk.
So while using the RealityKit
API, there's going to be four
main areas that you're going to
use no matter what type of
application that you're going to
be building.
And those include ARView,
anchors, scenes, and entities.
So let's start with the View or
ARView as it's called in
RealityKit.
So the View takes care of a lot
of the heavy lifting of building
your AR apps, so that you can
start focusing on your
experience right away.
And it comes with a lot of
useful functionality for you.
For example, full gesture
support so that you can add-- so
that you can respond to any
gesture on iOS devices, which
allows any entity to easily
respond to user input, as well
as very realistic camera
effects, which are powered by
the render that really helped to
integrate your virtual content
into the real world.
And in fact, ARView will give
you the exact same quality and
feature set as AR Quick Look
right out of the box.
So let's take a look at some of
these camera effects in action.
So one of the most important
effects to help content feel
like it's part of the real world
is very convincing shadows,
grounding shadows.
So notice in this video how when
the shadow isn't present, it
becomes difficult to determine
where this robot is relative to
the table underneath it.
Is it floating in space, is it
sitting on these blocks, it's
really hard to tell.
But when the shadow is there, it
becomes very clear where this
robot is in 3D space.
And ARView provides two
different grounding shadowing
techniques which you can choose
from to balance performance for
your particular application.
So either a simple drop shadow,
or the much more realistic
[inaudible] shadow, which is
what you see here.
ARView automatically reads the
camera exposure time, which is
provided by ARKit to perform
camera-based motion blur on all
virtual content in your scene,
which helps to match the blur
that's already present in the
live camera feed.
I hope I don't make anybody
sick.
OK. So notice how when motion
blur is not enabled, this
content feels like it's just
stuck on top of the video feed.
Cool. We built a realistic depth
of field algorithm to model
varying camera focus, which is
again using information provided
by ARKit.
So when the device camera
focuses on a particular feature
of the world, ARView will ensure
that that virtual content
follows the same focusing
pattern.
So for this video, the focus of
the camera is continually
shifting back and forth to focus
on each of these columns
individually.
[ Applause ]
Finally ARView adds digital film
grain to the virtual content
provided by the new ARKit
feature camera grain.
And since all digital cameras
have some amount of noise and
especially in really low light
situations, adding it to your
virtual content can really help
users feel like the content is
part of that world that they're
seeing and not just something
that's stuck on top of a camera
image.
So notice here how when that
robot doesn't have any noise.
It doesn't feel like it fits in
the environment very well,
whereas when the noise comes in,
it really feels like it's
beneath the camera image and not
just on top of it.
So next let's talk about
entities which form the main
building block for any
experience that you're going to
create.
All virtual content in your
scene is an entity with
different types of components to
give it very specific
functionality.
Any entity can be parented to
any other entity, which helps to
establish the structure of a
scene and build out a transform
hierarchy, so it's easier to
reason about objects within
their local space.
So for example, if you have a
virtual table and a virtual cup
and you want that cup to sit on
the table, you might parent that
table entity to the cup entity
so that they move together in
space.
Next, let's talk about anchoring
and why it's such an important
concept in AR.
So in the real world, objects
are often in motion.
And if we're projecting virtual
content into a real environment,
adapting to that motion is
crucial for a realistic
experience.
For example, if you have content
that's anchored to an image such
as like a magazine on your
table, that content should stick
to it regardless of how that
magazine moves in the real
world.
And RealityKit solves this
problem by exposing ARKit's
anchors as first-class citizens
of the API, supporting all of
the anchoring types available
such as plane, body, face, or
camera.
And since many surfaces in the
world can be anchors for
content, we treat each of these
anchors as a local root for
entity hierarchies.
So to illustrate how anchors
work in RealityKit, let's
consider that there are
horizontal and vertical planes
in the world that we want to
attach content to such as tables
or walls.
Each of these could be utilized
as an anchor.
And all anchors can have a
hierarchy of entities that are
attached to them.
And it's important to note that
the entire hierarchy of entities
will not be active until a
matching anchor is spotted in
the world by ARKit.
So for example, if you were to
define a horizontal plane anchor
and attach entities to it, you
won't actually see those
entities in your world until
ARKit has successfully
recognized a horizontal plane.
So this prevents content from
just floating in space until all
the anchors have been found.
So at one time, new anchors can
be introduced to your scene, for
example, an image anchor, which
maybe it's being used to display
a virtual frame around a real
life photograph that you have on
your wall.
So if you decide to move that
photograph for some reason, say
you decide you just want it on a
different wall or it just needs
to be a little bit to the left,
the virtual frame will move
right along with it.
And finally, let's take a look
at the makeup of an AR scene,
any of which is going to follow
what you see here.
So you start with the ARView,
which is the entry point to your
AR world and it contains a
reference to your scene.
And a scene has different
anchors which you can add
manually as you saw before.
And every time you load a new
entity, you can attach it to the
anchor of your choosing, or to a
previously loaded entity to form
an entity hierarchy.
So in this example, we have two
anchors that each form their own
entity hierarchies.
So now given all the things
we've just seen, let's see a
live demo of some of the stuff
in action.
[ Applause ]
So what we'll be doing here is
we'll be detecting this plane in
front of me and we'll be placing
virtual content on this plane
using the procedural mesh--
procedural mesh generation
library in RealityKit.
So let's bring them out there.
And I'll also bring in some
virtual toys that are going to
interact with these boxes.
So there we go.
So notice that the physics
system is handling the
interactions between all the
different objects.
The animation system is
animating this airplane as it
flies around me.
And notice how RealityKit is
automatically handling the
lighting, the shadowing, and all
the different camera effects to
try to make this fit in the
environment as much as possible.
So this whole app is only a few
lines of code and really just
involves loading in the cubes,
loading in the meshes, and
telling RealityKit where I want
them to be.
And that's that.
[ Applause ]
So next I'd like to invite Tyler
on the stage to dive deeper into
RealityKit and talk more about
how it works.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Cody.
I'm Tyler Casella and I'll be
walking you through some of the
features available in RealityKit
and Reality Composer.
Let's dive right into it by
looking at what you'll need to
get started with your AR
application.
So as Cody showed you earlier,
RealityKit uses the entity
component design pattern to
build objects within the world.
Entities establish the structure
of your scene and build out a
transform hierarchy so that it's
easier for you to reason about
objects within their local
space.
Now if you're not familiar with
the entity component design
pattern, it's no problem, it's
actually pretty straightforward
to use.
Entities themselves are actually
comprised of many different
pieces called components.
And components defined to be the
specific behaviors and data that
can be added to individual
entities.
Now, unlike strictly
inheritance-based patterns,
using entities and components
allows you to greater use of
code and more flexibility.
It actually also provides huge
performance benefits under the
hood, both in terms of memory
layout and multithreading.
So to help illustrate entity and
components, let's take a look at
an example.
So let's say for example we have
a couple of object types that we
commonly use within our
application, like a ball, lamp,
and camera.
Now there's often many pieces of
behavior that are shared across
all of them.
Let's take for example,
anchoring.
All of these objects need to be
anchored within the world, and
so we can add an anchoring
component to all of them.
Now since both the ball and the
lamp has-- have a visual
representation, we can add a
model component to both of them
but we omit it from the camera
because it's invisible.
And this is where the
compositional aspect of entity
component design starts to
become really powerful.
Now, to allow objects to collide
with each other, we can add a
collision component to them, and
then we continue this until we
have the combination that
exhibits the behavior that we're
looking for.
And you'll notice that all of
these objects behave in very
unique ways.
But by structuring your code in
this manner, you're able to
avoid duplicating code and reuse
behavior.
So here we can see how entities
look in code.
An entity itself doesn't take
any parameters to create, but
once you have an entity, you can
start adding components to it
using the subscript operator.
And in the same manner, you're
able to remove and modify
components on these entities.
This allows you to dynamically
modify the behavior of an
entity.
Now all entities also contain
children on them and you can add
a child using the addChild
method.
And with this hierarchy, setting
entities position, you're
defining its position relative
to its parent.
Now if you're interested in its
position in the world, you can
use the set position relative to
method and define nil as that
relative entity.
And this indicates you want
world space.
Now we also understand
developers just want to get
started building their
applications, so we provide a
number of useful variations of
entities that come preconfigured
and ready to use.
These cover all of the common
usages such as establishing
anchoring, adding visual content
to your scene or dynamic lights.
And by instantiating any of
these entities, all of the
necessary components come
preconfigured and ready to use.
So let's take a look at some of
these entities and how you can
use them.
The first of which is
AnchorEntity.
And this is our glue to the real
world and often the first thing
that you're going to be
establishing within your AR
application.
AnchorEntity-- With
AnchorEntity, you specify what
it should be anchored to within
the real world.
And as that object moves in your
environment, the AnchorEntity is
going to stay attached to it.
And because of this, the
AnchorEntity is often going to
be the root of your experience
and then additional content is
built on top of it.
AnchorEntity supports all of the
anchor types available within
ARKit.
This allows you to quickly get
your content into the real
world.
For instance, you can specify an
image or an object that your
content should be glued to, and
then upon detecting that anchor
that matches your specification,
it'll automatically become
attached and appear in the
world.
And if you already have an AR
anchor or an AR raycast result,
you can anchor to that directly
as well.
So let's take a look at how you
can create anchor entities in
code.
Now when you're creating anchor
entities, you're describing what
you would like to be anchored
to.
So here I'm describing, I would
like this AnchorEntity to be
attached to a horizontal plane
that has a classification of
table and has a minimum bounds
of half a meter by half a meter.
Next, we add that anchor to the
ARView scene and once added to
the scene, the anchor doesn't
necessarily immediately become
active.
Remember, if ARKit hasn't
detected an anchor that matches
that specification, it will
remain inactive.
And then once we do detect an
anchor that matches it, both the
AnchorEntity and all of its
sub-entities will become active.
Now although AnchorEntity is
often the root entity of your
experience, there are situations
in which you're going to want
multiple of them.
Take this for example where I
have content that I would like
to be anchored to a table, but
also separate content, I would
like to be anchored to an image.
These all exist within the same
scene but I have two different
real-world objects that content
is being glued to.
Now once you've established what
you want your content to be
attached to, the next is
actually getting content in
there.
And that's where ModelEntity
comes into the picture.
And this is really the workhorse
of RealityKit.
This is what you're going to
find yourself using very often.
ModelEntity comes with all the
building blocks that you need to
integrate physics, animation,
and rendering in the virtual
world.
In entity component terms, a
ModelEntity is an entity with a
model component, a physics
component, and a collision
component.
And these entities can be
created dynamically in code or
you can load them directly from
USDZ or Reality File.
So here we're loading a
ModelEntity from a file and
you'll notice that we make the
load very explicit with the
loadModel call.
This is so that you're always
aware when you're doing
something that's potentially
heavyweight and could be
blocking the render thread.
And in all of these cases we
provide you asynchronous
variants to address that, which
we'll cover in later-- in a
later session.
Now once your model is loaded,
you simply attach it to your
anchor and you're good to go.
As soon as that anchor is
detected, your model will show
up in the world and remain
attached.
Now let's take a look at the
actual anatomy of a ModelEntity.
The first item every ModelEntity
contains is a mesh resource,
which provides the geometric
representation of the model.
Mesh resources can either be
generated directly as a
primitive or the result of
loading from a USDZ or Reality
File.
And because meshes are often
heavyweight, they can be shared
across multiple entities and
this also allows us to optimize
our rendering to match draw
calls together under the hood.
Now if you're not getting your
mesh from a file, you can also
generate them directly from a
concise set of primitives.
This includes boxes, spheres,
planes, and texts which supports
all of the fonts on our
platform.
Now although mesh has defined
the geometric structure of a
model, you still need a way to
define how a model should look.
And this is where materials come
into play.
Materials provide the look and
feel of an object and how it
interacts with the light around
it.
Now RealityKit provides
rendering that's physically
based, which means we simulate
how light actually behaves in
the real world, to help ensure
that it's going to blend
seamlessly within it.
And materials customize how an
object participates within the
simulation.
Materials can either be
predefined when you load a
ModelEntity or you can create a
material yourself with some of
the material types that we
provide in RealityKit which we
can take a look at.
The first of these is
SimpleMaterial.
Now typically a physically-based
material has a lot of
parameters, and that's because
lighting in the real world is
really complex.
Now SimpleMaterial condenses
these into a concise set of
parameters that take either
scalar inputs or a texture if
you want to vary an input across
a surface.
Simple material allows you to
create a glossy plastic or a
brushed metal or even a tinted
glass.
And you can do this with the
three main properties,
basecolor, roughness, and
metallic.
As the name implies, basecolor
establishes the overall color of
the material, allowing you to
change an object from red to
blue for example.
And a metallic parameter itself
actually simulates how
conductive that material is and
affects how the light interacts
with that surface.
So, having a metallic value of
zero indicates that it's a poor
conductor.
And this actually means that
light tends to transmit into
that surface making the color of
the subsurface dominate the
appearance.
Now if we up that parameter to
1.0, this indicates it's a good
conductor which causes an
immediate reemission of light at
the surface level.
And this is what gives it that
metallic look.
And the roughness parameter
affects that perceived roughness
of the object and how reflective
the surface appears.
Now we also have unlit material,
which also provides coloring of
an object, but unlike
SimpleMaterial, it does not
participate within the
physically-based rendering and
is unaffected by the lights in
the scene.
So this gives it an overall flat
coloring.
This is often useful for text or
any content that should remain
bright, even when the
environment is dark.
So here we can see an example of
that in usage.
Here I placed a virtual
television within the
environment and I've used
SimpleMaterial for the TV box,
but unlit material for the
actual screen.
And you'll see as I turn off the
lights, the TV dims but the
screen remains bright, and this
is because it's unaffected by
the environment's lighting.
Both SimpleMaterial and unlit
material allow for a wide range
of appearances but RealityKit
also provides a third material
that behaves very different but
it's just as important and
that's OcclusionMaterial.
Now instead of affecting in
object's appearance,
OcclusionMaterial instead masks
any objects behind it and falls
back to the camera pass through.
This gives the appearance of
objects moving behind real-world
objects.
So here we can see common usage
in which I've created a plane on
top of the real-world table and
then I've applied that
OcclusionMaterial to it.
This gives the illusion that the
object is coming up out of the
table.
And you may have noticed this
during Cody's demo as well.
Now if you don't do this, it can
often be difficult to gauge the
position of an object and can
really break that immersive
experience for the user.
So these cover basic building
blocks of ModelEntity, and we
can take a quick look of how you
can use mesh resource and
materials in code.
Here we're generating a box mesh
and all of our calls to
dynamically generate mesh
resources, use the generate
prefix convention.
And this is again to make sure
it's clear that work is being
done under the hood.
Now since materials are
lightweight and fast to
initialize, they can be created
directly from their initializer.
And once you have both your mesh
and your material, you simply
create a ModelEntity and pass
these along.
And with this, you have your
basic building block from which
you can begin building the
visual content within your AR
experience.
But if you really want to bring
it to life, you're going to want
to add animation as well.
And as Cody showed you,
RealityKit supports two primary
forms of animation, skeletal and
transform animations.
These can both be loaded from
file but transform animations
can also be created directly
within RealityKit.
Both types of animations can be
played from the playAnimation
method on all entities.
And when you play an animation,
you're given back an animation
controller object.
This controller allows you to
control the playback of the
animation.
So with it, you can pause a
playing animation to maintain
its current timing, or you can
check the current state of the
animation and resume it, or even
stop the animation.
Now if you don't have any
animations baked into your
assets directly, you can still
animate your entities with the
move to function.
With this, you first provide the
transform that you'd like to
animate to, and here we're
moving 5 meters forward.
And then you optionally define
the relative space that
transform is in.
Here it's in the world space, so
I provide nil.
Next you provide the duration
that you'd like the animation to
take place, and then the easing
function to define how smooth
that animation should be from
start to finish.
And with that, you've created a
simple transform animation.
So by combining all of these
together, RealityKit focuses on
enabling you to build AR
experiences.
And this year, in addition to a
new framework, we're also
introducing a new tool to
accompany your AR development
workflow, and that's Reality
Composer.
We're introducing Reality
Composer for both macOS
available in Xcode 11, in iPad
and iPhone available in the App
Store.
And with Reality Composer, we're
really focusing on helping iOS
developers to easily create AR
and 3D experiences.
We know that moving to 3D can be
a really daunting task, and with
Reality Composer we want you to
feel right at home building out
your AR scenes.
There's a number of features
that we've integrated into the
tool to help you with this,
which we can dive into.
Now one of the first things that
you tackle when you're starting
a new project is often simply
just getting stuff into the
world.
And we wanted to make sure this
was easy, by already providing
you a set of content that you
can either directly integrate
into your scene or you can use
as a placeholder until you land
your final content.
This library ranges from simple
shapes to common objects to even
large buildings.
And these aren't static assets
either.
Here we have a spiral shape,
which provides a number of
parameters that give you a
flexible range of creativity.
Here I'm able to take it and
extrude it and compress it and
then apply an aluminum material
to it to really give it the look
and feel of a metal spring.
And we provide rich models as
well that you can integrate your
own content into directly, such
as this picture frame.
Here I'm able to pick a photo
and then place it within it and
then pick and choose a different
frame that matches the style of
the experience that I'm
building.
Reality Composer also gives you
a "what you see is what you get"
environment, making it easy for
you to lay out and pre-visualize
your scenes, as you're building
it.
Here I'm able to duplicate the
row of pawns and swap out their
appearance to build out the
other side of the chessboard.
And a big part of
pre-visualization is actually
seeing your content in AR so
that you can ensure that it's
correctly scaled and fits well
within that real-world
environment.
Now reality composer also allows
you to add behavior into your
scene and provide simple
interactions that help bring
that AR experience to life.
So let's walk through a quick
example.
Here I've got a chessboard that
I'd like to make an interaction
in, where I'd like to make it so
that when I tap the black rook
at the top, it will move over
and put the king into check
mate.
So my first step is to open up
the behavior panel and add a new
behavior.
Now there's a number of
predefined behaviors provided,
so I'll go ahead and pick tap to
flip.
Now, this gives me a tap
trigger, which will cause a
sequence of actions to play,
which currently plays an
emphasis animation on my rook.
For my interaction, I'm going to
modify the motion type to
instead be a jiggle instead of a
flip.
Next, I'll add a move by action
to move that rook into place and
I'll adjust my movement just
slightly.
And now we're good to go and I
can preview my interaction.
Now when I tap on my rook, it
does a little jiggle, and then
it moves over to put the king
into checkmate.
[ Applause ]
So with all of these features,
we really wanted it to be easy
for you to make great looking
content ready to view and
experience in AR.
And all of these features that
I've shown you here on the iPad
are also available on macOS and
iPhone.
Now although Reality Composer
runs as a separate application,
it's tightly integrated within
Xcode's development and
ecosystem.
When building your Xcode
project, the content within your
project is integrated and
optimized into your application.
But there's some magic that
happens in between building your
Xcode project and producing your
application.
And that's code generation.
As part of this step, the
content from your project is
compiled and optimized into a
Reality File.
And next we introspect that file
and generate customized code for
accessing objects that you've
created within your scene.
Now this code generation step is
performed automatically behind
the scenes by Xcode and
establishes a strongly typed
access to the content within
your scene.
And this has the wonderful
advantage that if there's any
mismatches between the naming of
the objects in your scene, you
get a compilation error instead
of a runtime crash.
Code generation also gives you
direct access to invoke triggers
within the behaviors of your
scene and create custom actions
within your code.
We feel that with this-- the
experience of building content
in Reality Composer and coding
in Xcode is seamless.
And that's a quick overview of
Reality Composer.
Now there's a ton more I'd love
to show you, because we've
really only covered the tip of
the iceberg today.
There's many other areas that I
haven't tackled like networking,
physics bodies, ray casting,
gestures and more, so I
encourage you to come to some of
our other sessions.
Tomorrow at 10:00 a.m., we have
the Building Apps with Reality
Composer session, which is going
to showcase how to build an AR
application which is multiplayer
in RealityKit.
And Thursday at 11:00 a.m., we
have the building AR Experiences
with Reality Composer session,
which explores how you can
integrate Reality Composer into
your AR application workflow.
And please come join us in the
labs tomorrow at noon.
We're happy to answer any
questions you may have and help
get you started.
So thank you for coming.
And I hope you have a great
WWDC.
[ Applause ]