[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
[ Applause ]
Thank you so much for coming.
This is a deep dive session for
ARKit.
We'll be showing you how we're
bringing people into AR.
My name is Adrian.
And, I'll be joined onstage by
Tanmay.
Earlier this week, Apple
announced the RealityKit
framework.
This is a new framework for
rendering photorealistic
content.
It has also been built from the
ground up to support AR.
We also held a What's New
session for ARKit 3, where we
showed you many of the cool
features that we're bringing
into ARKit this year.
And, for this deep dive, we're
going to focus on two of these.
First, I'll be showing you how
people occlusion works.
And then, I'm going to hand it
over to Tanmay to give you the
deep dive of how motion capture
works.
So, let's begin.
What is people occlusion?
In ARKit today, we're already
able to position rendered
content in the real world.
However, if we look at the video
behind me, we can see that
something is clearly wrong.
What we would expect, is for the
person closer to the camera to
occlude the rendered content as
it moves behind him.
And, with people occlusion,
we're bringing just that.
We're enabling rendered content
and people to correctly occlude
each other in the scene.
And, to understand what we need
to do in order to enable that,
I'm going to break down a frame.
So, here we have the camera
image, and we have two people
standing around a table.
And, we want to place a rendered
object on top of this table.
So far, for ARKit 2, the way we
position rendered content is by
simply overlaying it on the
image.
And, when we do it this way, we
see that we end up with an
incorrect occlusion.
This is not what we would
expect.
And, we want to turn that red
cross into a green checkmark.
So, the way we do that is, we
need to understand there's a
person closer to the camera than
the rendered object.
And, when we do so, we correctly
make sure that the rendered
object gets occluded.
And, this is essentially a depth
ordering problem.
And, in order to understand how
we're going to solve this, I'm
going to decompose the scene.
So, here's the same image in an
oblique angle, and let's explode
the scene and look at the
different depth planes that we
have.
We can see that we have
different things in different
depth planes, mixing real and
rendered.
And, here we have each person in
their own depth plane, with the
rendered object in between.
For rendered content, the
graphics pipeline already knows
exactly where it is, simply by
using a depth buffer.
And, in order for us to also do
the same thing for the real
content, we need to understand
where the people are in the
scene.
And, in order to enable this,
we're adding two new buffers.
We're adding the segmentation
buffer, which tells you, per
pixel, where a person is in this
scene.
And, we're also giving you a
corresponding depth buffer which
tells you where that person is
in depth.
Now, the amazing thing about
this feature is that the way
we're generating these buffers
is by leveraging the power of
the A12 chip and using machine
learning in order to generate
these buffers, using only the
camera image.
And so, these two new buffers
will be exposed on the ARFrame
as two new properties, the
segmentationBuffer, and the
estimatedDepthData.
Since we want to use these
buffers for people occlusion, we
also have to have them generated
at the same cadence as the
camera frame.
So, when your camera frame is
running at 60 frames a second,
we are also able to generate
these buffers for you at 60
frames a second.
We would also like these buffers
to be at the same resolution as
the camera image.
However, in order to enable this
in real time, the neural network
only sees a smaller image.
And so, if you take the output
of the neural network, and we
magnify it, we will see that
there's a lot of detail that the
neural network just simply did
not see.
So, in order to compensate for
this, we're doing some
additional processing.
We're applying matting.
And, what matting does is, it's
basically using the
segmentationBuffer as a guide,
and then looking at the camera
image in order to figure out
what the missing detail was.
And now, with a matted image,
we're able to correctly extract
the people from the scene, and
together with the
estimatedDepthData, we can then
position them in the correct
depth plane.
Finally letting us solve the
depth ordering problem, and we
can then recompose the scene.
Now, this is a lot of
technology, and we want to make
it as easy as possible for you
developers to adopt this.
So, we're enabling this feature
in three different ways.
First, we have RealityKit, the
new framework that we announced
this Dub-dub.
However, if you've already been
using SceneKit, and we also
added support for people
occlusion using the ARCSNView.
And, in case you have your own
renderer, or you're working with
a third-party rendering, we're
giving you the building blocks
to enable incorporating people
occlusion into your own app
using the power of Metal.
So, let's look at how we'd do it
in RealityKit.
RealityKit is the recommended
way if you're going to build a
new AR app.
It has a new UI element called
the ARView, which enables you--
gives you an easy-to-use API
that brings photorealism to AR,
further blending the border
between the real and the
rendered content.
It also has built-in support for
people occlusion.
And, if you attended the What's
New session, you have already
seen a live demo of how you can
enable people occlusion in
ARView.
And so, for this deep dive,
we'll do a quick recap.
Let's look at some code.
So, here I have my viewDidLoad
function in my view controller.
And, the first thing I need to
do is to make sure that it's
future supported.
I do that by checking my
configuration, shown as my
WorldTrackingConfiguration.
And, I need to look for a new
property called FrameSemantics.
And, the FrameSemantics we're
going to use to enable people
occlusion is
personSegmentationWithDepth.
Once I know that this is
supported on my configuration,
the only thing I have to do is
set the FrameSemantics on my
configuration, and then, when
the session starts running, the
ARView will automatically pick
this up, and enable people
occlusion for my AR application.
So, all we had to do was really
to change our configuration,
using the new property that
we're introducing for this year,
FrameSemantics.
And, as you saw in the previous
example, I was using
personSegmentationWithDepth.
But, we can also do only
PersonSegmentation in case you
want to enable a weatherman-like
experience.
Now, ARView is the recommended
way for using people occlusion.
And, the reason is, it has a
deep renderer integration.
And, what that means is the
entire graphics pipeline is
aware that there are people in
the scene.
And, it's therefore able to also
handle transparent objects when
you're using this feature.
It's doing this while also being
built for optimal performance.
And, if you're wondering what
kind of experiences you can
enable using people occlusion
and RealityKit, I would like to
play a short video for you.
[ Music ]
This is Swiftstrike.
It's a really cool demo that
we're showing right here in
Dub-dub, and I urge everyone to
check it out if you haven't done
so already.
So, what if you've been using
SceneKit?
Well, let's look at how I would
enable people occlusion for
SceneKit.
If you've already been using
ARSCNView, we're enabling people
occlusion in very much the same
way we're enabling for
RealityKit.
All we have to do is set the
FrameSemantics on our
configuration, and the ARSCNView
will automatically pick this up.
However, there's a difference
between the SceneKit
implementation and RealityKit,
where SceneKit does a
post-processing composition.
And, what that means for you
concretely is it may not work as
well with transparent objects,
depending on how you write
depth.
Finally, what if I have my own
rendering engine?
Well, we want to enable you to
incorporate people occlusion
into your own rendering engine,
or a third-party rendering
engine.
And, what this gives you is
complete control over the
composition.
We want to give you as much
flexibility as possible, while
still giving you easy-to-use API
in order to incorporate this
great feature.
So, before I show you how we do
this, let's do a quick review.
We had the segmentationBuffer
that came out of the neural
network, that was working on a
smaller image.
And then, we applied matting in
order to recapture some of that
missing detail.
Well, when we do our custom
composition, we're providing a
new class that will generate
this matte for you, using the
power of Metal, giving you the
matte as a texture for you to
incorporate into your own
pipeline.
Let's look at an example of how
we can do just that.
So, here I have my custom
composition function.
And, the first thing I do is to
make sure whether this feature
is supported.
And, once I've done that, all I
have to do is call
generateMatte, and I give it the
frame and the commandBuffer, and
it gives me back the Metal
texture that I can then use when
I do my own custom composition,
and finally schedule everything
to the GPU.
So, the class that we're
bringing to ARKit is called
ARMatteGenerator, and as you saw
in the example, it takes the
ARFrame and the commandBuffer,
and it gives you back a texture
that you can use.
However, we're not done yet.
Just like the segmentationBuffer
was of a lower resolution, the
estimatedDepthData is also
lower, and if we simply magnify
it, and overlay it on our matted
image, we will see that there
might be a mismatch.
We can have depth values where
there's no alpha value in the
matte, and more importantly, we
can have alpha values in the
matte where there's no
corresponding depth value.
Now, since the matte has already
recaptured some of the missing
detail, we can't really modify
the alpha itself.
Instead, we need to modify the
depth buffer.
So, let's go back to my previous
example, and see how we do just
that.
So, here we have the line where
I added-- we generated the matte
in order for me to use for my
custom composition.
And so I add an addition
function call to
generateDilatedDepth.
And, much in the same way, it
takes the frame in the command
buffer, and gives me back a
texture.
And, if you look at the API, it
looks very similar to how we
generated the matte, giving us
the texture, taking the frame
and the command buffer.
And, what this does is ensures
that for every alpha value we
find in the matte, we will have
a corresponding depth value that
we can then use when we do our
final composition.
So, with the dilated depth, and
the matte, we're now finally
able to move on to composition.
Composition is usually done on
the GPU in the fragment shader.
So, let's look at an example
shader of how I bring everything
together.
I begin by doing what we would
usually do for an AR experience.
I sample the camera image, as
well as the rendered texture,
but since we're going to do
occlusion, I'm also sampling the
rendered depth.
And then, I do what I would
usually do in AR, I simply
overlay the rendered content on
the real image, given the
rendered alpha.
The new part, in order to enable
people occlusion, is I also
sample my matte, and my
dilatedDepth.
And then, I make sure to compare
the dilatedDepth with the
renderedDepth.
And, if I find that there's
something in the dilatedDepth
that's closer to the camera,
meaning that there might be a
person there, I then mix the
camera back, given the value of
the matte.
However, if the render content
is closer to the camera, I
simply do what we always do, and
have the render content overlaid
on top of it.
And, with all of this, we're
finally able to do people
occlusion in our own custom
renderer.
[ Applause ]
Since this feature is using the
neural engine, and machine
learning, it's supported on A12
devices and later.
It also works best in indoor
environments.
And, in all the videos you saw,
you saw people standing in the
scene, but this feature also
works for your own hands and
feet.
It also works for multiple
people in the scene.
Before I hand it over to Tanmay
to show you all about motion
capture, let's do a quick recap.
So, with people occlusion, we're
enabling correct occlusion
between rendered and real
content for people.
The recommended way, if you're
building a new app, is to use
RealityKit and ARView, since
this does the deep integration.
If you already have an app using
SceneKit, we've also added
support for people occlusion in
the ARSCNView.
And, if you have your own
renderer, we're providing you
with a new API called the
ARMatteGenerator, so you can do
your own compositing and
incorporating into your own
renderer.
And, with that, I'd like to hand
it over to Tanmay to give you a
deep dive into motion capture.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Adrian.
Hello everyone.
I'm Tanmay, and today I'm going
to introduce you to this new
piece of technology that we are
bringing this year, motion
capture.
[ Applause ]
So, what is motion capture?
It's just a process of capturing
movement of people.
You see a person, you capture
all the movements, and you use
that motion to animate a virtual
character so that the character
performs the same set of actions
as the person you're looking at.
And, we're trying to enable this
technology in your applications.
Now, let's dive in.
We would like the character to
mimic the person that you're
looking at.
But, before we do that, we need
to understand what exactly are
we trying to animate?
What does a character entail?
So, this is an example of a
virtual character.
Let's take an x-ray of it and
see what's inside it.
You can see that it has two main
components.
The outer coating, which is
called a mesh.
And, the bony structure inside,
which is called a skeleton.
And, these two combined together
give you the complete character.
The skeleton is the driving
force behind the entire
character.
It contains all the limbs that
we use for motion, just like
people.
And so, in order to animate a
character, we need to animate
the skeleton with the same
motion.
So, what's the first step here?
We have a person.
And, the first step here is to
have the skeleton mimic this
person.
And, this is what it looks like.
And, once the skeleton moves,
the character follows suit.
And, you have the entire virtual
character mimicking you
automatically.
So, how do we do it?
How do we animate this skeleton?
Given this image, we use machine
learning technology to first
estimate the pose of the person
in the image.
And, we use that pose to build a
full-fledged, high-fidelity
skeleton.
And, finally, we use this
skeleton, and combine it with a
mesh to give you the final
character.
And, we interface all of this,
everything that you're looking
here, through ARKit.
To get a complete overview, we
are introducing the technology
of motion capture in this year's
ARKit.
And, with that, you can track
movement of people in real time,
on your devices.
It works seamlessly with
RealityKit, which gives you the
ability to drive animated
characters, and render them on
your screens.
It's powered by machine learning
and runs smoothly on Apple
Neural Engine.
And, we have made it available
on A12 devices and beyond.
So, now you have this
technology, what can you use it
for?
What can you enable with it?
Well, for starters, you can
always have a virtual character
follow and track a person.
You can have your own puppet in
AR.
And, this is something that we
enable out of the box.
But, beyond that, there are a
lot of other use cases as well,
that you can enable with it.
For example, you can enhance it
further by creating your own
models for detecting what
actions people are doing.
You can use it to build tools
for analyzing motions like how
good a golf swing is, or is your
posture correct, or are you
performing an exercise in a
correct way or not?
Also, now since a person has a
virtual presence in the scene,
you can enable interaction with
any virtual object that you
like.
And, it's supported for all the
virtual objects present in the
scene.
And, finally, you can also use
it for image and video
analytics.
Because we also provide 2D
version of the skeleton as well
in image space, and you can
build it to use editing tools,
or for semantic image
understanding.
And, this doesn't even cover the
entire set of possibilities that
you can enable with it remotely.
There are so many other things
that you can do with it.
Now, let me show you how you can
leverage motion capture for your
applications.
Depending on the use cases, we
have three different ways of
using it.
The first one is motion capture
in RealityKit.
If you just want to quickly
animate a character, this
high-level API will help you get
there.
If you want to enable advanced
use cases, like activity
recognition, analysis, or
interaction with 3D objects in a
scene, we've also provided
low-level APIs to extract each
and every element of the
skeleton.
And, it's for you to use it.
And, finally, if your use case
requires 2D versions of the
skeleton in image space, maybe
for doing semantic image
analysis, or for editing tools,
or for something else, we've
provided access to that as well.
So, let's get started with
motion capture in RealityKit.
As you all know, we introduced
RealityKit this year, and given
our API in RealityKit, in just
few lines of code, you can track
a person and add a character to
mimic.
We've provided a very simple and
easy-to-use API for this
purpose.
You can add your own custom
characters as well, based on the
structure of our provided
example.
So, you can use any mesh, any
character that you want,
provided that it is based on the
structure of our provided
example in the sample bundle.
Finally, the tracked person is
very easy to access here, via an
element called AnchorEntities,
which are basically just
building blocks of the scene.
And, it automatically gathers
all the required transforms that
we need for motion capture.
So, to start with, every element
of motion capture that you get
in ARView, which as you all
know, is the main UI element
combining AR and RealityKit
together, is powered by a new
configuration called
ARBodyTrackingConfiguration.
And, once you enable this, you
start adding anchors containing
bodies, and this entire thing is
encapsulated in a special type
of anchor entity called
bodyTrackedEntity.
So, let me give you a brief
description of what this
bodyTrackedEntity actually is.
A body tracked entity represents
one single person.
It contains the underlying
skeleton and its position.
It's tracked in real time and
gets updated every frame.
And, finally it combines the
skeleton to a given [inaudible]
mesh automatically and give you
the complete character.
Now, let's go to the code to
animate a character quickly, and
you'll see how easy it is.
You just have to follow three
steps.
The first step is to load a
character.
To automatically load a tracked
human, asynchronously, you just
need to call
entity.loadBodyTrackedAsync
function.
And, you can use .sync to either
catch errors in the received
completion block, or if
everything works fine, you can
get your character in the
received value block.
And, this character is of the
type bodyTrackedEntity.
We have a file called robot.usdz
in our sample code bundle, and
if you provided the file bot to
this file, it will automatically
add the skeleton to the robot
mesh, and provide you with a
character.
So, moving on, the second step
is to get the location where you
would like to put your character
on.
For example, let's say, if you
would like to put the character
right on top of the person that
you are tracking, you can get
the location by using
AnchorEntity with the argument
.body.
And, please note that this is
just an example, and it can be
any other location as well, be
it on the floor, on a tabletop,
or anywhere else.
You just have to provide an
anchor containing that location.
And, the character will still
mimic the person.
And, finally, just add your
character to the location, and
voila.
You can drive your character.
It's that simple.
So, you might be wondering that,
how can you replace this robot
with any other custom character
that you like?
Like I said before, we have a
file called robot.usdz.
And, this usdz file has an
entire structure.
And, if your custom model
follows the same structure, then
you can use it.
And, just to let you know that
the underlying skeleton that we
provide is a very high-fidelity
skeleton consisting of 91
joints.
And, for your information, here
are all of them.
It's a lot, right?
And, these are just regular
joints, contained in arms, legs,
and so on.
And, if your character follows
this naming scheme, you can use
it directly in RealityKit.
That was a quick and easy way to
load a tracked person and drive
the character.
Now, let's move on to low-level
APIs for advanced access.
Here we will provide you with
access to each and every element
of the skeleton.
And, we interface it through a
very easy-to-use API.
You can enable all those
advanced use cases that we
discussed earlier, which
requires either using the
skeleton data for analysis, or
as an input to your models.
And, finally the skeleton that
we provide is contained in a new
type of anchor that we're
introducing, called
ARBodyAnchor.
And, ARBodyAnchor is the
starting point of the entire
data structure that we provide.
And, this is what the data
structure looks like.
We have ARBodyAnchor on the top,
and it contains all the skeletal
elements.
So, let's just walk through this
structure, and start at the top.
ARBodyAnchor is just a regular
anchor.
It contains a geometry.
And, in this case, the geometry
itself is the skeleton.
And, this is what the skeleton
looks like.
It consists of nodes and edges,
just like any other geometry.
It also contains a transform.
And, this transform is just the
location of the anchor in
rotation and translation matrix
form.
Accessing the skeleton is what
we're interested in here,
mainly.
So, let's just get right into
it.
What is this skeleton that we
are showing you?
It's a geometry, composed of
nodes, which represent the
joints, the green points and the
yellow points that you see here.
And, it contains edges, which
represent the bones, the white
lines that you see here.
They show you how the joints are
connected.
And, once all the joints are
connected, you form this entire
geometry.
We call this skeleton as
ARSkeleton, and you can simply
access it by using skeleton
property of ARBodyAnchor.
The root node of this skeleton,
the topmost point in this
geometry in the geometry
hierarchy, is the hip joint,
which you can see here.
So, let's move on and have a
look at its structural
definition.
Definition, what we call here,
is just a property of the
skeleton, containing two
components.
The names of all the joints
present in the skeleton, and the
connections between them, which
show you how to connect those
joints together.
So, let's just have a look at
both of these properties.
Here, we are labeling some of
the joints in the skeleton, and
as you can see, that these
joints have semantically
meaningful names, like left
shoulder, right shoulder, left
hand, right hand, and so on.
Similar to people.
Here I would like to point out
that the green points are the
ones that we control and are
estimated from the person that
you're looking at, and the
yellow ones are not tracked.
They just follow the motion of
the closest green parent.
Zooming in, focus on the right
arm, and consider these three
joints.
Right hand, right elbow and
right shoulder.
They follow a parent-child
relationship.
So, your hand is a child of
elbow.
And elbow is a child of
shoulder.
And, this continues for rest of
the skeleton as well, thus
giving you the complete
hierarchy.
We know now what all the joints
are called, and how to connect
them.
But, how do we get their
locations?
We've provided two ways to
access the locations of all the
joints.
The first one is relative to its
parent.
If you want the location of your
right hand relative to the
elbow, you can have that
transform by calling
localTransform function, and
provide it with the argument
.rightHand.
And, if you want to transform
relative to the root, which in
our case is the hip joint, you
can call modelTransform
function, and provide, again,
same argument, .rightHand.
Now, if you don't want to access
the transforms of all the joints
individually, but instead you
want a list containing
transforms of all the joints,
you can also do that by simply
using localTransforms property
and modelTransforms property.
This will give you a list of
transforms of all the joints.
And, if you want that relative
to the parent, you can use
localTransforms, and if you want
relative to the root, you can
use modelTransforms.
So, now that we had a good look
over the skeleton, let's go to
the code and learn how to use
each and every element.
You start by iterating over all
the anchors in the scene.
And, just look for the
bodyAnchor.
Once you have the bodyAnchor,
you might want to know where
that bodyAnchor is located in
the world.
And, you can use the transform
property of the bodyAnchor to
get that.
And, since in our geometry, hip
is the root, so the
bodyAnchor.transform will give
you the world position of the
hip joint.
Once you have the transform of
the anchor, you might need to
access the geometry of the
anchor, and you can do that by
using skeleton property of the
anchor.
Once you have this geometry, you
need all the joints.
You need all the nodes.
And, to get a list of transforms
of all the joints, that is the
list of locations of all the
joints, you can simply use
jointModelTransforms property of
the skeleton.
Once you have this list, you can
iterate over this list and
access transform of every
element.
Or, every joint, in this case.
So, iterating over all the
joints, you can access the
parentIndex of each joint by
using the parentIndices property
in the definition.
And, just check if the parent is
not the root.
Because the root is the topmost
point of the hierarchy, so it
doesn't have a parent.
So, if the parent is not the
root, you can access the
transform of the parent by using
the same jointTransforms list,
but just index it with the
parentIndex.
And, that's it.
This gives you every child pair
in the entire hierarchy, and
once you have every child-parent
pair in the hierarchy, you have
the entire hierarchy of the
skeleton.
And, you can now use it however
you want.
So, let's just run this code.
Let's just take this, and simply
draw the skeleton, and see what
it looks like.
This is what it looks like.
All we did was, we took the
entire hierarchy.
We took all parent-child points,
and we just drew the skeleton,
that's it.
And, it starts to mimic the
person automatically.
And, this is the most basic
thing that you can do, because
once you have this entire
skeleton hierarchy, you can use
it for many other use cases that
we discussed earlier.
This technology is at your
disposal, wherever your
imagination takes you.
So far, we've only talked about
3D objects in world space.
But, in case you want 2D
versions of the skeleton in
image space, we have provided an
API for that as well.
Here, we provide you with
detailed access to each and
every element in 2D space.
We also provide all the skeleton
joints as normalized image
coordinates.
We have a very easy to use API
for this as well.
And, you can use it for semantic
image analysis, or for building
editing tools both for images
and videos.
And, finally this entire
structure is interfaced through
an object called ARBody2D.
And, this is what ARBody2D
object looks like when
visualized.
ARBody2D object contains the
entire skeletal structure.
And, this is what the structure
looks like.
So, you have the object itself
on the top.
And then, again, similar to its
3D counterpart, all the skeletal
elements under that object.
So, let's walk through this
structure, and just learn about
these elements quickly.
Starting with the ARBody2D
object on top, there are two
ways that you can access this
object.
If you're already working in 2D
space, the default way is to
access it via ARFrame.
And, you can simply do that by
using detectedBody property of
the ARFrame.
And, here the person is an
instance of ARBody2D object.
For your convenience, if you're
already working in 3D space, if
you're already working with a 3D
skeleton, and for some reason,
you want the corresponding 2D
skeleton in image space as well,
we have provided a direct way to
access it by simply using
referenceBody property of
ARBodyAnchor.
And, this gives you the ARBody2D
object as well.
After accessing the ARBody2D
object, we can extract skeleton
from it by simply using skeleton
property, and this is the
visualization of that skeleton.
So, like I said, this skeleton
is present in normalized image
space.
So, if this is your image grid,
and the top left is 0,0 and
bottom right is 1,1, all the
points on this diagram are in
the range of 0 and 1.
Both in x and y direction.
The green points that you see
here are called landmarks.
Note that here we don't call
them joints, although they do
represent joints.
We just call them landmarks,
because they are pixel locations
on image.
Similar to the 3D version, it
contains an object called
definition, describing what the
landmarks are called in the
skeleton, and how to connect
those landmarks.
In this skeleton there are 16
joints, and similar to 3D, they
have semantically meaningful
names like left shoulder, right
shoulder, left hand, right hand,
and so on.
The root node is still the hip
joint here.
Again, similar to the 3D.
So, focusing on the right arm,
we can see that the hand is a
child of right elbow, and elbow
is a child of right shoulder.
And, this is, again, similar
parent-child relationship that
you saw in the 3D version as
well.
And, the similar hierarchy is
formed here.
So, having all that information
with us, let's quickly walk
through this structure via code
now.
We start with accessing ARBody2D
object.
So, once you have your ARFRame,
you can simply use detectedBody
property to get ARBody2D object.
And now, once you have ARBody2D
object, you can access the
entire skeletal structure from
underneath it.
You can extract the geometry by
using person.skeleton.
In this case, person refers to
the ARBody2D object.
And, the definition of the
skeleton, which again, comprises
of the names of all the joints,
and the information of how to
connect those joints, is present
in the definition, which you can
access it by using definition
property of the skeleton.
Once you have this information,
you might need to know where
those landmarks are located.
And, similar to the 3D version,
we have a property called
jointLandmarks, which gives you
a list of locations of all those
green points that you see here.
But, please note that, in this
case, the green points are in
2D, so they're in image space.
They're normalized pixel
coordinates.
And, once you have that list,
you can iterate over all these
landmarks.
And, for each landmark, you can
access its parent by calling
parentIndices property in the
definition.
And, again, just check if the
parent is not the root, because
the root is the topmost point of
the hierarchy.
And, if the parent is not the
root, you can access its
transform by using
jointLandmarks list, and
indexing it with the
parentIndex.
And, again, in this way, you
have the transforms of every
child-parent pair in the
skeletal hierarchy.
And, you can, again, use it
however you want, and you can
continue from here and build
your own ideas, which brings us
to the conclusion.
We've introduced motion capture
in AR this year.
We've provided access to tracked
person in real time.
We have provided both 3D and 2D
skeletons for you guys to use
it, and that is how we interface
the pose of the person.
We've enabled character
animation out of the box.
And, it runs seamlessly in
RealityKit.
We have a RealityKit API that we
discussed earlier for quickly
animating a character, and like
I mentioned earlier as well, you
can use your own custom
characters as well, as long as
it's based on the structure of
our provided example.
And, we've provided an ARKit API
for all the advanced use cases
that you might think of, like
recognition tasks, or analysis
tasks.
And, that brings us to the end
of the session.
We presented two new features in
this session, person occlusion,
and motion capture.
And, we've provided APIs for
both of these features.
For more information from
today's session, please visit
our website, and please feel
free to download the sample code
and use it.
We will be in the lab tomorrow,
so come visit us to get all your
questions answered.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.