[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to the Metal for Pro
Apps session.
My name is Eugene, and together
with Dileep and Brian, we'll be
talking about utilizing Metal to
enable new workflows and unleash
all the power of Macs and iPads
for your Pro applications.
But what is a Pro App?
We at Apple define it as an
application used by creative
professionals in the content
making business.
That includes animators and live
TV, photography, 3D animation,
print media, and audio
production.
Additionally, it includes both
first party as well as
third-party apps created by
developers like you.
These are apps such as Autodesk
Maya for 3D animation rigging
and visual effects or maybe
Logic Pro for audio and music
production.
Serif Labs Affinity Photo for
professional image editing or
Black Magic's DaVinci Resolve,
professional application for
video editing.
Pro apps have always been an
important of our ecosystem, and
with the recent release of the
new Mac Pro our new Pro Display
XDR robust support for external
GPU's and the new A12X
bionic-powered iPad pro.
We really doubled down on our
focus and commitment in this
space.
So why are pro apps different
from other workloads?
One key thing is that they
operate on really large assets.
This includes up to 8K video,
billions of polygons, thousands
of photos, hundreds of audio
tracks.
They also require a lot of CPU
and GPU horsepower.
Finally, there is always the
challenge of achieving real-time
interaction while maintaining
the full fidelity of the
original content.
So let's go to the agenda of
today's talk.
First, we'll introduce the video
editing pipeline on our
platforms and discuss how to
optimize it for groundbreaking
8K.
Next, we'll talk about how you
can add HDR support to your app.
Then, we show you how to scale
across all CPU ports and GPU
channels.
And finally, we'll discuss how
to achieve most efficient data
transfers.
So let's start by talking about
the video editing pipeline with
8K content in mind.
We at Apple find video editing
as one of the most demanding and
creative workloads.
So we will use video apps as a
use case to show how Metal helps
you.
But before we start, I'd like to
give a huge thanks to our
friends at Black Magic Design.
We've been working with them
really closely optimizing both
DaVinci Resolve and our platform
to unleash new 8K workflows, and
we're really proud of what we
have achieved together.
But let's see how it all worked
before when we first tried 8K
raw content.
You see the result is not real
time.
We have heavy stuttering, and
the experience is not great.
So that doesn't work.
Let's see how professionals
worked around this problem.
So they have huge raw footage in
8K.
First, they transcoded to get
all the color base.
Then they sub-sampled and
downscaled it to 4K proxy.
So they can apply edits and
affects in real time, but there
is one really important catch.
You cannot color grade proxy
data simply because it's not
accurate.
So now you have to go back and
apply all of your edits to the
original content, run an offline
render job which may take hours.
Review it with your director and
then rinse and repeat.
We at Apple want to make it
faster for our users.
We really want all the
professionals to work straight
in 8K content out of the box.
So let me tell you the story of
how we enabled real time video
editing in 8K.
So it starts with building an
efficient video editing
pipeline.
We'll cover the general design
of an efficient pipeline, what
frameworks to use, and how to
maximize all the available
hardware.
Then, we'll discuss how to
manage real large assets.
And finally, we'll tell you
about some challenges you might
face trying to maintain a
predictable frame rate and how
to overcome them.
So let's dive into the video
editing pipeline.
Here are typical building blocks
most video editing apps need to
have.
So we start by reading the
content, then we need to decode
it so we can process it.
And finally, present or encode.
In today's session, I'll be
focusing on the decode process,
encode and display blocks.
We will be covering the import
and export blocks which
typically use AVFoundation
framework.
I encourage you to check out our
samples on AVAssetReader and
AVAssetWriter.
Let's dive in how to make
decoding part closer to Metal.
Apple provides a flexible
low-level framework called Video
Toolbox to achieve efficient,
high-performance video
processing.
It can be used on iOS, macOS,
and tvOS, supports a huge number
of formats and leverages any
available hardware on our
devices.
The building block for the
decode is a decompression
session, and let me quickly show
you how to set it up.
First, we specify that we want
to use hardware video
decoding.
Then we create a session for
each video stream.
We set it up with a completion
handler here.
While we go through our video
stream we call decode frame with
an async flag.
This is really important to make
the call a non-blocking one.
Apple frame decode completion,
our callback is going to be
called.
And finally please don't forget
to clean up after you are done.
So now we know how to decompress
our frames.
Now let's talk about how to make
sure that we are doing it in a
most optimal way.
Your Mac might have set several
hardware decoding blocks
available.
To make sure we are using the
same physical memory with zero
copies we'll leverage an
internal object called an
IOSurface.
IOSurface is a hardware
accelerated image buffer with
GPU residency tracking.
It also gives you interprocess
and interframework access to the
same GPU memory so it's perfect
for this scenario.
Core Video and Metal provides
you an easy way to leverage the
benefits of IOSurface using an
object called
CVMetalTextureCache.
Let's see how to set it up.
So here we create our
CVMetalTextureCache, and we want
to make sure we use the Metal
device we're going to be using
for pixel processing.
So next whenever we get a new CV
pixel buffer, we need to turn it
into a Metal texture.
It happens automatically at zero
cost if our pixel buffer is
backed by an IOSurface.
Finally, don't forget to clean
up your textures and pixel
buffers to ensure proper reuse
in the texture cache.
So now we have our frame as an
MTL texture, and we are ready to
do some pixel processing.
Here we have several options.
Of course, we can write our own
processing and grading kernels
and it's really easy since
Metal's shader language is
C++ based.
At the same time, we highly
encourage you to use Metal
performance shaders to do your
pixel processing.
You can even build your own
neural network as part of your
pipeline.
Now let's see how to use MPS to
run a typical blur filter.
So we start with the Metal queue
and the common buffer.
We create a Gaussian blur
kernel, one of many built into
MPS.
And now, we can attempt to
encode the work in place and we
provide a fallback allocator in
the case it fails.
And, finally, we commit our
common buffer.
MPS is a really powerful
framework tuned for every device
on our platform.
We encourage you to read more
and start using it.
So we are done with the pixel
processing and we are ready to
encode our MTL texture to the
output format.
Of course, we will again use
Video Toolbox here and let me
show you how to do that in the
most efficient way.
Your new Mac Pro might have
several GPU's and each of them
might have more than one
encoding engine.
Of course, we can let Video
Toolbox be the best available
device, but in many cases you'll
want to specify a device
explicitly to minimize copy
overhead.
So let's see how we do this and
how to use CVPixelBufferPool to
keep memory recycled.
So here is how we get a list of
all available encoders.
First, we use the enable
hardware flag to ensure we are
leveraging hardware encoding.
Then, we tell Video Toolbox
which device we want to use.
This is a critical step to
ensure we're encoding on the
same device we did our pixel
processing.
Another great thing here is we
can use CVPixelBufferPool to get
the surfaces in the exact format
used by the hardware encoder.
So this is how we get a buffer
from the pool and then we use
MetalTextureCache again.
Now we can convert our
interleaved process data to
biplanar format which is what
Video Toolbox needs.
And, as usual, we clean up
everything to keep buffers
recycled.
So we can now build the most
efficient pipeline possible and
that's really great.
We'll cover display section
separately and now let's talk
about 8K for a bit.
8K means really large assets.
So let's see how to deal with
them.
First, let's do the math.
An 8K frame is just huge.
It is 16 times larger than an HD
frame totaling up to 270
megabytes uncompressed.
And we have to send almost 300
megabytes every frame.
So for 30 frames per second we
have nine gigabytes per second
of bandwidth.
It's really close to the PCI
Express limit.
Moreover, even with ProRes
4 by 4 compression, a 10-minute
clip can easily take massive one
terabyte.
This creates a real challenge
for real-time playback.
So let's see what it looks like
when we trace it using
Instruments in Xcode.
So here is a system trace for
the video playback session we
showed earlier.
If we zoom into the Virtual
Memory Track, we see a huge
amount of page folds.
And the associated zero fill
cost is really high.
We can see it below.
So that naturally explains why
all the decoding threads are
stuck and cannot proceed.
We need to manage our memory
more carefully.
Modern operating system
don't actually physically
allocate memory pages until they
are used.
So once we start accessing all
of these new pages from many
decoding threads we have to
wait for the system to map all
those pages for us.
The way to figure that is
simple.
Pre-warm your CPU buffers before
use to make sure all the pages
are resident before playback
starts.
Now let me give you a few more
memory management tips.
Every allocation has a system
call.
One simple rule is to allocate
early enough and avoid
mid-workflow allocations.
Another good advice is to always
reuse your buffers.
This is why it's so important to
use objects such as
CVPixelBufferPool and
CVMetalTextureCache.
So now we have improved the way
we manage our frames but there
are always many, many smaller
allocations needed along the
lifetime of your app.
Let me give you some tips on how
to manage those.
With MTLheap's we can
efficiently manage all of our
transit allocations.
Allocating from a MTLheap
doesn't require a kernel call
since the entire heap is
allocated at creation time.
The heap is a monolithic
resource from the system's point
of view.
So it's made resident as a
whole.
Also, allocating from heap
allows for tighter memory
packing,
and with heaps you can alias
resource memory within the
common buffer.
Something we trust impossible
with the regular buffers.
Let me show you how to do this.
In this sample, we will be
aliasing transit allocations.
First, we created the heap using
our device.
Along the filter stages, we
created the uniforms for our
blur kernel from that heap.
Next, we allocate another buffer
for color grade uniforms from
that same heap.
So after the color grading
stage, we don't need those
anymore and we mark them as
aliasable, and the heap can
actually recycle that memory for
future allocations.
So when we allocate a new
intermediate buffer, the heap is
free to reuse any memory marked
as aliasable so this is really
efficient.
So that was a quick overview of
how to manage our resource
allocations.
Now let's talk about how to
present our friends with a
predictable frame rate.
So here is a timing sample for
triple buffer Metal application.
In this example, we're playing a
30-hertz video on a 60-hertz
display.
Notice how the frames are
showing up on the display at a
non-uniform cadence.
Users feel it as stutters.
So why is this happening?
Note how the CPU is incurring
GPU work without regard for
timing.
Once the third frame is
enqueued, the CPU is blocked
waiting for a drawable to
become available which is not
going to happen until frame one
leaves the glass.
So this approach maximizes GPU
utilization but produces visible
stutters.
We generally want each frame to
remain on the glass an equal
amount of time.
As a solution, Core Video offers
an interface called
CVDisplayLink.
This is a high-precision
low-level timer which notifies
you before every VBLANK at a
displaced refresh rate.
Rather than let the CPU
enqueue as many frames as
possible, We use display link to
determine the right time to
submit each frame to the GPU.
This significantly reduces video
playback jitter.
So let me show you the code
snippet how to do this.
We started by making a link with
the display we will be using.
Then, we set up our callback
handler and for every call we
will get the current time and
the next VBLANK time.
And we can use these values to
determine when to issue a
present call assuming we have
processed frames ready.
And we can adjust the desired
frequency to our needs.
So this will significantly
reduce stutters but we can take
it a step further.
For example, playing 24-hertz
content on a 60-hertz display,
we need three-two pull down.
It means we will present even
frames for three VBLANKS and odd
frames over two VBLANKS.
This is the best we can do given
the mismatch, and the code
snippet I just showed you will
handle this just fine, but the
good news is we can do even
better.
Our new Pro Display XDR supports
multiple refresh rates including
48-hertz.
So your 24-hertz content will
play extremely smoothly jitter
free.
So we have made quite a few
important optimizations.
Now I'd like to show you the
final result.
This is DaVinci Resolve now
playing that same 8k stream.
As you can see, playback is
smooth with no stutters.
This has been a great
collaboration for us with Black
Magic.
We achieved outstanding results
together, and we encourage you
to start leveraging our
high-performance frameworks and
start building new and exciting
pro apps for our platform.
We have tackled that 8k
challenge.
Now I'd like to invite Dileep to
talk about our support for HDR
and how you can enable it in
your app.
Dileep?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Eugene.
In recent years high-dynamic
range rendering and displays
have greatly enhanced the
quality of images that we see on
screen.
At Apple we have been constantly
adding support to improve
the image technology.
As you know, we have added many
technologies such as retina
display, 4K and 5K resolution,
wide gamut color space and many
and have enabled you, the
developers, to create amazing
and high-quality images.
Continuing in that part, this
year we are adding great support
for HDR on macOS.
I'm excited to give you an
overview of the support for HDR
rendering and display.
To do that, I'll cover four
topics with you.
One, I'll briefly talk about
some common traits of HDR
images.
Then I'll describe our approach
to HDR, our rendering model of
HDR.
Then I'll go into detail on how
to use Metal for HDR rendering.
And finally, wrap it up with
some recommendations on best
practices.
So let's begin with describing
some common traits of HDR
images.
What makes them special?
Compared to standard dynamic
range or SDR images, HDR images
have better contrast levels.
They have great details in the
dark and the bright areas of the
image.
Usually SDR images, these
details are not discernible.
They're either crushed or washed
out.
HDR images have more colors with
wide range of colors in them.
They look very realistic.
Also, they are really bright.
The brightness information is
encoded in the image itself with
such a high brightness and great
contrast ratios, they make it
possible to add lighting effects
in the scene that look closer to
real life.
And finally, they need to be
viewed on a capable display.
The display that can preserve
all the details of the image.
The display in itself should
have underlying technologies to
be able to produce high
brightness, high color fidelity,
and great contrast ratios.
Our new Pro Display XDR is a
great example of that.
Now, how do we render and
display these amazing HDR
contents on our devices?
At Apple, we have a unique
approach for this.
We call this EDR, extended
dynamic range.
In this approach, we use the
brightness headroom available on
the display to show the
highlights and shadows of HDR
images.
Let me explain the concept in
detail.
As you know, the brightness set
on a display is dependent on the
viewing conditions or the
ambient conditions.
For example, if you're in a
dimmed room the brightness set
on your display could be 200
nits, maybe low, and the
brightness set is ideal to view
SDR contents such as UI or
Safari or YouTube video.
But if your display is capable
of producing up to thousand nits
then you have a huge brightness
headroom available on the
display.
Similarly, if you're in well-lit
conditions such as office space,
the brightness set on the
display could be higher, say 500
nits.
And again, the brightness set is
ideal to view SDR contents but
still you have brightness
headroom left on the display in
this condition too.
In an approach to HDR, we take
advantage of this.
When we render the pixels, we
map the SDR pixels to the
brightness set on the display
and use the headroom to map the
HDR pixels.
The extent to which we map these
two categories really depends on
the viewing conditions as you
can clearly see in the two
examples here.
However, too, rendering this
model, the pixels needs to be
structured in a certain way and
we do that by scaling the HDR
pixels relative to the SDR
brightness of the display.
Let's use our previous example
of a dimmed room and see how the
pixel values are structured
relative to the brightness of
the display.
In here, we represent the
brightness in X axis and the
normalized pixel values in Y
axis.
In this example, the brightness
of the display set to 200 nits.
In our rendering model we always
reserve the pixel values, the
normalized pixel values in the
range 0 to 14 SDR contents and
we map it to the brightness set
on the display.
So a pixel value of one here
corresponds to 200 nits.
But as you can see, there is a
huge headroom available on the
display.
So you have pixel values from
one through five available to
represent HDR contents.
A scale factor of 5x relative to
the SDR range to take full
advantage of the display
brightness.
We call this scale factor as
maximum EDR.
If the viewing conditions change
or you're in a well-lit room and
the brightness is increased to
500 nits, then the maximum EDR
drops down but note the pixel
values in the range zero to one
are still dedicated for SDR
contents.
But they're mapped differently
now, so now a pixel value of one
corresponds to 500 nits instead
of 200 in the previous example.
And since you have a smaller
headroom available here, in this
case, you have a smaller range
of pixel calls available to
represent HDR contents.
So merely 2x here in this
example, relative to the SDR
range to represent HDR pixels.
As you can see, we structured
our pixels in such a way that
the HDR pixels are relative to
the SDR range and they scale
relative to the SDR range.
We also use negative pixels for
representing the darker side of
the HDR image.
So in summary, EDR or external
dynamic range is a display
referred rendering model in
which we use the brightness
headroom available on the
display for HDR pixels, and we
scale the HDR pixels relative to
the SDR brightness of the
display.
The advantage of this model is
that you can do HDR rendering on
pretty much any display on which
we can set brightness, but if
you have more capable display
such as of a new Pro Display XDR
with its huge headroom
availability then the contents
are going to look just better.
Now that we have looked into our
rendering model of our approach
to HDR, let's look into what
API's do we have and how you can
use those API's in your
application.
On both macOS and iOS, you have
a couple of options.
One, you can use AVFoundation
API's.
These API's are ideal for media
playback applications.
They handle all aspects of tone
mapping and color management for
you.
Two, you can directly use Metal.
Metal provides with a lot of
options and great flexibility.
Using the CAMetalLayer and EDR
API's, you can take full control
of HDR rendering in your
application including tone
mapping and color management.
These API's are ideal for
content creation.
Now using a code snippet, let's
look at how the metal layer and
the EDR API's all come together
in an application, shall we?
So the first and the foremost
that you do in your code base is
to check for the EDR support on
the display, and this screen
provides you with the property
for that.
Then as usual, you create and
set up your metal layer.
When you set up the metal layer,
you need to choose a wide gamut
color space that suits your
application.
Metal supports rendering into
wide gamut color spaces such as
BT2020 or B3.
Next, you need to choose the
transfer function that matches
your content.
Again, the API's have support
for all industry standard
transfer functions such as PQ,
HLG, or Gamma.
Then you need to choose pixel
format for your HDR rendering.
We recommend that you use float
16 as a preferred pixel format
for most of your HDR rendering
needs because float 16 has
enough precision to carry the
color and the brightness
information for HDR contents.
And finally, in the layers set
up you need to indicate to Metal
that you have opted in to EDR
rendering model.
So this is a typical layer set
up that you would do.
Next, moving on to main render
loop.
In the main render loop you need
to get the brightness headroom
that we talked about or the
maximum EDR information, right?
So NSScreen provides you with
the property for that.
But note, this property is
dynamic.
It keeps changing with the
viewing conditions or when the
brightness of the display
changes.
So you need to register for a
notification for any changes on
this property and as maximum EDR
changes, you need to redraw your
contents.
Now, if you are handling tone
mapping and color management
yourselves in the application,
you need to do some additional
pixel processing in the shaders.
Let's review some common steps
that you would do.
Typically the video come in
YUV or YCBCR color format.
So the first step in your
application or in your shaders
is to convert it to RGB.
Also, the video contents come
encoded with some kind of
non-linear transfer functions
such as PQ.
So the next step in the shader
is to apply inverse transfer
function and linearize your
pixels, and then normalize it in
the range zero to one.
And then use the maximum EDR
that you got from NSScreen and
scale the pixels as we discussed
in the EDR section.
And then perform editing,
grading, or any processing that
suits your application, and
finally, perform tone mapping.
If the brightness changes then
you need to do the tone mapping
with different set of
parameters.
If your contents are in a color
space that is different from the
one on the display then you also
need to apply proper color
conversions.
However, if you don't want to
handle tone mapping or
teleprocessing, and you want
Metal to handle it for you, you
can easily do that.
When you create a Metal layer,
attach an EDR metadata object
with it.
Typically the EDR metadata
object provides the information
on the mastering display and it
also tells Metal how you want to
map your pixels.
You also need to use one of the
linear color spaces available
with Metal.
So once all your pixel
processing is done, your frame
is ready.
Use the existing Metal API's to
present your frame on the
screen.
As we noted earlier, you need a
capable display such as of a Pro
Display XDR to view these
contents.
We also support HDR 10 and Dolby
Vision TV's available in the
market.
So this is a simple illustration
of how you can use Metal layer
and EDR API's for HDR rendering
in your application.
So before we end this section,
let's review some key takeaways
and some recommendations on best
practices.
Remember to redraw and update
your content as the brightness
changes.
Use float 16 as a preferred
pixel format for most of your
HDR rendering needs.
When you set up the Metal layer,
select the color space and
transfer function that matches
your content and then perform
any additional processing in the
shaders as necessary.
Last, but not the least, HDR
processing adds to computational
overhead and adds to memory pressure.
So bypass tone mapping if your
contents are already tone mapped
or if performance is more
important for you than color
accuracy.
So, in summary, we have provided
you with powerful API's, a
display for EDR rendering model
support on both iOS and macOS,
and a great support for our Pro
Display XDR.
I'm sure you can use these tools
to create amazing HDR contents.
In the next section, we are
going to talk about how you can
leverage the computational
resources available on the
platform to get the best
possible performance and to tell
you all about it, I invite Brian
Ross on stage.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Dileep.
Scaling your performance to
harness both CPU and GPU
parallelism is the most
important and sometimes the
easiest optimization you can do.
In this section, I'm going to
talk about several ways to scale
your performance based on the
architecture of your hardware.
So first, I'll talk about how
Metal can help you to scale
across any number of CPU cores.
Next, I'll talk about how to
leverage, utilize asynchronous
GPU channels.
And finally, I'll close this
section by going over a few ways
to use multiple GPU's.
So today's props are adding more
and more complexity.
They demand more CPU cycles to
decode frames, build render
graphs, and encode metal render
passes.
Doing all this on a single CPU
thread is not sufficient for
today's devices.
The latest iPhone has six cores
and a Mac Pro can have up to 28.
Therefore scalable multithread
architecture is key to great
performance on all of our
devices.
Metal is designed for
multithreading.
In this section, let's look at
two ways how you can parallelize
your encoding on the CPU.
So I'm going to set up an
example of a typical video
frame.
With a classic single threaded
rendering, you could serially
decode frames and build commands
into a single command buffer in
GPU execution order.
And you typically have to fit
this into some tiny fraction of
your frame time.
And of course, you're going to
have maximum latency because you
have to encode the entire
command buffer before the GPU
can consume it.
Obviously, there's a better way
to do this.
So what we're going to do is
start by building in parallelism
with the CPU.
Render blit and compute passes
are the basic granularity of
multithreading on Metal.
All you need to do is create
multiple command buffers and
start encoding passes into each
on a separate thread.
You can encode in any order you
wish.
The final order of execution is
determined by the order that you
added to the command queue.
So now let's look at how you can
do this in your code.
Encoding multiple command
buffers is actually quite
simple.
The first thing we do is we
create any number of Metal
command buffer objects from the
queue.
Next, we define the GPU
execution order up front by
using the enqueue interface.
This is great because you could
do it early and you don't have
to wait for encoding to complete
first.
And finally, for each command
buffer we create a separate
thread using the asynchronous
dispatch queue and encode passes
for the frame and that's it.
It's really fast and it's really
simple.
So as you could see in our
example, we've done a good job
parallelizing with multiple
Metal command buffer objects,
but what if you have one really
large effects and blending pass?
In this case, Metal offers a
dedicated parallel encoder that
allows you to encode on multiple
threads without explicitly
dividing up the render pass or
the command buffer.
Let's take a look at how easy
this is to doing your
application.
So here, the first thing we do
is create a parallel encoder
from the command buffer.
Then we create any number of
subordinate coders and this is
actually where we define the GPU
execution order by the order
that we create the subordinates.
Next, we create a separate
thread and call our encoding
function for each.
This is where the effects and
blending will be processed.
And finally we set up a
notification when the threads
are complete and we end
parallelizing encoding, and
that's it.
That's all you have to do.
It's very simple and very
efficient.
So I've shown you two ways on
how to parallelize on the CPU.
Now let's see how Metal can help
you to leverage asynchronous GPU
channels.
Modern GPU's today have a common
capability.
They each contain a number of
channels that allow you to
execute asynchronously so this
means that you can potentially
decode video on one channel
while also executing 3D effects
on another.
Metal could extract this type of
parallelism in two ways.
The first comes naturally just
by using the render, blit, and
compute encoders for the
appropriate workloads.
The other way Metal extracts
parallelism is by analyzing your
data dependencies.
But the most compelling detail
of all here is you get most of
this for free.
Metal does a lot of this for you
under the hood.
Let's see how.
So let's look at how the GPU
executes a series of these
frames.
Here I have another video frame
example.
In your application we're going
to be decoding with Video
Toolbox followed by using the
blit encoder to upload those
frames from system to VRAM.
Then we'll apply filtering with
compute and effects and blending
with render.
This work will happen
repetitively for each frame.
So now let's see how this gets
executed on both the CPU and the
GPU in a timeline diagram.
Let's also see if we can apply
some optimizations to improve
concurrency.
The first thing we're going to
do is encode frame one commands
using the various encoders on
separate threads.
This work is going to get
scheduled and eventually
executed across all the
channels.
And then we continue on with
frames two, three, and four.
Thanks to Metal, you can see
that we're already achieving
some parallelism for free.
But we can also see there's a
lot of gaps.
This means that some of the
threads and channels are sitting
idle during our valuable frame
time.
To maintain efficiency, we want
to saturate our channels as much
as possible.
Metal can't always do all this
for us.
So in this case it's time to
apply some optimizations.
You'll notice on the CPU there
is extremely large gaps.
This can happen for many reasons
but for simplicity I'll focus on
a common mistake.
Sometimes applications
gratuitously call or wait until
completed after encoding and
committing a command buffer.
In this scenario it's creating
large gaps or bubbles for the
duration of our decode workload.
It's also causing small gaps in
the decode channel in the GPU.
To fix that, we can try to
replace the weight with a
completion handler.
This will avoid blocking on the
CPU and schedule any post
processing after the GPU is
completed.
Let's try that and see where it
gets us.
So you can see that's much
better.
We're now keeping our CPU
threads busy.
You will also notice that the
decoding channel is saturated
really nicely.
We could still see quite a few
gaps in the blit, compute, and
render channels.
Looking closely, you can see
that there is a rewrite
dependency where the upload
can't begin until the decode is
finished.
One solution to fix this problem
is to decode say 10 frames
ahead.
This will remove that
dependency.
Let's try it and see what
happens.
So now our resource updates look
great.
We're saturating both the video
and the blit channels, but
you'll notice that there is
still a few gaps in the compute
and render channels.
Similar to last time if you look
closely, you could see that
there's another dependency but
the filtering cannot begin until
the blit channel has uploaded
all the data.
Similar to before, we can fix
this by preloading our bit maps
ahead of time.
This will remove that
dependency.
And with this, we've now closed
most of the gaps and we have a
really efficient pipeline.
So now that I've reviewed the
GPU channels and some example
optimizations, let's see how to
continue scaling performance on
more GPU's.
GPU's are quickly becoming a
performance multiplier.
Supporting more GPU's can
accelerate image processing,
video editing, and improve your
overall frame rate.
In this section, I'm first going
to go over how Metal can be used
to leverage multi GPU
configurations.
Then I'll show you a few load
balancing strategies proven
effective by Pro App developers
today.
And finally, I'll discuss how to
synchronize operations between
your GPU's.
So what can Metal do for your
Pro App?
To start, Metal gives you all
the tools you need to detect all
the connected GPU's and their
capabilities.
With Metal it's easy to manage
multiple GPU's because they're
essentially just separate Metal
device objects.
So program them as the same as
you do today for a single GPU.
Metal also supports a brand-new
peer group transferring PI.
This incorporates the concept of
remote texture views which allow
you to copy data between GPU's.
And finally, Metal offers
powerful shared events that
allow you to synchronize your
workloads between GPU's.
Now let's take a quick look at
how to detect multi GPU
configurations.
Metal exposes device properties
to identify the location,
location number, and max
transfer rate for each device.
This information could be used
to say determine the fastest
possible hosted device transfer
device.
It can also be used to determine
if a device is integrated,
discreet, or external or even
low power or headless.
So once we're able to detect
multiple GPU's with this, it's
time to think about how to
balance your workloads.
There is many, many ways to load
balance between GPU's, and
there's a lot of design
decisions that you have to
consider when you select
strategy.
At the end of the day what we
seek is a really simple load
balancing strategy with higher
scale and efficiency.
Let's go over a few proven
strategies that some Pro App
developers are using today.
The first and most
straightforward is supporting
alternating frames.
So the concept is to ping pong
odd and even frames between the
two GPU's.
This easily fits into existing
architectures and can
potentially double the rate that
you process frames.
However, sometimes apps have
variable workloads like UI
updates or graph building, and
this might result in unbalanced
load balancing.
So let's take a look at another
strategy.
This one uses small 32 by
32-pixel tiles to distribute
rendering more evenly among the
GPU's.
So if you have four GPU's, you
can preselect separate tile
groups for each.
Here we use a random assignment
to avoid too much correlation
with the scene.
This means that mapping of tiles
to GPU's is constant from frame
to frame.
This is a really good solution
for compute heavy workloads but
might not be the best choice for
bandwidth intensive ones.
To see this in more detail,
check out the rate tracing
section.
So here's a similar approach
that uses a tile queue.
In this case, the host
application can populate the
queue with all the tiles.
They can then be dequeued on
demand by each GPU based on an
algorithm that keeps the GPU's
busy.
This approach may provide really
good load balancing but it is
adding more complexity.
So once we've decided on our
load balancing scheme, we need
to think about how to
synchronize our workloads
between the GPU's.
To accomplish this, Metal
provides a powerful construct
called shared events.
They allow you to specify
synchronization points in your
app where you can wait and
signal for specific command
completion.
This can be done across GPU's,
between a CPU and the GPU, and
across processes.
Let's put this into practice.
So here's an example of a single
GPU workload that performs a
motion analysis on pairs of
frames.
Notice that these are all render
workloads so we can't take
advantage of the parallel
asynchronous channels that we
talked about earlier, but if we
have two GPU's, we can divide
this work between them to
improve performance.
So the strategy here is to move
the motion analysis to the
second GPU.
Keep in mind that each motion
pass has to analyze the previous
pair of frames.
This means that we have to wait
for the previous frames to be
written before we read them from
the motion pass and this repeats
for each frame pair.
So we can accomplish this by
using Metal shared events.
First, we need to signal
completion when the frames are
done rendering, and then we wait
for that signal before reading
them with motion pass.
And with this, we can safely
offload the motion analysis to a
second GPU and everything runs
in parallel.
And because the signal
and wait are encoded on the GPU,
you don't block any CPU
execution.
So now let's take a look at how
we can do this in our code.
So the first thing we're going
to do is create a shared event
from the device that renders our
frames.
We also create two command
queues, one for each device.
Now to render the frames, we
create a command buffer and
encode, then immediately encode
a signal event to notify the
other GPU's that we're complete.
And finally, to encode the
motion, we start by creating a
command buffer from the queue.
Then immediately encode a wait
event to avoid reading the
frames before they're done.
And then we encode the motion
analysis and commit, and as you
can see it's a fairly
straightforward process and it's
very powerful.
And before I move on, let's take
a look at how we can look at
multi GPU's and channels in our
tools.
So Metal System Trace shows the
work for each of your test
GPU's.
In this example we're using four
One internal, and three external
GPU's.
It exposes detailed visibility
into each GPU by showing all the
asynchronous workloads across
all the channels, and it maps
those workloads with relevant
symbol names.
In the activity summary, you
could actually see all the
execution statistics for all the
connected GPU's.
You could even dive deeper to
see more detailed channel
information for any GPU on a per
frame basis.
This includes details for page
on and page off in the blit
channel or compute and render
workloads.
You can even drill down to see
IOSurface access.
As Eugene mentioned, this is
something that's very useful
because a lot of Pro Apps need
to utilize IOSurfaces, which is
really necessary for framework
interoperability.
And finally, our tools give you
visibility into Metal events and
shared events.
So you can actually see where
the signal and wait events
occur.
It also shows how many
milliseconds are spent waiting
and draws dependency lines for
you to follow.
And finally at the bottom,
there's even detailed lists
about your events in the
activity summary.
So Metal system trace is a great
tool for all your Pro App needs.
So now that we understand how to
utilize multiple GPU's, let's
look at how to transfer data
between them.
Scaling performance across CPU's
and GPU's is extremely
important, but at the end of the
day your Pro App is only as fast
as its slowest bottleneck.
When you're transferring massive
8K frames, your data transfers
can quickly become that
bottleneck.
In this section, I'm going to
talk about bandwidth
considerations and how they
relate to the new Mac Pro.
Then I'll review a few Metal
peer groups transfer strategies,
and some of these are already in
use today by Pro App developers.
And finally I'll walk you
through an example use case to
show how Infinity Fabric Link
can help unlock challenging
workflows.
So let's start by looking at the
transfer rates for our key
connection points.
Our baseline here is PCI Express
gen 3 with 16 links.
So first we have Thunderbolt 3.
In the real world this maxes out
around one-quarter of the rate
of PCI Express.
It's a really great scalable
solution for compute heavy
workloads but maybe not the best
for bandwidth intensive ones.
Next we have two GPU's each with
their one PCI lanes.
This can double your bandwidth.
And this week we introduced the
new Infinity Fabric Link with
the peer group transfer API
which can transfer data between
GPU's at speeds up to five times
that of PCI Express.
So now let's look at some common
Mac Pro configurations.
This diagram illustrates a great
configuration for bandwidth
intensive ones.
Here we have a new Apple
Afterburner which has its own
dedicated PCI lanes.
We also have two internal GPU's
with their own dedicated PCI
lanes.
And finally, you can connect
those GPU's with Infinity Fabric
Link to quickly copy data
between them.
The Mac Pro also allows you to
have up to four internal GPU's
that share two sets of PCI
lanes.
Because the lanes are shared, it
lends itself maybe to a more
compute heavy pro application.
And in this case, it can also be
connected with the Infinity
Fabric Link.
So there is many, many ways to
manage these transfer
strategies.
I'm going to go over a few
proven strategies that some Pro
App developers are using today.
The most straightforward
approach is to transfer entire
frames for display.
The premise is to process
alternating frames.
Any frame processed on the
auxiliary device can be
transferred quickly to the
display attached GPU and then
sent to the display.
Another transfer strategy is to
send tiles to each GPU that are
essentially pieces of the entire
frame.
All the tiles processed on the
auxiliary device can be sent to
the display GPU and then
reconstructed as part of the
final output image.
This result has really good load
balancing.
So we've looked at two
strategies quickly.
Now let's see a great example of
a Pro App actually leveraging
the Infinity Fabric Link.
So over the last six months,
I've had the opportunity to
collaborate with the Final Cut
Pro team.
They've done an outstanding job
optimizing for the new Mac Pro.
They're scaling across 28 CPU
cores and all internal GPU's.
They've also fully utilized the
Infinity Fabric Link.
This is helping them to enable
real time editing of multiple 8K
ProRes video streams.
Now let's take a closer look at
how this works.
So here we have a simple
timeline diagram that shows how
video streams move from the CPU
to the display.
In this case we're focusing on
playback of three 8k ProRes raw
video streams with some effects.
This is how it might look on a
single GPU.
So first, we encode frame one
commands on the CPU.
Then upload all three streams
over PCI to VRAM.
Finally we process those streams
with effects on the GPU and
display.
We continue this process for
each of the additional frames.
And as much as we want this to
fit within our 30 frames per
second, it won't.
It's just too much work to pack
into that space.
A Pro App will drop at least 30%
of their frames in this
scenario.
Now let's see how this might
work on a dual GPU system.
So first, we encode frame one as
in the previous example.
For frame two, we follow a
similar process.
Now this is looking really good.
We've got things going in
parallel here.
But do we double our frame rate?
Unfortunately, we don't.
The problem comes when any frame
that we've processed on the
auxiliary device has to somehow
be copied back to the display
attach device, and this is where
things get tricky.
To get the display GPU, we have
to copy a 265-megabyte output
buffer over PCI to the host, and
then we copy a second time from
there to the display attached
GPU.
This can take up to 48
milliseconds on a good day.
So now, let's continue with
frames three and four to give
you a better picture.
And you can quickly see that
we're using a considerable
amount of PCI bandwidth but also
we see a lot of gaps and
dependencies.
We're still doing better than
the single GPU case, but it's
not going to double our frame
rate.
All this PCI traffic will result
in dropping some frames.
But to improve on this problem,
the Mac Pro introduces the new
Infinity Fabric Link feature
with the peer group API.
This completely blows away the
GPU copy.
You could see here with Infinity
Fabric Link the transfer is much
faster.
It also frees up a considerable
amount of PCI bandwidth and with
that bandwidth we can upload our
frames earlier.
Infinity Fabric Link also
operates on its own parallel GPU
channel.
This means you could transfer
data while using the render and
compute channels at the same
time.
This helps us to improve
concurrency and hide latency.
At the end of the day, this can
enable your Pro App to unlock
challenging workloads and enable
new use cases.
So this is what it looks like on
a boring timeline diagram.
But now let's see what it looks
in action.
This is the Final Cut Pro demo
you saw in the keynote.
You can see it plays back
multiple streams of 8K video
with effects and transitions.
This is also done in real time
using multiple GPU's and the
Infinity Fabric Link.
Final Cut Pro is an outstanding
example of a Pro App utilizing
efficient data transfers.
So now before we close this
section, let's look at how to
use Infinity Fabric Link and the
peer grant transfer group API in
your code.
So the first thing you need to
do is detect these connections.
To facilitate this, Metal
defines a brand-new peer group
API, defines properties on the
Metal device for peer group ID,
index, and count.
With this you can detect if you
have linked GPU's and if they
have shared PCI lanes or dual
PCI lanes.
More importantly, you can use
this to determine the best
configuration for you and scale
your performance based on the
bandwidth limitations.
And this is how you transfer
data between GPU's.
The first thing you need to do
is create your shared event from
the auxiliary device.
We also create a render texture
and a remote texture view.
The remote view will give our
display attached GPU access to
the auxiliary texture.
Next we create an encoder and
render.
This should immediately be
followed by the encoded signal
event.
Now on the display device we
create a blit command buffer.
We immediately encode a wait
event.
So we wait for the rendering to
complete before transferring the
data.
And finally we do a copy using
the textured view, and that's
it.
Very simple.
Utilizing Metal peer group API
to leverage Infinity Fabric Link
can unlock challenging workloads
by reducing your PCI bandwidth.
It also can enhance concurrency
by using a parallel channel.
So before I conclude this
session, let's look at one more
really great Pro App in action.
So now I'm excited to share a
demo of Affinity Photo from
Serif Labs.
The engineers at Serif have done
an outstanding job of adopting
Metal.
They're also a really, really
good example of how to
officially leverage platform
resources.
On a typical document, their
performance can be around 10
times faster on a single GPU
when compared to an eight course
CPU.
Let's take a look.
So in this example, Affinity is
going to be live compositing a
massive document called the
rabbit trick.
As the video demonstrates, it
has hundreds of massive layers,
and they'll be compositing at 4K
resolution.
Some layers have pixel data
while others have procedural
adjustments.
This will be hierarchically
composited in real time, and
this will also put a tremendous
load on both the CPU and the
GPU.
Now let's run this massive
document on the CPU.
This is using an 18-core system.
You could see that we're able to
composite in real time; however,
the document is so complex it
gets a little bit choppy in the
user interface.
Now let's switch and run that on
a single GPU.
Here, you can see the UI
responds really well and
everything runs smoothly.
The frame rate runs about 18 to
20 frames per second.
And now for the best part.
We're going to enable a total of
four external GPU's and as you
can see it runs incredibly
smooth and it maintains greater
than 60 frames per second the
entire time.
This is due in part to
Affinity's advanced tile-based
load balancing scheme.
They can distribute their work
efficiently among any number of
GPU's, and with this they can
achieve linear performance
scaling.
Here is one last example that I
want to share.
This is one of Affinity Photo's
most memory bandwidth intensive
filters known as depth of field.
Here we're previewing in real
time on the CPU.
You can visually see the time it
takes between applying the
effect and it actually
rendering.
This is still impressive, and
it's fast, but the GPU can make
this even better.
So now we're going to run the
same effect with four external
GPU's.
You could see here it runs
amazingly smooth and easily
maintains a frame rate greater
than 60 frames per second.
This particular filter is memory
bandwidth intensive.
So we get great improvement here
because of the massive memory
bandwidth available on modern
GPU's today.
And this is an outstanding
example of how to officially
scale performance across
multiple GPU's.
So before we close this session,
let's review some of the key
takeaways.
Apple provides a wealth of
frameworks to solve all your Pro
App needs.
You can leverage this ecosystem
to achieve real-time editing
performance on 8k content with a
predictable frame rate.
Apple's AV Foundation and Core
Animation Metal Layer provide
API's to seamlessly support high
dynamic range.
You can couple this with HDR
TV's and Apple's new Pro Display
XDR to generate amazing videos
and images.
The Mac Pro can have up to 28
CPU cores and four internal
GPU's.
Metal provides all the API for
you to scale your performance
across all these devices.
And finally, we introduced a new
hardware feature Affinity Fabric
Link with a Metal peer group
API.
This empowers you to leverage
this connection to unlock new
and exciting use cases.
For more information, please
visit our website and please
visit us in tomorrow's lab.
Also check out additional Metal
labs on Friday.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]