[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Great to see you.
I hope you're all having an
awesome WWDC.
We're super excited to be here
today to chat with you about
Building AR Experiences with
Reality Composer.
I'm Michelle and with me are my
colleagues, Pau and Abhi.
And today we're going to cover
what Reality Composer is and how
it can help you create an AR
app.
After this session, you'll know
what's provided with Reality
Composer, how to set up your
experiences in it, and then how
to take in-- take what you've
created in Composer into your
app in Xcode.
So, first, what is Reality
Composer?
As you've heard earlier this
week, Reality Composer is a
tool, an app, to help iOS
developers get started in
working with 3D and AR.
Some of you have already begun
and it's been really, really
amazing to see what you've all
been making, posting, and
tagging with Reality Composer.
So, please keep doing it.
If you're not familiar with 3D,
the first time you ever open a
3D app can be pretty daunting
and it can be kind of time
consuming to even get started in
AR.
But with Reality Composer, it's
really easy to just pre-vis and
lay out your experiences using
the built-in content library.
Or, if you prefer, you can use
your own USDZs.
And if you're not familiar, USDZ
is just a 3D file format that's
supported in Reality Composer.
Once you've got the experience
laid out, you can add simple
interactions and animations with
the behavior system before you
even commit to writing any code.
So, it really speeds up the
iteration time on the experience
itself.
And then finally, everything
that you've made in Reality
Composer you can take directly
into your app in Xcode.
And so much about building for
augmented reality is in seeing
how the experience feels in
physical space, looking at it on
the intended device and seeing
how your audience might see that
experience.
So, Reality Composer is
available on macOS, iPhone and
iPad, and you can edit on iOS so
that you can develop on your
regular dev machine and then
edit on iOS in order to continue
working on the exact same
project on iPad or iPhone.
Alternately, you can also just
start the project on your iOS
devices and take it the other
way.
So, today I'm going to take you
through building scenes.
Pau will cover adding behaviors
and using physics.
And then Abhi's going to take
you through building an app.
So, for building scenes, first,
what's a scene?
So, as you may have heard in the
introduction to RealityKit and
Reality Composer talk, a Reality
Composer scene is essentially a
collection of entities and it
contains an anchor, objects,
behaviors, and a physics world.
Every scene has exactly one
anchor, and when you start a
project or when you start a
scene, any scene, you'll be
asked what kind of scene, what
kind of experience are you
building.
If you're building something for
a room, a stage, or a tabletop,
you'll choose the horizontal
anchor.
If you want it to be on a wall,
pick vertical.
If you're augmenting a book or
some packaging, a brochure, or a
movie poster, choose the image
anchor.
And for selfie effects like
glasses or hats, choose the face
anchor.
Projects can have multiple
scenes but I think you'll find
when you're first starting out,
one or two scenes is usually
sufficient.
Okay, so in this case, let's
assume that you've picked the
horizontal anchor.
And so here we are.
The content is our focus in
Reality Composer.
So, it's laid out exactly as you
would see it in AR in the Main
View Port or the workspace.
And this pane on the right here
shows you the properties of
whatever you selected and shows
you options for configuring that
entity, be it the object itself,
like this text that's selected
here.
You can see that it's selected
because of the ring.
You can select the object, or a
scene.
I could show you more slides,
but why don't we check out
Composer together on iPad.
Oh, I want you to remember this
scene, though.
Because we're going to be
building up this little tutorial
over the course of the session
together.
It's Seasons and Solar System
lesson.
We'll build up in AR.
Okay, so for our demo, I'm going
to show you three quite
different RC projects today.
The first is a little primer.
And it's going to show you kind
of just five really basic
examples of things you could
create in Reality Composer
probably just in a couple of
minutes.
The second is a much more richer
and more complex experience, a
full experience, of what you
could create just in Reality
Composer alone if you didn't
want to write code at all.
So, this is great if you're not
a developer or you're just kind
of starting out and you want to
just try out the experience
before you fully commit to it
when you make your app.
And finally, we're going to
build that Seasons scene that we
saw together.
Okay, so here is the primer in
Reality Composer.
And I'm going to take us into
AR, because that was how we
intended to see it.
Okay, so these are the five
examples I mentioned, and let's
press play so that we kind of
see the interactions.
So, when we started, we're just,
oh, hi everyone.
When we just started, the spiral
started spinning.
And here, if I get close in the
second example, I can make this
chess piece jiggle.
I can tap this one for physics
[popping sound] and audio
[popping sound].
It's kind of a fun sound.
And then someone had asked if
I'm an animator and I have my
own models, I have my own
animations, can I bring them
into Reality Composer?
And yes, you can.
And you can trigger them on user
interactions like a tap.
And if you're not an animator,
you can use prebuilt emphasis
animations on any object in the
scene.
Here we've applied them to some
pretty basic shapes but you can
apply them, you know, to this
dancer as well.
So, that's the Scene in AR.
[ Applause ]
Next, I'm going to show you this
more complex experience, richer
experience.
Oh, and you're probably
wondering how I'm moving the
content around the scene and
moving the camera.
So, for panning, all I'm doing
is taking two fingers, moving
them across like this so I can
see the content exactly as I
want.
If you were watching State of
the Union on Tuesday, this
island might look familiar to
you.
And we wanted to build up the
experience a bit more.
So, if you imagine you're
making, like, a museum
installation or a tourism center
experience, that's something
that we kind of envisioned here.
So, let's look at this here in
AR and I'm going to press play
to start.
[ Crashing waves ]
So, you should hear some waves.
And now we're being prompted to
tap on the helicopter, so let's
do that.
[ Helicopter blades thumping ]
You can see we were also asked
to tap a location to learn more.
So, I'm going to do that tap on
these markers now, and you can
see I'm getting more information
about each location as I tap.
The other ones fade off.
[ Helicopter blades thumping ]
And so I'm just going to take
apart what we did to build up
this scene.
So, there's actually not much
custom content in this scene
itself.
There's only two artist-created
custom USDZs, the island and the
helicopter.
You can see here we imported
them.
You can import more if you want.
The rest are just built in from
the content library that comes
with Reality Composer.
You can see we have a lot of
stuff here.
Text, basic shapes.
And that's kind of what you're
seeing in this scene.
These markers are just basic
shapes.
We group them to create two
pieces as one marker.
Have text here.
The other question we get asked
a lot is I work mostly in 2D and
so I have a lot of photos and,
you know, company graphics.
Can I use them in Reality
Composer?
And the answer is yes, of course
you can!
You can bring them into the
experience as photos using the
Picture Frame, which is in the
Content Library that we just
saw.
Finally, you're probably
wondering how did we create
those little interactions.
So, if we go to Behaviors by
clicking on this Behaviors
button in the top right, you can
see the Behaviors we used to
create the flow of that sequence
and those interactions.
So, we're billboarding things to
look, you might've noticed as I
moved around the scene, those
items looked at me.
So, we're using the Look At
actions here to make everything
look at the camera.
At the beginning, you saw just
the island, and everything else
was hidden.
So, you can see that we hid
everything else and then we
showed them to you in sequence.
So, we waited for 0.2 seconds,
and then first we showed the
helicopter text.
Then we showed the helicopter
itself and its tap to start.
And then we faded the markers in
from below, so that's what this
move from below is doing and I
can preview that to you now just
by pressing play on the card.
I'm going to show you also a
little secret.
These birds, you might've
noticed--
I'm just going to look at them
here.
So, we asked them to orbit the
island as a group.
And they're not really birds at
all.
They're just primitives that
we're using, or just basic
shapes that we've put two move
cards on to flap their wings.
So instead of investing time in
creating birds, all we did was
we took a couple shapes and put
two action cards on them to make
an animation.
And if you've tried to animate
something in 3D before, you know
how time consuming a simple
thing like this can be, and this
takes just a couple of seconds.
So, that's an example of a full
experience that you can make in
Reality Composer without any
code at all.
And the really great part about
this is that once you have this
Reality file, you can just share
it with anyone and preview it in
AR QuickLook, and the experience
will be exactly as you've done
it in Composer.
So, that's that second project.
[ Applause ]
So, finally let's build up the
experience of the Seasons lesson
together.
So, I'm going to add three
celestial bodies, the Sun, the
Moon, and the Earth.
So for this I'll just block in
the scene with some placeholder
objects to start us off.
So, here's the Sun.
I've brought it in.
And now I'm going to duplicate
it
to create the Earth and I'm just
using pinch here to zoom us out
a little bit, to move the
camera.
So, let's grab this arrow to
move the Earth over.
And then next I need also a
Moon.
So, let's duplicate this guy one
more time.
Bring it over to about here.
And then I can kind of grab
anywhere in this ring to move it
up in this plane.
So let's move it over.
Okay, great.
And now I want to scale the Moon
down a little bit.
So I'm just going to grab the
ring and move inwards to scale
it.
There we go.
Move it a little closer.
Okay, so I have these three
celestial bodies.
Let's scale the Sun up.
So I'll grab the ring again.
Just grab it to scale.
Scale the Sun.
So we've got our three items
there.
Next I'm going to add some text.
So I go to the content library
again.
Let's grab the text.
And it's a little bit below
where I want it to be, so I'm
just going to grab this green
arrow and drag it up.
And you can see it pop up to the
ground plane.
And it's doing that because I
have snapping turned on.
So, if you look in the left
corner, we have this little
magnet, and I can turn snapping
off if I want to move stuff
freely, but actually I just want
to pull this blue arrow to bring
it forward.
And I want it to be about half a
meter or so from the Sun.
And I'm going to open the pane
that we saw on the right to
change up the text.
So, let's just make it say
autumn.
It's super easy to just add
these elements in Composer.
So, finally, I think that's
pretty much where I want it to
be.
So, all I'm doing to move the
camera around is using my finger
and touching the screen.
Next I'm going to add an arrow.
And it's not pointing the right
direction I want it to be, kind
of rotated.
So, I'm going to move the camera
so I can see the green ring
which is sitting on the ground
plane.
This ring rotates with the
camera as I move, so I can
always be working in the plane
that I want to be working in.
If I don't want to move the
camera to have to do that, I can
just tap on the arrow and that
will lock into the corresponding
area.
You can see the ring got a
little fatter there.
So I'm just going to rotate the
area and it's snapping to 15
degree increments.
Again, because I have that
snapping turned on.
But if I didn't want to have it
snap, I could move it freely.
So here I'm dragging it and it's
moving always in the horizontal
plane for this green ring here.
But I actually do want it to
snap between the Sun, sphere,
and the autumn text.
So, I'm going to turn snapping
on.
You can see it snapping into
place.
So, it's just super useful,
super easy.
Then I want to modify this arrow
a little bit.
So, I can go ahead and click the
icon next to snapping to modify
it.
I'm just going to zoom this in a
little so we can see better.
And I can grab this handle.
Drag it.
I'm also just going to make this
just a touch smaller, a little
flatter.
Okay. And then I'm going to move
it just a little bit more.
Okay, so now everything is kind
of blocked out, and we did that
in just a couple minutes.
I actually want to replace these
celestial bodies because they're
all pretty indistinct right now
and I want to import some custom
USDZs.
And since I already have them
placed exactly where I want, I'm
going to do a replace.
So I just tap on this object.
I get this edit menu.
Hit replace.
And I'm going to import the Sun,
and it'll just replace.
And you can see it's the same
scale and it's exactly in the
right position that I wanted.
I can do the same with the
Earth.
So let's do that really quick.
There it is.
And the Moon, I'm just going to
customize it a little bit here
with some, let's see, I want the
map material.
And I can make the Moon, like,
any color that I want, but I
think I'm just going to pick
grey for the sake of safety.
And if I want to see any of
these items a little better, I
can just double tap on them to
frame the object.
It's a really easy way to get
around the scene.
Or if I want to see the scene,
pull back, I can double tap on
anywhere in the grid to see the
scene.
Those shortcuts are here too.
Frame scene or frame selected.
Okay, so we're just about ready,
I think, to add Behaviors.
I could add all of the other
elements but for the sake of
time we won't do all of that
now.
There's a few tips I want to
leave you with before we finish
this part of the demo.
That replace that you saw?
If we had Behaviors applied to
this already like we were doing
any animations on, like, let's
say the Sun, if I replaced it,
those Behaviors would stay.
So, it's a huge time saver if
you're just like swapping in new
versions of content.
It's really powerful.
And then also we mentioned
having multiple scenes.
You can access them here with
the Scene Selector in the top
left.
And so if you wanted to add any
more scenes, you just add them
here.
If you are working with these
entities in Xcode, you're going
to want to name them.
And you'll see more about this
later on in the session.
And you can do that when you
open the pane.
There's a configure panel and
you can just name the entity
here.
I'm going to name it Sun.
Finally, if there's something
you didn't want to do, like
let's say I moved the Earth and
I didn't want to do that.
I can undo that action.
I can also long press and redo
and it'll tell me, like, what
the undo that I, what the undo
is that I'm about to invoke.
Okay.
Finally, some folks have asked
what's the easiest way for me to
share my RC projects?
And you can airdrop them between
your devices.
Or like we talked about earlier,
you can use the edit on iOS to
go easily between your
development machine and your iOS
devices.
Okay.
So, that's our scene now, ready
for Behaviors.
So, you just saw how to build
scenes in Reality Composer.
So, we took you through how to
lay stuff out quickly using the
content library.
We also showed you how to bring
in your own custom USDZs.
And now we're going to move on
to adding interactions and
behaviors.
So, to take you through all
that, let's welcome my
colleague, Pau.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Michelle.
So, now that we know how to
bring content to the scene, it's
time to bring all this content
to life.
So, you might want to play some
music when the user taps on an
object, or maybe show some text
when the user gets close to an
object.
Or maybe you just want to play
some USD animation.
And so in order to do that and
more, we need to take advantage
of Behaviors in Reality
Composer.
So, let's get started.
As we've seen before, a scene in
Reality Composer contains an
anchor, objects, behaviors, and
the physics world.
Behaviors are always scene
scope.
That means that you can only
target objects within the same
scene.
So, let's take a closer look at
what the behavior is.
A behavior is composed by two
items, the trigger and the
action sequence.
The trigger, as the name
suggests, is simply the criteria
for the action sequence to
begin.
So, let's say we have a scene
with a model of a record player.
And when the user taps on it, we
want to play some music and spin
at the same time.
Well, in order to do that, you
just need to create the new
behavior, use a tap trigger, and
then create an action sequence
comprised of a music action and
the spin action.
So, the first thing when
creating a new behavior is to
pick what trigger will begin the
action sequence.
Reality Composer comes with five
different triggers that you can
use.
With the start trigger, the
action sequence will begin as
soon as the scene is loaded.
With the tap trigger, the action
sequence will begin once the
user taps on an object that you
define.
With a proximity trigger, you
define a threshold distance from
the object to the camera.
Once the camera is close enough
to the object, the action
sequence will begin.
With collision trigger, you
define two objects, and once
those two objects collide, the
action sequence will begin.
And the last trigger is the
notification trigger.
This trigger is what allows you
to begin action sequences
programmatically from your app
and we'll take a look at this
trigger in the last section of
this talk.
So, now let's move into action
sequences.
There are three main ways that
you can modify the execution of
action sequences.
Those are groups, loops, and
exclusive action sequences.
So, let's start with groups.
By default, in Reality Composer,
groups play sequentially.
So, the actions go one after the
other.
But you can combine multiple
actions if you want to play them
in parallel.
So, in this example, action two
and three will play together
right after action one finishes.
And action four will only begin
once all the action in the group
are over.
Action sequences can also be
looped.
So let's say you want to have
some music in your scene and you
want that music to loop forever.
Well, you just need to create
the behavior with music action
in the action sequence and mark
that action sequence to be
looped.
And the last part is the
exclusive action sequences.
In Reality Composer, you can
mark an action sequence to be
exclusive.
Only one exclusive action
sequences will play at any one
time.
That means once an exclusive
action sequence starts or any
other running exclusive action
sequences will stop.
And action sequences that are
nonexclusive, they will play,
like, together with other
exclusive and nonexclusive
action sequences.
And that's pretty much all you
need to know about action
sequences.
So now let's take a look at some
of the actions available to you
in Reality Composer.
With the visibility actions, you
can bring objects in and out of
your scene using animations.
So, we support multiple type of
animations, and you can use
basic things like fade in-fade
out.
But you can also use more
playful animations like scale up
and then scale down.
Reality Composer also supports
animating objects in place with
the emphasis similar to the show
height, you can animate the
object with different motion
types and animation styles.
So, you can use BasicPop, but
you can also use a more playful
pop animation.
You can also spin or orbit your
object around other objects and
if you're using a USD asset in
your file, you can use their
transform and skeletal
animation.
Now, with the move actions, you
can translate, scale, and rotate
an object in the same.
With the Move By, the movement
will be relative to where the
object is right now.
Like in this example, where the
object always goes two units
forward and one left.
And with the Move To, you can
always move an object to a
specified location in the scene.
Like here, where the object is
going back to the origin of the
scene.
With the Look At, you can make
an object always face the
camera.
Like in this example, where the
horse will always face the
user's device.
Now that we have all the
animation actions, it's time to
bring some sound to your
experience.
In Reality Composer, there's
three actions that you can use
to bring some audio to your
scene.
With Play Sound, the audio will
originate from the object
itself.
Like here, where the horse is
doing a horse sound.
With Play Ambient, the sound
will be scene-oriented.
And with Play Music, the audio
will play without any
transformations.
So now let's take a quick demo,
and let's take a quick look at
how to bring some behaviors to
the scene Michelle was building
before.
Here we have a more complete
scene compared to what Michelle
was building.
So, we have the Moon, the Earth,
the Sun, and we have some text
and some sunrays showing the
different seasons.
So, let's bring up the behavior
final by clicking on the
behaviors button on the top
right corner.
And as you see here, there's
already some behaviors.
So let's hit play and see what
is going on in this scene.
So, you see here, there's no
movement for the Moon, the
Earth, or the Sun.
But the different rays and
seasons, text, are appearing in
a sequential order.
So, let's go ahead and create
the new behavior for 20 minutes
the different Moon, Earth, and
Sun objects.
So for that, let's start by
bringing a new behavior.
We hit plus, and then here we
can see all the available
presets that we can pick from.
But for this demo, we're going
to start with a custom trigger.
Now the first thing is to pick
what trigger we want to use to
begin the action sequence.
And because we want to start
animating these objects when the
scene is loaded, we can bring up
the library and choose the scene
start.
Great. Now it's time to start
with the action sequence.
For this action sequence, we
want the Earth to orbit around
the Sun, and then the Moon to
orbit around the Earth.
And at the same time, we want to
spin the Earth and the Sun.
So let's start with the orbits.
So we can bring the action
library and then select orbit as
the first action.
The first thing when creating a
new action is to define what
targets are the targets of the
action.
So in this case, the affected
object is going to be the Earth,
and the center is going to be
the Sun.
Great.
We have all the properties like
duration, revolutions, align to
path, and orbit direction.
And for the direction, we want
to use counter-clockwise.
So, now, we can easily preview
this action by just hitting play
on the play button in the action
card.
That was a bit fast.
So, let's change the duration to
something more suited for this
scene.
Let's start with 20 seconds.
You can change duration and try
again.
And yeah, I think that duration
looks right.
Now, let's bring the second
orbit.
So, we can bring again the
library and select orbit.
Now, the affected object is
going to be the Moon and the
center will be the Earth.
The duration, we want it to be
the same as before.
And for the revolutions, because
we are not trying to be
physically accurate, we just
want to have something that
looks nice in the scene, we're
going to use four.
I think four is a good number.
And now because the Moon is
tidally locked with the Earth,
we want the Moon to be aligned
to the orbit.
So, we have to select align to
path.
And now the direction will be
also counter clockwise.
So, let's give that a try and
yeah, this animation looks
right.
So now that we have the orbits
out of our way, let's begin with
the spin actions.
So for that, we bring another
spin action and let's start with
the Sun.
Same direction as before.
So, 20 seconds.
And for iterations, I think four
will be a good number.
And same direction, so counter
clockwise.
If we hit play, we see that
that's a good speed for the
spin.
Right. So, now, let's bring the
last action in the sequence
which is the spin for the Earth.
So, we create another spin.
We select the Earth.
Same duration.
And because we want to have a
higher number of iterations
compared to the Sun, let's use
10 for this example.
And direction, again, counter
clockwise.
Let's give that a try and yeah,
that looks right.
So now our action sequence is
completely laid out.
So, let's try to play the whole
action sequence.
And we can do that by just
pressing play on the play button
in the Action Sequence header.
And what we see here is that
only the Earth is moving.
And that's because the action
sequence is playing all the
actions sequentially, one after
the other.
What we want to do here though
is to make all these actions
running parallel.
And for that we can use drag and
drop and drag the different
cards on top of each other.
And just by doing that, we
create a group with the four
actions.
And now let's just go ahead and
try [applause].
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
So, now, let's go ahead and hit
play and see how all the
behaviors play together.
And what we can see here is that
now all the orbit and spin
actions play together at the
same time as the text, and the
rays appear in the scene when
the Earth is passing by.
[ Applause ]
Okay. Let's go back to the
keynote.
So, that's how it easy it is to
bring some interactions and
behaviors to your scenes in
Reality Composer.
Now, let's move onto physics.
And so in order to create
amazing and immersive AR
experiences, you need your
objects to feed right into the
real world.
You need your objects to move
like real objects.
And for that, we need to take
advantage o this powerful
physics engine available to you
in Reality Composer.
So, let's take a look at it.
This is an example of a scene
that you can build in Reality
Composer using physics.
I use it here.
The sphere is falling because of
gravity, then it's colliding
with the pins.
And right at the end, once it
bounces with the green box,
it's, we show this, like, winner
text.
So, let's see how we can build
this kind of scene.
There's three different ways
that you can influence the
physics simulation in your
scene.
A variety of materials will
define how your objects interact
with the scene and with other
objects.
With the force action and the
gravity, you can determine how
the forces will play into your
world.
And with the collision trigger
and the collision shapes, you
can define how the collision
mechanics will work in your
physics simulation.
So, let's start with materials.
In Reality Composer, there's six
different materials that you can
use.
You have to define the materials
for the scene and for the
objects.
So, let's say you use material
for your object.
Use ice as the material of your
object.
This will make your object slide
through the scene.
If you use rubber instead, your
object will be much more bouncy.
Now, let's move onto forces.
All your scene will have gravity
enabled by default and the value
will be set to the Earth's
gravity.
But you can change that to any
value you want.
With the force action, you can
give your object an initial
impulse.
You define a direction, how much
velocity you want to give to the
object.
And you can build these kinds of
behaviors where you can add the
force once the user taps on the
object.
And now that your objects have
materials and can be affected by
forces, it's time to make them
collide with each other.
So, by default, in Reality
Composer, all the objects don't
participate in the physics
simulation.
If you want your objects to
collide with other objects, you
have to set the collide option.
If you want your objects to be
moved by the physics simulation,
you need to set the simulate
option.
So, here you can see how default
collides and simulate options
affect the objects in the scene.
[ Applause ]
So, the collision mechanics are
determined by the shapes of the
object in a scene.
In Reality Composer, there's
three different shapes that you
can use.
And those are box, sphere, and
capsule.
Those shapes will determine how
your object moves in the scene
and how it collides with other
objects and the anchor.
And with the collide trigger,
you can build these kinds of
behaviors where here we have a
collide trigger with the sphere
and the box.
And that way we can detect when
the user is winning this game
and show the winner text.
And that's pretty much all we
have to say about physics in
Reality Composer.
So now I would like to hand it
over to my colleague, Abhi, to
talk you through how to build
apps using Reality Composer.
Abhi?
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
My name is Abhi.
I'm super excited to be here
today.
So, earlier in the session, we
saw how with Reality Composer we
can create amazing 3D
experiences and then bring it to
life with behaviors.
Now, let's see how we can take
those AR experiences and
integrate them into our app.
So to get started, we provide
three different ways.
The first is create a new
RealityKit AR or Game template
right in Xcode.
Then second is to create a new
project from Reality Composer.
And the third is to export a
Reality file from Reality
Composer and then include it
inside your app.
To get started, let's start
about the two essential files,
the Reality Composer project and
the Reality file.
And we'll get started by talking
about the Reality Composer
project.
So, this is the project file for
Reality Composer.
It's included automatically
inside of RealityKit AR and Game
templates.
It's previewable right inside of
Xcode; we have Xcode
integration.
And Xcode automatically exports
your Reality Composer project as
a Reality file during the build
step of Xcode.
So, here we can see our Reality
Composer project.
In Xcode 11, we're able to
preview it and we're able to
preview each of our scenes as
well.
And in the upper right-hand
corner, we can see an Open in
Reality Composer button, and
this will launch Reality
Composer right from Xcode.
As I mentioned earlier, if you
have a Reality Composer project
in your Xcode application during
the build step, we automatically
generate a Reality file for you.
And it's included inside of your
application, just like any other
resource.
You can access it exactly the
same way.
So, what is a Reality file?
This is a central object for how
you will use your application
and work with your AR
experience.
It contains all the data
required for rendering and
simulation, and it's optimized
for RealityKit.
Like I said earlier, it's
exported from Reality Composer
or it's automatically exported
by Xcode during the build step
of your project.
You can use a Reality file
either by referencing it
directly in your application or
previewing it in AR Quick Look,
and we encourage you guys to go
check out the Advances in AR
Quick Look session tomorrow to
learn more about that.
Diving a little bit deeper, what
is a Reality file?
So because this is a file
exported from Reality Composer,
it'll contain each of the scenes
that you've created in Reality
Composer.
For example, we have two scenes
here, and it also contains every
object that you've created in
the application.
When we think about a scene in a
Reality file, we consider a
scene an anchor, an anchor
entity, specifically.
So, this contains for example
the horizontal anchor
information that you set up in
Reality Composer.
So, we thought one of the
biggest difficulties in working
with Reality files was being
able to access things with
strings.
And we both have the Reality
Composer project and Xcode.
So, we wanted to introduce a way
to make this very easy to work
with, almost like just an
object.
And so we decided to do that
with code generation in Xcode.
What code generation will do is
analyze the structure of your
Reality Composer project and
generate an object, a real
object that you can use inside
of your application.
So for example here, we have our
Solar System Reality Composer
project, and we automatically
generate a Solar System object
that you can use in your app.
So, the code generated for you
is an application-specific API
for your scenes, for your named
entities that Michelle mentioned
earlier, for notify actions, and
for notification triggers.
And we'll get to the second,
those last two items later in
the session.
The first step to get started
with code generation and working
with your AR experience is to
give names to everything you
care about and one axis in code
right in Reality Composer.
And you can do that here in the
Settings pane under Configure.
So for example here we've given
the Sun, our Sun USDZ that we
imported, the name Sun.
And we'll use this name to
access it in code.
So, how does our Reality
Composer project get converted
into an object that we can use?
At the top level, our Reality
Composer project becomes, for
example, solarsystem.swift.
Our scene becomes an entity that
has anchoring.
And this is really important,
because it means when you load
it, you can add it right into
your scene's anchors.
Additionally, any objects you
set up get converted into
entities.
These are real RealityKit
entities that you can use.
You can work with exactly the
same way.
In addition, we also provide two
different ways to load your
scene.
One that is synchronous and one
that is asynchronous.
So, taking a look at loading a
Reality file synchronously, here
we have our solar system as our
example again and we'd like to
load the seasonsChapter.
And we can do that with a single
line of code.
So, we can say solarsystem.load
seasons chapter.
And we'll get returned an anchor
that we can then add into our
view.
It's super simple.
Next, if we want to load our
seasonschapter asynchronously or
any scene, we can use for
example the solarsystem.load
seasons chapter async, and we'll
get a result object.
And we can handle the success
case.
We'll get the anchor.
Or we can handle the failure
case, and display the error to
the user.
In addition, if we want to
access the named entities in our
scene, we can do so as easily as
calling for example seasons.sun,
.earth, and .moon.
And this will give us access to
the entity that we named in
Reality Composer.
It's just like working with any
other object.
So, putting it all together with
code generation in Xcode and
Reality Composer, we can load
our AR experience in our
application with just two lines
of code.
The first is loading our chapter
or loading our scene, and the
second is adding it right into
our view.
It's super easy.
[ Applause ]
So, that's code generation in
Xcode.
We also provide a way to access
your Reality file.
For example, in cases where
you're downloading content off
of a server and you want to
display that in your
application, to do that, we have
RealityKit API.
So, to load a Reality file
synchronously, you first need to
get the URL just like any other
resource in your application
bundle.
And next, using the entity.load
anchor method, passing the URL
of the resource, and the name of
the scene that you'd like to
load, and this will give you
back an anchor that you can use.
Optionally, you can also use
entity.load which will load the
entity tree without the anchor
information.
To load your Reality file
asynchronously, there's also a
way to do that.
So the first step is exactly the
same.
Just get the URL resource of the
resource.
Use entity.load anchor async,
passing in the URL and the name
of the scene that you'd like to
load.
This will give you a load
request.
And using the new combined
framework, we can receive a
completion and then receive the
value, and the value contains
the anchor that we'd like to
load.
So, you can put this right into
your AR view scene.
Accessing entities.
You can do this through
anchor.find entity, and then
passing the name of the object
that you'd like to load.
For example, Sun, Earth, and
Moon.
So, that's how easy it is with
code generation in Xcode with
the RealityKit to bring your AR
experiences into your
application.
So, next, let's talk about how
our application can interact
with our AR content.
We can create amazing
experiences right inside of
Reality Composer, but how do we
actually work with it?
So, as Pau mentioned earlier, we
have a great built-in set of
actions already for you, but
there might be actions that you
want to define yourself.
So to do that, we've created the
notify action.
This is an action that you set
up in Reality Composer.
It's called alongside your other
action sequences, exactly in the
same order.
For example, if it's sequenced,
it'll be called in that
sequence.
There's a settable closure in
your application code, so you
can define the implementation of
this action.
And just like accessing an
entity through code generation,
the Notify action is also
accessible through your object.
So, in Reality Composer, we can
set up a notify action here and
we can give it an identifier.
This is the identifier we'll use
in code to reference our notify
action and provide a custom
implementation.
In the structure of our
generated object, the actions
lives alongside your energies
inside of the scene object.
So here we have actions and a
property actions.
Inside of the actions class,
you'll see multiple notify
actions that have the name of
the identifier you've given your
notify action.
So you can access these as
simply as the loaded
anchor.actions and then the name
of the action that you care
about.
In addition, we also generate an
all actions array, so you can do
great things with this, just
like any other collection in
Swift.
You can filter over it, you can
iterate over it.
Anything you can do with an
array in Swift, you can do with
this all actions property.
To actually set the
implementation of a notify
action, you first need to access
it through your Alert anchor.
So, for example here,
seasonschapter.actions .display
Earth details, and then provide
the custom closer.
So .onaction.
And the entity that you'll get
returned inside of this closure
is the target entity you set up
in Reality Composer.
On the other side, to actually
kick off action sequences and
provide a way to do this as
well, we have a couple of great
built-in triggers such as Scene
Start and Proximity.
But there might be times you
want to provide custom triggers.
For example, selecting a segment
of control or tapping on a
button.
And for that, we're providing
the Notification Trigger.
So Notification Trigger is set
up in Reality Composer.
It starts an action sequence or
multiple sequences that have the
same identifier.
It's posted from the runtime of
your application.
And it's accessible just like a
Notify Action and acts as your
entities just by name in your
code.
You can set up a notification
trigger right inside of your
behavior and here we have given
it the identifier show gold
star.
And we'll use this name in code.
Just like actions, it lives
right alongside your entities in
the generated code inside of a
new notifications object class.
And inside of Notifications,
just like Notify Actions, you'll
have Notification Triggers
corresponding to the names, the
identifiers that you've given to
those Notification Triggers in
Reality Composer.
And just like Notify Actions,
you have an array that you can
filter over it or iterate over
as well.
That's called all notifications.
You can post a Notification
Trigger by calling the post
method, and this will fire an
action sequence or sequences
with the same name.
And you can also pass in an
optional override set.
This is really powerful for
cases where you want to copy an
entity and dynamically call an
action sequence on only the new
entity.
The overrides will take as a key
the name of the original target
of the action in Reality
Composer, and then you pass in
the new target.
So when the action sequence
runs, it only targets the new
entity.
So, let's pull this all together
and let's check it out in Xcode.
[ Applause ]
So, here I have my application.
Over the course of the session,
Pau and Michelle have built up
the Seasons chapter of our Solar
System lesson.
And here I want to implement a
second chapter based on the
sizes of different celestial
bodies.
So here we have our Xcode 11,
just our base application, and
we have already included our
Reality Composer project.
Again, you can create a new AR
or Game template or you can drag
a Reality Composer project right
into Xcode.
We can preview the project right
in Xcode here and go ahead and
open it in Reality Composer.
Let's take a quick tour of this
and the application before
writing some code.
So, in our chapter we've set up
a couple of entities and we've
given our scene a name and we've
given different entities that we
care about a name.
For example this gold star is
called special star.
This is the name we'll use in
our code.
Additionally, we've set up a
couple of behaviors.
So for example, for the Moon, we
want to know when the Moon is
tapped so we can store some
application state, and also hide
all the other text labels and
only display the Moon's labels.
And all of these actions happen
at the same time because they're
grouped.
Additionally, we have a notify
action and we'll use this to
know when the Moon is tapped
inside of our application.
We've implemented the same
action sequence for the Earth
and the Sun as well.
We also have a Look At camera
action set up when the scene
starts, so each of our text
labels will look at the camera
no matter where we're looking.
And we have a hide on start
action sequence which will hide
all the entities that we want to
view only at specific times.
For example, the chapter
completed, text, and the text
labels.
Additionally, we have some
action sequences that will be
triggered in code.
We'll get to this later in this
demo, that will scale the
celestial bodies to their
relative sizes, scale them back
to the same size.
Display the chapter completed
text.
Begin the Earth orbit.
And hide all of the other
celestial bodies.
And we have a cool little
animation fired from a
notification trigger that will
show the gold star, spin it, and
give it a bounce.
So let's jump back to our Xcode
application now and do a quick
tour.
So this application is pretty
straightforward.
It's a single view application.
And at the top level we have an
AR view, a segmented control to
switch between size and detail
view, a lesson completed button,
so the student can just say I'm
done with the lesson and view
the chapter at the end.
In a detail view, that will show
more details as we tap on the
Moon, the Earth, and the Sun.
Additionally, we have some view
models that will just drive that
detail view, so it just shows
some text, and then some basic
application logic to kick off
our loading.
And let's look at loading first.
So down here, the first thing
you'll notice is we're using
code generation in this project.
So our Reality Composer project
is automatically converted into
an object that we can use.
It's a real type, so we can use
it right here for the size
chapter property.
So for example, Solar System
lesson.size chapter is a real
type that we can use.
We can go ahead and load our
scene and let's walk through
this code as well.
So what we're doing is loading
the size chapter asynchronously
and then we're handling, we're
giving the loaded anchor
collision shapes so that tap
triggers work.
And then we're adding it into
our scene.
Because we'll be using the size
chapter later, we're storing it
in the size chapter property and
we're setting up notify actions,
which we'll get to later.
Right now it's not hooked up.
So let's go ahead and run this.
We'll see with just a few lines
of code we're bringing our
entire AR experience and it
should work exactly the same way
it did in Reality Composer.
So here we go.
We have our scene.
We see the content.
For example, chapter completed
is hidden and when we tap on
each of our celestial bodies,
we'll see text automatically
appear and it will face the
camera no matter where we're
looking, and same with the Sun.
So, that looks pretty great.
With a few lines of code, we
brought our entire Reality
Composer project into Xcode.
It's super simple.
What I want to do next is
actually fill in this detail
view.
You'll notice when I tapped the
Sun, for example, the detail
view didn't actually get filled
in.
So let's jump back to Xcode and
fill in the notify actions.
So because our notify actions
are automatically generated for
us, we also get an all actions
array that we can filter over.
And we're going to filter over
those actions to get only the
actions we care about which
begin with display.
So, let's walk through this
code.
Because we set up notify actions
in our size chapter, we can jump
back to Reality Composer to look
at those.
For each the Moon, the Earth,
and the Sun, right here, display
Moon details, display Earth
details, and display Sun
details, we can access these in
code.
And we want to actually filter
over our notify actions for only
actions that begin with display,
because we want to set the same
closure for each of them.
So, jumping back to Xcode,
that's what we're doing here.
We're doing size chapter.actions
.all actions, and we're
filtering over it, getting the
identifier from the notify
action object, and checking that
it starts with display.
Next we're iterating over all of
the display actions and setting
the same closure for each using
the on-action property.
And we're taking the target of
our notify action, in this case
for the Moon it's the Moon, for
the Sun it's the Sun, and for
the Earth it's the Earth, and
using that entity to display
different view models.
So let's run this application
now.
And what we like to see is
different view models appear
when we tap on each of our
celestial bodies.
There we go.
So we have our content, and now
when we tap on the Moon, because
we've set up a notify action and
we're observing those
notifications, we're now seeing
the Moon detail right at the
bottom here.
When we tap on the Earth, we see
Earth's details, and we tap on
the Sun, we're seeing the Sun's
details.
That looks pretty great.
We also were keeping some state.
So, when we tap on all three of
our Earth, Sun, and Moon
actions, we're just making sure
that three different actions
were called, and we display a
complete lesson button up here
in the right-hand corner.
So what we want to do now is
using Notification Triggers,
fire off those size relative
size, and size to same size
action sequences that we set up
in Reality Composer using the
segmented control at the top and
the button in the upper
right-hand corner.
So, we can do this with a
segmented control value change
method.
This is an Interface Builder
method that we've set up and
hooked up in Interface Builder
itself.
And using our Notification
Action, Triggers, we can fire
the scale to same size action
sequence, which we set up in
Reality Composer down here,
which will scale each of our
celestial bodies back to their
original scale of 100%.
And when the size segmented
control is selected, we want to
scale our Sun to a relative size
to the Earth.
To do that, we can fire our
scale to relative sizes action
sequence.
And finally when the lesson
completed button is tapped, this
is an Interface Builder action
that we've set up and hooked up,
we'll fire the chapter completed
Notification Trigger.
And what this one does is
because there are three
different Notification Triggers
hooked up in Reality Composer,
we'll fire all three of these
action sequences.
We'll fade out the existing
content.
We'll then begin an orbit of our
little Earth and little Moon.
And we'll show the chapter
completed section.
So, let's run this now and see
our application.
All right, so here we have our
content.
We can tap on the Moon.
Everything works exactly the
same as we set up in Reality
Composer.
And now when we tap the size
segmented control when looking
at the Earth and the Sun, we get
a really good scale of just how
big the Sun is compared to
Earth.
It's pretty tiny.
So, that looks great.
Let's size it back, and let's
complete our lesson.
I'm going to tap the lesson
completed, the complete lesson
button at the top right-hand
corner.
And we'll see our content fades
out, and we see our chapter
completed along with an orbit
starting for our tiny Sun.
That looks pretty great, and we
can see how with Notification
Triggers and Notify Actions, we
can work with our application
and our AR content.
There's one last thing I want to
do.
We discussed post with
overrides, and I want to show
you how we can use that to
display dynamic content using
application state.
So because this is a lesson
application, we want to display
gold stars based on how well a
student does.
For this session, I think we all
did pretty great so I'm just
going to give us three stars,
and we can see how we can set
this up.
This is a method that we're
calling inside of our display
details view up above where
we're keeping state.
So this looks like a lot of code
that I just pasted in, but let's
walk through it.
So the first thing we're doing
is accessing our special star
entity that we set up in Reality
Composer right here.
We've given it the name special
star, so we're now accessing it
right in Xcode.
Next, we're triggering the show
gold star action sequence right
in code, so that will display
the first gold star.
But we want to display three.
So, we can do that by
dispatching after maybe two and
a half seconds for this demo,
and we're going to clone the
star.
Then we're going to position it
to the right and up a little
bit.
We're going to add it to our
scene.
And then using post overrides,
we're passing in the original
target of the action sequence,
and then passing in the new
action, the new target of the
action, in this case the right
star.
And we want to do the same thing
for the left star.
So, we're copying it again,
copying the star.
Positioning it to the left and
down a little bit, adding it to
our scene, and again, posting
with overrides, taking the
original name and passing in the
left star this time as the
target of our action sequence.
So, let's build and run this app
now, and what we'd like to see
is three gold stars appear, even
though we've only set up one in
our application.
This is driven entirely by
application logic.
So here's our scene again.
We can walk through the lesson.
I think I'm done now, so I'll
click complete lesson.
And we see one gold star
appears.
We'll see a second gold star
And there's our third star.
We did a great job, so we got
three stars here.
[ Applause ]
So, that's how easy it is to
load your AR content into your
application, begin working with
it with notify actions to
provide your custom own
implementations, and then
Trigger Action sequences that
you set up in Reality Composer
using Notification Triggers.
So, let's take a tour of what we
learned today.
We learned with Reality Composer
we can create amazing AR
experiences using the built-in
modular assets, for example the
sphere or the cube.
And then we can bring those
assets to life with behaviors
and simple interactions.
Finally, we can bring those
amazing AR experiences into our
applications using code
generation and deep integration
with Xcode.
We have already seen some
amazing stuff being created by
you guys using Reality Composer.
We encourage you guys to keep
creating.
We're super excited to see the
amazing AR applications that you
can create.
We have some sessions and labs
available to you guys today and
tomorrow, and we encourage you
guys to bring questions, your
projects, anything else, we're
happy to help you.
Have a great rest of your WWDC.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]