[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
Welcome to the session.
Today, I would like to talk
about multiuser AR in ARKit 3.
My name is Kuen-han.
I'm a ARKit engineer.
I would like to show you all the
enhancement we made in ARKit 3,
so building a multiuser AR app
becomes easy and intuitive.
So, you can focus on all the
amazing content within your app.
Are you interested in bringing
more people to the AR world?
Then, this talk is for you.
Let's begin.
Building a shared AR experience
is about synchronization.
Like the SwiftStrike video you
are seeing here, not only we
need to keep tracking the
location of the bowling pin but,
also, we need to track the
location of the user and their
interaction with the ball.
But sometimes, track that
information can be tricky and
complicated to make it right.
And that is what ARKit 3 want to
solve for you.
In ARKit 3, we introduce
collaborative session, which
makes sharing 3D content
location easy.
And with RealityKit, all the
game setups and physics
simulation can be synchronized
automatically under hood.
So, you can focus on your
content.
Let's look at today's agenda.
First, we're going to introduce
the collaborative session, a new
way to build multiuser app in
ARKit 3.
Next, we're going to dive into
some best practices for using
ARAnchors, especially in the
context of multiuser AR.
Last, David is going to
introduce you the SwiftStrike.
By utilizing ARKit 3 and
RealityKit, SwiftStrike provide
a new level of multiuser AR game
experience.
Let's start from collaborative
session.
To begin with, let's recap last
year's multiuser AR feature we
delivered in ARKit 2, Map Save
and Load.
In ARKit 2, we delivered Map
Save and Load which is designed
for persistent AR experience.
The user can record their
current AR experience and
recontinue after loading the
map.
The same feature can also be
used for multiuser AR.
Within this feature, we
introduced a data structure
called the ARWorldMap which
contains map of 3D landmarks
that are used for camera
position tracking.
And also, a list of ARAnchors
which represents the 3D corners
of your virtual content.
Within this example, we have a
tabletop scene and we load the
ARWorldMap on top of it.
So, we have several three
landmarks on the table and two
ARAnchors.
When you use this feature for
multiuser AR, each user loaded
from the same ARWorldMap.
Then, ARKit will use the three
landmarks within the ARWorldMap,
try to localize the device
itself against to the map.
Once ARKit managed to do that,
the user can start to see the
same virtual content at the
right physical location.
This feature provides a good
multiuser AR experience.
If you already pre-map the
environment and also have all
the anchors you need saved in
the ARWorldMap.
However, any new information
that ARKit gathered afterwards
won't be shared.
For instance, one of the user
may keep exploring the table on
one side and putting one extra
anchor while the other user
doing the same.
Those newly learned map
information and ARAnchors won't
be visible to all the users.
So, that makes this feature as a
one-time sharing AR experience
and is not optimized for unseen
environment beyond the pre-map
area.
And that is what collaborative
session want to solve for you.
Collaborative session is mainly
designed for the live multiuser
AR experience.
All the learned map information
and anchors are shared
continuously throughout the full
session.
That means any user can add
anchor at any point of time and
that will reflect on all the
users' screen.
And also, every user exploring
the map together, that means
they are benefit each other to
have the best tracking and also
most consistent tracking
experience.
That means this feature is
friendly for unseen environment.
You can also use this feature
with or without the map.
In addition, this feature use a
decentralized design with
peer-to-peer communication
pattern, similar to
MultipeerConnectivity.
Therefore, there is not host
user within the session.
Any user can come join the
session or leave the session at
any point of time without
interrupting others' user AR
experiences.
Let's see one example.
Here, we have two users running
in collaborative sessions.
They both start their own AR
experiences.
At the beginning, they both do a
small world exploration and put
in one ARAnchor.
As the user keeps exploring the
environment, once they start
seeing the area other use have
explored before, the user can
start seeing the ARAnchors added
by others.
In this case, the first user
starts seeing the yellow cube,
while the second user starts
seeing the purple cube.
Afterwards, any anchors that
added by the users will
immediately shows up on the
other's screen.
Because the sharing happens live
continuously, so there is no
interruption for the users' AR
experience.
And also, even most of the
existing multiuser AR app
requires a host user within the
session.
With collaborative session, now
it enables the new possibility
to build a decentralized
multiuser AR app.
Next, I'm going to dive into
more about this decentralized
design and how does it affect
the current systems within
collaborative session.
In this decentralized design,
there is no host user within the
session.
That means each user can start
their own AR experiences before
they start to receiving each
other.
So, that means each user can
have their own AR world
coordinates.
In this example, we have two
user running collaborative
session.
Each user start doing the small
world exploration and putting
one Anchor on each side of the
table.
Then, within the collaborative
session the ARKit will transmit
the so-called the collaboration
data pushes a piece of your
ARWorldMap information to all
the other users and save it as
external maps.
Then, as the user keep exploring
the environment, once they start
to see the same area others have
seen before, ARKit will utilize
those 3D landmarks in the common
area and try to localize itself
against the external map.
When they succeed, those
external maps will merge locally
into each user's local
coordinate.
Note that at this point, user
still have different world
coordinate.
But because ARAnchors is
attached to the map so the user
can still see the virtual object
at the right physical location.
And that is why it is important
to use ARAnchor in collaborative
session.
So, let's take a look how to use
collaborative session in ARKit
3.
In order to use collaborative
session, first you need to make
sure all the users are in the
same networking layer.
This networking layer can be
either MultipeerConnectivity or
any other alternative solution
that provides reliable
communication.
Once they are in the same
networking layer, they can
transmit information to each
other.
Then, you simply need to enable
collaboration in your own AR
session.
Once that is enabled, your AR
session will periodically
generate the collaboration data
as I mentioned before.
Then, it is the app's
responsibility to transmit this
data to all the other users.
That is the only new code you
need to add in ARKit 3 in order
to use collaborative session.
Let's take a look.
To begin with, you need to
create a AR world tracking
configuration.
Then, you simply set the
isCollaborationEnabled to true.
Then, you just run a session.run
to run your AR session.
If you are using RealityKit,
this is the only new code you
need to add to use collaborative
session.
If you are not using RealityKit,
then you need to implement
additional two delegate
functions to transmit the
collaboration data.
The first delegate function is
ARSession
didOutputcollaborationData.
When your own AR session create
this collaboration data, you
need to transmit to all the
other users.
Here, we have one example using
MultipeerConnectivity.
If your networking solution
replies a failure to transmit
this data, then it is your app's
responsibility to transmit this
data again to make sure the data
is delivered.
Then, once you receive this
data, you simply need to call
arSession.update delegate
function to pass this received
data to your underlying AR
session.
By implementing these two
delegate functions, you complete
the flow to transmit
collaboration data.
Once the collaboration data
transmission is running in the
background, the transmission
will happens throughout the
whole session.
Then, for each user, they just
start their own AR experience,
as before.
As I mentioned earlier, the
shared AR experience will begin
after the user can localize
itself against the other user's
map.
When that happen, your own AR
session will start to receive
the first ARAnchors added by
others which can be served as
indication of the beginning of
your shared AR experiences.
Let's look at some new
properties for ARAnchors in
collaborative session.
Within collaborative session,
all the user created ARAnchors
are lifetime are synchronized.
That means the user can add or
remove the anchors at any point
of time and that will reflect to
all the other users.
And also, we add a session
identifier to each ARAnchor
which can be used as a indicator
who is the original creator of
this ARAnchor, so your app can
react accordingly.
Last, only the user created
ARAnchors are shared.
That excludes all the subclass
ARAnchors, including
ARImageAnchor, ARPlaneAnchor,
and ARObjectAnchor.
That also excludes the user
subclass ARAnchor which were
used to attach user data within
Map Save and Load.
At the beginning, you may think
this is the drawback of this, of
this collaborative session
design.
But don't worry.
This is where collaborative
session and RealityKit plays
well hand-in-hand.
By using RealityKit, you can
attach your user data to
corresponding entity component.
Once you attach your user entity
to the corresponding ARAnchor,
all those information will be
synchronized under hood,
including all the physical
simulation, scene change, and
sound effects.
For more information, you may
want to check Introducing
RealityKit and Reality Composer
that we present in Tuesday.
So, let's take a look about the
code, how to use ARAnchor in
collaborative session.
Now, within collaborative
session, when you receive
ARSession didAddAnchors
delegate function, you may want to check
the session identifier to see
whether this anchor is added by
yourself or added by others.
Same thing when you receive the
ARSession didRemove anchor.
You may also want to check
whether it's removed by yourself
or by others, so your app can
react accordingly.
So, that summarize the ARAnchor
which represents the 3D
[inaudible] existence of your
virtual object.
Further, in collaborative
session it's also important to
know other users' position.
For that, we introduce a new
anchor called
ARParticipantAnchor.
ARParticipantAnchor represents
other users' location within
your own world coordinates.
It has a high frame rate update
rate, same as other users' AR
frame rate.
This ARParticipantAnchor is
ultimately created by your own
AR session when it managed to
localize itself against the
other user's map which means you
can also use this
ARParticipantAnchor as
indication of the beginning of
your shared AR experience.
By using ARAnchor and
ARParticipantAnchor, you can
correctly visualize other users'
3D content in your own world
coordinate.
So, that is how you would use
collaborative session in ARKit
3.
Let's look at some practical
advice how to start a shared AR
experience using collaborative
session.
As I mentioned before, a shared
AR experience will begin after
each users localize their self
in other users' map.
That means they have to see the
area other user have seen
before.
But sometimes, depends on users'
motion, this could take time.
If you want the user to have
shared experience faster, we
have two advice.
First, it is recommended to have
one of the user approach to the
other user to have the same
camera perspective.
For instance, in this example,
we have two users seeing the
table but they are seeing in
cross direction.
Then, it's not likely for ARKit
to localize them self to begin
the shared AR experience.
However, if you have two users
stand side-by-side and looking
at the same direction, then it
is more likely for ARKit to
localize and also to start a
shared AR experience.
Second, while you are doing
this, it is the best to have one
your user stay in map-tracking
status.
That is, ARFrame
WorldMappingStatus mapped.
By doing this, you make sure one
of the user is actually seeing
the 3D landmarks that are stored
inside the ARWorldMap,
therefore, when the other user
approach it is more likely they
can use those three landmarks to
localize them self and start a
shared AR experience.
Let's see one example.
Here, we have two users running
in collaborative session.
The first user simply do a small
world exploration and adding one
ARAnchor and stay in
map-tracking status.
While the other user simply
approach the first user and see
the same view, then they will
start seeing the same anchors
which is used to also indicate
the beginning of your shared AR
experience.
This device is also applicable
for last year Map Save and Load.
So, you may want to put this
advice in your app to recommend
the motion of two user so user
can start their shared AR
experience faster.
So, that summarize our
introduction and suggestion for
using collaborative session.
Our API is simple and intuitive.
With RealityKit, you only need
to add a few lines to enable the
experience.
I encourage you to give it a try
and see the new multiuser AR
experience in ARKit 3.
Next, I would like to talk about
the best practices for using
ARAnchors.
As I mentioned before, ARAnchors
are the main way to share
virtual content within
collaborative session.
Here, we have three simple but
effective suggestions for using
ARAnchor.
To begin with, let's look back
the ARWorldMap.
As I mentioned before, each
ARWorldMap consists collection
with 3D map landmarks and, also,
list of ARAnchors.
In addition, we also save
collection of camera poses.
Those camera poses represent the
camera view when three landmarks
are first observed.
For instance, in this example,
we have five camera poses where
they are created when the three
landmarks are first created.
So, with this camera view we can
segment the three landmarks into
different groups to present
different parts of the map.
Once you have those views, when
the user added one ARAnchor, the
user will provide a global
position of this ARAnchor
respect to the world coordinate.
However, what is actually save
within our ARWorldMap is the
relative position of this
ARAnchor to the one of the
nearest view.
It is this relative positions
we're keeping inside the
ARWorldMap and also transmit in
the collaborative session.
To make sure, even if issues are
have different world coordinate,
they still can see the ARAnchor
at the right physical location.
So, once again, that is why it
is important to use ARAnchors in
collaborative session.
With this knowledge in mind,
let's look at our best practices
for using ARAnchor.
First, always respond to the
ARAnchor update.
As AR [inaudible] exploring the
map more and more, it will
optimize the 3D landmarks
position by fine-tune the camera
pose location.
When that happen, your ARAnchor
position will change as well
because it is attached to the
view.
So, you need to react to those
anchor update function so you
can change your virtual object
position accordingly.
Second, when you place your
virtual object, it is the best
to place virtual object near to
the ARAnchor but not far away
from the ARAnchor.
The reasoning is the same as
before.
When the anchor update happens,
if you have virtual object far
away from the ARAnchor, then you
could experience a large and
spatial update to your virtual
object which is not desirable.
So, it is the best to place your
virtual object near to the
ARAnchor, so you can represent
the tracking quality correctly.
Last, if you have multiple
independent virtual objects,
then it is recommended to use
multiple ARAnchors so they will
attach to different parts of the
maps.
Therefore, make sure virtual
object to corresponding ARAnchor
distance is small.
However, if you have a scenario
where you have multiple virtual
objects that you want to
maintain their relative
distance.
Then, it is legitimate to use
one single ARAnchor to represent
them all as long as they are not
far away from the anchors.
So, that summarize our best
practices for using ARAnchors.
By following those best
practices, you can utilize the
best tracking quality that ARKit
provides to your app.
Next, we're going to move to
David to talk about SwiftStrike.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks.
Well done.
Hi, everyone.
I'm David and I'm here to talk
to you about SwiftStrike which
is the new multiplayer AR
experience that we developed for
the show here at WWDC 2019.
We were inspired by the work we
did last year with SwiftShot and
we wanted to build something new
that leveraged RealityKit and
ARKit 3 to deliver an all-new
experience.
We have a Tabletop version
that's available as sample code
now.
And we're working on releasing
the full version as sample code
in the future.
If you want to, you can also go
look at last year's session
about SwiftShot.
I'm going to talk a little bit
about a couple of things we did
in SwiftShot and compare and
contrast what we're doing this
year.
So, you may want to take a look
at that.
Now, there's a lot that goes
into building a game like
SwiftStrike.
There's sound design, asset
design, animations, all kinds of
things.
I'm really going to focus on
three areas here.
How we use RealityKit networking
to get the shared experience up
and running.
The physics simulation to make
sure that the game played and
was fun.
And also, a little bit about how
we designed the game around the
new capabilities of RealityKit
and ARKit 3.
So, first, RealityKit
networking.
RealityKit networking is based
on the entity-component
architecture that's built into
RealityKit.
As you write and change
components, they're
automatically synchronized
across the network for you
including all the physics state.
You don't have to do any of that
code yourself.
You can also define custom
components for your own apps,
application, or game, game
logic.
And it will take care of the
synchronization for you, as
well.
It used MultipeerConnectivity as
the network layer.
This is built into all iOS and
macOS devices.
It's easy to set up and get
going.
And it, all you have to do is
create that network session,
hand it to the ARView object,
and it takes care of the rest.
That includes moving the
collaborative mapping data that
Kuen-han talked about with the
new ARKit 3 collaborative
mapping.
And so, in SwiftStrike, we
discovered that the best way to
get things working you know,
MultipeerConnectivity,
RealityKit are all hostless,
true peer-to-peer systems.
We discovered that for our game
to really get things working we
needed to define one device as
the host.
It's the one that keeps track of
what the state of the game is
and how the physics is working.
The other devices participate
and provide input and also
receive the information from the
host about where the game is
running.
So, again, about custom
components in RealityKit.
They're really easy to set up.
You define a struct.
You register the components
before you instantiate the
ARView.
And you comply with the Swift
Codable protocol.
That provides all the
information RealityKit needs to
serialize your structure and
send it across the network.
So, here's one way we use that
in the game.
We've discovered through
playtesting in SwiftStrike, it
was really important to make
sure that both players were
positioned in their starting
spot when the game starts.
Otherwise, it was possible for
one player to get an advantage,
be closer to the ball, and kind
of get around the other user.
So, we have an object we call
the Match object.
It keeps track of whether or not
each player is in the starting
space or not and then, decides
when to launch the ball.
That state is also synchronized
over the clients so that we can
present instructions to them
using UIKit as to where they
need to stand.
The component also maintains a
log of all those states.
There's not many that it goes
through, and it helps ensure
that every client will see every
state as it occurs.
So, here's an example of that in
work.
We wait until both players have
gotten into position before we
launch the ball.
Once they have, the ball
launches and the game begins.
Here's the code that we used to
do that.
First, is the component we
define.
The MatchStateComponent.
It conforms to both the
RealityKit component protocol
and the Swift Codable protocol.
We define a transition within
it.
And there's an array of
transitions.
So, each device gets a full log
of all the Match states as they
go forward.
You can respond appropriately.
Before we get started, we
register our component with AR,
with RealityKit so that it is
ready to start synchronizing it.
That's all we need to do.
Now, changes to the component on
the host are automatically
synchronized over to the
clients.
On the client, we, we then use
that.
We create a, a MatchObserver
object that watches that
component for changes and then,
broadcasts them out to all
interested parties.
We're using the combined
framework for this.
It's a great alternative to
using delegation and really
gives you a lot of flexibility.
I'd recommend looking in on some
of the combined sessions from
this year.
So, when we were doing
SwiftStrike, we kind of started
by bringing over a lot of the
code from SwiftShot.
And if you watched the session
from last year, we spent a lot
of time talking about how we
synchronized the physics data,
how we encoded it, how we really
compressed it and made it tight
to limit our network usage.
So, here's a list of most of the
classes or types that we had to
implement that.
Well, RealityKit does the
Physics, PhysicsSync for us.
And using custom components, it
can also synchronize game state
for us.
So, we deleted all of that.
Didn't need it, anymore.
And then, we took a look at the
messages that were left, which
were really only about deciding
whether to use collaborative
mapping or world map sharing to
get the game started.
It only gets set once.
So, they don't need to be
tightly encoded.
So, sad to say, I deleted the
BitStream code.
That's about 1500 lines of code
that we were able to get rid of
and that's lines of code that
you won't have to write,
anymore, thanks to RealityKit
networking, to get your shared
AR experience up and running.
[ Applause ]
Next, let's talk about the
physics simulation itself.
That synchronization, as I said,
is handled by RealityKit using
its built-in physics engine.
On any of these, you can
configure the physics properties
by setting up components.
We set up the rigid body.
That defines the shape of the
object in the scene.
You define collision masks that
configure which device, which
objects in your scene can
collide with which other
objects.
And then, also, the additional
physical properties of the
object.
The mass, the friction, the
restitution.
All of those play into getting
that right to get a great
experience.
In SwiftStrike, the host device
owns the simulation.
But the client devices provide
information about where each
individual player is to make the
game happen.
And I'll talk about how that
works, later on.
Now, in SwiftStrike, most of the
objects are pretty simple.
The ball is the sphere, the, the
you know, the play surface is a
plane.
We put walls on the sides to
make sure the ball doesn't fly
out.
But there's one object that we
really needed to get right,
that's a little bit more
complicated than that.
And that's the bowling pin.
You know, really needed this to
bounce true and sound right for
the game to be compelling.
This is the just the wire frame
of the 3D model our technical
art has provided for us.
And this is then updated to make
it really look great when it
renders.
But really, it's far too much
data for the physics simulation.
We wanted to take this and make
it a lot simpler while still
maintaining a great bowling pin
kind of feel.
So, here's kind of what we did
with that.
We used a combination of the
primitive shapes as that's part
of RealityKit because it's
networking the spheres at the
top and in the middle.
And then, we also built convex
hulls around the pin to give it
a base to stand on and, and the
neck to bounce of off other
things.
You know, when you're doing a
physics simulation, you want to
be careful to use primitives
whenever you can.
If you can't, make sure that
your convex hulls are relatively
simple.
This will give you the best
performance.
So, we spent a lot of time
tuning this to get the right
combination.
So here's what that looked like
all together in the data.
But of course, on the court, you
just see the great looking pin
itself.
RealityKit's physically based
rendering really gives a good
shine on it and makes it looks
great.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, last thing, let's talk a
little bit about the game
design.
And that has three areas.
You know, designing for People
Occlusion, building an on-site
experience, and defining a
control mechanism for the game
itself.
When we learned about ARKit 3's
Person Occlusion, we knew right
away that we wanted this year's
game to be a full-size
experience.
And we designed it so that you
see Person Occlusion happening
right from the start.
When you're in starting position
you see the ball in front of
you, you see the other player,
and you see the pins behind the
other player.
Right away, Person Occlusion is
a big part of the game.
Previously, building an AR
experience, you had to kind of
make sure that you didn't get a
person between the camera and
the content.
And then, so SwiftShot pretty
much had to be a Tabletop game
last year.
With SwiftStrike and Person
Occlusion, now you've got a lot
more possibilities as to how you
want to include the virtual
content in your, in your game.
Now, a full-size game requires a
full-size space to play it in.
So, we worked with the
facilities team and had a custom
floor installed here at the
Convention Center for people to
play on.
The wood flooring not only
evokes a bowling alley but also
provides lots of great feature
points for the ARKit tracking.
So, you get a nice stable
display.
We also used the image on the
logo in the center of the court
to position the gameboard
property properly.
ARKit image anchors are used to
find that location, put the
board there.
So, every time it starts the
game is correctly positioned and
people are ready to go.
Now, for the AR localization,
we're using a combination of
ARKit world maps and
collaborative data.
The players start with a world
map on their device that they
load and get localized very
quickly.
And then, they start sharing
collaborative data after that.
So, they get up fast with the
Quick Start and then, maintain
that over time as the devices
share the data about the world
around them.
Finally, let's talk about the
control mechanism.
With SwiftShot last year, we
thought we had a pretty simple
control mechanism.
Right. Just tap to grab, pull to
release.
We made it even simpler this
year.
You don't have to touch the
screen; you just move it to push
the ball.
We discovered through game
playtesting that it was great if
the faster push, faster movement
would mean a bigger push on the
ball.
Give it a kick and make it
really bounce past the other
player.
The other thing we discovered
though in our playtesting was
every once in a while, the ball
would roll right through you.
And that wasn't great.
So, instead, we added an
invisible physics body located
where the player is.
And then, we discovered that we
could just win the game by
running around and knocking over
all the, all the other players'
pins.
So, instead, we're using
collision masks to filter that
out.
The ball will collide with the
pins and with a person, but the
pins and the person won't
collide with each other.
That was some of the ways that
we used the networking system
and the physics to really get,
get a great, great experience.
Now, one of the things that we
needed to solve then, is how do
we get the input from this
device moving around onto the
device while maintaining control
over when the paddle is active
and how much force it's applying
on the host.
And so, we solved this using the
ownership support within
RealityKit.
When the host starts the AR
session, it creates a
AnchorEntity as all content
within RealityKit is all
parented to an AnchorEntity that
the host maintains ownership
over.
When the Client joins, it adds
another entity to the scene that
we call the
PlayerLocationEntity, using the
subclassing support with
RealityKit.
This maintains ownership by the
Client, so the Client can update
its location with every frame.
And that's parented to the
AnchorEntity so it appears in
all the devices.
As a child of that, we add the
PaddleEntity.
And it's parented to the
PlayerLocationEntity.
So, as the player moves around,
the PlayerLocationEntity
location gets updated.
And that moves the PaddleEntity
that the host maintains control
over what, what actions the
PaddleEntity takes.
It can turn it on and off and
make sure that the gameplay
remains fun for everybody.
So, let's look at that, that,
how all that came together with
ARKit 3 and RealityKit to make a
great gameplay experience.
Here again, is part of the video
from the State of the Union on
Monday showing everyone playing
the game.
And Adam is, once again, the
winner.
Now, when we, we're building
this, we started to learn about
the other things that were
coming out this year.
And one of those was Dark Mode
in iOS.
And we decided we needed to take
that a step further.
And so, we implemented Cosmic
Mode in SwiftStrike.
We swapped out the assets,
darkened the video feed, and
used some cards with
billboarding effect to really
give a glow effect.
Let's take a look at that.
Here we go.
Took me a few tries to get the
winner on the first try.
[ Applause ]
So, that's SwiftStrike.
So, in summary of what we talked
about today, Kuen-han covered
the new collaborative session
sharing feature in ARKit 3 and
how that enables much easier
localization and new shared
experiences.
We talked about the best ways to
use ARAnchors to position
content within your AR
experience.
And then, we talked about
SwiftStrike, our new game for,
for 2019.
We've done a Tabletop version
using Reality Composer and the
source for that is available
now.
You can get more information
about that by looking at the
''Building AR Experiences with
Reality Composer'' session.
And we're planning to release
the codes, the source for the
full version of SwiftStrike with
the features seen.
For more information, you can
look at our URL for this
session.
Kuen-han and I will both be at
the ARKit and RealityKit labs,
immediately after the session at
3:00.
And also, for those of you who
have gotten really good as
SwiftStrike, we're having a
tournament on Friday at 12:30.
So, we hope you all come and
participate and see that.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]