[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon.
My name's Justin.
I'm an engineer in GPU Software,
and this is Metal for Machine
Learning.
Today we'll be discussing the
Metal Performance Shaders
framework, and new machine
learning features that we added
this year.
The Metal Performance Shaders or
MPS is a collection of
GPU-accelerated primitives,
which allow you to leverage the
high-performance capabilities of
metal in the GPU.
MPS provides kernels for image
processing, linear algebra, ray
tracing, and machine learning.
Now machine learning kernels
support both inference and
training, and they're optimized
for both for iOS, macOS, and
tvOS.
MPS also provides a convenient
way of building neural networks
through the graph API.
So, here we can see how MPS fits
into the larger Apple ML
ecosystem.
You have higher-level frameworks
like Core ML and Create ML that
give you a convenient way to
implement many of your networks.
But if you want a little more
flexibility and control over
your program, you can use a
lower-level framework like MPS.
And this year, we have expanded
our machine learning support
with several new features.
We've added kernels to support
even more networks than before,
we've improved performance on
existing networks, and we've
made MPS even easier to use.
Now, as we go over these new
features, it's going to be
helpful to know a few things
about how inference and training
work in machine learning.
So, let's briefly review these
concepts.
So, inference is the process of
applying a network on an input,
in this case an image, and
producing an output or a guess
of what it is.
Now, the network is made up of a
variety of functions such as
convolutions and neuron
activations, and these layers in
turn depend upon a set of
parameters.
During inference, these sets of
parameters are fixed, but their
values are determined during the
training process.
So, what happens during
training.
During training, we give the
network many images of known
objects.
The training process involves
repeatedly classifying these
images, and as we do so, we
update our parameters, and each
iteration of the network
produces a better set of
parameters until we finally
reach a set of parameters that
allows us to best classify the
images.
Now, at that point we stop the
training process, and our
parameters are ready to be used
in inference.
So, let's look at how we can MPS
to implement some of these
ideas.
But I would like to mention that
there's a lot more to inference
and training than what we just
covered here.
So if you want more details,
please see some of our talks
from the past couple years.
Now, we added several new
features this year to better
support a wide range of
inference and training networks.
So, first we made creating
graphs of your network simpler
by supporting implicit creation
of your training graphs from
your inference graphs.
We've added kernels for
separable loss layers and random
number generation to enable a
variety of new networks and
we've added support for things
like predication and better
control over how MPS commits its
work to improve performance.
So, let's start with implicit
graph creation.
With implicit graph creation, we
can implicitly create our
training graphs from our
inference graphs.
So, let's first review how we
create a graph for our network.
Here we have a simple inference
network.
It's made up of some convolution
layers, some pooling layers, and
finally some fully connected
layers.
So, we're going to create a
graph for this network by
creating nodes for each layer.
We're going to create a
convolution node for each of the
convolution layers, a pooling
node for each of the pooling
layers, and finally some fully
connecting nodes for the fully
connected layers.
So now with our inference graph
defined, we can extend it to a
training graph.
We do this by first attending a
loss node at the end of our
inference graph, and then then
we add gradient nodes for each
of our forward nodes, moving in
the reverse order of our
inference graph.
So, we can look at the code for
this section.
As before, we start by adding
the loss node, and then we add
each gradient node, just moving
in the same order we just
mentioned.
So, here we can see that each
gradient node is pretty easily
created from the forward node,
but with implicit graph
creation, this is even simpler.
Now, once you've initialized
your gradient image with the
loss node, we can automatically
create the entire training graph
corresponding to the inference
graph.
So, as before, we create our
loss node.
Then with a single line of code,
we can create our entire
training graph.
Now, in this case, we're
creating the training graph from
the loss node.
We're going to use a nil
argument for our source
gradient, which tells the loss
node to use its result to
initialized the gradients.
But we could use another image
if we wanted.
And we're also providing nil for
the second argument.
This is called a node handler.
The node handler allows you to
provide a block, which you can
use to execute some custom code
to configure your nodes after
they're created.
I also want to mention another
useful feature, the stop
gradient property.
So, typically, when you generate
your training sequence, all of
your trainable layers will
update their weights.
In this case, those are
convolutions and the fully
connected layers.
But in some cases, you may only
want to update the weights for
some of the layers of the
network, as in transfer
learning, for example.
Now, in transfer learning, we
are going to use pretrained
weights for many of the layers,
and we only want to train the
weight for some of the layers.
Let's say, for example, the
final fully connected layers.
Implicit graph creation also
supports creating graphs for
these types of networks through
the stop gradient property.
So, to do this, we're going to
set the stop gradient property
on the first, on the first
layer, whose weights we want to
update.
In this case, the fully
connected layer.
And then when the graph is
generated, none of the
subsequent gradient nodes will
be created.
So as you can see, using
implicit graph creation is a
very easy way of generating your
training graphs from your
inference graphs.
So now let's look at a feature
we added to support some new
networks.
Separable loss kernels.
So, earlier, we just saw how to
use a loss node using MPS CNN
loss.
MPS CNN loss consumes a final
image, which is usually the
result of something like a soft
max layer along with the ground
truth data in order to compute
gradient values to begin the
back-propagation phase.
But there are some networks
which use multiple intermediate
loss values in order to produce
a final loss.
So, to support this, we added
separate forward and gradient
loss kernels.
So, here we can see two loss
values being computed using
forward loss nodes, and then we
take those results, add them
together to produce a final
loss.
Now, we need to initialize the
gradient value to begin the
back-propagation phase.
Before this happened implicitly
through the loss node now, we
need to add an initial gradient
kernel.
This is going to generate just a
gradient image of ones, and it's
going to be sized to the result
of the final loss calculation.
So with the gradient values
initialized, we can start the
back-propagation phase.
We're going to use gradient
kernels for each of our forward
kernels with an addition
gradient and gradients for each
forward loss kernel.
Now, let's take a look at a
network that uses separable
losses.
Specifically, we're going to
look at style transfer.
Now, the style transfer network
produces images which are
combinations of a style and an
original image.
The model we'll be looking at is
one that you can find and to
re-create, and it's implemented
using MPS.
Now in inference, this network
consists of a transformer node,
which is made up of things like
convolutions and instance
normalization layers, and their
weights make up the trained
parameters.
This is where the style is
incorporated.
It's learned into the parameters
through the training process.
So let's look at how we do the
training.
So here we have an overview of
the network.
Now, as an inference, we're
going to apply the transformer
to produce a stylized image.
Now, in this case, this is going
to be the network's current
guess at the best styled image,
which combines the style and the
content.
And since the goal of the
network is to match both the
desired style and the content of
the original image, we're going
to need two loss values.
So, the first loss value is
computed by this sum network
that we're going to call the
style loss network.
This loss value is going to help
ensure that the network
converges on a result, which
closely matches our desired
style.
And then we also want to make
sure that the generated image
also retains the features of the
original.
So, for this we're going to use
a second loss network.
This is the content loss.
And we can use our new forward
loss kernels for each of these
loss calculations.
But let's take a closer look at
the style loss network.
So, in order to compute the
style loss, we need a way of
sort of measuring the style of
an image.
So, to do this we're going to
calculate what's called the Gram
Matrix for several intermediate
feature representations of the
images.
This year, Gram Matrix
calculations are natively
supported in MPS with both
forward and gradient kernels.
So let's take a quick look at
the Gram Matrix and how it's
computed.
So, the Gram Matrix represents
uncentered cross-correlations
between feature vectors.
Now, each feature vector results
from spatially flattening the
results from a single image in a
single feature channel.
We compute dot products between
each feature vector to produce a
Gram Matrix.
So let's take a look at how it's
used.
So, before we get to the Gram
Matrix, we're going to use the
VGG image classification network
to extract some features from
both our style and our stylized
input image.
Now, as we described before, the
Gram Matrix gives us
correlations between feature
vectors.
Now, when we take these from the
features extracted from the
style, this gives us our sort of
ground truth for the style that
we want to apply, and we're also
going to do the same thing for
our current guess at the best
stylized image.
Now, we take these two values
together to form our style loss.
So now let's look at how we
compute the second of our two
losses, the content loss.
So, as before, we're going to
extract features using VGG and
then compute a loss using those
features and our features from
our stylized image.
And then the network's final
loss is going to be the sum of
the content loss and the style
loss.
So, now let's look at how we can
use MPS to compute these values
and initialize gradients.
So first, let's assume we have
our feature representations, as
produced by VGG.
First, we're going to add our
Gram Matrix calculation nodes to
compute the Gram Matrix for both
the style and our stylized
image.
We're going to feed these
results into a forward loss node
to just compute the loss for our
style.
The source image here is the
result of the Gram Matrix
calculation for our network
stylized image.
The Gram Matrix for the
reference style image is going
to be used in the labels
argument.
Now this shows an important
feature of the new forward loss
kernels.
Previously, you had to pass
labels using MPS state objects.
But now, you can used MPS
images.
So now we can add the loss node
for the content loss using the
features of the stylized image
and the original image, and we
can combine them to get our
total loss value.
And now we need to initialize
the final loss gradient to begin
the back-propagation phase.
We do this using the initial
gradient node we discussed
before.
Now we saw before how the result
of the loss node can be used to
implicitly generate the training
graph.
This is because it generates the
initial gradient.
But now, as I mentioned before,
with the separable loss kernels,
we do this explicitly using the
initial gradient node.
So, this is the node that were
going to use to generate our
training graph.
So, with the graph generated,
let's take a look at what this
network does in action.
So, here we can see the style
transfer network running on the
GPU using MPS.
This was run on a Mac Book Pro
with an AMD Radeon pro 560
graphics card.
Now this is showing the results
of the style transfer training
at each iteration as it
progresses.
As you can see, the style is
being applied progressively, but
the content of the image is
being retained.
I also want to mention that
these iterations have been sped
up for this video from real time
to better illustrate the
progression of the training
network.
So now, I'd like to look at
another feature that we added
this year, random number
generation.
This year we added support for
two types of random number
generators in MPS.
We have a variant of the
Mersenne Twister called MTGP32
and a counter-based generator
called Philox.
Now these generators were chosen
because their algorithms are
well suited to GPU
architectures, and they still
provide sequences of random
numbers with pretty good
statistical properties.
Now, you can use these kernels
to generate large sequences of
random numbers using buffers and
GPU memory.
And since you have this result
available in GPU memory, you can
avoid having to synchronize
large rays and numbers from the
CPU.
And generating random numbers
like this is important for
several machine learning
applications.
They're required, for example,
for initializing your weights of
your networks for training and
also for creating inputs when
training generated adversarial
networks, or GANs.
Now GANs are an especially
important use case for random
number generators.
You had to generate the random
input at each iteration of your
training.
If you had to synchronize an
array of numbers from the CPU,
every iteration, it could make
training your network
prohibitively expensive.
So, let's take a closer look at
those networks and how we can
use the new random number
generators.
So, generative adversarial
networks or GANs are built
around two networks.
We have a generator network and
a discriminator network.
Here we have an example of a
generator, which just generates
images of handwritten digits.
Now, similar to image
classification during training,
we're going to provide the
network with many examples of
handwritten digits.
However, instead of attempting
to classify them, the network is
going to attempt to generate new
images from a random initial set
of data to look similar to its
training set.
So, in order to perform this
training process, we needed some
way of determining how similar
these images should be.
So, for this second network,
we're going to use what we call
the discriminator.
Now as this name suggests, it's
designed to discriminate between
training images and those images
which are simulated by the
generator.
So, in this case, it acts as an
image classifier network but
with only two possibilities.
The input is either real, from
the training set, or it's a
generated, or a fake image.
So you can see, here's the
discriminator, looking at some
numbers and coming with whether
they're real or fake.
Now, typically both the
generator and the discriminator
are trained together.
We trained the generator to
produce more realistic images,
while we trained the
discriminator to better
distinguish synthetic images
from the training images.
So, here we have a high-level
overview of the nodes for your
training network.
So here's our discriminator
training, training network.
It consists of two loss
calculations.
So, this is an example of where
you could use the separable loss
nodes we just talked about.
We have one loss where we
attempt to ensure the
discriminator properly
classifies the simulated images
as fake, and we have a second
loss where we trained the
discriminator to classify the
real images from the training
set as real.
After computing the separate
loss values, we can use an
initial gradient node to
initialize your training graph.
And secondly, here we have the
generator training network.
This one is a little simpler.
It just has a single loss value.
But in this case, we use a label
value of real to ensure that our
generator generates images,
which the discriminator
subsequently classifies as real.
Now, I mentioned earlier that
the generator network begins
with a random set of data that
we're going to use our random
number generator for.
So, let's take a closer look at
random number generation.
Now random number generation
kernels belong to the MPSMatrix
subframework, and they're
accessed through MPSMatrix
random classes.
So, they operate on MPSMatrix
and MPSVector objects, which
means they work with metal
buffers, and they support
generating random integers with
the underlying generator, or you
can generate floating point
values using a uniform
distribution.
So, here, we're going to create
a distribution descriptor for
uniform distribution of values
between 0 and 1.
Then we're going to create our
generator, testing the proper
data types, and then we give it
an initial seed.
Finally, we create a matrix to
hold the result, and we encode
the operation to the command
buffer.
So, now let's go back to the
network and see how we can use
it.
So, here's a closer view of the
generator network.
We have some convolution layers,
some ReLu layers, and the
hyperbolic tangent neuron.
Now the input image is going to
be the output of our random
number generator.
As we saw before the random
number generator works with
matrices, but the graph and all
the neural network kernels
require images.
So, we're going to use our MPS
copy kernel to copy the data
from the matrix into an image.
So, first we'll create a matrix
to hold our random values.
Then we'll also create an image,
which is going to serve as the
input for our network.
And we're going to initialize a
copy kernel to perform the copy.
Then were going to encode our
random number generator to
generate the values.
We're going to encode the copy
to copy them into the image, and
now we're going to encode the
network using the image.
Now, for more details on this
network and using MPSMatrix
random number generation
kernels, please see the online
documentation.
There's also some sample code.
Now we also added features to
help improve the performance and
efficiency of networks using
MPS.
So let's take a look at one of
them now, predication.
With predication, you can now
conditionally execute MPS
kernels.
The kernels' execution is
predicated on values which exist
in GPU memory, and they're
referenced at the time of
execution of the kernel.
So, let's take a look at a
network, which illustrates how
this can be used.
This is image captioning.
This is a network we showed a
couple years ago, and it
generates captions of images
using a convolutional neural
network and a recurrent neural
network.
The convolution network is the
common classification network.
In this case, we're using
Inception V3.
It's going to be used to extract
features from the source image.
Then we take these feature maps,
and we feed them into a small
LSTM-based network where those
captions are generated from the
extracted features.
Now, then we iterate this
network to produce the image
caption.
In this case, we need to know,
in this case, we need to run the
LSTM-based network for some
number of iterations, which is
going to be fixed, and we need
to do it at least as many times
as we believe will be needed to
generate the captions for the
image.
In this case, for example, we
run the LSTM-based network 20
times.
Each iteration then computes the
best captions by appending a new
word to the captions produced in
the prior iteration.
But if the caption were to only
require five words, then we've
had to run many more iterations
than we need.
With predication, we can end the
execution early.
In this case, after the
five-word caption has been
generated.
So let's look at how we can use
this in MPS.
But to do so, we need to first
discuss how we provide predicate
values to MPS commands, and for
this, we introduce the
MPSCommandBuffer.
Now, MPSCommandBuffer is a class
that conforms to the
MTLCommandBuffer protocol, but
it adds a little bit more
flexibility.
It can be used anywhere you're
currently using metal command
buff, and like a
MTLCommandBuffer, it's
constructed from a
MTLCommandQueue.
Now, it provides several
important benefits.
It allows you to predicate
execution of MPS kernels, and as
we'll discuss later, it allows
you to easily perform some
intermediate commits as you
encode your MPS work, using a
method called commitAndContinue,
but we'll get back to that
later.
First, let's look at how we an
use MPSCommandBuffers to supply
predicates to MPS kernels.
So an MPS predicate object
contains a metal buffer, which
contains 32-bit integer
predicate values, and they're at
an offset.
We take the value within the
metal buffer at the offset as
the execution predicate.
Now, a value of 0 means we don't
want the kernel to execute, and
a nonzero value means to execute
as normal.
So, in this diagram here, we've
effectively bypassed the
execution of this kernel by
setting the value at the offset
to 0.
And the offset is important.
It can allow you to share a
single metal buffer among
multiple MPS predicate objects
so you can send a predicate to
multiple kernels.
Each predicate value will be
referenced with a different
offset.
Now, in order to use a predicate
value, we have to attach it to
an MPSCommandBuffer.
This way, any MPS kernels that
we encode on that command buffer
will perceive the predicate
values.
So, let's take a look at how we
can create a predicate and set
it on an MPSCommandBuffer.
So, first, we create an
MPSPredicate object, and we
attach the predicate to our
MPSCommandBuffer.
Now, we'll encode an operation
that modifies the predicate
values.
Now because of the existing
metal buffers, we need a kernel
that produces its result in a
metal buffer.
You can use your own kernel, or
you may be able to use one of
the MPSMatrix kernels, which is
what we're going to do here.
So, we're going to start by
wrapping the predicate in an
MPSMatrix object.
Then we're going to encode a
kernel to modify the predicate
value.
So, here, we're just using a
linear neuron kernel, and we're
going to use it to do something
simple.
We're just going to decrement
the value of the predicate.
And finally, we're going to
encode a cnnKernel to read the
value of the predicate prior to
execution.
So, using predication in
MPSCommandBuffers is an easy way
of eliminating unnecessary work
in your networks.
If you have kernels, which can
be bypassed, you can use
predication to take advantage of
the reduced workload.
And if there are multiple
kernels for which this applies,
you can use multiple predicates
and use only a single metal
buffer by setting unique offset
values.
So, now let's talk about the
other feature of
MPSCommandBuffers,
commitAndContinue.
Now this is a method which
allows you to easily get better
GPU utilization when executing
your work.
So, to see how it can benefit,
let's first review how a typical
workload is executed.
Now, the usual way of executing
MPS kernels is to encode your
work onto a command buffer and
then commit it for execution.
So, here we have a case of a
single command buffer, you
encode some work, and then we
execute it afterwards.
Now, in reality, the CPU's
encoding time is going to be
less than the GPU's execution
time, but we want to avoid any
idle time due to throttling and
things like that.
So you can see we're going to
get some stalling here between
the CPU and the GPU.
Now, one way of solving this is
to use double buffering.
With double buffering, we're
going to keep around two command
buffers, and we're going to
encode work to one while
executing the other.
Now, this should pretty well
eliminate the idling that we saw
before, but it has some
limitations.
So, first off, as I mentioned,
you're going to have to keep two
sets of work, which means you're
going to have to find a way to
partition your work into two
independent workloads.
And as a result, you can have
substantially increased memory
requirements.
However, we the
commitAndContinue method, we can
gain much of this performance
benefit by dividing each
workload into smaller portions.
So, here we're going to break
down the work by utilizing
independence of layers within
each command buffer.
Then we're going to commit the
smaller groups of work using
double buffering.
Now, commitAndContinue is
automatically going to handle
this internal division of work
while also ensuring that any
temporary objects that you
allocated on the command buffer
will remain valid for subsequent
work to be encoded.
As with double buffering, it
allows you to execute work on
the GPU while continuing to
encode it on the CPU.
And by easily allowing you to
partition your workload, you can
avoid the increased memory
requirement of double buffering
while still getting much
improved GPU utilization.
So let's see how you can take
advantage of this in your own
code.
So here we have four MPS kernels
we're encoding to a
MTLCommandBuffer.
And finally, we commit the work
for execution.
As we showed earlier, this is
going to give you the stalls
that we saw.
However, by using
MPSCommandBuffers and the new
CommitAndContinue method, we can
easily improve this.
So, here we're going to create
an MPSCommandBuffer.
We'll encode our first two
kernels.
Then we'll call
commitAndContinue.
This will commit the work that
we've already encoded, move any
allocations forward, and allow
us to immediately continue
encoding the other two kernels.
Finally, we can commit the
remaining work using a regular
commit.
So you can see, using
commitAndContinue requires very
few changes to your code, but if
you're taking advantage of the
graph, it's even easier.
When you encode and MPS in graph
using MPSCommandBuffer, it will
automatically use
commitAndContinue to
periodically submit work
throughout the encoding process.
No further changes are needed.
Simply use an MPSCommandBuffer
instead of a MTLCommandBuffer.
And finally, I want to point out
that you can still combine
commitAndContinue with double
buffering and get even better
performance.
So, as you can see here, it
allows you to eliminate even the
small stalls that we saw with
commitAndContinue.
So, we now have a variety of
options for committing our work
for execution.
You can use a single command
buffer, executing a single piece
of work at a time.
For better performance,
potentially with increased
memory consumption, you can use
double buffering.
And now, with MPSCommandBuffer,
you can achieve nearly the same
performance using
commitAndContinue.
And if you still want even
better performance, you can use
commitAndContinue and double
buffering.
So let's take a look at how
these approaches perform on a
real-world network.
So for this case, were going to
look at the ResNet 50 network
running on a CIFAR-10 dataset.
Now this data was measured using
an external AMD Radeon Pro Vega
64 GPU.
It's a common image
classification network with many
layers, so it's a good example
of what we can see with
commitAndContinue.
So we're going to start with our
single buffering case as our
baseline.
We have performance and memory
consumption here on the vertical
axis.
So, let's see how double
buffering compares.
Now we've improved the
performance quite a bit, but
we've also increased our memory
consumption by a similar amount.
That's because we achieve double
buffering by maintaining twice
as much work in flight at any
given time.
So, let's look at using
CommitAndContinue.
We come very close on the
performance and with
significantly less memory
overhead, and here we also see
CommitAndContinue along with
double buffering.
We still get a little bit better
performance, but we still use a
lot more memory as well.
So, you can see, using
CommitAndContinue is a very easy
way to achieve much better
performance with minimal
increase in memory pressure.
So now, let's put all of these
approaches together by looking
at another application of
machine learning, denoising.
Now as this name suggests,
denoising seeks to remove noise
from a noisy image and produce a
clean one.
Now, we're going to be looking
at this in the context of ray
tracing.
If you saw the earlier metal for
ray tracing session, you saw
another example of denoising,
one using image processing
techniques.
Here, we're going to be looking
at a solution based on machine
learning.
So for this example, we'll look
at three phases.
We're going to create an offline
training process.
We're going to run the training
network, and finally we're going
to deploy the inference graph to
filter new images.
So, first, we need to create the
graph.
Let's take a closer look at the
structure.
So here we're going to start
with our input image, which is
our noisy image, which came out
of our ray tracer.
We're going to feed this image
into encoder stages.
Now encoders are small
subnetworks which extract
higher-level feature
representations while spatially
compressing the image.
We're going to pass these
results into our decoder stages.
Now these perform the reverse
process.
They're going to reconstruct the
image from the feature maps.
Now we're also going to use what
are called skip connections.
These boost features from the
encoded image into each decoder
stage.
This is done by forwarding the
result from each encoder to its
decoder.
Finally, the denoised image is
fully reconstructed.
So, let's take a closer look at
the encoder stages.
The encoder stage compresses the
images while trying to learn how
to preserve its features,
consists of three pairs of
convolution and ReLu layers and
finally a max pooling layer.
Let's look at the code.
Now, as we saw before, we can
construct each node in the
sequence in the same order they
appear in the network.
And we'll construct the decoders
in the same way.
You start with an upsampling
layer.
After this, we add the result of
the corresponding encoder via
the skip connection, and then
finally we have two pairs of
convolution and ReLu layers.
Again, as before, we're going to
insert nodes corresponding to
each layer in the network.
Now we can put our encoder and
decoder stages together.
So, first we're going to connect
our encoder nodes.
But before we move on and
connect our decoder nodes, we
need to put in one more encoder
node, which we're going to call
the bottleneck node.
It's identical to an encoder
except it doesn't have the final
max pooling layer.
And after the bottleneck nodes,
we're going to connect our
decoder nodes.
Now, by passing the result image
from the corresponding encoder
nodes, we're going to satisfy
the skip connections.
So now we have the inference
graph.
Let's look at the training
phase.
To begin the training phase, we
need to compute the loss value.
So we're going to start we the
inference, we're going to start
with the result of the inference
graph, which for a training
iteration is now our network's
best guess at the current
denoised image.
Now, we're going to take the
clean RGB image for our ground
truth, and we're going to use
that to compute a loss value.
Now, we're also going to want to
compute a second loss.
We're going to perform some edge
detection.
We're going to do this doing a
Laplacian of Gaussian filter.
Now, we want to do this because
we want our network to learn how
to denoise the image, but at the
same time we also want to make
sure that it preserves the edges
of the original image.
So, were going to implement the
Laplacian of Gaussian or the LoG
filter using convolutions here.
Finally, we're going to combine
these two losses.
The first loss we're going to
call the RGB loss and the second
the LoG loss, and we're going to
combine these into the final
loss.
So now let's take a closer look
at how we do this.
So, we're going to create our
RBG loss node using the result
of the inference graph and the
ground truth RGB images.
So, as you mentioned earlier, we
can use separable loss kernels,
and we're going to pass both of
our, we're going to pass images
for both our source and our
labels.
For our LoG loss, we need to
apply the LoG filter to the
target RBG images as well as the
result of the inference graph.
So, were going to implement the
LoG filter using convolution
nodes.
We're going to compute the LoG
loss using the results of the
convolutions, and finally with
both loss values computed, we
can add them together to produce
the final loss.
Now with the final loss value,
we can begin the
back-propagation phase and look
at the training graph.
So, we're going to do this as
before by computing the initial
gradient.
With the initial gradient value,
we can begin the training graph.
So, this involved several
gradient nodes first for the
addition followed by gradient
nodes for each forward loss and
then for the encoder and decoder
stages.
Now, implementing graph nodes
for each of these layers would
take a substantial amount of
code and introduce plenty of
opportunity for errors.
However, with implicit graph
creation, we can have the graph
do all of this work for us.
So, here's all we need to write
to generate the training graph.
First, we add the initial
gradient node using the result
of the final loss.
Then using implicit graph
creation, we generate all of the
remaining gradient nodes.
So now that we have our graph
created, we can begin training
it.
So first, let's discuss our
input training data.
Now, the inputs are images for
which we know the desired
result.
In this case we have noisy
images and we have the
corresponding clean images.
Now both images were generated
using a ray tracer built on top
of MPS.
We generated the noisy images by
only letting the ray tracer run
for a short period of time.
And the clean images we obtained
by running the ray tracer for an
extended period of time.
Now, by training with these
images, we hope our network will
learn to approximate the clean
ones from the noisy ones.
And further, we're going to
augment our input data with a
few other images, also produced
by a ray tracer.
Surface normal and albedo.
The albedo image is a
three-channel image containing
values which for the amount of
reflected light, the surface
normals are a three-channel
image where each channel is
going to contain a component of
the surface normal vector.
Now, before we can begin
training, we need to do a little
bit of preprocessing.
So, as I mentioned, these all
contain their data in three
channels.
However, MPS networks and MPS
cnnKernels use their images as
four-channel textures.
So, we're going to have to
concatenate these values
together.
Now, because each image is three
channels, we need to concatenate
these into a single metal
texture array, and we can't
necessarily use the MPS cnn
concatenation because it
requires feature channels in a
multiple of four.
However, we can write a simple
kernel to do this for us.
So here's a simple metal compute
shader to concatenate these
images together.
We're going to start using a
grid of threads mapped to each
four-channel pixel the result.
Our arguments are going to be a
result to hold the concatenated
image, the RGB input, the albedo
input, and our normal image.
So we're going to start having
each thread read a pixel from
each input at its location in
the grid.
We're going to concatenate those
values together, and we're going
to fill the remaining unused
channels with 0.
Finally, we're going to write
out the result at its same
location in the grid.
So now that we have a shader
which can concatenate these
values together into a single
MPS image, let's look at how we
hand it to the graph.
Or rather, let's look at how we
encode it first.
So here's an example of how we
encode our kernel and wrap the
result in an MPS image.
So our inputs are images
containing the data, and we're
going to want to use the result
as an input to the graph.
So, we need to construct an MPS
image.
We're going to use its texture
to hold the result of our
concatenation kernel.
Next, we're going to bind each
argument at its appropriate
location.
We'll dispatch our threads and
then finally return the image
ready to be passed into our
network.
So, now that our inputs are
prepared, let's look at
executing the training graph.
Now during training, we'll be
executing the graph from many
iterations.
We're going to be executing
multiple batches within each
training set, and then we're
going to be executing multiple
batches over each epoch.
So, here we're going to run one
iteration of the training graph.
We're going to concatenate our
images together using the kernel
we just showed except for each
image in the batch.
We're going to put these
together into and array because
the graph requires an array of
images, one for the source
images and one for our labels.
Now we're going to use
MPSCommandBuffers here, because
as we saw earlier, it's an easy
way of getting improved GPU
utilization.
So finally, we're going to
encode the graph and then commit
it for execution.
So, now let's look closer at
each training epoch.
Now in this scheme, we're going
to process the full training
data set, each epoch, to allow
for better convergence.
We're also going to update the
training set every some number
of epochs, in this case every
100, and at that point, we're
also going to perform our
network validation.
Finally, at every thousandth
epoch, we're going to decrease
the learning rate of our
optimizer.
This will also help improve
convergence.
So let's look at the code for
this.
So, we're going to begin by
processing the entire training
set once each epoch.
Here we see every hundredth
epoch.
We're going to update our
training data set, and we're
going to run the validation.
And finally, every thousandth
epoch, we'll decay our learning
rate by a factor of 2.
So, now that we've trained the
graph, we can begin denoising
new images.
Now, because MPS is available
and optimized across multiple
platforms, we can easily deploy
the training network on a
different device.
For example, you may want to
execute the computationally
expensive task of training on a
Mac and then use the train
network to filter images on an
iPad.
So, first, let's take a look at
serialization support in MPS.
Now all MPS kernels as well as
the graph support a secure
coding.
This allows you to easily save
and restore your networks to and
from disk.
And for networks which load
their weights from a data
source, you're going to have to
implement secure coding support
on your data source yourself.
Now this requires the support
secure coding property and the
init and encode with coder
methods.
Now, once your data source
conforms to secure coding, it's
easy to serialize and save the
graph.
So, first we're going to create
a coder in which to encode the
graph.
Then we're going to call encode
with coder on the graph.
Now, when this happens, it's
going to serialize each of the
individual kernels, and if those
kernels have data sources, it
will serialize those as well.
That way, the resulting archive
contains all of the information
necessary to restore and
initialize the graph.
Finally, we can save the data to
a file.
Now let's look at loading it.
So, in order to ensure at the
unarchived kernels initialize on
the proper metal device, we
provide you with the
MPSKeyedUnarchiver.
It's like a regular unarchiver
except you initialize it with a
metal device, and then it will
provide this device to all the
kernels as they're initialized.
So, after we load our data,
we'll create an unarchiver with
the device.
We'll restore the graph on the
new device, and with the train
network now initialized, the
graph is ready to be used to
denoise new images.
So, let's take a look at this
network in action.
So, here we applied our denoiser
to a scene.
The top region shows how the
scene looks in our input noisy
image.
The center region shows the
result of our denoiser, and you
can see the bottom region shows
the ground truth clean image.
As you can see, the denoised
region looks nearly as good as
the clean target, except we're
achieving this with
significantly less work because
were not running the full ray
tracer.
So as you saw, using MPS, we can
easily implement complex
networks like denoising and
style transfer.
This year we've expanded support
for inference and training to a
new class of networks with
features like separable loss and
random number generation.
And with MPSCommandBuffering, we
now support improved performance
and better utilization through
things like predication and
commitAndContinue, and we made
all of these features easier to
use through implicit graph
creation.
So, for more information about
MPS and metal, please see the
online documentation and our
sample code, and for more
information about MPS and ray
tracing, please see the Metal
for Ray Tracing session earlier.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]