[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
And thanks for joining us today.
My name is Garrett, and I work
on the security engineering and
architecture team here at Apple.
And today, we're here to talk
about some of the advances in
security coming in macOS
Catalina.
Here's a quick agenda for the
talk.
We're going to talk a little bit
about the security principle of
defense in depth and how it's
applied in macOS.
Then we'll dig into two very
different parts of the macOS
security model, Gatekeeper and
user privacy protection.
So let's get started with
Defense in Depth.
Now, with a product as complex
and with as many use cases as
macOS, it's-- there is no single
technology or feature that can
deliver perfect security alone.
So instead, macOS is designed
with many different layers of
security.
Each designed with a specific
purpose or goal.
And every year, we improve the
technologies and policies at
each of these layers to help
keep you safe.
And this is an application of
the principle of Defense in
Depth.
And the goal is to ensure that
one layer of security failing
doesn't defeat the entire
security model of the system.
Instead, we rely on multiple
layers of protection with
different properties.
Some layers are designed to
delay the advance of an
attacker, others to reduce the
attack surface of a component,
and some to create choke points
that make it easier to defend a
specific asset.
And today, we're here to talk
about two very different layers
of security in macOS.
First, we'll talk a little bit
about Gatekeeper, which is an
important outer layer of
security, designed to prevent
malicious software from ever
running on your system in the
first place.
Then, we'll talk about user
privacy protection, which is
designed to ensure that even if
malicious software is able to
get around Gatekeeper, it
doesn't necessarily have access
to your most sensitive data and
resources.
So let's talk about Gatekeeper.
When Gatekeeper was originally
introduced, along with the
Developer ID program, its goal
was to prevent the widespread--
prevent the outbreak, a
widespread outbreak of malicious
software.
But over the years, its goals
have broadened a bit.
And now, it's designed to
protect users from running
malicious software while leaving
them in control of what they run
on their Mac.
Now, exactly how it does this
has changed over the years too.
And while there's a lot of
nuances, Gatekeeper's intent can
generally be boiled down to a
few simple questions.
So let's talk about how
Gatekeeper achieves this goal
today.
There's four things that we
think of as part of a Gatekeeper
scan.
The first is a malicious content
scan to ensure that there's
nothing known malicious in the
app it's about to run.
Second, there's a signature
validation, to ensure that the
app hasn't been tampered with
since it was signed by the
developer.
Third, there's an identity
validation.
And this is what we use to
enforce the computer's local
security policy.
If the user has selected that
they only want to run software
from the App Store or identify
developers, then we don't want
to allow something that's been
signed by anyone else, or that
doesn't have a signature at all.
And finally, there's a first
launch prompt, which is meant to
ensure that the user actually
wants to run this application.
Now, we can't talk about what
Gatekeeper checks without
talking about when Gatekeeper
checks it.
And in macOS Mojave, Gatekeeper
runs its scans on the first
launch of quarantined software
launched via LaunchServices.
Now, to understand that a little
better, we need to dig in on
what quarantine means and what
it means to be launched by
LaunchServices.
So let's jump into that.
Quarantine is a technology built
into macOS to mark files that
have arrived from somewhere else
off of the device.
When you download a file in a
web browser or when someone
sends you something via
iMessages, or if you get an
AirDrop, those files all get
quarantined.
Additionally, macOS will add
metadata to that file about
where it came from.
So when we present a first
launch prompt, we can give you
more contexts about where that
file came from.
Now, quarantine is an opt-in
model, which means that apps
have to opt in to quarantining
the files that they place on
disk.
And that generally means that
when an app downloads files in
the background as part of, for
example, a self-update, those
files generally never get
quarantined.
The exception there is if the
app is App Sandboxed.
Because quarantining files is
the default for Sandboxed
applications.
So that helps you understand a
little bit more about what files
on a system will get
quarantined.
Now, let's talk about Launch
Services.
Launch Services is a framework
for finding and launching
applications.
And it's generally responsible
for most of the ways that you
think of launching applications
on your Mac.
For example, when you open an
app in Finder or the Dock that
will use Launch Services.
If you use the NSWorkspace APIs,
those generally go through
Launch Services also.
And when apps get open via
document handlers or directly
through URLs, that all goes
through Launch Services.
Now, for the rest of the
presentation, I'll use this
Finder icon when I'm
specifically talking about
something that goes through the
Launch Services path.
But there are also many ways of
loading code that don't go
through Launch Services.
Some examples that are not
exhaustive, include using NSTask
to start a process, or the exec
and posix spawn's calls or
loading a library into your
process using the NSBundle APIs
for loading or dlopen.
And for the rest of the
presentation, I'll use this
terminal icon when I want to
refer to loading code off of the
Launch Services path.
Now, let's quickly summarize
everything that we've learned
about Gatekeeper in a format
that will make it easier to talk
about what's changed this year.
So here, we can see Gatekeeper's
behavior and macOS Mojave that
on the first launch of
quarantine software on the
Launch Services path, Gatekeeper
will perform a malicious content
scan and a signature check to
ensure that there's no known
malicious content and that the
application hasn't been tampered
with.
Then it will perform a local
policy check where the default
is that it must be signed with
the Developer ID certificate or
by the App Store.
And finally, it will present the
first launch prompt to the user,
so that the user must approve
the application.
Now, starting with the latest
release of macOS Mojave 10.14.5,
the default policy was changed
slightly such that new Mac
developer certificates required
their software to be notarized
to pass Gatekeeper, which brings
us to the first improvement in
macOS Catalina.
We're expanding on this policy
such that all new software
requires notarization.
And in this case, new means that
the software was signed or built
after June 1st, 2019.
This means that all existing
software will continue to pass
through Gatekeeper as is, with
just a Developer ID certificate
signature.
But that all new software must
be notarized to pass Gatekeeper.
Now, the next improvement that
we've made in macOS Catalina is
that Gatekeeper is going to be
expanding to enforce the same
policy on all quarantine
software.
And that means that regardless
of how the software is loaded,
if it's quarantined, it must
contain no known malicious
content, it must not be tampered
with, new software will require
notarization.
And the first launch policy will
be slightly different, where we
won't be requiring first launch
user approval for standalone
executables or libraries, but
all bundled software will show
first launch prompt.
So now, Gatekeeper has been
expanded to scan and enforce
policy on all quarantine
software.
And that brings me to the final
improvement in macOS Catalina,
Gatekeeper will be further
protecting you by ensuring that
all software gets a malicious
content scan.
And that means that regardless
of whether software is
quarantined, and regardless of
how that code is loaded, if any
known malicious content is
found, it will be blocked and
the user will be alerted.
So this is a summary of all the
ways that Gatekeeper has been
expanded to help protect you in
macOS Catalina.
But it's important to keep one
thing in mind.
Our goal is to make every Mac
user safe by default, but not to
prevent you from running the
software that you want to run on
your Mac.
And that means that there will
always be a way to run a
specific piece of software that
you want to run on your system.
Now, I talked a little bit
earlier about how every year
we're continuously improving the
technologies and policies that
we have at every layer.
So I'd also like to take a
minute to talk a little bit
about what's next for
Gatekeeper.
Now, we have a really big goal
on the security engineering
team.
We want to make macOS just as
secure as iOS, while still
maintaining all the flexibility
that you've come to expect out
of your Mac.
And that presents some really
interesting challenges.
But one thing has become really
clear, the security of the
platform has become increasingly
reliant on the validity of code
signatures.
And this means that if an app
has no signature, it's
impossible to detect tampering.
And further, if a bundle
signature has become broken at
runtime, it's very difficult to
differentiate malicious
tampering from mundane tampering
when in out modifies itself at
runtime.
And in a future version of
macOS, unsigned code will not
run by default anymore.
And to get there, there's a
couple of things that you can do
to help improve the security of
the platform.
First, sign and notarize all the
software that you distribute,
even if it doesn't get
quarantined today.
Second, don't break application
or bundle signatures at runtime.
If you do need to update an
application, make sure that it
results in an application on
disk that is properly signed and
notarized still.
And finally, remember that
loading code can fail.
If you try to load a quarantine
library or process and the user
chooses not to run it, that will
fail and ensure that your apps
gracefully handle these
failures.
So these are all the ways that
Gatekeeper has been expanded to
try to prevent malicious
software from ever running on
your Mac.
Now, let's bring up Kelly to
talk about advancements in user
privacy protection.
Kelly.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Well, thank you, Garrett.
Good morning, everyone.
My name is Kelly Yancey.
I work with Garrett in the
security engineering and
architecture team at Apple.
And last year at WWDC 2018, it
was my privilege to introduce
the new privacy protections in
macOS Mojave, broadly
characterized-- sorry.
Let's get to that.
These protections were designed
to improve user's transparency
over their-- how their data was
being accessed and give them
control over those accesses.
And I'm really excited to be
back here today to talk about
the improvements that we've made
in macOS Catalina.
Now, broadly characterized,
their privacy protections
require user consent to access
hardware that could record the
users, such as the camera or
microphone, or to access the
user's privacy sensitive files
or folders, such as photos, mail
or messages.
In addition, they also protect
the ability to automate other
apps, so that the user is in
control over how their data is
being shared between apps.
I like to start today by looking
at the recording capabilities.
Beginning in macOS Mojave, users
have to consent before an app
can access the camera or
microphone.
And then macOS Catalina further
requires consent to record the
contents of your screen or the
keys that you type on your
keyboard.
And this is important because
just like we don't want people
shoulder surfing, looking over
our shoulder to see what we're
doing or are typing, we don't
want apps to eavesdrop on our
contact information, our bank
details or passwords and so on,
whether that's intentionally or
accidentally.
So how do we do that?
Let's start by looking at screen
recording.
Here's a simple example of using
CGDisplayStream to record the
contents of a display in real
time.
On macOS Catalina, the first
time this app runs and this call
to create the CGDisplayStream is
made that'll return nil, and a
dialogue is displayed directing
the user to the security and
privacy preference pane, where
the user can approve the app to
record the screen if that's what
they want to do.
The same is true when reading
the contents of other apps
windows.
For example, here's a function
that saves the contents of a
window to an image on disk.
Now, notably, the call to
CGWindowListCreateImage can
return nil, if passed the window
ID that does not belong to the
calling app, and doesn't belong
to the desktop background image
or to the menu bar.
And I like to emphasize, this is
the background image, it doesn't
include the icons or names of
any files on the desktop.
Again, an authorization dialog,
directing the user to approve
the app for screen recording,
may be displayed.
And I say may, because the
dialog is only displayed the
first time
CGWindowListCreateImage or
CGDisplayStream fails due to a
lack of approval for screen
recording.
Another topic I'd like to cover
that's peripherally related to
screen recording is window
metadata.
Apps can query metadata about
the windows that are on or off
screen using the core graphics
CGWindowListCopyWindowInfo
function.
The metadata returned includes
the size and position of the
window and the unique window
identifier, as well as the name
and process of identifier of the
app that owns the window.
However, the window name and
sharing state are not available,
unless the user has preapproved
the app for screen recording.
And this is because some apps
put sensitive data such as
account names or more likely web
page URLs in the window's name.
And CGWindowListCopyWindowInfo
never triggers an authorization
prompt, instead it filters the
set of metadata that it returns
to the caller.
So, if in your app you depend on
getting the window name, for
example, and you find that the
metadata that's being returned
doesn't include the window name,
you may want to alert the user
and direct them to the privacy--
security and privacy preference
pane.
So, here's an example of a
function that gets the unique
window identifiers for the
desktop background image for
each display.
And once again, the background
image doesn't include the icons
on the desktop.
This function first gets a list
of all of the windows on the
screen, using the
CGWindowListCopyWindowInfo
function.
But then, it gets the window
level or Z order that core
graphics uses for the desktop
background image window.
Then it filters that whole
window list to just those
windows at the desktop
background window level.
So if you look on the internet,
you'll find a lot of code
samples filter by the kCG window
name which, since the window
names may contain privacy
sensitive information, would
require the app to be
preapproved for screen
recording.
However, by identifying the
desktop background windows by
their window level rather than
by the window name, this works
regardless of whether the user
has preapproved the app for
screen recording.
And this is an example of how a
small change in your-- the
design of your app can make a
big difference in the user
experience.
So that's how macOS Catalina
protects the contents of your
screen from being recorded
without your permission.
Apps can freely record the
contents of their own windows,
the menu bar and the desktop
background image.
But the user must use the
security and privacy preference
pane to preapprove apps to
record the entire screen or the
contents of windows other than
their own.
Now, I'd like to present the
other recording capability now
protected in macOS Catalina,
your keyboard.
Most users have an expectation
that their keystrokes are only
going to the app that they're
interacting with, the front most
app, and most apps only require
a keyboard input when the user
is actively using them.
And in fact, if your app uses
the standard UI components, they
handle those keyboard events
that are being delivered to your
app automatically.
Now, some apps want to be able
to intercept those events as
they're being delivered to their
app.
And that's fine, they can
subclass NSApplication and
override the sendEvent method,
or as shown here, you can use
NSEvent's
addLocalMonitorForEvents
function.
Monitoring all keyboard events,
including those for other apps,
however, requires user approval.
And here you can see an example
of using CGEventTapCreate to
invoke a callback for key press
and release events.
Now, the first time this code
runs, this call, the
CGEventTapCreate will fail and
return nil.
Meanwhile, a dialog is displayed
directing the user to the
security and privacy preference
pane, where the user can approve
your app to monitor keyboard
events in the background, if
they so desire.
Now, apps may check the
authorization status without
triggering the approval prompt,
using the IOHIDCheckAccess
function with the
kIOHIDRequestTypeListenEvent
parameter.
And apps can request an approval
dialog to be displayed without
creating an event tab or trying
to post an event by using the
IOHIDRequestAccess function,
again with the same parameter.
So in summary, macOS Catalina
now requires user consent for
apps to record the contents of
your screen or the keys that you
type on your keyboard.
Now, I'd like to turn your
attention to how macOS protects
access to your privacy sensitive
files.
So continuing the approach in
Mojave, macOS Catalina offers
two broad levels of privacy
protection for the user's files
and folders.
First, user data that apps may
generally access such as
contacts or photos, and for
these, macOS will confirm that
the user consents before sharing
that data with apps.
But second, there's also user
data which-- for which the file
system is really just an
implementation detail, it's not
part of their API.
And these are things like mail
or messages and Safari browsing
history.
And these have a high barrier to
access because the files are
typically only accessed by
specialized apps such as disk
management or backup utilities.
But first, let's talk about
those files and folders that
require user consent to access.
Now, macOS Mojave introduced
user consent requirements to
access your contacts, calendars,
reminders, or your photos
library via the file system.
And what that looks like is a
prompt like this, when an app
tries to access files in one of
these categories.
Now, this is different than the
authorization dialogs that we
just saw for screen recording
and keyboard event recording,
rather than denying the access
and displaying an alert to the
user, the calling thread is
actually blocked, waiting for
the user to approve or deny the
app access to files in the
category.
In macOS Catalina, we
complemented these categories
with these additional categories
for data where the file system
is API.
These represent various
locations where the users store
their documents.
They double click on them in
Finder.
They select them via Open or
Save panels, and so on.
The user's desktop and document
folders were prime candidates
for protection since that's the
default location where many
users store their files.
And downloads because some apps,
including Safari, save
downloaded files there by
default, also protecting
documents stored in iCloud Drive
or third-party cloud storage
providers or on removable volumes
and if you've been around as
long as I have, you may be
thinking floppy disks.
But here I mean any storage that
can be physically removed,
including USB thumb drives or
external disks.
And as I'm sure you
photographers out there can
attest, some people have their
entire lives chronicled on
external disks, or on
network-attached storage.
So, macOS Catalina is now
protecting many of the most
common locations where we store
our files.
Now, user consent is not
required for an app to create
new documents in any of these
protected locations, just to
read existing contents, the
contents of files that are
already there.
So, for example, a file transfer
app can continue to save new
files to the user's downloads
folder without triggering a
consent prompt.
And user privacy protections in
macOS Catalina now support the
notion of user intent, when--
which is inferred when double
clicking on files in Finder,
when dragging and dropping from
another application or when
selecting files in an Open or
Save panel.
And when the user performs any
of these actions, the file--
performing any of these actions
on a file protected location,
your app gets access to the file
or files that the user selected
without the need for a consent
prompt.
So let's see how Catalina's
inference of user intent
compares with user consent.
Sorry. So, first of all, user
consent is reactive.
Access may be granted only after
your app tries to read or write
a file, whereas user intent is
proactive.
Access is granted before the
app, even tries to read or write
the file.
And user consent prompts to kind
of interrupt the user's
workflow, whereas user intent is
inferred from standard UI
interactions.
In order to minimize those
interruptions, user consent
applies to an entire class of
data, for example, all files on
your desktop.
Whereas user intent is inferred
for just the file or files that
the user is interacting with.
Now, that said, the two are not
mutually exclusive.
So long as your app is accessing
files it created or which the
user selected, no consent
prompts are necessary.
But if your app accesses files
in a privacy protected location,
other than ones that it created
itself or ones that the user has
selected, the user will need to
approve that access via consent
prompt.
Now, one common scenario where
an app might need to access a
file other than one that the
user selected are sidecar files.
For example, to automatically
open a subtitle file that's--
with-- of the same name but next
to a movie file.
So using the related items
support in NSFileCoordinator,
it's possible for the inferred
permissions for one file to be
extended to other files.
To use NSFileCoordinator to open
a sidecar file, you need to
first declare the extension of
the sidecar file in your apps,
CFBundleDocumentTypes Info.plist
key.
And, set the NSIsRelatedItemType
to Boolean true.
Then in your code, you subclass
NSFilePresenter, set the
primaryPresentedItemURL to the
file that the user selected.
So that's the one that your app
already has access to.
And the PresentedItemURL to the
sidecar file.
That's the one that you want to
access to.
And note that the sidecar file
may have a different extension
as the user selected file, but
all other path components must
be identical.
Finally, you create an
NSFileCoordinator referencing
the NSFilePresenter instance.
And when you call the
NSFileCoordinator's coordinate
method, your app gets access to
the sidecar file as well for the
duration of that block.
And that's a quick rundown of
how your apps can use
NSFileCoordinator to gain access
to files with the same name, but
a different filename extension
as ones that the user has
selected without triggering a
user consent prompt.
Now, to securely infer user
intent, the Open and Save panels
are now always hosted out of
process.
As a result, the class
inheritance and view hierarchies
have changed, which could affect
your app if you have subclass
NSOpenPanel or NSSavePanel.
And apps can no longer
programmatically accept the
panels by calling the OK method,
the user must do that
themselves.
There are also slight changes to
the NSOpenSavePanelDelegate
methods as well.
Apps can no longer rewrite the
user selection using this
method.
And accessing the files that
URLs provided to these methods
may trigger user consent
prompts, because these methods
are invoked by the panels while
the user is still interacting
with the panel, so they haven't
selected the file yet.
So therefore, your app has not
yet been granted access.
Now, apps can test whether a
given file is readable or
writable without triggering
consent prompts using these
APIs.
And, so long as your app only
accesses files that the-- that
in itself creates or that the
user-- that it receives via file
open events or drag and drop or
Open panel or Save panel
selections, your app's
permission to access those files
is inferred and no user consent
prompt is necessary.
However, if a consent prompt is
required, all of the new
protected file system locations
support purpose strings.
And purpose strings can be
specified in your Info.plist to
explain the context of the
access when a consent prompt is
displayed.
And while purpose strings for
these categories are optional,
if your app access is one of
these protected locations,
intentionally, a purpose string
for that location is highly
recommended so that the user
understands why your app is
accessing their documents.
Now, if you find in your testing
your app is triggering consent
prompts that you don't expect,
you can click the Don't Allow
button and go to the console app
and look for the resulting
Sandbox violation, that'll tell
you the file that your app was
trying to access and the
backtrace that caused to require
the consent prompt.
So that's how macOS Catalina is
protecting user's documents and
how the standard UI and how it's
using standard UI interactions
to infer which documents they
expect apps to access.
So let's look at how macOS
protects user data that's
managed by the system and how
your apps can request access to
that data if necessary.
Here, we see the categories of
data protected starting in macOS
Mojave.
Now, some software such as disk
management or backup software
work with all files regardless
of their content.
And those software-- those apps
can use the same APIs that we
just saw a minute ago to
determine whether a given file
is readable or writable.
And then depending on what's
appropriate for the app, they
could skip inaccessible pass or
they could alert the user and
direct them to approve the app
in the security and privacy
preference pane to have full
functionality.
And here's where they would
approve that for Full Disk
Access.
And while we're here, I'd like
to talk about one of the
enhancements that we've made in
macOS Catalina to how apps are
approved for Full Disk Access,
while users can still manually
add apps to the list using the
plus button here.
One piece of feedback that we've
gotten from developers is that
it can be awkward for users to
locate their app's privileged
helpers.
So, now in macOS Catalina,
executables that are denied
access to files due to a lack of
Full Disk Access approval are
now prepopulated unchecked.
Here, we see one such helper
identified by its executable
name.
If that helper were embedded in
a bundle, the display name in
icon specifying the bundles
Info.plist would be displayed
instead.
So, again, this data is
accessible for apps that have
been preapproved for Full Disk
Access, apps can test for
authorization using FileManager
or POSIX level APIs, and if
necessary, can guide the user to
the security and privacy
preference pane, where the user
can then approve the app if
that's what they want.
Now, in Catalina, the universe
of data that requires
preapproval for Full Disk Access
has been expanded to include
trash.
Now, a lot of people think of
files as being gone when they
move them to their trash.
So the last thing they would
expect is for something to go
digging through their trash
files.
That's terrifying, at this size.
As with these other categories,
trash may contain lots of
privacy sensitive data.
However, unlike these other
categories, trash is file
centric and does have API for
manipulating those files.
APIs like these, which move
files into the user's trash.
Now, I'd like to drill down on
the FileManager trash item API a
little.
It takes a URL of the file to
move to the trash as it's
argument.
Now, the caller needs to already
have access to that file, you
can't move files to the trash
that you're-- you don't have
access to yourself.
But when successful, it
populates the out resulting URL
parameter, with an NSURL for the
file at its new location in the
user's trash.
And it still has access to that
URL.
To make sense, it had access to
the file before it moved it.
It still has access to the file
after it moved it.
And this allows you to use
FileManager APIs, for example,
to move the file back out of the
trash.
So in summary, while apps
require Full Disk Access to
enumerate the files in the trash
or to see those files contents,
no authorization is required to
move files into the trash or to
access files that they had
previously put in the trash.
Finally, I like to talk briefly
about automation.
macOS Mojave introduced consent
requirements for automation of
the system or of other apps.
And this is important to prevent
malware from abusing apps that
you've trusted with your data.
So, first, there's synthetic
events.
And synthetic input events are
typically used by accessibility
software in providing aid for
keyboard or mouse input.
But because user consent
dialogs, user intent inference
or various other security
prompts all rely on user input,
it's important that synthetic
input events are only allowed
from apps that the user has
installed for the purpose of
acting as their proxy.
Here's a sample code-- Here's an
example of code that simulates a
key press and key release.
The first time this code runs
and tries to post these events
as if they were actually typed
by the user, the events are
discarded.
And a dialog like this one is
displayed alerting the user that
they will need to go to the
security and privacy preference
pane to authorize the app for
accessibility features.
Now, earlier, we looked at this
sample code for listening to
keyboard events.
If I change the listenOnly
parameter to defaultTap, like
that, CGEventTapCreate now
creates a modifying event tab,
where the callback can alter the
event stream.
And this means now your app has
a way to influence what events
are delivered to the rest of the
system, where a listen-only
event requires authorization for
input monitoring, a modifying
event app requires authorization
for accessibility features.
Now, apps can test whether the
user has approved the app to
synthesize local-- synthesize
input events using the
IOHIDCheckAccess function.
And this is the same API for
checking authorization for
keyboard input monitoring.
But, here you can see that we're
passing the
kIOHIDRequestTypePostEvent
instead.
So, that was automation via
synthetic events.
Now, let's talk about automating
apps via Apple Events.
So, the user must consent before
one app can use AppleScript or
raw Apple Events to control the
actions of another app.
These consent prompts make it
clear, which apps are acting
under the influence of which
other apps and give the user
control over that automation.
Now, there are exceptions for
Apple Events that don't give the
sending process access to
privacy sensitive data.
Many of these events are exposed
via NSWorkspace APIs.
The
AEDeterminePermissionToAutomate
Target function can be used to
test whether authorization would
be required to send Apple Events
to a target application.
And here's an example, testing
whether the caller can send any
Apple event to Keynote.
And by passing Boolean true for
the askUserIfNeeded parameter,
you could ask that a approval
prompt is triggered if
necessary.
But I will point out that if a
prompt is displayed, the calling
thread is blocked waiting for
the user's interaction, so you
wouldn't want to call this on
your app's main thread.
Now, this API is pretty low
level, returning an OSStatus
code indicating whether the
caller is permitted to send the
Apple event to the target or
not, whether trying to send the
Apple event would result in a
prompt confirming the user's
consent, or whether the target
is not running at the moment and
that trying to send the Apple
even would cause it to launch,
or whether some error occurred.
So that was a quick summary of
how macOS captures user consent
before allowing apps to automate
other apps, and how your apps
can determine whether consent
was given and adjust
accordingly.
So, now, in macOS Catalina, user
consent is required to record
your screen or keyboard, that's
an addition to the existing
protections for camera and
microphone.
And now, a number of common
location-- common document
locations are also protected
such as user's desktop documents
downloads, their iCloud Drive or
third-party storage, removable
network volumes and, of course,
trash.
Now, the Privacy Preferences
Policy Control MDM payload has
also been extended with services
for the new protected resources
in macOS Catalina.
And, I'd like to point out that
during development, you may want
to trigger-- be able to
retrigger prompts while you're
testing your app behavior.
And you can use these same
service names that you see on
the left side, with a tccutil
command line tool to reset the
prompting status for the
respective protected resources.
So, earlier, we heard from
Garrett about the enhancements
in Gatekeeper, and we just
discussed some of the
improvements in the user privacy
protections in macOS Catalina.
I'd like to recap by saying,
remember to sign and notarize
all of the software that you
distribute.
And, don't modify those bundles
once signed.
If you do need to modify the
bundles, be sure that you just
transform them into another
bundle that is also signed.
And, for user privacy
protections, try to leverage
standard UI as much as possible.
Be sure to handle errors and
APIs that may return, if the
user-- sorry, handle any errors,
APIs may return if the user
declines consent.
And remember that once users
authorize your app to access
their personal data, it's-- the
responsibility to protect their
privacy passes to you.
So handle user's data with care.
Thank you very much.
I hope you enjoy the rest of the
week here at WWDC.
There's a security lab
immediately afterwards if you
have any questions about these
or any other of the privacy or
security protections in macOS.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]