[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone, and
thanks for joining us today.
I'm Garrett, and I work on the
Trust and Execution Team here at
Apple and today we're here to
talk All About Notarization.
Here's a quick agenda for the
talk.
We're going to start with a
brief overview of what
notarization is and some of the
benefits that it provides.
Then we're going to talk about
the application requirements to
get your software notarized.
And then finally we'll run
through the workflows and tools
you'll need to use to notarize
your software.
So let's get started.
What exactly is notarization?
Well, it's a process that we
introduced last year at WWDC to
help identify and block
malicious software prior to
distribution.
Now it's an extension of the
Developer ID Program, which
means that you don't need to
register for anything different
or use different certificates
which also means that you stay
in control of signing and
distribution of your software
just like you did before
notarization was introduced.
The key to this is the Notary
Service which performs automated
security checks on Developer ID
signed content.
So let's run through a little
bit about what the workflow
looks like when you need to
start notarizing your software
for the first time.
Here's a diagram that talks a
little bit about what the
development workflow can look
like and local development
remains completely unchanged.
You build and sign at your desk
using your Apple Developer
Certificates until you have a
release candidate.
At that point you sign the
software with your Developer ID
Certificate, and you can send a
copy of it to the Apple Notary
Service for notarization.
When notarization is complete
and successful, the Notary
Service can send back a ticket
which you staple to your
software prior to distribution
and once it's stapled, the
software is ready for
distribution just like you did
before.
Now it's worth calling out that
this workflow didn't change at
all from last year, so this is
just a bit of a refresher.
Now what we didn't talk about
last year was what happens when
someone downloads your software
and uses it for the first time.
So when a user downloads your
stapled software and
double-click it to launch it,
the gatekeeper will perform a
verification.
It'll check the local ticket and
it will also reach out to the
Notary Service via CloudKit to
check for a ticket also.
As long as the ticket checks out
and the ticket matches the
content of your app, gatekeeper
will allow the application and
the user will see the normal
first launch prompt.
Now I want to remind everyone
that notarization is not an app
review.
The Notary Service performs a
set of automated security
checks.
Now last year we made a goal to
get most responses back from the
Notary Service within an hour
and it actually turns out that
over the last year 99% of
submissions have had an answer
back within 15 minutes.
Also, the status of the Notary
Service is now on Apple's public
status page.
So you can easily check to see
if there any service problems
that would cause problems.
Now what are the benefits to
notarization?
Well, there are many of them.
So I'm just going to highlight a
few of them today.
First the Notary Service can
help prevent you from
inadvertently shipping a
malicious dependency.
Second, apps with a hardened
runtime are more secure by
default, and we'll talk a little
more about that later.
That can help prevent your app
from being abused by attackers.
Third, users are more likely to
download and try new software
knowing that Apple has scanned
it for known security issues.
And finally, notarization also
provides an audit trail of
software notarized by your
developer ID account that you
can use to check the submission
history and ensure that software
hasn't been released that you
didn't intend to release from
your account.
So that's a little bit of an
overview of notarization.
Now let's bring up Robert to
talk about the application
requirements to notarize your
software.
Robert.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; So to start I want to say
that for any of the software
that you previously distributed
it doesn't have to meet any new
requirements.
You can submit your existing
distributed software for
notarization as is without
change, but for new software you
need to make sure that it meets
a few security requirements.
In particular, it has to be
completely and correctly signed
and it needs to adopt the
hardened runtime.
And by new software I mean
software signed on or after June
1st of 2019.
So we're going to go into detail
on what we mean by both of those
things, but the correct signing
and the hardened runtime.
So first when you, to completely
sign everything you need to sign
everything.
That means bundles, Macho-Os,
installer packages wherever they
are or whether you have Mach-Os
in your installer packages,
installer packages in your
bundles, anywhere that they're
found in any place within your
product they need to be signed,
they need to be signed
correctly.
So to sign correctly that means
you have to sign bundles,
Macho-Os and code, and I'll talk
more about code in a second,
with your developer ID
application certificate and be
sure to include a secure
timestamp.
For executables they need to opt
into the hardened runtime.
You don't need to opt into the
hardened runtime for dylibs or
frameworks or bundles just for
executables.
For installer packages you need
to sign them with your Developer
ID Installer Certificate and
this is different from your
Developer ID Application
Certificate so be careful.
Also, if you choose to sign your
disk images to avoid gatekeeper
path randomization, those must
be signed with your Developer ID
Application Certificate and
include a secure timestamp.
So if you're using Xcode for
building your package, your
software, this is easy.
If you turn on automatic code
signing, Xcode does all of this
for you, but you have to be
careful.
If you use script build phases
or copy build phases, those
might be introducing new code
into your software that Xcode
doesn't know about and then you
have to make sure that those get
correctly signed.
So I mentioned code files.
So when we introduced code
signing a number of years ago,
we documented in the technote
that these things called code
places.
So any files found in any of
these places within their bundle
are considered code by the code
signing infrastructure and that
means they need to have an
attached signature.
Mach-Os are the best for this.
You can embed the signature
inside of any Mach-Os that you
put in these places as well as
for bundles, but if you put
other types of files such as
JPEGs or raw binary files, those
have to be signed as well, but
they don't get attached
signature instead the signature
ends up as an extended
attribute.
And that means that you have to
be careful when you're packaging
up your code to make sure that
that extended attribute stays
within those.
To avoid having to be too
careful with that we recommend
that you put anything that isn't
a Macho-O or a bundle containing
a Macho-O in a place other than
any of these places when you're
structuring your app.
So to get singing right when
you're doing it outside of
Xcode, we recommend what we call
inside-out code signing.
That means you sign the most
deeply nested bundle or piece of
code within your app first.
In this case, it would be the
updater.app inside of the
Sparkle framework inside of the
Watching Grass Grow app and then
you move up a level and sign
each of the things individually.
Note that when you sign the
Sparkle framework by itself or
the Sparkle framework that grabs
the Sparkle main executable as
well as signing the updater.app
together.
And note you need to go
individually to watch Grass
Grow, savergrowgrass.dylib and
Watching Grass Grow Helper.
And finally, after you've signed
all of those you sign everything
together at the top bundle and
again this will sign the main
executable your bundle as
indicated by your Info.plist.
Some of you use the -- Deep Flag
in your custom workflows, but
you need to be careful.
The -- Deep Flag only looks for
code in code places and in this
case the Grow Grass dylib the
Watching Grass Grow Saver and
the updater.app wouldn't be
found as code.
They would be signed in as
resources, but they wouldn't be
signed as code and, therefore,
they would be rejected by the
notarization unless you took the
extra steps to do the inside out
signing.
And see Technote 2206 for more
information on inside out
signing and code places after
the talk.
So once you've completely and
correctly signed your bundle,
your software, you have to make
sure that you don't invalidate
your signature.
That means you should never be
changing files in your bundle
except during installation or
update and when you update make
sure what is the result of that
update is correctly signed and
notarized on your customer
system.
So now we're going to dig deeper
into the hardened runtime.
We introduced the hardened
runtime last year at WWDC and
now we're going to give a bit
more detail to discuss its
benefits and configuration.
So the hardened runtime extends
many of the system integrity
protections that we have on
macOS to your app.
This means Runtime Code Signing
Enforcement, library validation,
DYLD environment variable
protection and debugging
protection.
Note that all of these
protections are owned by default
and not configurable on iOS but
on a macOS that are configurable
via entitlements that any
developer can set.
So if you're using Xcode,
adopting the hardened runtime is
easy.
Just go to the signing and
capabilities tab and make sure
that the runtime capability is
present on your target.
Then you can select which
entitlements you need to
configure the hardened runtime
on your project using the
checkboxes provided.
If you're using a custom
workflow outside Xcode, you can
use the codesign command to
adopt the hardened runtime and
to do that use the option
runtime command to codesign and
make sure you use the timestamp
option as well to ensure that
there is a secure timestamp on
your application.
To verify that you have adopted
the hardened runtime correctly
use the display option to
codesign with the verbosity
level of 2 and look for the
runtime word in the flag
section.
Also note that the hardened
runtime is versioned.
When you sign with the hardened
runtime, we record what version
you were signing with so that
when, if we were to add
additional protections to
hardened runtime in the future,
we'll ensure that only the ones
that your app has been tested
with get applied on future
systems.
So what is Runtime Code Signing
Enforcement?
It prevents creation of
executable memory without an
associated code signature within
your process and it does this by
ensuring first that all bytes
mapped into your process match
their associated code signature
when they're read from disk and
this includes not just
executable regions of your
Mach-O but also the
non-executable mappings like
your read-only sections.
And we prevent execution for
modified memory that doesn't
match its signature.
So by verifying that the memory
is, the memory that we're
reading from disk is correct as
it's coming in and making sure
that we can't change it we
ensure the integrity of your
process as it's running.
Now one of the challenges that
can come up with working with
the Runtime Code Signing
Enforcement is if your code uses
JIT to make non-native code run
fast within your app.
To do this we recommend that you
use the allow JIT entitlement
and then use the MAP-JIT flat
when allocating your
Read/Write/Execute memory that
you're compiling the code into.
This allows us to keep the rest
of the protections on all of
your other memory within the
system while giving you this
scratch space memory to do what
you need with respect to JIT.
If you can't adopt the MAP-JIT
flag because you don't have
source code access to your JIT
engine.
You can use the
allow-unsigned-executive-memory
entitlement.
This will lower the security
predictions provided by Runtime
Code Signing Enforcement to just
verifying that for every piece
of memory that does have a code
signature associated all of the
bytes that you read from disk
are, in fact, match that, but it
allows modification to any of
your memory inside your process
and allows the creation of
unsigned executable regions.
Another thing that we've seen
some developers having
challenges with is if they
attempt to patch some system
frameworks that they've loaded
in after they have adopted the
hardened runtime.
We don't recommend that you do
this and you should see whether
any of the hardened runtime
features actually make the,
solve the reasons why you're
doing this.
But if you need to the
allow-unsigned-executable-memory
entitlement will do what you
need to allow you to modify
those memory pages that you've
mapped in.
So another thing that we've seen
come up with respect to Runtime
Code Signing Enforcement is some
people have seen crashes while
they're updating their app.
This is because code signatures
are latched to files on first
use in the kernel and that means
if you modify a file that has
been run and was signed, then it
will no longer match the
signature that's sitting in the
kernel and you'll see a code
signature violation.
What we recommend instead is
that instead of modifying
existing files on disk you
always create a new file with
the updated changes and move the
old file out of the way.
This will ensure that the new
file on its first use gets its
code signature without causing
the code signature violations
that you're seeing.
So next we'll talk about library
validation.
So library validation protects
your app from code injection and
dylib hijacking by making sure
that your app only loads
codesigned by your team or
signed by Apple.
And some of you might ask, why
does it need to load codesigned
by Apple?
Well, remember that all the
frameworks and libraries that
you're loading from the
operating system are Apple
signed.
So you have to be able to call
those and load them into your
process.
Note that library validation
prevents the loading of unsigned
and adhoc signed code.
So be careful during your
development process.
Make sure that you use Apple
development certificates rather
than turning off code signing or
just using adhoc signing.
So library validation can cause
challenges for apps that have an
in process plug-in or an
ecosystem.
We recommend that you consider
moving to an out of process
plug-in model so that you don't
have to load unknown third-party
code into your app but if you
can't, you can use the
disable-library-validation
entitlement and this will allow
loading of unsigned and adhoc
sign plug-ins.
And note you can take this by
itself without taking any of the
runtime code and sort
enforcement related entitlements
by having
disable-library-validation on
when the system sees that you're
loading a adhoc signed or an
unsigned plug-in, it will lower
the security of your process to
allow that because you've said
you want to load unsigned
plug-ins.
So next is DYLD environment
variable protection.
DYLD environment variables can
be very useful during your
development process to load
debug libraries into your app
while you're testing or to use
libraries that are, or
frameworks that you're building
that are in development but
aren't quite ready to be built
into your app just to test them,
but they can be dangerous
because everything that you can
do during your building and
testing process an attacker can
do on a customer system to take
advantage of privileges or data
that's available to your app.
So because of this the hardened
runtime blocks these variables
by default when you ship with
it.
If you need to use DYLD
environment variables during
your debugging process, you can
use the get-task-allow
entitlement on your debug build
and note that Xcode
automatically puts this on for
you when you build for debug and
takes it off for you
automatically when you build for
release.
Note though that if you're using
a custom workflow, the notary
service in most cases doesn't
accept binaries with the
get-task-allow entitlement.
So make sure you take this
entitlement off before you ship
your release build to the Notary
Service.
So in a few cases, we have seen
developers needed to use the
DYLD environment variables when
they ship their app to customers
and, again, we don't recommend
you do this.
This can be very dangerous for
taking advantage of your app on
customer systems, but if you
need to there is an entitlement
to
allow-DYLD-environment-variables
which will allow these to be
used and is accepted by the
Notary Service.
Next is debugging protection.
So we all know that debuggers
allow developers to inspect the
state of registers and memory
and modify process memory.
That means they allow hackers to
steal sensitive user data and
inject malicious code.
So by default the hardened
runtime doesn't allow debugging
of hardened processes, but if
you need to use the debugger
during your development flow,
again, the get-task-allow
entitlement is what you need.
Along with DYLD environment
variables the get-task-allow
entitlements allows your app to
be debugged.
But be careful if you do all of
your testing with the debugger
attached.
This will mask some of the other
hardened runtime related issues
that you could run into
especially around Runtime Code
Signing Enforcement.
Basically, once the debugger
attaches, we can't force code
signing enforcement anymore
because debuggers like setting a
breakpoint automatically change
your data within your process
and they would just crash
immediately if we continue to
enforce that.
So make sure you test a release
build to see what other effects
the Runtime Code Signing
Enforcement might have and then
if you need to make a debug
build without get-test-allow
through Xcode, you can use the
CODE-SIGN-IN-INJECT-BASE-
ENTITLEMENTS=NO option in your
Xcode project to get all of your
debug settings except
get-task-allow.
So this can be a challenge also
in the plug-in ecosystem because
plug-in developers need to debug
their plug-ins within the app
that they're going to load.
So, again, we recommend
considering out of process
plug-in model or consider
shipping a debug version to,
yeah, debug version of your app
to register plug-in developers
so that they have the power to
debug, but you don't ship that
to all of your customers, but if
absolutely necessary, the Notary
Service will accept the
combination of get-task-allow
entitlement and the
disable-library-validation
entitlement to allow this
workflow.
So we'll talk briefly about
protected resource access.
So we all know that your
customers use their Macs to
store tons of information about
their lives and the Macs have
access to sensors that are
security sensitive.
In order to or once you've
adopted the hardened runtime,
your app needs to declare its
intent to access any of these
protected resources.
So we mentioned all of last
year, but if you need to access
any of these resources you need
to take the entitlement on your
main bundle and then declare the
usage string that is associated
with the entitlement so that
when your app attempts to access
one of these resources, the
system can provide a dialogue
saying, oh, this is why I need
to have access to this resource
so that you can collect the
user's consent.
So some recommendations a
summary of this section.
Take only the entitlements you
need.
The entitlements turn off
security provided by the
hardened runtime and they can be
inspected by anyone looking at
your app to try to see what
kinds of things they can do with
it once it's shipped to
customers.
So be careful, take only what
you need, put the entitlements
only on the processes that need
them.
If you have multiple processes,
multiple executables within your
app, it's unlikely that all of
them need the same protections.
You probably aren't doing JIT in
every process.
You probably aren't loading
plug-ins into every process.
So take only the ones you need
in the processes that need them
and when you're declaring
resource access make sure that
those entitlements are only on
the main bundle of your app.
Those getting inherited by any
other executables within your
bundles, they don't need to be
all around.
Just on the main bundle.
Now I'm going to hand it back to
Garrett to go over what you need
to do to actually submit for
notarization.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Robert.
So now you know everything to
think about while you're
building and designing your
application to get it ready to
be notarized, but how do you
actually submit it to the Notary
Service?
Well, let's talk a little about
the notarization workflow and
regardless of whether you're
using Xcode or have a
custom-built workflow, the rough
workflow is about the same.
You submit the app for
notarization, you check the
status of the Notary Service.
Once notarization is complete,
you can staple a ticket and then
when you're done you might want
to verify that the stapling and
notarization were successful.
Before we talk a little bit more
about this we should talk about
what and when to submit and at a
minimum you should be submitting
all the software that you
distribute, but really it's okay
to upload more regularly so
anything that runs outside of a
developer's machine feel free to
upload as a Notary Service.
You probably don't need to
upload every CI build though and
anyone on the team can submit
process submit software for
notarization.
This has changed from last year
when it used to be restricted to
certain roles.
So now you're ready to submit to
the Notary Service.
Well, if you use Xcode, it's
quite easy and it's built into
the archive and distribution
workflow.
So once you build an archive,
you can open up the Xcode
organizer like you see here and
you can select distribute app
just like you did before with
Developer ID.
Select Developer ID and then use
the upload option to submit a
copy to the Notary Service.
You'll see a progress bar during
the upload and after everything
is complete, you'll get dropped
back into the organizer and
you'll notice that the status
has changed to processing.
Once the Notary Service is
complete, you're going to push
notification to Xcode and when
you come back to the organizer,
you'll note that the status is
changed to ready distribute and
in the lower right corner, the
export notarized app is now
available.
When you click export notarized
app, Xcode will take care of
stapling the app for you and
what you get is completely ready
for distribution.
Now we'll talk a little more
about how you can verify that
yourself later because that's a
shared workflow between custom
workflows and Xcode.
Now, if you don't use Xcode,
submitting with custom workflows
is equally easy.
The first thing you need to
think about is what you want to
submit to the Notary Service.
Now the Notary Service accepts 3
main formats; disk images,
installer packages and zip
archives.
So if your build output is
anything but one of these 3,
you'll need to convert it to one
of these 3 formats before you
send it to the Notary Service.
And remember that when you're
creating a zip archive it's
important to include macOS
specific metadata like extended
attributes.
If you don't know what tools to
use, there is support in ditto
and Archive Utility built into
the operating system.
Now one other thing to think
about is if you actually have a
custom installer and custom
installers can be a little bit
trickier if they pull down
content from the Internet as
part of their installation or if
you use custom packaging
formats.
And if you have a custom
installer that does one of these
things, you may need to perform
2-step notarization where you
actually take all the content as
it's going to arrive on disk,
submit that for notarization
using one of the 3 supported
formats, staple it up and then
you submit your custom installer
app separately.
So now that you know what you
want to submit to the Notary
Service, how do you actually do
it?
Well, Xcode 10 and newer
contains a command line tool
called altool that's generally
used for interacting with the
Notary Service.
If you do have multiple versions
of Xcode, you'll want to use
Xcode select to make sure that
you've selected Xcode 10 or
later and then you can use
altool with the notarize-app
command.
With that you'll need to pass in
the primary bundle ID along with
the file that you want upload.
You will need to authenticate
with your Apple ID, but if you
look at the main page you'll see
the options for using the
keychain or environment
variables so you don't need to
always type in your password.
When notarization upload is
complete, you'll get a
RequestUUID.
This is a UUID that represents
your submission, which you can
turn around and use with the
notarization-info command also
as part of altool to check on
the status of processing and
this is how you can find out
when your notarization is
complete and what the status
was.
Here's an example of a
successful notarization and one
important thing in here is the
log file URL.
Regardless of whether
notarization was successful or
had issues you can take a look
inside of the log file URL to
learn a little bit more.
Now the log file URLs are not
long-lived.
They only work for about a day.
So really you probably want to
pass around a new UID and
whatever you call notarization
info you'll get a new log file
URL.
Here's an example JSON log from
a successful processing.
Notice that the status was
accepted.
Now if this had failed, the
thing that you really want to
look at here is the issues
array.
And in a successful
notarization, this will
generally be empty.
But if something failed, there
will be object in here and each
one represents some failure
during notarization.
It will indicate things like
which binary may not have
adopted the hardened runtime or
if something wasn't signed
properly.
So this will be the key if
anything was rejected.
If it was successful, you'll
probably want to look in the
ticket contents especially if
you do anything interesting
around how you package your
software.
The ticket content should list
every binary that was discovered
by the Notary Service and,
therefore, every binary whose
information is included in the
ticket that you'll staple.
So if you notice that anything
is missing in the ticket
contents, you may need to try to
figure out what went wrong and
try it again.
Now regardless of whether you
use Xcode or altool when the
Notary Service is done
processing a submission, you'll
get an email.
Here's an example of a success
email indicating that this
software is ready for stapling.
Which brings us to the next
step.
Stapling uses a tool also built
into Xcode 10 and newer called
Stapler.
Here you can see an example
invocation of stapler with a
staple command that can be used
to staple directly to a package
or a disk image.
Now note that you can't staple
directly to zip files so you'll
need to unpack the zip file,
staple the contents of the zip
file and then you can package it
back up for distribution.
And note that stapling of
command line tools and libraries
is not supported right now even
though these items still can and
should be notarized.
Now, after you staple the next
step is to verify that
everything was successfully
notarized and this step varies a
little bit based on what you
want to verify, but the first
thing is simple.
If you really just want to check
that something has been stapled,
you can use the Stapler tool
again.
Here you can see the stapler
tool with the validate command
to check that an item has been
properly stapled, but what about
if you want to verify
notarization on something that
you didn't put up for stapling
or that you didn't staple
yourself?
Well, then you will want to
generally use the SPCTL command,
which is a tool built into macOS
that runs gatekeeper
assessments.
And this does vary slightly
based on what you want to check
for notarization, but if you
want to check an application
bundle, you can use the SPCTL
command with the assess option
and the verbose output and path
to the app to the application.
The source will tell you whether
or not it was notarized.
Notarized Developer ID means
that it was successfully
notarized and if it shows
anything else, that mean that it
wasn't notarized.
If instead you want to check an
installer package for
notarization, you can use the
SPCTL command just like before
but with the additional type
option and passing that it's an
install.
Again, this will show you the
source and if it was
successfully notarized, you'll
see notarized developer ID.
Next what if you want to check
notarization on a signed disk
image?
Well, you can use a fairly
similar command except now you
want to use the type open and
you need to pass in the context
that's listed here on the slide.
That will show you the same
output as before and if it says
notarized Developer ID,
notarization was successful for
that signed disk image.
If you want to check
notarization status of anything
else, you'll need to fall back
to using the codesign command.
Here's an example of using the
codesign command with the verify
function verbose output testing
a very specific requirement
notarized and then a path to the
binary or the thing that you're
trying to check and the third
line of the output will say
explicit requirements satisfied
indicating that the test
requirement you passed in on the
command line was successfully
satisfied, which in this case
means the binary was notarized.
If it says that the explicit
requirement failed, that means
the binary wasn't successfully
notarized.
So that's everything about
verifying notarization.
I want to jump back and hit on
one other usage of altool that I
mentioned very early in the
presentation.
Altool is also able to give you
a notarization history using the
notarization history command of
all of the software that's been
submitted for notarization on
your account.
Here you can see an example of
the command and an example of
the output.
It also accepts pagination so
that you can paginate through
all of the submissions that have
been made.
I know that that was a lot of
information to digest in one
short talk, but there's a few
important things that I really
want you to take away from this
conversation.
First, it's really important to
sign your software properly
using inside-out code signing.
This is important not just so
that gatekeeper can verify your
software hasn't been tempered
with but also for notarization.
Second, don't take hardened
runtime entitlements that you
don't need.
Think about the benefit that the
hardened runtime provides to
your app and your users and
remember that every entitlement
you take reduces the security of
your application.
So only take those that you
need.
Finally notarize and staple all
the software that you distribute
so that it passes gatekeeper in
macOS Catalina.
Thanks for attending, and if
you're interested in talking
more about notarization, please
come to the notarization lab
that's going to be following
this session immediately at 4
o'clock.
Also, there are a couple of
other labs running throughout
the week where we can talk more
about security, notarization and
signing.
So thank you.
[ Applause ]