[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon everyone.
As you just saw, privacy is
something people expect, value,
and make space for every day.
I'm Mark from Privacy
Engineering Team at Apple, and
with my colleague, Julien, we're
thrilled to tell you today about
designing for privacy on our
platforms and in your
applications.
Privacy isn't just about closing
doors.
It's also about opening doors to
the trust you build with your
customers.
Customers have let our devices
into their homes, captured the
memories in their photos,
monitor their health, and
transmit their thoughts and
emotions, knowing that they are
in control of their data.
As Tim said last year, we at
Apple can and do provide the
very best to our users while
treating their most precious
data like the precious cargo
that it is.
And if we can do it, then every
one of you can, and in today's
talk, we'll help you design for
privacy.
At Apple, privacy starts with
data minimization.
Examine carefully what data do
you need for the functionality
of your app, and what data can
you edit out?
Some of the most interesting and
challenging features use
sensitive, personal data, and at
Apple, we build these features
with on device intelligence, so
your device personalizes itself
to you, while Apple doesn't
collect this data.
When data is shared with Apple,
we ask the customer.
The customer is always in
control, and they always know
what's being shared.
And security is foundational.
It not only protects people's
data on their devices and on our
servers but also enforces both
the privacy protections we've
built and the choices that
people have made.
Some companies think that
privacy is just security, that
you can use or collect data so
long as you protect it.
But that's short sighted, as
security alone isn't adequate in
the long run.
You do have a responsibility to
protect the data that you
collect, but it's less risky to
just not collect it in the first
place.
Some other companies define
privacy as just transparency and
control.
Let users know what you're doing
with their data, and let them
opt out if they don't like it.
But this is privacy after the
fact, and it forces people to
choose between privacy and
features.
And the burden shouldn't be on
individuals to exercise control
to get privacy.
Because privacy is a fundamental
human right.
It's essential to the
functioning of good societies,
and it's too important to not
just work in the technologies
that we use.
That's why at Apple, privacy is
designed into our futures.
It's [inaudible] how they work,
not something added on at the
end.
At Apple, we challenge ourselves
every day to build great
features with privacy, and we're
confident you can too.
In the rest of our talk, we'll
explore privacy and the user
experience.
Dive into what's new and updated
in frameworks, and then we'll
take a step back and show how
you can overcome privacy
challenges through innovation.
I'm going to talk about four
user experiences today.
First, Sign In with Apple, which
allows you to connect your
user's experience across
platforms without having to
store or manage user
credentials, and it's a great
example of data minimization.
Apple doesn't track how people
use your application because
it's none of our business, and
we've pared down the data that
people share through Sign In
with Apple to just what's needed
to sign into your application.
So, ask yourself if you really
need the customer's name or
email address.
If you need a name for billing
or shipping purposes, you can
get it later, for example,
through Apple Pay.
And if you don't ask for any
additional data, the user has
just one button to tap, and
they're signed into your
application.
If you do need to contact the
user, for example, to provide
receipts or for account
recovery, we provide an easy way
for you to do so.
People can be hesitant to share
their real email address.
We've all seen email lists
stolen or resold and then abused
by spammers.
So people may give you a fake
email address or one for an
account they never check.
You could make the user verify
their email at sign-in, but this
takes them out of your
application, potentially to
[inaudible] their spam folder,
and that's not a great
experience.
With sign-in with Apple, you
will get a verified email
address associated with the
user's AppleID.
Customers can choose to hide
their email address, in which
case you'll get an address
managed by Apple through which
we relay your emails to the
customer and vice versa.
And Apple won't retain emails
after we've delivered them.
For each customer, this managed
address is different for each
developer, so customers are in
control of which developers they
want to receive email from, and
you're in control of who can
send emails to the managed
address we provide you, since
you can whitelist domains or
addresses that we'll accept
incoming mail from.
And because both parties are in
control, we think this is your
best shot at getting your emails
in front of your customer.
We understand you face
challenges in preventing abuse
and fraud from account farming.
And you may want to ask users to
fill out a CAPTCHA such as this.
But these are cumbersome, and
they're difficult to localize
and make accessible.
Other alternatives are invasive
to user's privacy, such as
trying to reidentify them with
personally identifiable
information or fingerprinting.
With Sign In with Apple, we can
leverage on-device intelligence
to provide you with one bit that
indicates a user is likely real.
And this flag is supported on
iOS, and we provide it at
account creation.
The real user status property of
ASAuthorizationAppleIDCredential
is how you check for this bit.
And keep in mind that a new user
on a new phone will likely show
up as status unknown, so you
shouldn't just deny service if
you see this state and provide
the user and ultimate flow or a
way to appeal this
determination.
So that was Sign In with Apple,
a great privacy friendly single
sign on solution.
Now, let's talk about location.
People are protective of where
they are and where they've been.
It reveals where we live, places
we frequent, our patterns of
life, and when those patterns
change.
Like if you start attending a
different set of afterparties
this year with a different crowd
of people.
And in iOS 13, we're making
changes to help users exercise
smarter control over when
they're sharing their location.
Previously in iOS, there was a
one-time prompt for location
permissions, and at this point,
the user hasn't experienced
location in your app before.
So they may select don't allow
and miss out on the value that
location can provide in your
application.
And while many of you have built
experiences to explain your use
of location before asking,
nothing explains better than
using your app.
So, in iOS 13 were introducing a
new option, Allow Once, giving
users the ability to try out
location in your application
before committing to a decision.
If the user selects Allow Once,
your app will have access to
location, just as if the user
had selected While in Use up
until the system no longer
considers your app in use.
The next time the user launches
your app, they'll be asked
again, and if they want to give
you app access without being
asked, they can grant While in
Use when they're comfortable
doing so.
What about Always?
The ability to access a user's
location always is a very
powerful capability, and you
just may be surprised if your
app asks for it right away
before you've had a chance to
demonstrate your app's value,
the value of location in your
app's value, or why you need it
in the background when they're
currently using your app.
Location prompts in app will now
always be for just once or While
in Use.
If you do request Always, we'll
show the same prompt and defer
asking for Always.
And if a user selects While in
Use, your delegate object will
be told you're authorized for
always.
And iOS will continue to
generate Always location events
for your app, just as it did
before.
Before we deliver the first
Always location event to your
application, we'll then prompt
the user to upgrade from While
in Use to Always, and you'll
only get the location event if
the user grants us permission.
We'll only ask users while
they're on the home screen, not
while they're in another
application, so this may not
happen immediately.
To provide increased
transparency, we'll periodically
remind the user that your app is
accessing location in the
background.
And shortly after upgrade to iOS
13, we'll remind the user for
all existing apps with Always
access.
The good news is, there are no
capability breaking API changes,
but you should test for the new
Allow Once and Always behaviors
to ensure that your app handles
these state transitions
gracefully.
And if you do use Always data,
now is a good time to ensure
that your use of Always provides
clear user value.
We think these contextual
prompts will help users make
informed, smarter choices about
when they're sharing their
location.
Come talk to us at our lab if
you have any questions, check
out the video from What's New in
Core Location session in the
WWDC app or the Core Location
lab Friday at 1 p.m. The third
user experience I'm going to
talk about is Bluetooth.
You used to only need user
consent if you wanted to share
information using
CoreBluetooth's peripheral
manager APIs in the background.
IOS 13 will now require user
consent if your application uses
any CoreBluetooth APIs, and this
applies to apps linked against
older SDKs as well.
You should provide an
NSBluetoothAlwaysUsage
Description purpose string in
your Info.plist to help users
understand what your app needs
Bluetooth for and so they can
make an informed choice, and
this will be required for all
apps linked on or after IOS 13,
or your app will crash.
Please refer to our talk last
year for tips on how to write a
great purpose string.
Adoption is easy.
If the user hasn't previously
granted permission, then when
your app instantiates a CB
peripheral or central manager
object, iOS will ask the user if
they want to allow your app to
access Bluetooth APIs.
And you can check the new
authorization property on the
central and peripheral manager
objects for your current
authorization state.
For more information, please
check out what's new in
CoreBluetooth Friday at 3:20.
The last user [inaudible] change
is on macOS Catalina, where
we're adding user consent for
more types of functionality and
data.
Last year in macOS Mohave, we
protected these resources on the
file system and required user
consent to access them.
This year we're adding
protection to the Desktop,
Documents, and Downloads
folders, iCloud Drive and
Third-Party Cloud Storage as
well as Network and Removable
Volumes.
In addition, the camera and
microphone controls introduce
macOS Mohave or infusing screen
recording and keyboard input
monitoring in macOS Catalina as
well as user control over
synthetic input events and
AppleEvents.
For more information, check out
advances in macOS security
session in the WWDC app or their
lab tomorrow at 2 p.m. Next, I
have three new frameworks with
new behaviors.
First, I have some exciting news
for web developers.
We introduced Intelligent
Tracking Prevention, ITP, two
years ago, to protect against
cross-site user tracking.
On by default in Safari, it's
had a big impact, and we're
thrilled to see other browsers
adopt similar techniques and
build consensus against
cross-site tracking.
We don't, however, believe that
a web without free of tracking
is necessarily a web without
advertisements.
And last year we took a first
step in building privacy
friendly ad infrastructure with
installed validation, which
allows developers to measure
conversions from advertisements
to app installs.
This year, we're tackling the
web.
Privacy Preserving Ad Click
Attribution is a new way for
advertisers and merchants on the
web to measure the success of
their ad campaigns without
tracking individual users.
Let's say they sell running
shoes on SneakerNet.
I buy ads on search.example, and
I want to know how effective
those ads are at driving visits
and purchases to my site.
This used to be done through
cross-site tracking, which ITP
now blocks.
In Privacy Preserving Ad Click
Attribution, Safari connects
clicks on ads with conversions
on the merchant and reports
these attributions to the ad
provider.
Let's walk through how this
happens.
Now when a user clicks on an ad
on search.example for
SneakerNet, Safari will remember
this for seven days.
And in that seven-day window, if
the user makes a purchase on
SneakerNet, the merchant or
advertiser can identify this as
a potential conversion, and
Safari will connect this
potential conversion with a
previously stored ad clicks and
record that conversion did occur
from search.example to
SneakerNet.
Safari will then report this
conversion as a delayed
ephemeral post the
search.example.
Adoption is easy.
The ad provider just needs to
decorate their outgoing link
anchor tags with two new
attributes, adDestination, the
site where you expect
conversions to occur.
Here, SneakerNet.example and the
adCampaignID.
Search.example might be running
many concurrent ad campaigns for
SneakerNet, and the CampaignID
allows you to measure them
separately.
We can detect conversions
without any change on the
merchant site by leverage
existing tracking pixels, which
a search provider can then
redirect the server side to a
well-known URL that identifies
the ConversionID as a past
component.
Conversions can be anything from
putting an item in a shopping
cart, to creating an account, to
making a purchase, and the
ConversionID allows the merchant
to distinguish between these
different Conversion events.
To preserve the user's privacy,
Safari limits the Campaign and
ConversionIDs each to 64
possible values.
So, each conversion between an
advertiser and merchant can only
be linked to 1 of 4000 possible
values.
Safari will wait 24 to 48 hours
before reporting this
attribution, both to aggregate
multiple Clicks and Conversions
and to prevent correlation with
user activity on either site.
The Conversion attribution will
be reported in an ephemeral
session without any cookies.
And Clicks and Conversions are
not recorded in private
browsing.
Privacy Preserving Ad Click
Attribution is available to try
out in Safari Technology Preview
83.
It will be on by default in iOS
13 and macOS Catalina, and we've
submitted to W3C for
consideration as a web standard.
And you can see more details at
webkit.org/blog.
Next, I'm going to talk about
the Speech Recognizer framework,
which allows you to transcribe
audio.
We've heard many requests for a
way to perform transcription
locally, and this is especially
helpful in regulated
environments such as healthcare.
In iOS 13, we're introducing
offline transcription, so you
can transcribe audio without
internet connectivity and
without sending potentially
sensitive audio off device.
To adopt, you can check
isAvailableForLocal Recognition
on Speech Recognizer and specify
requiresLocalRecognition when
creating a speech recognition
request.
Third, we have new ways for test
users to provide feedback in
TextFlight.
We understand as app developers
it's really important to
understand exactly where users
are running into issues in your
app, and we want to help you
learn from your test users while
preserving their privacy.
So in iOS 13, we're introducing
the ability for TextFlight users
to submit screen shots directly
from the Screenshot UI through
TextFlight.
They can also now send feedback
along with crash reports so you
can understand exactly what they
were doing at the time of the
particular crash.
Testers are in control of
sharing data from their device,
and this is available in
TextFlight 2.3 on iOS 13 and you
can give feedback in App Store
Connect.
For more information, please
check out What's New in App
Store Connect in the WWDC app.
Now, I'm going to turn it over
to my colleague, Julien, to talk
about privacy updates.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Mark.
In this next section, let's talk
about privacy updates to
existing APIs.
We go through a series of five
updates in rapid fashion.
First, CNCopyCurrentNetworkInfo.
The CNCopyCurrentNetworkInfo API
returns the name and Mac address
of the Wi-Fi access point a
device is currently connected
to.
This affects privacy as a Wi-Fi
access point reveals a user's
location.
Starting in iOS 13, CNCopy will
only work for certain categories
of apps, apps that declared the
CNCopy entitlement and apps that
configured a virtual private
network.
Or apps that configured a Wi-Fi
network using the
NEHotspotConfiguration API or
apps that obtain location
permission from the user.
What this means for you is that
you may not be able to access
CNCopy anymore.
You can find out more details
about this in the networking
sessions listed below.
Second, contacts access.
Starting in iOS 13, apps that
have been authorized by a user
to access contacts will no
longer have access to the notes
field of a contact.
The notes field of a contact
potentially includes sensitive
details such as sneaky comments
about your boss.
Most apps do not need access to
this data.
If you believe you need access
to it, please file an
entitlement request at the
following URL.
Third, Custom URL Schemes.
Previously, if your app was
launched by a Custom URL Scheme,
you could identify the app that
launched you via an option of
open URL.
This revealed applications
installed on a user's device.
Starting in iOS 13, the source
application is only revealed to
apps from the same developer.
Fourth, Game Center.
In order to improve player
privacy, Game Center introduces
two new APIs.
The teamPlayerID for a
team-scoped player identifier
and the gamePlayerID for a
game-scoped player identifier.
The existing playerID identifier
is being deprecated.
This changes which identifier
you may use in your gaming app.
For more information, please
check out the Game Center video
in the WWDC app.
And five, contextual
information.
IOS doesn't know when your app
is most helpful to users.
You can provide contextual
information, entry point into
your app via two main APIs,
NSUserActivity, to promote your
app in Search results, and
SiriKit INInteraction to promote
your app on on-device
intelligent scenarios such as
Maps Shortcuts and new this year
in the Share Sheet.
If you do promote your app, be a
good sport.
Delete content that was removed
from your app.
You don't want Siri Shortcuts to
make a suggestion to content
that does not exist anymore.
Simply call the corresponding
deletion APIs.
We just went through a series a
five privacy updates to existing
APIs.
In our next section, we take a
step back.
We discuss how a privacy
challenge can be a chance to
innovate.
Privacy is fundamental to the
design of every product.
At Apple, in the Privacy Team,
we work with engineers all
across Apple to build privacy
into our products.
Once in a while, we hit a very
hard problem, a feature that we
really want to ship, but it's
not obvious how to protect
privacy.
So when that happens, we decide
to challenge ourselves.
We aim to build a great feature
without giving away user
information, so we lean on our
privacy principles to find
solutions and innovate.
Today, we want to inspire you to
do the same.
Let's look at three critical
areas of the user experience,
Machine Learning, Find My, and
Home.
Let's start with Machine
Learning.
There are many ways to build
Machine Learning applications.
Usually we need to train a model
and then evaluate it.
So the first privacy challenge
with Machine Learning is how to
train a machine learning model
but without collecting sensitive
user data while personalizing
the model to every user and
significantly improving the user
experience.
And again, it usually starts
with data, and it's usually a
lot of data.
And it can be challenging to
find data.
There are multiple options.
The first option is to collect
data from users.
So to protect user privacy, it's
important to apply best privacy
practices such as randomizing
identifiers, rounding or
sampling.
But sometimes data is inherently
sensitive, like the picture of
user's face.
A second option is to run a user
study.
We invite select users to test
or feature in private and
collect their data.
We did this ourselves to train
Face ID.
Finally, their external
datasets.
Some are publicly available for
research purposes.
Others require careful
collaboration with other
companies and raise their own
privacy challenges.
Once you have data, you can
train a model.
You can, for example, use Create
ML.
A train model is great for most
users, but users are different,
each with their own needs.
What if you needed to tailor, to
personalize a model to specific
users?
This year, we introduce
updatable Core ML models.
Send your updatable model to the
device.
An updatable model takes in
training data from the user and
produces a new personalized
model.
We do this ourselves with Face
ID.
Face ID automatically adjusts to
your appearance.
If you grow a beard or grow
longer hair, Face ID still
recognizes you.
And this all happens on the
device.
Training uses resources though,
and it may affect a user
experience.
While there's a new Background
Task API that allows you to
schedule machine learning tasks
in the background, we recommend
scheduling a task within a week
or less.
If you choose a date too far
into the future, iOS may not
schedule it.
You can learn more about the
Background Task API in our
session below.
But sometimes, we need more than
one user's data.
We need data from many different
users.
Today, I want to share with you
a new technique that we are
developing.
This is an example of how we
innovate in privacy for machine
learning.
Federated Learning is a new
approach that is picking up
steam in the machine learning
community.
Today, we're introducing Private
Federated Learning by combining
Federated Learning with
differential privacy.
The idea is simple, instead of
collecting user data with
Private Federated Learning, we
collect model updates.
In other words, devices tell the
server how a machine learning
model should be updated.
Let's walk through an example.
It all starts with the server
giving devices an original
model.
We show it in white here.
Each device trains the model
under local data and obtains a
new model.
We show it here by changing the
color.
They compute the difference
between this new model and the
original one and send these
model updates back to Apple
servers.
The server aggregates these
model updates into a new
enhanced machine learning model
that we show here with a
gradient color.
Note that in this process no
user data is sent in plain, and
we have no needs for any user or
device identifiers.
The server then updates the
devices back with a new model,
and this cycle can go back and
forth between the devices and
the server.
From a privacy perspective, we
need to analyze whether those
model updates include sensitive
data.
It's often considered that model
updates are fine.
They're not plain user data.
But unfortunately, in some
corner cases, a curious server
could attempt to reconstruct the
user data from model updates.
For example, here, if a user
sent model updates relative to
this castle, a curious server
may be able to reconstruct the
castle image from the model
update.
So, to prevent this, we protect
model updates using on device
and on the server Separated
Differential Privacy and Central
Differential Privacy.
Differential Privacy adds noise
to the model updates.
This ensures that a curious
server cannot reconstruct the
image anymore.
You can find more details about
how we use Separated
Differential Privacy in the
paper below that we wrote.
Private Federated Learning can
be used to improve on-device
intelligence.
This is not a research
experiment.
We are starting to use this
technology in iOS 13 in a
variety of use cases including
QuickType keyboard, personalized
Hey Siri, and more in the
future.
Once you train a model, you want
to use it.
This raises the second privacy
challenge with machine learning.
How to evaluate a model without
collecting user data in a fast
way and without suffering from
Internet connection delays.
The first way that comes to mind
is to simply send user data to
the server, evaluate the model
there, and get back the
inference.
But this means sending more user
data to the server.
Instead, we prefer on-device
intelligence.
We send a model down to the
device.
The device evaluates it locally.
This has a lot of advantages.
It's less data sent to the
servers.
It works even if you don't have
Internet, and it's fast if you
use Core ML.
Core ML is optimized to run fast
on iOS devices and others.
It's easy to convert your
existing model to a Core ML
model, and this year, we expand
the number of model
architectures that are
supported.
You can learn more in the Core
ML session listed below.
On-device intelligence provides
strong privacy advantages, and
we like to communicate those
advantages to our users in the
form of privacy assurances.
A privacy assurance is a simple
privacy sentence that we share
with our users.
This is not a privacy policy
with legalese.
For example, with Face ID, we
say, Face ID data never leaves
the device.
This is a clear and strong
statement about our approach to
privacy with Face ID.
It's easy for all users to
understand.
All right, this was machine
learning.
Let's talk about Find My next.
This year we announced a new
Find My application that merges
the Find My Friends and the Find
My iPhone apps.
One feature that we were very
excited about is the offline
finding feature.
Here's a challenge that was
brought to our attention.
A user forgot their MacBook at
the public library.
The user realizes that, launches
the new Find My app and attempts
to find the MacBook, but it may
not work because the MacBook is
not connected to the Internet.
So the privacy challenge is
support finding devices between
Mac and iPhone or a Watch that
is, even when it's not connected
to the Internet when it's
offline while protecting the
privacy of the lost devices but
also of anyone that would help
you find those lost devices and
making sure that Apple doesn't
learn anything in the process.
And, of course, with limited
impact on the battery life.
This was a long list of
challenges, and so the idea for
us was to rely on crowd
sourcing.
We wanted to make it easy to
detect a lost MacBook via
Bluetooth and report its
location to Apple servers.
But we couldn't rely on a static
identifier broadcast over
Bluetooth.
A static identifier could allow
anyone to track any device at
any time, and we couldn't do
that.
Instead, the MacBook broadcasts
and ephemeral public encryption
key.
This key changes over time.
Any nearby phone can receive
over Bluetooth this encryption
key, compute their own location,
and encrypt it with the
encryption key.
Then, this encrypted data can be
submitted to Apple servers.
Note here that since location is
encrypted, Apple cannot see it.
Also, note that no information
is provided about the nearby
phone that helped find the lost
device.
Finally, the owner can ask Apple
later on for the corresponding
encrypted data, decrypt it to
obtain the location to its lost
device.
With this proposal, we can share
the following privacy assurance
with our users.
Apple does not know the location
of any offline devices or
finders.
This is a big result.
We found a way to design a
fantastic feature with industry
leading privacy.
Next, let's talk about the Home.
The Home is a safe place, and
important place for all of us.
It's a safe place we go to after
work or after a long day at
WWDC, and as the popularity of
Smart homes increases, so does
new privacy threats emerge.
Many customers have concerns
about Smart home accessories,
and nothing is more sensitive
than security cameras in the
home.
So the privacy challenge here is
allowing users to view their
security cameras from anywhere
while allowing no one else to
access the video feed, not even
Apple, and still enabling Smart
camera experiences.
So we worked with camera
providers on two main things.
First, we rely on on-device
intelligence to do computer
vision in the home on the home
resident device.
Be it a HomePod, an Apple TV, or
an iPad, we detect people and
objects directly in the home,
not in the Cloud.
Second, we store camera
recordings in an end-to-end
encrypted manner.
This means only you can see the
content from your camera, and we
can make the following privacy
assurance.
Only you can see the video from
your camera.
Short and sweet.
It's time to wrap up the privacy
session.
We talked about three privacy
challenges and showed you how we
solved them.
Throughout this presentation, we
also talked about API updates
and new features that we
designed with privacy.
Every year, every release, with
every product we challenge
ourselves to build great
features without giving away
user information.
Because privacy is fundamental
to the design of every product,
we share privacy assurances with
our users.
Simple sentences about our
commitment to protect user
privacy.
There are three things we want
you to remember today.
First, among the first questions
you should ask yourselves when
working on a new project is how
you will protect user data.
Ask what you should do, not what
you can do with your app.
Earn the trust of your users by
making it easy for them to know
that their privacy is protected
in your app.
Second, if you face a tough
privacy problem, challenge
yourself to find a solution.
Privacy is a chance to innovate.
Find a way to deliver your
feature without giving away more
user data.
And third, privacy is an
opportunity to engage with your
users.
Privacy is about people.
Don't let a privacy policy take
that away from you.
Share your privacy assurances
with your users.
If you have any more questions,
please join us in the privacy
lab right after this talk.
On behalf of the entire privacy
team, thank you very much for
joining us today.
[ Applause ]