[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome to Network
Extensions for Modern macOS.
My name is Jamie Wood.
I'm a Software Engineer working
on Internet Technologies at
Apple.
And I am thrilled to be here
today to tell you about a bunch
of great new powerful APIs that
we've added in macOS Catalina
that allow you to create apps
that extend and customize the
networking capabilities of macOS
without the use of Network
Kernel Extensions.
To start off, I want to say
thank you for your feedback.
Over the past few years here at
WWDC we've asked you to file
bugs and give us feedback about
how you're making use of Network
Kernel Extensions in your apps
today.
We got a lot of great feedback.
We've taken your feedback, and
we came up with a set of
categories of apps where on a
macOS Mojavi and earlier you
really need to use Network
Kernel Extensions to fully
implement apps in these
categories.
So today I want to take you on a
journey for each one of these
app categories and talk about
all the great new APIs we've
added in macOS Catalina that
allow you to create apps in
these categories without using
Network Kernel Extensions.
So let's go ahead and get
started.
First, I want to talk about
Content Filter Apps.
One example of a Content Filter
App is a Personal Firewall App.
These are apps that examine the
network traffic as it's flowing
through the system and block
traffic that's deemed to be
malicious in some way.
Another example of a Content
Filter App is a Parental
Controls App.
This is an app that focuses on
web-browsing activity and blocks
access to websites that are
deemed inappropriate for
children.
Another example of a Content
Filter App is an app that
doesn't actively block any
network traffic but instead just
keeps a record of network
activity on the Mac so that that
log of no activity can be
analyzed later, for example, to
determine when some sensitive
data was transmitted.
So before I talk about the APIs
we've added that allow you to
create Content Filter Apps, I
want to talk about some
particular runtime requirements
that Content Filter Apps have.
So the code in your Content
Filter App that is actually
filtering network traffic has
some specific runtime
requirements.
Your code needs to be running
all the time, and it needs to be
running even when there's no
user logged into the system.
For example, in your Parental
Controls App, you app needs to
be doing its job of blocking
access to inappropriate websites
even when your app isn't
actually running.
In your Personal Firewall App,
your app needs to be doing its
job of protecting the Mac from
incoming attacks coming in over
the network even if there's no
user logged into the system.
Now, when you've implemented
your content filter code inside
of a Kernel Extension, these
runtime requirements are
obviously met because your code
is running in the Kernel.
So it's running all the time and
it's running even when there's
no user logged into the system.
So to satisfy these runtime
requirements in user space,
we've introduced a new
technology in macOS Catalina
called System Extensions.
Now you're probably familiar
with app extensions.
These are bundles of executable
code that you can use on macOS
to extend and customize various
aspects of the macOS user
experience.
So system extensions share a lot
of similarities with app
extensions.
Like app extensions, system
extensions are packaged inside
of your app and they're
completely managed by the
operating system.
So this is great because it
means you don't need to write
any customer installer package
to place your system extensions
somewhere in a file system, and
you don't need to write an
uninstaller to remove your
system extension when the user
uninstalls your app.
Also you don't need to worry
about starting and stopping your
system extension.
The operating system will run
your system extension as needed.
Another similarity with app
extensions and system extensions
is that system extensions are
very easy to develop and debug.
You can use all the regular
tools you use to develop any
regular app -- Xcode, LLDB,
Instruments.
This is in contrast to Kernel
Extensions which are notoriously
difficult to develop and debug.
You frequently have to reboot as
you're developing your
extension.
And to debug a Kernel Extension
you have to have two separate
machines and if you do manage to
connect these two machines
together and drop into the
debugger in your Kernel
Extension Code, single-stepping
through your source code is a
very dicey proposition and -- if
it works at all.
Unlike app extensions, system
extensions run independently of
any user logged into the system.
So systems extensions are really
an ideal place for you to be
running your network processing
code like your content filter
code.
For information and details
about system extensions and for
some other use cases of system
extensions, please see the
session that happened earlier
this week, System Extensions and
Driver Kit.
All right.
So you use system extensions to
implement several different apps
in these categories that I've
listed here -- Content Filter
Apps, Transparent Proxy Apps,
DNS Proxy Apps and VPN Apps.
Now I want to dive into the APIs
we've added that allow you to
implement Content Filter Apps.
So the Content Filter APIs are
in the Network Extension
Framework and these APIs were
first introduced back in iOS 9.
And so what we've done in macOS
Catalina is brought these APIs
over and made them available on
the Mac and added a bunch of
great new enhancements that make
these APIs even better.
So let's take a look at the
Content Filter APIs and how you
use them in your app.
So in your main UI App, you use
NEFilterManager to create a
content filter configuration.
The content filter configuration
registers your content filter
with the system so the system
knows how to run your filter.
You also create a system
extension.
This is where your code that
actually filters network content
will run.
The Content Filter APIs allow
you to filter network content at
two different layers.
You can filter content at the
flow layer or at the packet
layer.
For flow layer filtering, you
create a subclass of any data
filter provider.
Once your content filter
configuration is registered with
the system, and your filter's up
and running, the system, as new
connections, as new TCP and UDP
flows of network data are
created on the system, those
flows get passed to your --
NEFilterDataProvider subclass
represented as individual
NEFilterFlowObjects.
It's then the responsibility of
your subclass to make a allow or
drop decision about each
individual flow.
You can make this decision about
each flow at any point in the
lifetime of the flow.
You can make it right up front
when the flow is first opened or
you can wait after you've seen
some amount of the flow's data.
I want to note here that the
NEFilterDataProvider class gives
you read-only access to flows.
You can't modify any aspect of a
flow, including any of the
flow's data.
By default, the system will pass
every single flow of TCP and UDP
data to your
NEFilterDataProvider subclass.
If this isn't exactly what you
want -- for example, if you're
writing a Parental Controls App,
so you're only interested in Web
traffic, you use NEFilter
settings to create a set of
rules that inform the system
about the flows that you want to
see in your filter.
So that's how flow level
filtering works.
If you want to filter traffic at
the packet layer, you create a
subclass of
NEFilterPacketProvider in your
system extension and as network
packets are flowing through the
system, the system will pass
those packets to your
FilterPacketProvider subclass as
individual packet objects, and
you make a Allow or Drop
decision about each individual
packet.
Okay. So there's a brief
overview of the Content Filter
APIs and how you use them in
your app.
Next I want to give you a brief
demonstration of an app that
uses the system extensions and
content filter APIs to implement
a firewall.
So the functionality of my app
is very simple.
I'm going to prompt the user to
allow or deny incoming TCP
connections on Port 8888.
So let me go ahead and run the
app and show you how it works.
So the app's called Simple
Firewall.
Go ahead and run the app.
And you can see my UI indicator
here.
The red dot is showing that my
content filter is not currently
running.
So I'm going to go ahead and
click start.
Alright. So I get this dialog
from the system indicating that
my system extension has been
blocked from running.
Now system extensions are very
powerful.
They give you the ability to do
lots of things on the system
including looking at network
traffic that's flowing through
the system.
So we want to make sure that we
get the user's permission before
allowing system extensions to
run.
So I'm going to go ahead and
open Security Preferences.
This will take me to the
Security and Privacy Preferences
pane.
I'll provide my admin
credentials and go ahead and
click allow to allow my system
extension to run.
The network extension framework
also prompts the user to confirm
that they want to allow the
system extension to filter
network traffic on the Mac.
So go ahead and click allow.
All right.
So, now back in simple firewall
we can see that my content
filter is now running.
So let's go ahead and connect to
Port 8888 here on my local Mac
and see what happens.
So I'm running a webserver on
Port 8888.
So I'm going to go ahead bring
up Safari.
And I have it bookmarked to my
local webserver.
So I'll click on that.
So the webpage starts to load,
but you can see it pauses here.
And sure enough, over in the
simple firewall app I have this
dialog inform me that a new
connection has been created on
Port 8888 asking me if I want to
allow or deny.
So I'll click allow, and the
webpage loads.
So, cool.
My app is working.
Now let's go ahead and take a
look at some of the code in
simple firewall to see how it
makes use of the system
extensions and content filter
APIs.
So over here you can see my
project.
I have two different targets.
I have the SimpleFirewall Target
which is my main UI App.
And I have the
SimpleFirewallExtension Target
which is my System Extension.
Let's start off my looking at
some of the code in the app.
We'll take a look at the
implementation of my main View
Controller Class.
And I want to start by looking
at the startFilter function.
So this is the function that was
called when I clicked on the
start button in the
SimpleFirewall UI.
I start off by getting the
bundle identifier of my system
extension and using that to
create a system extension
activationRequest.
I set the view controller object
as the delegate of the
activationRequest so that it
will be notified when the
Request is complete.
Once the activationRequest is
created, I submit it to the
OSSystemExtensionManager.
This kicks off the process of
activating the system extension
including prompting the user to
allow the SystemExtension to run
if necessary.
Okay.
So once the user has allowed the
SystemExtension to run, my view
controller's request did finish
with result function gets
called.
I make sure that the activation
request was completed and I go
ahead and create my content
filter configuration.
So here's where I'm using
AnyFilterManager to create my
filter configuration and
register it with the system.
So here you can see I'm setting
up some details about my -- on
my configuration.
I specify True for filter
sockets.
This indicates that I'm going to
be filtering network traffic at
the flow layer.
I set filter packets to False to
indicate that I'm not going to
be filtering network traffic at
the packet layer.
I go ahead and Enable my Content
Filter Configuration and then
register the Configuration with
the system by calling Save to
Preferences.
So since my Content Filter
Configuration is enabled, this
will cause the system to start
the SystemExtension and start my
Content Filter.
So let's go ahead and take a
look at the implementation of my
NEFilterDataProvider subclass
running inside of the system
extension.
So here's by subclass.
It's called FilterDataProvider.
And I've overridden three
different methods in this class
-- StartFilter, StopFilter, and
HandleNewFlow.
So, first, let's take a look at
StartFilter.
This is the function that is
called when the system starts my
content filter.
Now, by default, the system is
going to pass every single TCP
and UDP flow to my content
filter.
And this isn't really what I
want to do here.
I'm only interested in inbound
TCP connections connecting to
Port 8888 on my Mac.
So I'm going to create an
NEFilterSettingsObject to inform
the system about what traffic I
want to see.
Now I don't care where the TCP
connections are coming from, and
I also don't care what address
the TCP connections are
connecting to on my Mac.
So I'm going to create two
NEFilter Rules, one with the
wildcard IPV4 address and
another with the wildcard IPV6
address.
For each Filter Rule that I
create, I create an
NENetworkRuleObject that
specifies the characteristics of
the flows that I want to see,
that I want the Filter Rule to
match.
So for remote network and remote
prefix, I'm passing nil and
zero.
So this means that my filter
rule is going to match traffic
coming from anywhere.
I don't care where it's coming
from.
For a local network, I pass in a
NWHostEndPoint that I've created
using the wildcard address and a
local port of 8888.
Okay.
So this means that my filter
rule's going to match flows that
are coming in and connecting to
Port 8888 on any address.
I specify a protocol of TCP and
a direction of Inbound.
I go ahead and create the
NEFilterRuleObject, passing in
the NENetworkRule, and an action
of filter data.
So when a new flow of network
data that matches my
NENetworkRule is created on the
system, the system will pass
that flow to my content filter
per the filter data action.
All right.
So once I've created these
NEFilterRules, I go ahead and
create my
NEFilterSettingsObject, passing
in the rules and specifying a
default action of Allow.
So what this means is if a new
flow is created on the system,
and it doesn't match any of my
filter rules, I want the system
to just allow that flow.
Don't pass it to my content
filter.
I go ahead and call Apply to
apply my filter settings to the
system and then, when that's
complete, I call the
StartFilterCompletionHandler to
indicate to the system that my
filter is now up and running and
is ready to start handling
network flows.
Now let's look at the
HandleNewFlow function.
So this is the function that's
called when a new flow is
created that matches my filter
rules.
The function takes a parameter,
the NEFilterFlowObject that
represents the flow, and it
returns a new flow verdict to
indicate to the system what to
do with the flow.
So what I'm doing here is
packaging up some details about
the flow in a dictionary, and
sending that dictionary off to
my UI app to prompt the user to
allow or deny the flow.
Now, getting the user's decision
is obviously a very asynchronous
process.
So while I'm waiting for them to
make a decision and go ahead and
return a verdict of Pause to the
system.
So this tells the OS, just hang
onto this flow.
Don't do anything further with
it until I resume the flow.
Once the user makes their
decision, I create a new flow
verdict of either Allow or Drop,
depending upon what the user's
decision was, and then I call
Resume Flow with the new
verdict.
Alright. So that was an example
of an app that uses the System
Extensions and Content Filter
APIs to implement a simple
firewall.
Next I want to talk about
Transparent Proxy Apps.
So one example of a Transparent
Proxy App is a cloud security
app.
These are apps that divert
traffic destined for specific
websites to a cloud service.
And that cloud service applies
some additional security checks
to the traffic such as
additional user authentication
or authorization.
Another example of a Transparent
Proxy App is an app that applies
some special transformation to
traffic such as applying an
encryption algorithm to network
traffic or caching resources
downloaded over the Web in some
special way.
Transparent Proxy Apps can also
multiplex multiple flows of
network traffic over a single
connection.
Or they can use some custom
special protocol that reduces
network latency.
There are a lot of really
interesting use cases for
Transparent Proxy Apps.
So I'm really excited to tell
you that in macOS Catalina we've
introduced some new APIs in the
network extension framework that
allow you to create Transparent
Proxy Apps without using Kernel
Extensions.
So let's go ahead and take a
look at these APIs.
They're in the NetworkExtension
Framework.
Let's see how you use them in
your app.
So in your main UI App, you use
any Transparent Proxy Manager to
create Transparent Proxy
configurations and register your
Transparent Proxy with the
system.
So your system knows how to run
your Transparent Proxy.
You also create a system
extension.
This is where your proxy will
run.
So these APIs allow you to proxy
flows of network data at the
flow layer.
To do this, you create a
subclass of NEAppProxyProvider.
Now, unlike content filter, by
default the system does not
divert any flows to your proxy.
So you must create a set of
NENetworkRules that specify what
flows you want to proxy.
So once your Transparent Proxy
is up and running and you've
installed your NENetworkRules,
as new TCP and UDP flows are
opened that match your rules,
those flows are diverted to your
NEAppProxyProvider subclass.
From there, it's up to you to
completely handle each
individual flow.
You can multiplex the flow over
another connection, apply your
special transformation, whatever
you need to do.
It's completely up to you.
So there's a brief overview of
how to use these Transparent
Proxy APIs in your app.
Next, let's take a look at DNS
Proxy Apps.
Now the DNS protocol is a great
protocol, very powerful and
useful.
But it's not very secure.
So it's pretty easy to spoof DNS
responses and cause browsers to
go to malicious websites or to
spy on somebody's Internet
browsing activity simply by
looking at the DNS queries that
they're sending.
So to address these
deficiencies, DNS Proxies apply
additional security to the DNS
Protocol.
For example, the app may apply
some encryption to DNS traffic
or a proxy DNS traffic over some
sort of secure channel.
So I'm pleased to tell you that
in macOS Catalina we've
introduced some great new APIs
that allow you to implement DNS
Proxy Apps without using Network
Kernel Extensions.
So these APIs are in the
NetworkExtension Framework.
They were actually introduced in
iOS 11, so in macOS Catalina we
brought them over and made them
available on the Mac.
Let's take a look at these APIs
and how they work in your app.
So in your main new IA app,
you'll use NEDNSProxyManager to
create your DNS Proxy
configuration, register your
configuration with the system so
the system knows how to run your
DNS Proxy.
You create a System Extension.
This is where your DNS Proxy
will run.
And you implement your proxy as
a subclass of the
NEDNSProxyProvider Class.
So once your DNS Proxy
configuration is registered with
the system, your system
extension is running, the system
will start diverting all DNS
queries to your
NEDNSProxyProvider Subclass.
From there it's totally up to
you to completely handle each
DNS query.
You can encrypt it.
You can send it over some sort
of secure channel.
It's totally up to you.
Alright. So that's an overview
of the DNX Proxy APIs.
Next I'm going to talk about VPN
Apps.
So the classic use case for VPN
Apps is to allow companies to
provide their employees with
secure remote access to their
internal corporate network.
Another use case that has grown
in popularity a lot in recent
years are personal VPN Apps.
So these are apps that are used
to securely and anonymously
browse the Internet.
So we actually introduced VPN
APIs on macOS back in macOS
10.10.
So in this release we've
enhanced those APIs to make them
even better.
Let's take a look at the VPN
APIs and how you use them in
your app.
So in your main UI app, you use
NETunnelProviderManager to
create VPN configurations and
register your VPN client with
the system.
You also create a System
Extension, which is where your
VPN client code will run.
You implement your VPN client as
a subclass of the
NEPacketTunnelProvider class.
The system creates a utun
interface corresponding to your
NEPacketTunnelProvider.
Your NEPacketTunnelProvider is
responsible for telling the
system about which networks you
want to be routed through your
VPN.
So once you've specified your
routing rules for your VPN and
those are installed in the
system, as IP packets get routed
to your utun interface per those
routes, those packets get
diverted to your
NEPacketTunnelProvider where you
can send those packets through
your tunnel connection using
your custom tunneling protocol.
Okay.
So there's a brief overview of
how the VPN APIs work.
Next I want to talk about a
couple of enhancements we've
made to the VPN APIs.
So the first is
IncludeAllNetworks.
This is a new flag you can set
on your VPN configuration.
This is particularly useful in
personal VPN apps.
In these apps, it's really
important that no traffic leak
outside of the VPN tunnel.
You want all your traffic to be
going through the VPN
[applause].
Yes.
So by enabling
IncludeAllNetworks on your
configuration, you cause this to
happen.
The system will route all
traffic through the VPN and if
the VPN is not available
temporarily for some reason --
for example, if the Mac is
switching between the WiFi
networks it's connected to or if
your VPN is just down for --
temporarily for whatever reason,
in those scenarios, traffic will
actually be dropped instead of
being routed outside of the VPN.
Now, if you've enabled
IncludeAllNetworks, but you
still want to allow access to
local network resources such as
printers, you can enable
ExcludeLocalNetworks to allow
that access to still happen.
Okay.
So we've also made some
enhancements to Per-App VPN.
We've added three new lists of
domains that you can use to
route traffic to your Per-App
VPN.
So the way these work is, for
each one of these lists, if the
corresponding app creates a
connection to a host and that
host domain matches one of the
domains in the list, that
connection's traffic will be
routed through the Per-App VPN.
Let's look at an example.
So, if you were using the Mail
App, and you have the Mail App
set up with two accounts -- you
have your personal e-mail
account and you have your
corporate e-mail account.
By specifying the domain of the
corporate e-mail server in the
mail domain's array, when Mail
opens up a new connection to
your corporate e-mail server,
that connection will be routed
through the Per-App VPN, while
connections to your personal
e-mail server will not be routed
through the Per-App VPN.
So the CalendarDomains and
ContactsDomains lists behave the
same way except for the Calendar
App and the Contacts App.
Okay.
So that was a brief overview of
the VPN APIs that are available
on macOS, and some enhancements
we've made that allow you to
create VPN Apps without the use
of Network Kernel Extensions.
Next, I want to talk about
Virtual Machine Apps.
So these are apps that create
and manage virtual machines.
And, honestly, a virtual machine
probably is not very useful if
it can't connect to the network.
So on macOS we have the
vmnet.framework that allows you
to do just that, connect virtual
machines to the network.
The vmnet.framework was
introduced on macOS back in
macOS 10.10.
But we made a lot of
enhancements in this release to
give you more ways to connect
virtual machines to the network.
The way the framework works is
it gives you several different
modes of connecting virtual
machines to the network.
We've made some enhancements to
Shared Mode.
You can now use IPv6 in Shared
Mode.
You can specify the range of IPs
you want to assign to your
virtual machines.
And you can set up Port
Forwarding Rules between your
virtual machines and the
network.
We've also added a brand new
mode called Bridged Mode.
In this mode your virtual
machines show up on the local
network as if they were
physically connected to the
local network.
Okay.
So that's a brief overview of
the Virtual Machine APIs you can
use to connect virtual machines
to the network.
Next, I want to briefly talk
about apps that use custom
low-layer protocols.
So one example of such an app is
an app that needs to communicate
with a piece of hardware such as
a camera or an audio device, and
that device only understands
some low-layer protocol like a
custom link-layer protocol or a
custom IP protocol.
Another example of an app that
uses a custom IP protocol, for
example, is an app that needs to
communicate with other machines
on a local network using some
highly-optimized protocol.
So I'm pleased to announce that
in macOS Catalina we've
introduced some new APIs that
allow you to communicate over
the network using custom
low-layer protocols without the
use of a Kernel Extension.
First, let's look at the API for
Custom IP Protocols.
This is a new API in a Network
Framework.
The way this works is in your
app you create a new kind of
NWParameters object specifying
the identifier number for your
custom IP protocol.
You then use that NWParameters
object to create an
NWConnection.
And you then use that
NWConnection just as you would a
TCP or UDP NWConnection to
communicate over the network
using your Custom IP Protocol.
For a lot more details about
NWConnection, please see last
year's talk, "Introducing
Network Framework."
Now let's look at a brief code
sample showing how to use this
Custom IP Protocol API.
So, first what I'm doing here is
creating an NWParameters object
using this new constructor that
takes in the identifier number
for a Custom IP Protocol.
Now, it's important to note here
that you must pass the
identifier number for a Custom
Protocol here.
You can't pass the number of a
protocol that the system is
already handling such as TCP,
UDP, or ICMP.
Next, I create the destination
that I want to communicate with
and I create the NWConnection,
passing in the destination and
my parameters.
So, from there I use the
connection just as I would any
other NWConnection, start the
connection, and I can start
sending/receiving packets using
my Custom IP Protocol.
Next, let's look at the Custom
Link Layer Protocol APIs.
These have also been added to
Network Framework.
The way this works is in your
app you create a
NWEthernetChannelObject
specifying the -- your custom
ether type that you're going to
be using.
You then use your Channel Object
to communicate over an Ethernet
Interface using your custom
ether type.
Let's look at some code to see
how this works.
So first I get a reference to
the current wired Ethernet
Interface.
Then I create my
NWEthernetChannel object passing
in the Interface and my custom
etherType.
Now, just like with the custom
IP Protocol API, you must pass a
custom etherType here.
You can't pass an etherType that
the system is already handling
such as IP or IPV6.
After creating the channel, I
set some callback blocks on the
channel.
The stateUpdateHandler block
gets called as the state of the
channel changes.
When the channel becomes ready,
I can go ahead and start sending
and receiving packets that use
my custom etherType.
The receiveHandler block gets
called when a new packet that
uses my custom etherType is
received from the network.
So after my channel is all set
up, I go ahead and start it so I
can start communicating using my
custom etherType.
Great.
So that was a brief overview of
the new APIs we've added that
allow you to communicate over
the network using custom
low-layer protocols without the
use of a Kernel Extension.
Alright.
So we've covered a lot of ground
here today, a lot of great new
APIs that we've added in macOS
Catalina that allow you to
create apps in all these
categories without the use of
Network Kernel Extensions.
So now I want to talk briefly
about the future of Network
Kernel Extensions.
So Network Kernel Extensions
have several problems.
First, they're hard to develop,
so I mentioned before if you're
testing out new functionality,
you probably have to reboot a
lot.
And also, in the case of Network
Kernel Extensions you frequently
have to work with some very
low-level concepts like doing
manual M-Buff Chain Manipulation
which is very tricky code.
It's very easy to get it wrong.
Also Kernel Extensions are hard
to debug.
You have to have two separate
machines and, as I mentioned
before, single stepping through
your code can be very tricky if
it works at all.
Also Kernel Extensions can -- a
stability problem in a Kernel
Extension can be really
catastrophic for the system.
So if your Kernel Extension
crashes, it just doesn't bring
down your app.
The entire system reboots, which
is extremely disruptive to the
user and can lead to serious
data loss.
So because of all these problems
with Kernel Extensions and
because we've reached this major
milestone on macOS where now we
have all these APIs that you can
use to create apps without the
use of Network Kernel
Extensions; in macOS Catalina,
we are officially deprecating
Network Kernel Extensions.
Now, your existing Network
Kernel Extensions should
continue to work just fine in
macOS Catalina.
However, we strongly urge you to
please check out all these great
new APIs that we've added and
start adopting them in your
apps, replacing your use of
Network Kernel Extensions.
It's important that you do this
as soon as you can because
before too much longer, we will
remove support for Network
Kernel Extensions entirely for
macOS.
Okay.
So today we talked about a bunch
of great new powerful APIs that
we have added in macOS Catalina
that allow you to create adapts
that filter network content,
proxy network content, tunnel
network content, connect virtual
machines to networks, and
communicate over the network
using custom low-layer
protocols, all without the use
of Network Kernel Extensions.
This is great news because we
strongly urge you to please
adopt these new APIs in your
Apps because Network Kernel
Extensions are now deprecated
and support for them will be
removed in a future release.
For more information, please
check out the webpage for this
session.
There you can find a link to the
sample simple tunnel code that I
demoed here today.
We also have a Networking Lab
that's actually going on right
now.
And so we'd love to see you
there to answer any questions
you may have.
Thank you so much for coming.
Enjoy the rest of your day.
[ Applause ]