[ Music ]
[ Cheering and Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. Welcome to Core NFC
Enhancements.
I hope everyone's had a great
WWDC this year.
And I hope everyone had a great
time at the bash yesterday.
My name is Gordon.
I'm a member of the NFC Software
team here at Apple.
A little bit later, we'll bring
up another team member,
Lawrence.
But let's talk NFC.
So two years ago, we introduced
the Core NFC framework to enable
NDEF Tag reading within your
applications.
And last year, we introduced
background tag scanning to
support the automatic discovery
of NDEF Tags and application
launching.
Now, however, since -- ever
since we've launched the Core
NFC Framework, developers have
been asking for one specific
thing.
And here at Apple, we've
listened to your requests.
And this year, we are super
excited to announce support for
both NDEF Tag writing and native
tag access.
[ Cheering and Applause ]
So yep, thank you.
[Chuckles]
[ Applause ]
So not only will your
applications be able to read and
write NDEF-formatted tags, but
you'll be able to interact with
tags using their native
protocols.
And this has a huge impact on
the kinds of things you can do
with NFC within your
applications.
For example, you can read
passports, contact with smart
cards, and interact with
NFC-enabled hardware.
And all this is available on
iPhone 7 and later phones.
So after we review the API
changes, we'll take a look at
how to write an NDEF tag within
your applications.
Then we'll dive into using
native tag access.
And finally, end up with a demo
showing all of this in action.
So let's take a look at the new
API changes.
As a quick review, the general
structure of the Core NFC
Framework remains the same as it
does today.
Your applications will retrieve
a reader session object from the
Framework.
And when that session becomes
active, you're free to go ahead
and perform NFC operations.
The tag-reading action sheet
will still be shown on-screen
anytime a reader session is
active.
And the new tag writing and
native tag access features are
available to your applications.
However, the background tag
scanning feature still requires
NDEF formatted tags and is
read-only.
Also, the existing 60-second
maximum scan time still exists
for each reader session.
So what is new?
So this year, there's a new NFC
tag-reader session which will
allow your applications to scan
for and connect to tags based on
their underlying technologies.
It will also allow you to stop
and restart the polling cycle to
discover new tags or to
reconnect if needed.
Also, the NFCNDEFReaderSession
has been modified to also
support tag writing.
Now, both of these sessions will
provide your applications with
NFC tag objects, allowing you to
use a new tag-based interface
when interacting with tags.
So here's a quick look at the
new tag protocols in Core NFC.
As you can see, there are
protocols for all the major
types.
NDEF, ISO7816, MIFARE, ISO15693,
and FeliCa.
Now, if you're not familiar with
all the various NFC
technologies, I would suggest
focusing first on NDEF.
So let's go over the basic steps
of how to use these new features
in Core NFC.
First, you'll need to enable the
entitlement in Xcode, just as
you do today.
So here's an example of an
application enabling the NFC
capabilities.
There are no special permissions
required to do this.
And as you can see here, there
are two different capabilities,
one for NDEF, and one for native
tag access.
So next, you'll need to decide
what your application requires,
NDEF or native access, and use
the appropriate reader session.
You'll need to implement the new
protocol delegate callbacks to
receive the new tag objects.
Once you have the tag object,
you use the reader session to go
ahead and connect to the tag.
At that point, you're free to go
ahead and perform all your
interactions using the tag
object.
And finally, when you're done,
invalidate the session and
release your tag.
All right.
So as I mentioned, if you're new
to NFC, start first with the NFC
Data Exchange Format, or NDEF.
It is the easiest way to add NFC
capabilities to your
applications.
The new tag running support
allows for quick implementation
and prototyping using any --
NDEF-formatted tag regardless of
its type.
As an example, an NDEF tag can
be used in the same manner as a
QR code and can easily be
integrated into many existing
use cases.
To extend that even further,
using the new tag-writing
support in NFC, you can create
NFC tags that are compatible
with background tag scanning
directly from iOS.
So let's take a look.
[ Applause ]
Yeah. Thank you.
Let's take a closer look at just
how simple it is to write an
NDEF tag within your
application.
So as I noted, you'll need to
use the NFCNDEFReaderSession for
this.
And you'll need to implement the
new didDetect tags callback
method to receive the NDEF tag
objects.
This will allow your application
to do various things, such as
query the NDEF-related
information about the tag,
including its maximum capacity,
and determine whether the tag is
writeable or not.
You'll be able to read the NDEF
message, write the NDEF message.
And if the tag supports it, even
lock the tag so that it can no
longer be rewritten.
So let's take a look at some
code.
To start writing an NDEF tag, we
instantiate our
NFCNDEFReaderSession.
We provided our new delegate.
And we set the
invalidateAfterFirstRead
parameter to false.
Next, when a tag is discovered,
we receive it in our new
Delegate callback method here.
Once we have a tag, we then send
it to the reader session's
Connect method to go ahead and
connect to the tag.
Now at this point, your tag will
remain connected until you
either connect to a different
tag, restart polling, or
invalidate your session.
So the next step here, after
we've connected to the tag, we
go ahead and query the NDEF
information.
If the tag returns a read-write
status, then we're free to go
ahead and write a new message to
the tag.
So the next step here.
We create an NFC NDEF message
with our payload and then send
it to the tag's writeNDEF method
to update the tag.
Finally, when we're all done, we
call the invalidate method.
This will terminate all NFC
operations and end our session.
And that's it.
Pretty simple, right?
This is all it takes to write an
NDEF tag within your app.
Now there might be some use
cases where you need to interact
with tags that are not NDEF
formatted.
And for that, we'll need to go
ahead and use native tag access.
So let's dive into that.
We'll start first with ISO7816.
The ISO7816 interface is used in
Type A and Type B NFC tags.
And it's used in a variety of
different use cases, including
electronic IDs such as
passports, access, contact with
smart cards, payments, and
transit systems.
Tags that support 7816 utilize
the Application Protocol Data
Unit interface.
This is commonly referred to as
APDU.
And your applications will be
able to send and receive APDU
commands using the 7816 tag
objects.
Now there are a few special
requirements for interacting
with 7816 tags.
So let's go over those first
before we look at some code.
First, your application will
need to add an entry into its
info.plist file that declares
the specific application
identifiers, or AIDs, which your
application intends to use.
Next, once Core NFC has
discovered a tag, it will first
check to see if that tag
supports an AID listed in your
application's info.plist file.
It does this by trying to select
each AID in turn until it finds
a match.
At that point, the Delegate
callback will be invoked, and
you will receive the tag object
with that AID preselected.
However, at this point, you're
free to go ahead and select any
other AID listed in your
info.plist file.
Now, we're excited about these
new features in Core NFC.
However, for the time being,
reading payment cards will not
be supported.
So here's an example of an
application info.plist file
listing the AIDs it intends to
use.
Here, you can see the
application is listing the AID
for NDEF operations.
So now, we'll take a look at the
actual 7816 tag object.
The protocol has properties that
are specific to the 7816
technology.
You can see the attributes here
include the unique identifier
and the historical bytes.
So is anyone excited about the
unique ID here?
This is the second-most popular
request that we get.
There's also a sendCommand
method for transmitting any form
of APDU to the tag and receiving
the response.
So to start scanning the 7816
tags, as I mentioned, the first
thing that we'll need to do is
implement a Delegate object
which conforms to the
NFCTagReaderSession Delegate
protocol.
There are only three required
methods, and you can see them up
here.
So to start scanning for 7816
tags, we instantiate our
NFCTagReaderSession object,
provide it our delegate, and set
the polling option to ISO14443.
This is the underlying NFC
technology for Type A and Type B
tags.
Next, when Core NFC discovers a
tag that has a matching AID, we
receive it in our Delegate
callback.
And once we're assured that we
have a 7816 tag, we use the
reader's session.connect method
to go ahead and connect to the
tag.
And finally, after we're
connected, we create an APDU
using the helper class and use
the same command method of the
tag to transmit the APDU and
receive its response.
Now during the transaction, we
may find an application-related
error has occurred, and we
should not continue.
As an example, imagine we're
trying to read a passport.
And it turns out we don't have
the proper credentials, or we've
calculated the password
incorrectly.
In a scenario like this, we
would really like to indicate
this error to the user.
Calling the Invalidate method
with an error message will
invalidate the session, and an
error symbol, along with the
supplied error message, will be
shown on the action sheet UI
rather than a checkmark.
So here's an example of what
this error indication looks
like.
We'll see this later in the
demo.
But this is pretty great, right?
This is the third-most requested
feature we get.
[ Applause ]
And just for reference, here's
the existing success indication.
So that was 7816.
Let's move on to our second
technology, MIFARE.
MIFARE is the technology similar
to 7816.
And it's based on NFC Type A
tags.
MIFARE is a technology defined
by NXP and is used heavily in
ticketing and badging systems
throughout the world.
So the NFC MIFARE tag protocol
has properties similar to that
of 7816.
In addition, there's another
property of the MIFARE family.
This will indicate the specific
MIFARE tag type that has been
discovered.
It can be MIFARE Ultralight,
MIFARE Plus, or DESFire.
At this time, MIFARE Classic
tags are not supported.
There's also a method here for
sending any MIFARE command.
In addition, there's a
convenience method for sending
7816 APDUs for those tags, such
as DESFire and Plus, which will
support them.
So now, let's see this in
action.
Just start scanning for a MIFARE
tag.
We again instantiate our tag
reader session.
Again, we set our polling option
to ISO14443.
And we set the Delegate and Call
Begin.
Please note that a MIFARE tag
that supports a 7816 interface
and contains an AID listing the
applications info.plist file
will instead be returned as a
7816 object and not a MIFARE
object.
So at this point, when our
callback gets invoked, we
specifically check to make sure
that we have a MIFARE tag object
returned.
Once we're sure we have one, we
send it to the reader's
session.connect method and
connect to the tag.
And then use the tag to send a
MIFARE command.
Okay, so that's two of the four
technologies.
So let's look at ISO15693.
This is also known as type five
or vicinity tags.
And these are commonly used in
retail, industrial, and even
medical applications.
So once again, this protocol has
properties specific to the
ISO15693 technology.
Here, we also have the unique
identifier, as well as the
manufacture code and the serial
number.
And the command set for 15693,
if you have not seen it, is
quite large.
And the protocol has convenience
methods for some of the common
operations.
You can see them listed up here.
They cover reading and writing
single or multiple blocks,
locking blocks, select, and
reset.
Again, there's also a method for
sending any custom command.
You can construct any command
according to the ISO15693
specification and use that
method to send it.
You can go ahead and refer to
the specification for more
details.
So to start scanning for
vicinity tags, which should now
be looking very familiar to
everyone, we create our
NFCTagReaderSession, provide it
our delegate.
But this time, we changed the
polling option to ISO15693.
When Core NFC discovers a 15693
tag, again, we receive the tag
in our callback.
We again verify that we have the
proper tag type and then connect
to it using the sessions.connect
method.
And once connected, we use the
tag to issue a readSingleBlock
command.
So finally, we're on to our
fourth and final technology,
FeliCa.
FeliCa is a format defined by
Sony, and it's used heavily in
transit and payment systems
around Japan.
Now the FeliCa usage also has
some additional requirements.
Similar to 7816, your
application will need to add an
entry into the info.plist file
that declares the specific
FeliCa system codes your
application intends to use.
And for security and privacy
reasons, we're asking that these
be discreet FeliCa system codes
and not wildcard entries.
Again, similar to 7816, when
Core NFC discovers a FeliCa tag,
we'll first validate -- detect
that that tag contains a system
code listed in your info.plist
file.
If it does, you'll receive the
tag and the Delegate callback.
If it does not, the callback
does not get invoked, and your
application does not get
notified about the presence of
the tag.
So here's an example of an
info.plist file registering for
FeliCa system code reserved for
NDEF operations.
Again, taking a look at the
FeliCa tag protocol here, we see
properties specific to FeliCa.
We have the manufacturer ID, or
IDM, and the current selected
system code.
Also, there's a
sendFeliCaCommand method for
sending any FeliCa command to
the tag.
And this protocol also has
convenience methods for some of
the common FeliCa operations.
You can go ahead and refer to
Sony's FeliCa command
specification for more details.
So continuing what should now be
a very familiar usage model, we
instantiated an
NFCTagReaderSession, provide it
our delegate, and this time,
changed the polling option to
ISO18092, which is the NFC
technology for FeliCa.
So once Core NFC has discovered
a tag and found a matching
system code, we again receive
the tag object in our same
delegate.
We ensure that we have the
proper tag type we were
expecting and then connect to
the tag.
And then finally, we use the tag
to send a requestResponse
command.
So we've now covered NDEF tag
writing and interacting with
tags using all four of the
native technologies.
So at this point, I'm going to
bring Lawrence onstage and show
us a demo of all of this in
action.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; All right, thank you, Gordon.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome.
To demonstrate how Core NFC
Framework can be used in a
real-life example, let me take
you through a quick journey of
my imaginary fishmonger.
As a tech savvy fishmonger, I
have heard that the NFC
technologies can improve
customer engagement and also be
used in inventory management.
After listening on this great
presentation, I have decided to
create two applications to help
my business, The Great Fish
Company.
I'm going to use NFC in two
ways.
First, I'm going to create NFC
NDEF tags to describe my
product.
And second, I'm going to create
coupon tags using MIFARE
Ultralight tags, which is also
known as NFC Type II tags.
Here is an overview of how we
deliver our products.
After we catch our fish, we
integrate NFC NDEF tag to
describe the catch.
The message contains the fish
they have catch, the fish name,
and the price.
The tag is then attached to the
product packaging and eventually
gets delivered to our customers.
The first application that I'm
going to create is called the
Fish Tag Creator.
This is what it looks like here.
Once I've entered all the
information into my app, I can
click on the Write to Tag button
to write to the NDEF tag.
The Fish Tag Creator application
also allows me to create NFC
coupon codes to promote my
business.
I use a MIFARE Ultralight tag to
store the special coupon code
and send it to my customers.
Here, I can select one of the
three possible coupon values to
write.
The second application that I
create is called a Fish Tag
Reader.
My customer will be able to
download this app from the App
Store to read the NDEF fish tag
that come with their purchase.
In the first panel, we have the
Click Scan button to scan the
fish tag that comes with the
fish.
The app would then display the
information stored it on the
tag.
In the second panel, we can
click on the Scan Coupon button
to read our MIFARE Ultralight
fish tag -- coupon tags.
Customer can redeem this coupon
in their future purchase.
Now let's take a look at both of
these apps in actions.
All right.
I have basically put the -- the
Fish Tag Reader app right --
creator app right now.
Today I brought with me a
creative rainbow salmon with me.
[ Chuckling ]
Let me first select today's
dates and the fish name, which
is Creative Salmon.
Okay, this one is definitely the
large size, right?
[ Multiple Voices ]
So now I click on the Write to
Tag button.
The action sheet will be shown.
And now, at this point, I can
hold my phone near the NDEF tag.
Bingo.
Now let me next then create a
coupon tag for your audience
here.
I'm going to select Create
Coupon button.
I'm going to choose a 50% off
since, you know, this is a
special WWDC promotion, right?
[ Cheering and Applause ]
All right, so let's click on the
button.
The action sheet again will be
shown on the screen.
And now, I can hold my iPhone
near the coupon tag.
Voila!
Okay, so now let's switch over
to the NFC Tag Readers app to
retest all my NFC tags.
Here, I have the app open.
I'm going to press on the Scan
Tag button and read my NDEF fish
tag.
The description of the product
is now displayed on the screen.
Wow, that's cool.
Alright. Now let me try to scan
the coupon tag.
This is done by selecting the
second panel and clicking on the
Scan Coupon button.
All right, yeah.
This is the fish 50% off coupon.
Okay, so now let me try to read
the second coupon again.
Okay, this is not a valid
coupon.
So after seeing both of these
are running in actions, let me
switch over to the source code
and take a look at how this is
implemented.
All right, let's walk through
the Fish Tag Creative Offers.
Here, I'll set the NDEF and
native tag capabilities in my
entitlement file.
This is because I'm going to use
both the NDEF and tag readings
-- reader session in my
application.
Now let's take a look at the
Main View controller to see how
they NDEF writer is being
implemented.
In the --
Sorry, one second here.
In the Write Tag Action
function, we have to instantiate
an NFCNDEFReaderSession.
We set the alert message and
call the Begin Method to start a
session.
When an NDEF tag is found, it is
going to be sent to the Delegate
function.
We connect to the tag and call
queryNDEFStatus.
If the tag is writeable and has
sufficient storage, we call the
writeNDEF function to write to
the tag.
Finally, we call the
invalidateFunction to end the
session.
Now let's take a look how a
coupon is created.
Here, we have the createCoupon
action function.
We instantiate a
TagReaderSession object.
We call the setAlert message and
call beginFunction to start a
session.
Here, we are looking
specifically for a MIFARE
Ultralight coupon tag in the
Delegate function.
When a tag is actually found, we
connect to it and start the
write operation.
To write to the tag, we
basically create a coupon code
and then call sendMIFARE command
to start a write operation.
When all write operations are
completed, we invalidate the
session.
We have used both NDEF and
native tag reader session to
create NFC tags.
Now let's take a look together
with the Fish Tag Reader app.
The NFCTagReaderSession has
convenience methods to perform
NDEF operations.
This is what we use here.
However, it's required us to add
the 7816 AID and Type F system
code into the -- for the NDEF in
our info.plist file, which is
shown here.
Now in the Scan View controller
--
We have the scan tag action
function.
Here, we create a
TagReaderSession, set the alert
message, and call begins to
start the -- write the Reader
action function.
When an NFC tag is found, it is
then delivered to our Delegate
callback.
We connect to the tag and
perform NDEF status query.
If the tag is readable, we call
readNDEF method.
Now let's -- finally, we
actually invalidate the session
by calling Invalidate.
Now let's take a look how we
read a coupon tag.
Here, we have a ScanCoupon
action function.
And just like before, we
instantiate a
NFCTagReaderSession object.
We set the alert message.
And we start a session by
calling the Begin.
When a tag is found, we check to
see if it's a MIFARE Ultralight
tag.
If it is, we connect to the tag.
To read from the tag, we call
the sendMIFARE command.
We then validate the queue
point.
At the end, we call the
Invalidate method to end the
session.
If the coupon is invalid, we
call invalidateErrorMessage
instead.
Now that's everything that you
need in order to create a great
app using the Core NFC
Framework.
Back to Gordon.
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Lawrence.
So we hope the new tag writing
and native access allows you to
add awesome new features to your
applications.
As we've seen, it's pretty
straightforward and pretty
simple.
Let's do a quick review of what
we've gone over today.
First, decide which type of
reader session your application
has required.
NDEF, native access, or even
both.
Implement the newDelegate
methods to receive the new tag
objects.
Once you have those tag objects,
go ahead and perform all your
reads and writes using those
objects.
And when you're all done,
indicate the proper success or
error indication using the
appropriate Invalidation call.
And that's it.
So all the sample code that we
have gone through today is
available to you online now,
along with other information.
iOS 13 is available now along
with Xcode 11.
Everybody should go ahead
download that and use Core NFC
to start doing awesome, new
things.
And if anybody has questions,
the Core NFC Lab is immediately
following this session over in
the labs.
So come talk to us and say
hello.
[ Cheering and Applause ]