[ Music ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. My name is Simon
Gladman and I'm with the Vector
and Numerics group.
In this presentation, I'll be
talking about two topics.
First, our new Swift Overlay for
Accelerate.
And second, measuring
Accelerate's performance using
the Linpack benchmark.
Before we dive into the Swift
Overlay, let's recap exactly
what the Accelerate framework
is.
The primary purpose of
Accelerate is to provide
thousands of low-level math
primitives that run on a CPU and
support image and signal
processing, vector arithmetic,
linear algebra, and machine
learning.
Most of these primitives are
hand tuned to the
microarchitecture of the
processor.
This means we get excellent
performance and this performance
translates directly into energy
savings.
So, if you're an app developer
and you use the Accelerate
framework, not only will your
application run faster, but
you'll also use less battery
life.
We provide the primitives across
all of Apple's platforms.
This includes not only macOS and
iOS but watchOS and tVOS as
well.
This means your users are going
to have an overall better
experience.
Accelerate's libraries are
immensely powerful but up until
now, their interfaces weren't
that friendly to Swift
developers.
We've looked at four libraries
and created new Swift-friendly
APIs to make using Acclerate in
Swift projects really easy.
The four libraries we focused on
are vDSP that provides digital
signal processing routines
including arithmetic on large
vectors, Fourier transforms,
biquadratic filtering, and
powerful type conversion.
vForce that provides arithmetic
and transcendental functions
including trig and logarithmic
routines.
Quadrature, that's dedicated to
the numerical integration of
functions.
And vImage, that provides a huge
selection of image processing
functions and integrates easily
with core graphics and core
video.
Accelerate gets its performance
benefits by using vectorization.
To understand vectorization,
let's first look at a simple
calculation over the elements of
an array using scalar code.
If, for example, you're writing
code that multiplies each
element of one array with the
corresponding element in
another, and you're using a four
loop, each pair of elements are
separately loaded, multiplied
together, and the results
stored.
So, after the first elements in
A and B are multiplied together
to calculate the first element
in C, the second pair are
processed.
Then, the third.
And, finally, the fourth.
However, if you're processing
the elements of an array using
Accelerate, your calculation is
performed on single instruction
multiple data, or simD
registers.
These registers can perform the
same instruction on multiple
items of data by packing those
multiple items into a single
register.
For example, a single 128-bit
register can actually store four
32-bit floating point values.
So, a vectorized multiply
operation can simultaneously
multiply four pairs of elements
at a time.
This means that not only will
the task be quicker, it will
also be significantly more
energy efficient.
The multiply function we just
looked at part of Accelerate's
digital signal processing
library, vDSP.
So, let's begin by looking at
how the new Swift API simplifies
using vDSP.
vDSP provides vectorized digital
signal processing functions
including Fourier transforms,
biquadratic filtering,
convolution, and correlation.
Furthermore, vDSP also provides
some powerful, more general
functions including element-wise
arithmetic and type conversion.
So, even if you don't have an
immediate need to, for example,
compute the coherence of two
signals, you may find that
vDSP's general computation
routines offer a solution to
improve your app's performance.
Let's take a look at some basic
arithmetic.
An example could be given four
arrays of single-precision
values, you need to calculate
the element-wise sum of two of
the array's the element-wise
difference in the other two, and
multiply those results with each
other.
Using a four loop is a perfectly
reasonable solution to this
problem and calculates the
expected results.
Here's how you perform that
calculation using vDSP's classic
API.
Using vDSP is approximately
three times faster than the four
loop.
Here's the same computation
using our new Swift API for
vDSP.
We're exposing the new
Swift-friendly functions through
our vDSP namespace and you can
see the function and parameter
names explain the operation.
Because the new functions work
with familiar types including
arrays and array slices rather
than pointers, you no longer
need to explicitly pass the
count.
So, the entire function call is
clearer and more concise.
Passing an initialized result
array offers the best
performance and you can
obviously reuse that array in
other operations for further
performance benefits.
However, we're also providing
self-allocating functions.
These make use of Swift's new
ability to access an array's
uninitialized buffer to return
the result of a computation.
Although not quite as fast as
passing existing storage, it's
still faster than the scalar
approach and, in some cases,
will simplify your code.
Another common task that vDSP
can vectorize is type
conversion.
This example converts an array
containing double precision
values to 16-bit unsigned
integer values rounding toward
zero.
The scalar version uses map with
explicit rounding.
Again, this is a perfectly
reasonable technique to use, but
vDSP can vectorize this task to
improve performance.
In this example, vDSP is
approximately four times faster
than the previous scalar
implementation.
The new Swift version of the
vDSP function offers a clear
interface.
The function accepts a source
array.
The integer type you ought to
convert each element to, and an
enumeration to specify the
rounding.
vDSP provides Fourier transforms
for transforming one-dimensional
and two-dimensional data between
the time domain and the
frequency domain.
A forward Fourier transform of a
signal decomposes it into its
component sign waves.
That's the frequency domain
representation.
Conversely, an inverse transform
of that frequency domain
representation recreates the
original signal and that's the
time domain representation.
Fourier transforms have many
uses in both signal and image
processing.
For example, once an audio
signal has been forward
transformed, you can easily
reduce or increase certain
frequencies to equalize the
audio.
The classic API is reasonably
easy to follow if you're
familiar with it.
You begin by creating a setup
object specifying the number of
elements you want to transform
and the direction.
Then, after creating two arrays
to receive results, you call the
execute function.
Once you're done, you need to
remember to destroy the setup to
free the resources allocated to
it.
The new API simplifies the
instantiation of the setup
object and the transform itself
is a method with parameter names
on the DFT instance.
And now you don't need to worry
about freeing the resources.
We do that for you.
And much like the vDSP functions
we've looked at, there's a
self-allocating version of the
transform function that creates
and returns the result's arrays
for you.
If you work with audio data, you
may be familiar with biquadratic
or biquad filtering.
Biquad filters can be used to
equalize audio to shape the
frequency response, allowing you
to, for example, remove either
low or high frequencies.
vDSP's biquad feature operates
on single and multichannel
signals, and uses a set of
individual filter objects called
sections.
The filters are cascaded; that
is, they are set up in a
sequence and the entire signal
passes through each filter in
turn.
The filters are defined by a
series of coefficients that plug
into the equation shown here.
In this example, these values
form a low pass filter; that is,
a filter that reduces high
frequencies.
Here's the code using vDSP's
classic API to create the biquad
setup using the coefficients in
the previous slide.
And here's the code to apply
that biquad filter to an array
named signal, returning the
result to an array named output.
Let's look at the same
functionality implemented with a
new API.
As you can see, the new API
vastly simplifies the creation
of the biquad structure.
You simply pass the coefficients
to the biquad initializer and
specify the number of channels
and sections.
Applying the biquad filter to a
signal is a single function
call.
Now, let's look at the new API
we've created for Accelerate's
library for fast mathematical
operations on large arrays,
vForce.
vForce provides transcendental
functions not included in vDSP.
These include exponential,
logarithmic, and trig
operations.
A typical example of vForce
would be to calculate the square
root of each element in a large
array.
The scalar version of this code
could use map.
vForce provides a vectorized
function to calculate the square
roots that in some situations
can be up to 10 times faster
than the scalar implementation.
The new Swift overlay offers an
API that's consistent with the
new vDSP functions and provides
the performance and energy
efficiency benefits of
vectorization.
And much like we've seen
earlier, there's a
self-allocating version that
returns an array containing the
square roots of each element in
the supplied array.
Next, we'll take a look at the
new API we've created for
Quadrature.
Quadrature is a historic term
for determining the area under a
curve.
It provides an approximation of
the definite integrative
function over a finite or
infinite interval.
In this example, we'll use
Quadrature to approximate the
area of a semicircle, shown here
in green, by integrating the
functions shown.
Much like the Biquad code for
vDSP, there's a fair amount of
code required to use the
existing Quadrature API.
The first step is to define a
structure that describes a
function to integrate.
The second step is to define the
integration options including
the integration algorithm.
Finally, with the function on
options defined, you can perform
the integration using the
Quadrature integrate function.
The new API simplifies the code.
One great advantage is that you
can specify the integrand, that
is, the function to be
integrated, as a trading closure
rather than as a C function
pointer.
This means you can easily pass
values into the integrand.
Also note that integrators are
now enumerations with associated
values.
So, there's no need to supply
unnecessary points for interval
or maximum intervals here.
For example, you can pass the
enumeration for the globally
adaptive integrator specifying
the points for interval and
maximum intervals.
Now, let's look at the new API
we've created for Accelerate's
image processing library,
vImage.
vImage is a library containing a
rich collection of image
processing tools.
It's designed to work seamlessly
with both core graphics and core
video.
It includes operations such as
alpha blending, format
conversions, histogram
operations, convolution,
geometry, and morphology.
Our new Swift API introduces
lots of new features that makes
using vImage in Swift easier and
more concise.
We've implemented flags as an
option set.
vImages throw Swift errors.
And we've hidden some of the
requirements for mutability and
working with unmanaged types.
If you're working with core
graphics images, there's a
common workflow to get that
image data into a vImage buffer.
First, you need to create a
description of the CG images
format.
Then, instantiate a vImage
buffer.
Initialize that buffer from the
image.
And finally, check for errors in
a non-Swift way.
And that's a lot of boilerplate
code for a common operation.
The new API wraps up all of that
code into a single throwable
initializer.
However, since we're going to
use a CG images format later,
here's similar functionality
implemented in two steps with a
new API.
We've added a new initializer to
CG image format using a CG
image, and an alternative buffer
initializer that accepts a CG
image and an explicit format
description.
Once you're finished working
with a buffer, here's the
classic vImage function to
create a CG image from the
buffer's contents.
And our new API simplifies that
operation too with a new create
CG image method that uses the
format we've just generated from
the image.
One important use case for
vImage is converting between
different domains and different
formats.
vImage's any-to-any convertors
can convert between core video
and core graphics, and convert
between different core graphics
formats.
For example, you might want to
convert a CMYK core graphics
image to RGB.
The existing API to create a
convertor accepts the source and
destination formats for the
conversion and returns an
unmanaged convertor.
You take the managed reference
of the convertor and pass that
to the function that does the
conversion.
Our new API adds a new static
make function to the existing
convertor type that returns a
convertor instance.
The conversion is done with the
convert method on the convertor
instance.
Finally, let's look at working
with core video image formats.
In a typical example, you may
want to create an image format
description from a core video
pixel buffer and calculate its
channel count.
Here's the code required by the
classic vImage API to create an
image format description from a
pixel buffer and get its channel
count.
The new API provides the same
functionality in two lines of
code.
You create an instance of a core
video image format from a pixel
buffer using a new static make
function.
And simply access its channel
count as a property.
That was a quick tour of a
fraction of the new API.
Let's now take a look at Linpack
Benchmark and see just how much
faster and more energy efficient
Accelerate can be.
The Linpack Benchmark came out
of the Linpack library which
started as a set of routines for
providing fast computational
linear algebra.
This was later subsumed by a
library called LApack, which
stands for Linear algebra
package.
LApack was developed to take
advantage of these new things at
the time called caches.
LApack is comprised of many
blocked algorithms.
These algorit6thms are built on
top of another library called
BLAS, which stands for basic
linear algebra subroutines.
We'll talk more about BLAS later
in this presentation.
For now, keep in mind that the
Linpack Benchmark runs on top of
LApack, which runs on top of
BLAS.
The Linpack Benchmark measures
how quickly a platform can solve
a general system of linear
equations.
It is comprised of two steps.
The matrix factorization step,
followed by the backsole step.
By fixing the algorithm, we're
able to see how well different
platforms are at running the
algorithm.
This provides us with a method
of comparing different
platforms.
The Linpack Benchmark has
evolved over time.
Originally, it solved a 100 by
100 system, and later a 1000 by
1000 system.
The variant most often used
today is the no holds barred
variant, where the problem size
can be as large as you want.
This is the variant we will be
running today.
We are now going to compare
Linpack performance on an iPhone
10S.
At the top in orange, we're
going to run an unoptimized
Linpack.
This Linpack Benchmark does not
make use of the accelerate
framework.
It relies on software that is
not tuned to the process that it
is running on.
Let's see what that looks like.
We are now going to compare that
with using the Accelerate
framework; that is, we're going
to run the same benchmark on the
same platform, but using the
Accelerate framework which is
tuned to the platform.
We can see that by using the
Accelerate framework, we are
over 24 times faster.
This will not only save time,
but also energy, which improves
battery life.
We're now going to shift gears
and take a look at the primary
workhorse routine for the
Linpack Benchmark called GEMM.
As I mentioned earlier, Linpack,
which runs on LApack, is built
on top of BLAS.
Within BLAS is a routine called
GEMM, which stands for general
matrix multiplier.
This routine is used to
implement several other blocked
routines in BLAS, which are used
inside the blocked algorithms at
LApack, most notably the matrix
factorization and solver
routines.
Because of this, GEMM is
sometimes used as a proxy for
performance.
For this presentation, we are
specifically going to look at
the single-precision variant of
GEMM.
Here, we're going to compare the
performance of the Eigen library
with that of Accelerate.
Both the Eigen library and the
Accelerate framework will run on
top of an iPhone 10S.
Both will be performing a
single-precision matrix
multiplier.
Let's see how well Eigen does.
Eigen tops out at about 51
gigaflops.
Now, let's see how well
Accelerate does.
We can see that the Accelerate
framework is almost two and a
half times faster than Eigen on
the same platform.
This is because the Accelerate
framework is hand-tuned to the
platform, allowing us to fully
take advantage of what the
platform can offer.
So, if you're a developer, using
Accelerate in your app will
offer better performance.
This performance translates into
less energy, which means better
battery life and an overall
better experience for your
users.
In summary, Accelerate provides
functions for performing
large-scale mathematical
computations and image
calculations that are fast and
energy efficient.
And now we've added a
Swift-friendly API that makes
Accelerate's libraries super
easy to work with so your users
will benefit from that
performance and energy
efficiency.
Please visit our site where we
have samples, articles, and
extensive reference material
that covers the entire
Accelerate framework.
Thank you very much.