[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
&gt;&gt; Hi. I'm Jay.
I'm a designer on the Siri and
Shortcuts team.
And today, we'll be talking
about how to design great
shortcuts for your apps.
We're going to cover three main
topics today.
First, I'll talk about looking
at all the use cases of your
app, and deciding which ones
might make sense as shortcuts.
Then, I'll talk about how to
make these shortcuts
discoverable in your apps.
And, finally, I'll walk through
how to design a great Siri
experience for the new
interactive capabilities of
shortcuts in iOS 13.
Now, stepping back for a moment,
shortcuts in general are a great
way to bring your app's
functionality in front of more
users in more places in the OS.
So, let's take a look at the
places where your apps'
shortcuts can appear to get a
feel for what might be useful.
If you tell the system when the
user does something in your app,
the system can automatically
suggest a shortcut when it
predicts the user will next want
to do that action.
And, these shortcuts can appear
in lock screen and search.
Here, this shortcut lets you
quickly start a guided workout,
you usually do at this time of
day.
If a user adds a shortcut to
Siri, by assigning it a custom
phrase, they can invoke it at
any time with their voice.
Here, the shortcut lets them
order their usual dinner.
In one quick confirmation step,
the user can get some great
Mediterranean food.
Another great use for shortcuts
with Siri is getting information
hands- and eyes-free.
So, to your HomePod, if you have
a transit app shortcut, you can
say, Hey Siri, bus schedule.
And, Siri will speak out the bus
schedule information from your
app.
And, you can also incorporate
your app's functionality as part
of a multi-step shortcut.
Here, the shortcut handles your
evening routine, ordering soup
in time for your arrival home,
playing your favorite music for
your car ride, and showing the
fastest directions.
So, looking at these examples,
we can see that shortcuts are
great for accelerating
frequently used, useful actions
your app can do.
Presenting information at a
glance, or with your voice, or
as building blocks for powerful
multi-step shortcuts, where your
app can work alongside others.
We introduced Siri shortcut
suggestions in iOS 12, so look
back at past sessions for more
information on how to develop
great shortcuts to be
automatically suggested on lock
screen and search.
Today, I'm going to focus on how
to make shortcuts to take
advantage of the new Siri
capabilities in iOS 13.
We're going to walk through how
to prioritize the features in
your app that might make for
good Siri shortcuts.
To do that, let's take a look at
one of our favorite apps,
SoupChef, which lets you order a
wide variety of soups for pickup
or delivery.
Let's walk through the design
process for making a SoupChef
shortcut.
List out all the things that
your app can do.
When doing so, start thinking
about things that a user might
want to repeat with their voice.
So, with SoupChef, you can do
things like browse the menu of
soups.
Order a soup.
Check your order status, or view
past orders.
Let's take a look at some of
these features one by one.
Browsing a menu is a very visual
activity that requires a lot of
structured information that
won't translate well to voice.
It requires scrolling, tapping,
and navigating.
And, it provides information
that isn't likely to change from
invocation to invocation.
And, it's more of a means to an
end, and not a valuable action
in and of itself.
So, this might not be a good
candidate for a shortcut.
Checking an order status could
be something a user might want
to do with their voice, getting
a quick summary of information
from Siri.
But, it's also only applicable
for a narrow window of time,
right after a user's ordered
something.
So, this is something that you
could consider allowing users to
turn into a shortcut, but maybe
only if your delivery periods
are long, or have multiple
phases.
And viewing past orders is nice
to have, but I don't know about
you, I'm not regularly checking
that.
So, not a great shortcut.
Ordering a soup is a very
valuable activity.
In fact, the most important
activity of your app.
And, you can imagine it being
repeatable if a user has a
favorite soup.
So, let's call this a pretty
good candidate for a shortcut.
So, in summary, a great use for
shortcuts will be something that
is valuable, or interesting to
repeat.
Doable with your voice by not
relying on visuals or tapping.
And, invokable in many contexts.
So, the shortcut isn't just
applicable during a small window
of time.
So, now that we know that we
want users to be able to reorder
soup with shortcuts, let's take
a look at how we might make that
discoverable in your app.
We provide a standard Add to
Siri button, that makes it easy
for users to see what features
in your app can be turned into a
Siri shortcut.
But use it thoughtfully.
Don't do this, where you put an
Add to Siri button on every item
on your main menu.
As beautiful as the button is on
its own, repeating it like this
looks ugly, and it's not really
relevant here.
The user's probably just trying
to make an order in the first
place.
And, these buttons are getting
in the way.
And, these could be items that
the user has never ordered
before.
So, it doesn't make sense to
suggest reordering them just
yet.
Instead, look at opportunities
where you can present it in a
focused UI, where you have a
clear signal that a user might
want to repeat something.
For example, it might be better
to show an Add to Siri button
right after a user has ordered
something.
The logic being, if a user's
found it good enough to order
before, the user's more likely
to want to order it again.
And, you're not interrupting
anything a user's trying to do.
They just finished their order,
so this is a good opportunity.
To make the Add to Siri button
fit in to your app's visual
appearance even better, you can
now customize the corner radius
of the button.
And, you can have its appearance
automatically change based on
the user's light or dark mode
preference.
Now, if you've tried really
hard, like really hard, and the
button's visual style doesn't
fit into your app, you can make
your own button.
But, you should replicate all of
Add to Siri's functionality.
The standard Add to Siri button
shows the user's shortcut phrase
once configured.
And, this is a good way to
remind the user what they can
say to run the shortcut.
Tapping on it will reveal a
standard sheet which allows the
user to edit or delete the
shortcut.
If you want a centralized place
in your app where you list all
your shortcuts, it might be too
much to have the Add to Siri
button on every row, like we saw
earlier.
So, instead, you're free to use
standard UIKit elements.
Just make sure that when a user
sets up a shortcut, just like
the Add to Siri button, you show
the phrase the user has set up
the shortcut with.
Tapping on it should also reveal
the sheet, where you can edit or
delete the shortcut.
So, let's get back to users
setting up the shortcut for the
first time.
Once the user taps on the Add to
Siri button, they'll see the Add
to Siri sheet, where the user
can choose what phrase to use to
invoke the shortcut.
In iOS 13, your app can pre-fill
a shortcut of your own choosing.
And, most users will probably
just assign this phrase if you
provide it, so make sure you
provide a good default.
Order Soup is a good, short,
memorable phrase in this case,
that the user might want to
genuinely want to use for the
shortcut.
Let's take a look at another
example, and take a break from
soup for a while.
Checking the bus schedule.
While this might look like a
sensible phrase, given how
relatively short it is, there
are plenty of opportunities for
the user to forget words, or
switch words around.
They might try to say, Look up
the bus schedule.
Or, the bus schedule for the 35.
Or, just drop the "the"
altogether.
While Siri will do its best to
match these to the phrase, users
can still get pretty creative
when trying to recall longer
phrases.
So, this might not be the best
suggested phrase.
Instead, keep it short, at
around three or fewer words.
Try limiting it to a proper
noun, or just a verb and an
object.
This reduces the chance that
users will mix up word order, or
use different prepositions.
OK.
A user wants to set up a
shortcut for ordering tomato
soup.
But, what if the user wants the
shortcut to do something
slightly different every time,
like order a different soup.
In iOS 13, users can tap on the
cell under the Do area, and
customize how much information
is pre-baked into the shortcut
by simply tapping on one of the
fields.
The user can choose to leave
certain fields blank, like the
type of soup itself.
And, when they do that, Siri can
ask for this missing information
on your app's behalf.
Now, ideally a shortcut has very
minimal interaction.
After all, it should accelerate
people to something that they do
frequently.
So, when you present the ad to
Siri sheet, the action should
include as much information as
possible, to run the shortcut
with just one or two steps.
In this case, this shortcut goes
straight to the confirmation
screen, because everything is
already specified.
But, what happens when a user
chooses to leave everything
blank, and wants to specify all
of the details of their order in
an interaction with Siri?
Let's take a look at how we
might design a complete ordering
soup interaction with Siri.
Think about what information you
need to know in order to carry
out a soup request.
Like, the kind of soup it is.
Whether you're ordering for
delivery or pick up?
And, if you're ordering for
delivery, what location are you
delivering to, and if you're
ordering for pickup, what you're
picking up from.
To start thinking about the
order and manner in which you
might collect this information,
you should think of your app's
interaction as a conversation
between your user and Siri.
And, one way to visualize this
conversation is with a script,
which is useful for quickly
jotting down one conversational
path.
Of course, there isn't just one
path you can go down.
You should write down all of the
possible paths in which the
conversation might go.
For example, a user could say an
option that's not supported by
your app.
In that case, Siri should
probably indicate that to the
user.
Now, handing over a book of
scripts might get unwieldy as a
design specification, so, at the
end of the process, you'll
probably end up with something
more like this; a flow diagram
that covers all the possible
states and transitions within a
conversation.
Now, there are specific ways
that Siri can present choices,
and handle user input, so let's
dive straight into the
conversational patterns you have
at your disposal.
The first pattern that you have
is the prompt.
This is the most open-ended way
you can collect a value from the
user.
You should write your prompt as
a question, and phrase it in a
way that sets the user up for a
well-formed response.
When a user says something that
might mean multiple things to
your app, you can present an
option list which allows the
user to specify which one they
meant.
This is called a disambiguation
prompt.
You can minimize disambiguation
prompts, which add another step
to your conversation, by
presenting an option list up
front.
Notice that the user has said
their shortcut phrase, Order
Soup, and went straight to the
list.
You should use this instead of a
free-form prompt if there's a
constrained list of options to
choose from.
Make sure your prompt dialog
encourages choosing from a list.
Questions that start with the
word "which" work really well
here.
When using s shortcut without a
display, Siri will read out
options.
Like on AirPods, on HomePod, or
when the user says Hey Siri.
And, Siri will read these out as
you would provide them in your
visual UI.
But, you can imagine that this
could get verbose, especially if
a lot of the options are
similar.
To improve this experience, you
can separately specify how Siri
reads your options out loud, by
providing pronunciation hits
that you can add to each option.
Let's take a look at a slightly
different example.
The user has asked for Noodle
Soup.
And, there are two kinds.
Instead of saying Beef Noodle
Soup, or Veggie Noodle Soup, you
might want to just say Beef or
Veggie?
So, consider only reading out
the details that differentiate
between each item.
Now, conversations are a two-way
street, so you also have to
account for what the user might
say.
And, the user may not use the
exact words that you've labeled
the option with.
To handle natural variations in
responses, for each option, you
should provide Siri with
synonyms that mean the same
thing as that option.
So, when the user just says
Beef, it'll match to Beef Noodle
Soup.
When coming up with these
synonyms, you should also keep
in mind that the phrasing of
your question impacts the way
the user may respond.
So, if you have a more casual
way of describing the options,
like the one with meat, or the
vegetarian one, you should make
sure that you recognize the user
repeating that kind of phrasing
back to Siri.
If a user provides a response
that you want to be extra sure
about, like a value of
particularly high consequence,
you can provide a parameter
confirmation prompt.
But, use this judiciously, and
only for truly exceptional
cases, as this slows the user
down.
One alternative way of using a
parameter confirmation prompt is
if your app has its own logic
for predicting what a user might
want.
You can present your best guess
to the user, and they can either
confirm it, in which case, yay,
they don't have to provide
additional details.
Or, they can deny it, in which
case you can fall back to a more
open-ended prompt.
If you can guess what the user
wants, it's a great way of
making your shortcut interaction
even faster.
At the end of the flow, consider
using a confirmation prompt that
applies to the action as a
whole, particularly if the
action itself is of high
consequence.
In this step, you can confirm
all of the details of the action
about to be performed that's
relevant to the decision, like
price and delivery time in a
visual user interface that you
can fully customize.
Note that for actions in the
ordering category, the system
requires the user to confirm.
So, make sure, if you fall under
that category, you provide a
great confirmation experience.
But, remember that your shortcut
can be run by a user not looking
at a screen, so you should
provide dialog for voice-only
experiences.
In this case, we provide
additional dialog to help the
user make a choice.
The purpose of this additional
dialog is to provide information
that can't otherwise be
displayed in a visual user
interface.
So, think of this extra dialog
as a spoken equivalent of the
most important information you
would otherwise draw in a
display.
Finally, your response.
Siri will indicate the status of
the action.
You can provide a visual UI
summary here to describe
additional details, like who's
going to be delivering your
soup, and the latest estimated
delivery time.
Notice that we just say, "OK.
Ordered" here, because we're
using a display to show the
additional information.
For voice-only experiences, you
should specify a more
descriptive dialog.
And, again, think of this extra
dialog as a spoken equivalent of
the most important information
of the response UI you would
draw on a display.
When you're thinking about your
confirmation and response
dialog, you should keep in mind
that you'll need to select a
category for your shortcut.
When you define your shortcut in
Xcode, select the category that
is the closet match to your
shortcut's functionality.
In our SoupChef case, it's
pretty clear that the order
category fits the bill.
In confirmation prompts, Siri
will provide the question
itself, based on the category
you select.
So, don't include a question as
part of the confirmation dialog
you customize, highlighted in
white here.
In response dialog, Siri will
provide a status that is
appropriate to the category.
Your custom dialog gets appended
to the end of the dialog Siri
provides.
Voice interactions should also
be as robust as possible, to
avoid forcing the user to open
the app to continue manually.
For example, you should provide
clear error messages if a
parameter value is invalid.
Siri will then automatically
re-prompt for that value.
You should also avoid getting
yourself into this scenario in
the first place.
If you're presenting option
lists, make sure you don't
present any options that you
know to be invalid at runtime.
You should also consider
opportunities to dig users out
of holes.
Users may include values like
delivery location in their
shortcut, since it's usually
just their home, and so they get
used to not saying their
delivery location to Siri.
One day they might use the
shortcut when they're far from
home.
You should check for that case,
and prompt for a different
location.
And, for whatever reason, users
might want to continue running
the shortcut in your app.
They can tap anywhere in your UI
to do that.
So, when you present UI, keep in
mind that the whole area is one
big button that opens your app.
So, don't draw elements that
look individually interactable.
They can't be.
Make sure that when a user does
tap this area, your app opens up
to the right place, with all of
the information the user has
already provided up until that
point, filled out in the app.
And, finally, we encourage you
to take time when writing
dialog.
It's not something that you can
just do a quick pass at, to have
something to demo, and then
leave in your final shipping
product.
Remember, that in a voice
interaction, language is the
user interface.
So, you should treat the words
in your Siri interaction with as
much respect and care as you do
the pixels in your app.
With that said, let's walk
through a small set of
guidelines.
Don't be overly polite or inject
too much personality.
Users who want to customize
their soup will hear this
non-essential dialog every time
they run this shortcut, which
will get irritating.
When in doubt, test it.
Listen to Siri speak your
dialog.
How does your dialog feel to you
after the third time hearing it?
What about the 10th?
If parts of it feel annoying, it
might be a good signal that you
should reduce the verbosity of
your dialog.
Dialog should be concise,
neutral, and communicate the
type of response that you're
expecting.
Don't include your app name in
your dialog.
Your app will already be
attributed, visually, via your
confirmation and response UI,
and occasionally via Siri's own
additions.
So, just take your name out.
Don't worry, your brand is safe.
Similarly, you shouldn't include
your user's name in your dialog.
Siri may at times speak the
user's name on HomePod to verify
their identity.
If your app does so as well, it
might sound repetitive and
annoying.
So, just take your name out.
Avoid using first-person
pronouns, since Siri isn't
performing the action, your app
is.
It's a subtle distinction, but
it's an important one.
By saying "I" or "we" in Siri's
voice, users might think Siri
has a better understanding of
your app's capabilities than it
does, and might try to take
follow-up actions that your app
and Siri can't understand.
Instead, present options
neutrally, using words like
"here" or "there are a few
options."
So, what have we learned today?
Shortcuts are meant to elevate
your app's most repeatable
features.
You should use the Add to Siri
button to make sure users know
what they can turn into a
shortcut from inside your app.
You should make your Siri
interactions logical, concise,
and robust.
And, you should take extra care
when writing dialog.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]